<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
	<title>iZooto</title>
	<link>http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/izooto-1.712150?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout</link>	
	<atom:link href="http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/izooto-1.712150?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" ></atom:link>
	<description>Flash News</description>
			        <language>en</language>
    				<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Latifa bint Mohammed inaugurates fourth edition of ‘Al Marmoom: Film in The Desert’ festival]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/latifa-bint-mohammed-inaugurates-fourth-edition-of-al-marmoom-film-in-the-desert-festival-2025-01-05-1.736061</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/latifa-bint-mohammed-inaugurates-fourth-edition-of-al-marmoom-film-in-the-desert-festival-2025-01-05-1.736061</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Organised by Dubai Culture under the theme &lsquo;Where Stories Come to Life,&rsquo; event running until 12 January aims to support creative talent in the local film industry</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Her Highness: The festival celebrates the authenticity of Dubai&rsquo;s identity, its dynamic spirit, and future aspirations, fostering intellectual dialogue</strong></li>
	<li><strong>&ldquo;Cinema has the profound ability to shape generations rooted in values while addressing the aspirations and challenges of societies and preserving the rich history of nations&rdquo;&nbsp;</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Drawing inspiration from the Ghaf tree, the festival also features an array of musical performances, live shows, and heritage displays</strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p><br />
Her Highness Sheikha Latifa bint Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Chairperson of the Dubai Culture and Arts Authority (Dubai Culture), inaugurated the fourth edition of the &lsquo;Al Marmoom: Film in the Desert&rsquo; festival. Organised by Dubai Culture in the Al Marmoom Desert Reserve, the event seeks to advance the local film industry by providing an innovative platform that supports talented creatives, encouraging them to express their visions and showcase their works and productions to a wider audience.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The festival, an initiative under the Dubai Quality of Life Strategy 2033, features screenings of over 80 feature films. Running until 12 January under the theme &lsquo;Where Stories Come to Life,&rsquo; the event will also host interactive workshops, panel discussions, and talks with a distinguished group of directors, artists, and film industry experts.</p>

<p>Her Highness Sheikha Latifa emphasised that Dubai has excelled in attracting leading directors and talents in the film industry thanks to its extensive capabilities, state-of-the-art infrastructure, and unique creative environment that fosters innovation. She highlighted that, through its ambitious projects and initiatives, the emirate continues to enhance its global leadership, solidify its standing as a cultural and artistic capital, and establish itself as a premier destination for cinematic content creation and production.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Cinema is one of the most powerful expressions of human creativity, distinguished by its unique visual language that seamlessly blends technical mastery with artistic purpose. It has the profound ability to shape generations rooted in values while addressing the aspirations and challenges of societies and preserving the rich history and culture of nations,&rdquo; Her Highness said.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>She added: &ldquo;The Al Marmoom: Film in the Desert festival is a remarkable addition to Dubai&rsquo;s artistic and cinematic landscape through its exceptional cultural experiences and high-quality cinematic works, celebrating the authenticity of Dubai&rsquo;s identity, vibrant energy, and ambitious future aspirations.&nbsp;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Reflecting the beauty of our heritage, the essence of our culture, and the depth of our history, the festival&rsquo;s significance lies in its role as a catalyst for intellectual dialogue, a bridge for cultural exchange, and a source of inspiration for emerging talents. It nurtures creativity; encourages filmmakers to explore the latest industry trends, practices, and opportunities, contributing to fostering a new generation capable of advancing this vital sector, which stands as a cornerstone of Dubai&rsquo;s thriving creative economy.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>Immersive Experience Zone</strong></p>

<p>Sheikha Latifa took an elaborate tour of the festival, exploring, among other highlights, an Immersive Experience Zone. The zone showcased digital artworks created using Artificial Intelligence, in addition to inspiring murals, and installations featuring the work of artists Ghaleb Hawila, Abdullah Lutfi, and Mikhail Antykov.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Her Highness also visited the festival&rsquo;s dedicated pavilions for workshops, seminars, and family-friendly activities and the &lsquo;VIP Barzah&rsquo; area, where she engaged with artists participating in the event, commending their creativity and the diversity of their artistic works. She praised the powerful messages and concepts conveyed through their creations, which reflect a wide array of unique perspectives and artistic visions.</p>

<p>Audiences at the Al Marmoom: Film in the Desert festival will be able to enjoy a curated selection of films chosen from amongst 240 submissions, including notable entries competing for the Al Marmoom Short-Film Competition awards across four categories: documentaries, animation, live-action, and films made using Artificial Intelligence.</p>

<p>The festival&rsquo;s programme includes more than 30 workshops led by renowned creatives and cinema experts, including four workshops organised by the College of Arts and Creative Enterprises at Zayed University. It also offers a diverse array of seminars, panel discussions, and activities tailored to inspire young talents and encourage them to embark on professional careers across the cinema and the arts sectors.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Array of activities</strong></p>

<p>Inspired by the iconic Ghaf tree, the festival serves as a platform to strengthen intercultural engagement and raise environmental awareness by encouraging visitors to explore the Al Marmoom Desert, a treasured nature reserve and one of Dubai&rsquo;s key cultural landmarks. The event features a wide array of activities, including performing arts, musical and heritage shows, and interactive experiences such as &lsquo;Create Your Own AI Movie.&rsquo; Visitors can also visit the planetarium for a stargazing session, or take in the reserve&rsquo;s stunning landscapes on a safari bus tour. A photography competition is also sure to add to the excitement.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dubai Culture dedicates significant space to showcasing traditional crafts and elements of local heritage, reflecting its commitment to promoting cultural authenticity at artistic and cultural events across the emirate. Additionally, attendees can savour traditional cuisine in a heritage-rich and creatively designed setting.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The festival is held in collaboration with an extensive list of partners, including Dubai Mounted Police, Dubai Municipality, Dubai Ambulance, Dubai Police, Dubai Civil Defence, the Roads and Transport Authority, the Islamic Affairs and Charitable Activities Department in Dubai, Mohammed Bin Rashid Space Centre, The Climate Tribe, Lina Kattan, Emirates Airlines, Zayed University, Sandooq Al Watan, Emirates Photography Society, Maraya, Freej, Ferjan Dubai, and Immersee.&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 5 Jan 2025 19:12:41 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736062.1736089926!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_360/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736062.1736089926!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_360/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Latifa bint Mohammed inaugurates fourth edition of ‘Al Marmoom: Film in The Desert’ festival]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai Municipality awards contracts for second phase of Al Mamzar Beach Development Project]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/dubai-municipality-awards-contracts-for-second-phase-of-al-mamzar-beach-development-project-2025-01-05-1.736059</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/dubai-municipality-awards-contracts-for-second-phase-of-al-mamzar-beach-development-project-2025-01-05-1.736059</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Entailing a cost of AED400 million, the two-phase project, which includes a seasonal events area and world-class wellness facilities, is eyeing completion by the end of 2025</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Among other highlights, the project features a dedicated public beach for women with manifold privacy and safety considerations incorporated into its design</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Jogging, walking, and cycling tracks linking the creek and corniche areas aim to further elevate the visitor experience</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Badr Anwahi: We continue to work towards the vision of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum to make Dubai the world&rsquo;s best city to live, work, and visit</strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>In alignment with the directives of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister of the UAE and Ruler of Dubai, Dubai Municipality has awarded contracts for the second phase of Al Mamzar Beach Development Project. This phase focuses on developing the beachfront in Al Mamzar Corniche, with completion of both phases of the project expected by the end of 2025. The total cost of the project is projected to be around AED400 million across both phases.</p>

<p>The project aims to elevate beach infrastructure through innovative designs that seamlessly connect the creek and the corniche, creating a new beach tourism destination that meets international standards while adhering to sustainability principles and addressing future concerns regarding climate change. It seeks to redefine global beach design concepts by offering integrated beaches equipped with state-of-the-art recreational, sports and commercial facilities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>These enhancements align with the highest specifications and standards, reinforcing Dubai&rsquo;s position as a leading global tourism hub and underscoring its commitment to improving quality of life and well-being for all. Spread over 125,000 square metres and spanning 80 metres across, Al Mamzar Corniche Beach will feature a dedicated public beach for women. Keeping privacy and safety factors paramount, the facility will include a secure gated entrance and fencing. The ladies beach will also enable night swimming and offer tailored amenities such as a sports club, commercial services, and children&rsquo;s play areas.</p>

<p><strong>Novel design</strong></p>

<p>The public beach on Al Mamzar Corniche will also feature 1,000 metres of running, walking, and cycling paths linking Al Mamzar Creek Beach and Al Mamzar Park. This innovative design, the first of its kind in the region, provides a convergence of beach paths with park areas to offer visitors a unique and multifaceted experience. The development will also feature green spaces crafted to the highest standards of aesthetic landscaping. Facilities will include a 5,000-square-metre area for seasonal events and activities, a 2,000-square-metre skateboarding area, children&#39;s play areas, restrooms, and beach lounges.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dubai Municipality will also equip the corniche with public health and wellness facilities, including toilets, changing rooms, showers, and services for people of determination. An administrative building will house a control room and first aid centre. Smart services, including AI-supported surveillance systems, drowning rescue technologies, crowd management tools, and smart luggage lockers, will ensure a seamless visitor experience.</p>

<p>The corniche development also focuses on encouraging business opportunities, introducing waterfront restaurants, food and beverage outlets, beach seating, and spaces for recreational activities, ultimately fostering economic growth while providing visitors an enhanced experience.</p>

<p>Bader Anwahi, CEO of the Public Facilities Agency at Dubai Municipality said, &ldquo;We continue to work towards the vision of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum to make Dubai the world&rsquo;s best city to live, work, and visit. This project reflects our commitment to creating innovative, sustainable infrastructure that aligns with Dubai&#39;s future ambitions, solidifying its leading position across various vital sectors, and supporting the achievement of Dubai Economic Agenda D33 targets.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He added: &ldquo;The development of infrastructure projects for tourist and beachfront facilities is a key strategic objective of Dubai Municipality aimed at building a sustainable and attractive city that offers advanced tourism and recreational facilities. This enhances Dubai&#39;s appeal, elevating quality of life for all, and solidifies the emirate&rsquo;s position as a leading global tourist destination.</p>

<p>&ldquo;We are redefining concepts and standards for the design and development of beaches to align with the future and position them as the most advanced and appealing globally. Our goal is to showcase Dubai&rsquo;s uniqueness in implementing pioneering projects that combine advanced, sustainable infrastructure with modern, aesthetic designs. These projects provide top-notch services and facilities, offering exceptional tourism and recreational experiences that support the emirate&rsquo;s future economic and tourism agendas.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>First phase nears half-way stage</strong></p>

<p>The first phase of the development, work on which commenced in June last year, has achieved 45% completion. Covering an area of 275,000 square metres, the beach ranges in width from 30 to 90 metres at various points. The project includes the construction of a 200-metre-long pedestrian pontoon bridge to connect the two banks of the creek, ensuring ease of access for the public. It also features a 300-metre-long night swimming beach designed to be accessible for people of determination, along with a 5-kilometre walkway and dedicated running and cycling tracks along the beach. These enhancements aim to create an inclusive and vibrant community space for both residents and visitors.</p>

<p>The development also incorporates three children&rsquo;s play areas, two recreational zones, and comprehensive visitor facilities such as barbecue spots and jet ski marinas. In addition, the beach will feature eight toilet blocks, changing rooms, and shower rooms, with eight outdoor shower areas and 1,400 car parking spaces.</p>

<p>Dubai Municipality, which is tasked with the management of waterways and public beaches, aims to enhance recreational facilities across the emirate. By creating world-class tourism infrastructure, the Al Mamzar Beach Development Project will cater to the growing numbers of residents, tourists, and beachgoers, reinforcing Dubai&rsquo;s status as a premier destination for leisure and recreation.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 5 Jan 2025 19:00:36 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736060.1736089258!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_360/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736060.1736089258!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_360/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai Municipality awards contracts for second phase of Al Mamzar Beach Development Project]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid approves AED5.4 billion housing projects offering beneficiaries 3,004 new homes across Dubai]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-approves-aed5-4-billion-housing-projects-offering-beneficiaries-3-004-new-homes-across-dubai-2025-01-05-1.736056</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-approves-aed5-4-billion-housing-projects-offering-beneficiaries-3-004-new-homes-across-dubai-2025-01-05-1.736056</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong>His Highness emphasises that public wellbeing remains the end goal of all development plans and the primary driver of all government work&nbsp;</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Offering diverse choices for citizens, the projects are aligned with the Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme</strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister of the UAE and Ruler of Dubai, has approved the implementation of a series of housing projects worth AED5.4 billion to benefit citizens across different areas of Dubai.</p>

<p>The projects will see 3,004 new homes being built for Emirati citizens. Of these, 1,181 homes will come up in Latifa City for beneficiaries under the housing loan category. For beneficiaries in the housing grant category, the projects envisage 606 new homes in Al Yalayis 5, 432 homes in Wadi Al Amardi, 398 homes in Al Awir 1, 200 homes in the Makan area of Hatta, 120 homes in Oud Al Muteena, and 67 homes in the countryside and rural areas of Dubai.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The housing projects, offering diverse options for Emirati citizens, align with the Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme launched by Her Highness Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum bin Juma Al Maktoum, wife of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum. The programme aims to support the wellbeing of families in Dubai, strengthen their stability and cohesion, renew community values, enhance the overall quality of family life, offer a stimulating social environment, and help families achieve optimal work-life balance.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed emphasised that citizen wellbeing is the end goal of all development plans and the primary driver of all government work, besides being a key criterion in evaluating the success of development programmes and initiatives in the jobs, manufacturing, infrastructure, and services sectors.</p>

<p>His Highness said: &ldquo;Housing programmes for citizens represent a top priority and we are committed to ensuring that our people have the best living standards and all the support they need to foster stable family environments and community wellbeing. People are the foundation of our renaissance, our successful development experience, and the cornerstone of the global standing we have achieved in all respects.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>Comprehensive plan</strong></p>

<p>His Highness added that major housing initiatives will continue to be part of a comprehensive plan to fulfil the aspirations of citizens for stability and good living standards while helping achieve national strategies to drive ever greater prosperity and shape the future that the people of the UAE truly deserve.</p>

<p>His Excellency Omar Hamad Bu Shehab, CEO of the Mohammed bin Rashid Housing Establishment, said that the new housing projects embody the leadership&rsquo;s vision to offer citizens exceptional quality of life by providing an integrated residential environment that meets all their needs while ensuring the highest levels of comfort and safety.</p>

<p>He added: &ldquo;The housing projects plan is part of a series of projects implemented by the Mohammed bin Rashid Housing Establishment to provide for the future housing needs of Emirati citizens within integrated communities. These plans are implemented drawing upon the best urban planning standards, placing citizens at the forefront of all goals aimed at ensuring public wellbeing over the next 20 years.&rdquo;</p>

<p>According to the Dubai 2040 Urban Master Plan, housing programmes for citizens in Dubai aim to address future housing needs through optimal planning of available spaces in the emirate. This is achieved by ensuring the sustainability of available land in keeping with rigorous standards. A significant effort also goes into ensuring a diverse choice of housing units and communities offering the highest quality of life, with an accent on green spaces, recreational facilities and commercial centres.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 5 Jan 2025 18:53:28 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736058.1736088927!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_360/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736058.1736088927!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_360/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid approves AED5.4 billion housing projects offering beneficiaries 3,004 new homes across Dubai]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Three UAE aid convoys arrive in Gaza Strip as part of 'Operation Chivalrous Knight 3']]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/three-uae-aid-convoys-arrive-in-gaza-strip-as-part-of-operation-chivalrous-knight-3-2025-01-05-1.736054</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/three-uae-aid-convoys-arrive-in-gaza-strip-as-part-of-operation-chivalrous-knight-3-2025-01-05-1.736054</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Three UAE convoys loaded with various humanitarian aid crossed this week into the Gaza Strip through the Egyptian Rafah Border Crossing.</p>

<p>This is part of the UAE&#39;s efforts to support and provide relief to the Palestinians during the current circumstances in line with &quot;Operation Chivalrous Knight 3&quot;.</p>

<p>The convoys consist of 29 trucks carrying more than 364 tonnes of humanitarian aid. This includes food, winter clothing, shelter tents and other essential needs.</p>

<p>This brings the number of aid convoys that have entered the Gaza Strip through Egyptian border crossings as part of Operation Chivalrous Knight 3, to 150 convoys consisting of 2,319 trucks transporting more than 29,025 tonnes.</p>

<p>Since the start of the crisis, the UAE has provided 46,659 tonnes of urgent relief supplies to the Gaza Strip. This aims to contribute to alleviating the difficult conditions suffered by the people of Gaza.</p>

<p>Operation Chivalrous Knight 3 seeks to assist all affected groups in the Gaza Strip, especially children and women. The UAE is keen to intensify relief efforts and promote humanitarian work for Palestinians.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 5 Jan 2025 18:48:44 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736055.1736088511!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_360/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736055.1736088511!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_360/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Three UAE aid convoys arrive in Gaza Strip as part of 'Operation Chivalrous Knight 3']]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai ranks among world’s top 10 cities in Global Power City Index for second consecutive year]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/business/economy-finance/dubai-ranks-among-world-s-top-10-cities-in-global-power-city-index-for-second-consecutive-year-2025-01-05-1.736051</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/business/economy-finance/dubai-ranks-among-world-s-top-10-cities-in-global-power-city-index-for-second-consecutive-year-2025-01-05-1.736051</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Dubai has been ranked eighth worldwide and first in the Middle East in the Global Power City Index 2024 (GPCI) for the second year in a row.</p>

<p>In an annual study released by Japan&rsquo;s Mori Memorial Foundation, the index highlights Dubai&rsquo;s role as a leader in innovation, economic dynamism, and global connectivity.</p>

<p>This achievement makes Dubai the only city in the Middle East to feature in the top 10, reaffirming its position as a major global hub for business, talent, and investment.</p>

<p>H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister, Minister of Defence, and Chairman of The Executive Council of Dubai, attributed this achievement to the visionary leadership of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President, Prime Minister and Ruler of Dubai.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Dubai continues to redefine what is possible, combining innovation, sustainability, and a focus on nurturing talent,&rdquo; said Sheikh Hamdan. &ldquo;The city has created one of the world&rsquo;s best environments for businesses to thrive, creative ideas to take shape, and individuals to realise their aspirations while enjoying an exceptional quality of life. This achievement reflects not only visionary leadership but also the collective contributions of countless individuals who share a commitment to excellence.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The Crown Prince highlighted the key drivers behind Dubai&#39;s success, including its world-class infrastructure, which continues to attract global investment and top talent. He highlighted the city&rsquo;s flexible and progressive legislative framework, designed to foster innovation and adapt to evolving global trends.</p>

<p>He also underscored the importance of Dubai&rsquo;s strong public-private sector partnerships, which have created a dynamic ecosystem for collaboration and growth.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Dubai&rsquo;s high ranking on global indices shows that we are not just keeping pace with the world, we are setting new benchmarks for excellence,&rdquo; he added.</p>

<p>Reaffirming Dubai&#39;s commitment to sustainable growth, Sheikh Hamdan said, &ldquo;We remain steadfast in our efforts to consolidate Dubai&rsquo;s global status as a city of the future. By embracing strategic innovation and maintaining a strong commitment to excellence, we are creating new opportunities across industries.&rdquo;</p>

<p>With a strong focus on improving quality of life and fostering economic opportunities, Dubai continues to attract the world&rsquo;s leading minds, businesses, and investors. One of the fastest-growing cities in the index, Dubai is also constantly establishing new benchmarks for urban innovation, connectivity, and resilience.</p>

<p>The Global Power City Index (GPCI) evaluates and ranks the major cities of the world according to their &ldquo;magnetism,&rdquo; or their comprehensive power to attract people, capital, and enterprises from around the world. It does so by measuring six functions&mdash;Economy, Research and Development, Cultural Interaction, Livability, Environment, and Accessibility&mdash;providing a multidimensional ranking.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 5 Jan 2025 18:45:28 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736053.1736088390!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_360/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736053.1736088390!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_360/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai ranks among world’s top 10 cities in Global Power City Index for second consecutive year]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Business</category>
										
																			
											<category>Economy and Finance</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Business/Economy_Finance</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE President meets with Prime Minister of Pakistan]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-meets-with-prime-minister-of-pakistan-2025-01-05-1.736049</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-meets-with-prime-minister-of-pakistan-2025-01-05-1.736049</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan today met with His Excellency Muhammad Shehbaz Sharif, Prime Minister of the Islamic Republic of Pakistan.</p>

<p>During the meeting, which took place in the city of Rahim Yar Khan in Pakistan, His Highness and the Pakistani Prime Minister discussed cooperation between the UAE and Pakistan and opportunities to enhance ties, especially in the economic, trade, developmental, and other fields that serve their mutual interests and aspirations for sustainable economic development and prosperity for their peoples.</p>

<p>This came as part of the close historical relations that unite the two countries and their shared interest in continuing to develop these ties.</p>

<p>During the meeting, the two sides also exchanged views on a number of regional and international issues of common interest.</p>

<p>For his part, His Excellency Muhammad Shehbaz Sharif underscored his pride in the strong friendship between his country and the UAE, expressing his appreciation to His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan for the continuous support provided by the UAE to Pakistan, especially in developmental fields and through the UAE&#39;s notable initiatives in this regard.</p>

<p>His Excellency stressed the two countries&#39; keenness to strengthen relations and further develop bilateral cooperation in all economic, investment, and developmental fields in a way that benefits their peoples and contributes to achieving joint interests.</p>

<p>The meeting was attended by H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Chairman of the Presidential Court for Special Affairs; Ali bin Hammad Al Shamsi, Secretary-General of the Supreme Council for National Security; and Hamad Obaid Al Zaabi, UAE Ambassador to Pakistan.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 5 Jan 2025 18:41:50 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736050.1736088024!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_360/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736050.1736088024!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_360/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE President meets with Prime Minister of Pakistan]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
