<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
	<title>Mobile - Lifestyle</title>
	<link>http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-lifestyle-1.708770?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout</link>	
	<atom:link href="http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-lifestyle-1.708770?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" ></atom:link>
	<description>Lifestyle</description>
			        <language>en</language>
    				<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Latifa bint Mohammed inaugurates fourth edition of ‘Al Marmoom: Film in The Desert’ festival]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/latifa-bint-mohammed-inaugurates-fourth-edition-of-al-marmoom-film-in-the-desert-festival-2025-01-05-1.736061</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/latifa-bint-mohammed-inaugurates-fourth-edition-of-al-marmoom-film-in-the-desert-festival-2025-01-05-1.736061</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Organised by Dubai Culture under the theme &lsquo;Where Stories Come to Life,&rsquo; event running until 12 January aims to support creative talent in the local film industry</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Her Highness: The festival celebrates the authenticity of Dubai&rsquo;s identity, its dynamic spirit, and future aspirations, fostering intellectual dialogue</strong></li>
	<li><strong>&ldquo;Cinema has the profound ability to shape generations rooted in values while addressing the aspirations and challenges of societies and preserving the rich history of nations&rdquo;&nbsp;</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Drawing inspiration from the Ghaf tree, the festival also features an array of musical performances, live shows, and heritage displays</strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p><br />
Her Highness Sheikha Latifa bint Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Chairperson of the Dubai Culture and Arts Authority (Dubai Culture), inaugurated the fourth edition of the &lsquo;Al Marmoom: Film in the Desert&rsquo; festival. Organised by Dubai Culture in the Al Marmoom Desert Reserve, the event seeks to advance the local film industry by providing an innovative platform that supports talented creatives, encouraging them to express their visions and showcase their works and productions to a wider audience.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The festival, an initiative under the Dubai Quality of Life Strategy 2033, features screenings of over 80 feature films. Running until 12 January under the theme &lsquo;Where Stories Come to Life,&rsquo; the event will also host interactive workshops, panel discussions, and talks with a distinguished group of directors, artists, and film industry experts.</p>

<p>Her Highness Sheikha Latifa emphasised that Dubai has excelled in attracting leading directors and talents in the film industry thanks to its extensive capabilities, state-of-the-art infrastructure, and unique creative environment that fosters innovation. She highlighted that, through its ambitious projects and initiatives, the emirate continues to enhance its global leadership, solidify its standing as a cultural and artistic capital, and establish itself as a premier destination for cinematic content creation and production.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Cinema is one of the most powerful expressions of human creativity, distinguished by its unique visual language that seamlessly blends technical mastery with artistic purpose. It has the profound ability to shape generations rooted in values while addressing the aspirations and challenges of societies and preserving the rich history and culture of nations,&rdquo; Her Highness said.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>She added: &ldquo;The Al Marmoom: Film in the Desert festival is a remarkable addition to Dubai&rsquo;s artistic and cinematic landscape through its exceptional cultural experiences and high-quality cinematic works, celebrating the authenticity of Dubai&rsquo;s identity, vibrant energy, and ambitious future aspirations.&nbsp;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Reflecting the beauty of our heritage, the essence of our culture, and the depth of our history, the festival&rsquo;s significance lies in its role as a catalyst for intellectual dialogue, a bridge for cultural exchange, and a source of inspiration for emerging talents. It nurtures creativity; encourages filmmakers to explore the latest industry trends, practices, and opportunities, contributing to fostering a new generation capable of advancing this vital sector, which stands as a cornerstone of Dubai&rsquo;s thriving creative economy.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>Immersive Experience Zone</strong></p>

<p>Sheikha Latifa took an elaborate tour of the festival, exploring, among other highlights, an Immersive Experience Zone. The zone showcased digital artworks created using Artificial Intelligence, in addition to inspiring murals, and installations featuring the work of artists Ghaleb Hawila, Abdullah Lutfi, and Mikhail Antykov.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Her Highness also visited the festival&rsquo;s dedicated pavilions for workshops, seminars, and family-friendly activities and the &lsquo;VIP Barzah&rsquo; area, where she engaged with artists participating in the event, commending their creativity and the diversity of their artistic works. She praised the powerful messages and concepts conveyed through their creations, which reflect a wide array of unique perspectives and artistic visions.</p>

<p>Audiences at the Al Marmoom: Film in the Desert festival will be able to enjoy a curated selection of films chosen from amongst 240 submissions, including notable entries competing for the Al Marmoom Short-Film Competition awards across four categories: documentaries, animation, live-action, and films made using Artificial Intelligence.</p>

<p>The festival&rsquo;s programme includes more than 30 workshops led by renowned creatives and cinema experts, including four workshops organised by the College of Arts and Creative Enterprises at Zayed University. It also offers a diverse array of seminars, panel discussions, and activities tailored to inspire young talents and encourage them to embark on professional careers across the cinema and the arts sectors.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Array of activities</strong></p>

<p>Inspired by the iconic Ghaf tree, the festival serves as a platform to strengthen intercultural engagement and raise environmental awareness by encouraging visitors to explore the Al Marmoom Desert, a treasured nature reserve and one of Dubai&rsquo;s key cultural landmarks. The event features a wide array of activities, including performing arts, musical and heritage shows, and interactive experiences such as &lsquo;Create Your Own AI Movie.&rsquo; Visitors can also visit the planetarium for a stargazing session, or take in the reserve&rsquo;s stunning landscapes on a safari bus tour. A photography competition is also sure to add to the excitement.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dubai Culture dedicates significant space to showcasing traditional crafts and elements of local heritage, reflecting its commitment to promoting cultural authenticity at artistic and cultural events across the emirate. Additionally, attendees can savour traditional cuisine in a heritage-rich and creatively designed setting.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The festival is held in collaboration with an extensive list of partners, including Dubai Mounted Police, Dubai Municipality, Dubai Ambulance, Dubai Police, Dubai Civil Defence, the Roads and Transport Authority, the Islamic Affairs and Charitable Activities Department in Dubai, Mohammed Bin Rashid Space Centre, The Climate Tribe, Lina Kattan, Emirates Airlines, Zayed University, Sandooq Al Watan, Emirates Photography Society, Maraya, Freej, Ferjan Dubai, and Immersee.&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 5 Jan 2025 19:12:41 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736062.1736089926!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736062.1736089926!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Latifa bint Mohammed inaugurates fourth edition of ‘Al Marmoom: Film in The Desert’ festival]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Hatta Running Championship to showcase sporting vibe of Hatta Winter initiative]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/hatta-running-championship-to-showcase-sporting-vibe-of-hatta-winter-initiative-2025-01-03-1.736038</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/hatta-running-championship-to-showcase-sporting-vibe-of-hatta-winter-initiative-2025-01-03-1.736038</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The Hatta Running Championship returns on January 4 under the patronage of Sheikh Saeed bin Hamdan bin Rashid Al Maktoum, President of Hatta Club.</p>

<p>Organised by the Hatta Sports, Cultural and Social Club in collaboration with the Dubai Sports Council (DSC) and the Hatta Winter Festival committee, the event has already confirmed over 1,000 participants, including a strong international presence.</p>

<p>The championship is part of the Hatta Winter initiative, with DSC as a key partner.</p>

<p>The event features competition across eight categories, including the Emirati men&rsquo;s category and an open category over a distance of 8 km, the Emirati women&rsquo;s category and an open category over a distance of 5 km, the Emirati youth category and an open category for under-20-year-olds over a distance of 5 km, and the Emirati children&rsquo;s category and an open category for under-16s over a distance of 3 km.</p>

<p>With over 1,000 runners from different nationalities and age groups, the competition offers a prize pool of AED100,000. The routes highlight Hatta&rsquo;s scenic landscapes and tourist spots, with all races concluding at the picturesque Leem Lake.</p>

<p>The Hatta Running Championship is among the highlights of diverse sporting activities organised as part of the Hatta Winter initiative, which is overseen by the Supreme Committee to Supervise the Development of Hatta, and is implemented by Brand Dubai, the creative arm of the Government of Dubai Media Office, in partnership with various government and private entities.</p>

<p>The Hatta Winter initiative serves to provide added impetus to the goals of the Dubai 2040 Urban Master Plan, especially in terms of enhancing tourism competitiveness, driving development activities with the participation of the private sector, supporting efforts to promote tourism and encourage entrepreneurs, as well as organising and hosting activities and sporting events that will help boost the number of visitors to the Hatta region.</p>

<p>The Hatta Running Championship also aligns with concerted efforts being made to enhance the region&rsquo;s profile as a destination for sports tourism and diverse sporting activities, besides its capability to host major sporting events that directly benefit local communities and usher in significant economic benefits.</p>

<p>Among recent sporting events held in Hatta was the Hatta Winter Football Championship, which featured the participation of eight community teams, and the preliminary and exhibition phase of the Dubai International Rally events from 29th November to 1st December. The Emirates Motor Sports Organisation (EMSO) partnered with the Dubai Sports Council to organise the latter event. Another highlight was a walking competition organised by Hatta Adventures, with local farms and the area&rsquo;s unique aflaj irrigation network providing a fascinating backdrop for the event.</p>

<p>The Hatta Winter initiative has also set the stage for mountain biking and kayaking races organised by Hatta Adventures and Hatta Kayak (January 11), and the Stand Up Paddling and Kayaking Challenge (January 25-26), besides sporting challenges with a family flavour on February 1. The Hatta Ramadan Tournament will keep the community engaged in sporting pursuits during the holy month while the Spartan Race is yet another event that promises to be a major draw for international participants as well as local communities.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 3 Jan 2025 18:27:10 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736039.1735914515!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736039.1735914515!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Hatta Running Championship to showcase sporting vibe of Hatta Winter initiative]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sports</category>
										
																			
											<category>Other</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Sports/Other</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Global Village announces seven drone shows coinciding with seven New Year’s Eve firework countdowns]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/global-village-announces-seven-drone-shows-coinciding-with-seven-new-year-s-eve-firework-countdowns-2024-12-31-1.736022</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/global-village-announces-seven-drone-shows-coinciding-with-seven-new-year-s-eve-firework-countdowns-2024-12-31-1.736022</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p><strong>-&nbsp; A new surprise unveiled, adding to the packed calendar of festivities taking place at the destination tonight 31 December 2024.</strong></p>

<p><strong>-&nbsp; Countdowns to light up the sky at 8:00PM, 9:00PM, 10:00PM, 10:30PM, 11:00PM: 12:00AM and 1:00AM.</strong></p>

<p><strong>- All celebrations and activations are included in the entry ticket for every guest to enjoy.</strong></p>

<p><strong>-&nbsp; Park is open on NYE from 4:00PM to 2:00AM welcoming families, couples and ladies.</strong></p>

<p><strong>- Watch the festivities video here</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>Global Village, the region&rsquo;s premier multicultural family destination for entertainment, dining, shopping, and attractions, has announced the demonstration of seven drone shows, each perfectly timed to coincide with one of the seven New Year&rsquo;s Eve firework countdowns. The unveiled surprise is the latest addition to the signature celebrations the park is set to host tonight 31 December 2024 at 8:00PM, 9:00PM, 10:00PM, 10:30PM, 11:00PM: 12:00AM and 1:00AM.</p>

<p>As part of its dedication to delivering new guest experiences every season, Global Village has featured the drone show display to its New Year&rsquo;s Eve activations for the first time. The show will illuminate the sky above the destination jointly with the renowned firework displays amidst the on-ground festivities. Highlights include Main Stage live performances, extravagant DJ show and several roaming entertainment acts across the park. All celebrations are part of the Global Village&rsquo;s entry ticket, ensuring every guest can fully enjoy the flagship experience.</p>

<p>With Global Village named the leading destination for exploring cultural diversity and proudly hosting guests from across the world, each drone show will present the &lsquo;Happy New Year&rsquo; message alongside the firework display, marking the arrival of the New Year in a different time zone.</p>

<p>End-of-year shopping experiences across 30 cultural pavilions and 3,500 shopping outlets as well as 250+ dining options and over 200 rides and entertainment attractions are all available throughout the night for adults, teens and children visiting.</p>

<p>The destination&rsquo;s three renowned gates will open on the New Year&rsquo;s Eve exclusively from 4:00PM to 2:00AM, welcoming guests from families, couples and ladies.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 18:44:28 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736023.1735656204!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736023.1735656204!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Global Village announces seven drone shows coinciding with seven New Year’s Eve firework countdowns]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Lifestyle</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Lifestyle</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai Set to Amaze the World with Spectacular New Year Celebrations]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/dubai-set-to-amaze-the-world-with-spectacular-new-year-celebrations-2024-12-30-1.735999</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/dubai-set-to-amaze-the-world-with-spectacular-new-year-celebrations-2024-12-30-1.735999</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<ul>
	<li><strong>Broadcast live, on Dubai Media Incorporated&rsquo;s flagship channels, including Dubai One TV, these festivities highlight the spirit of the city&rsquo;s glamour as 2024 ends and 2025 is welcomed in style.&nbsp;</strong></li>
</ul>

<p>As the countdown begins, all eyes will be on Dubai&rsquo;s iconic landmarks. From the world&rsquo;s tallest building, Burj Khalifa, to The Palm&rsquo;s The Pointe and the historic Al Seef district, the emirate will come alive with breathtaking fireworks displays and choreographed drone shows. The dazzling light and pyrotechnic spectacle at Burj Khalifa, lasting from 11:50 PM to 12:10 AM, promises to be the centrepiece, captivating global audiences and thousands of visitors in attendance.</p>

<p>Dubai Media Inc. (DMI) has announced its comprehensive plans to cover Dubai&rsquo;s highly anticipated New Year&rsquo;s Eve celebrations, showcasing the emirate&rsquo;s unmatched festive spirit and world-renowned attractions. Starting from Tuesday evening, December 31, 2024, until the early hours of January 1, 2025. Bringing the celebrations to life with exclusive broadcasts and special programming across its platforms and will broadcast the festivities across its channels, including Dubai TV and Sama Dubai, with unified programming starting at 11:00 PM.&nbsp;</p>

<p>From Dubai One TV, Amy Kitchingman will be delivering live updates and capturing the energy of the city&#39;s most iconic New Year&rsquo;s Eve destination. The program will provide an insider&rsquo;s look at Dubai&rsquo;s dazzling celebrations, featuring live reports, interactive segments, and exclusive stories highlighting the city&rsquo;s vibrancy as it welcomes 2025.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Emirati superstar Ahlam will perform as part of the &quot;In Love with Dubai&quot; program, a live New Year&rsquo;s Eve special hosted by Ahmed Abdullah and Roaa Al Sabban at 9pm on Dubai TV.</p>

<p>Alongside the show, Jad Shihab and Sally Saeed from Dubai TV will report from various other locations throughout the city, showcasing the vibrant celebrations and fireworks displays capturing the energy and excitement of the emirate as it ushers in the New Year.</p>

<p>Sarah Al Jarman, Senior Vice President of TV and Radio Channels at DMI, emphasized the global significance of Dubai&rsquo;s celebrations, stating: &ldquo;New Year&rsquo;s Eve in Dubai is a global event that highlights the emirate&rsquo;s ability to deliver extraordinary experiences. Our goal is to bring the spirit of Dubai to viewers worldwide, ensuring they witness the magic and grandeur of this remarkable city.&rdquo;</p>

<p>DMI&rsquo;s broadcast will also spotlight the meticulous planning and innovative logistics behind Dubai&rsquo;s New Year&rsquo;s celebrations, from seamless transportation provided by the Roads and Transport Authority to the safety measures led by Dubai Police. These celebrations include several iconic locations, like Dubai Frame, Festival City, Dubai Creek Harbour, and Expo City Dubai, will host immersive celebrations, featuring live entertainment, cultural displays, and family-friendly activities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As the world turns its gaze to Dubai this New Year&rsquo;s Eve, DMI&rsquo;s coverage promises to showcase the city as a beacon of innovation, culture, and celebration, making it the ultimate global destination to welcome 2025.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:04:00 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736003.1735525398!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736003.1735525398!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736003.1735525398!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736001.1735491745!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736000.1735492188!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai Set to Amaze the World with Spectacular New Year Celebrations]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Lifestyle</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Lifestyle</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[2025 New Year's Celebrations in Dubai – FAQs]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/2025-new-year-s-celebrations-in-dubai-faqs-2024-12-29-1.735993</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/2025-new-year-s-celebrations-in-dubai-faqs-2024-12-29-1.735993</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Where are the fireworks and drone show locations for the 2025 New Year&#39;s celebrations</p>

<p><a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dubai-events-calendar/nye-downtown-dubai"><strong>Burj Park</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li>Time: 11:59 PM</li>
	<li>Location: Burj Park &ndash; Opposite Burj Khalifa</li>
</ul>

<h1><strong>Burj Al Arab</strong></h1>

<ul>
	<li>Time: 11:59 PM</li>
	<li>Location: Burj Al Arab &ndash; Jumeirah</li>
</ul>

<h1><strong><a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dubai-events-calendar/dsf-drones-light-show">Dubai Shopping Festival (DSF) Drones Show</a></strong></h1>

<ul>
	<li>Time: 8:00 PM and 10:00 PM</li>
	<li>Location: Bluewaters and The Beach opposite Jumeirah Beach Residence</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dubai-events-calendar/dsf-fireworks-nights"><strong>Dubai Shopping Festival (DSF) Fireworks</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li>Time: 11:59 PM</li>
	<li>Location: Dubai Festival City Mall, Al Seef, Bluewaters, The Beach opposite Jumeirah Beach Residence, and Hatta<strong><span dir="RTL">.</span></strong></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://marine.rta.ae/rta_b2c/opentickets.html"><strong>Marine Transportation</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li>Departure locations for cruises: Marina Mall, Al Ghubaiba, Bluewaters, Al Fahidi, and Al Jaddaf.</li>
	<li>Advance booking is recommended through <a href="mailto:marinebooking@rta.ae" target="_blank">marinebooking@rta.ae</a> to secure a starting point nearest to your location.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>How can I reach the celebration sites?</strong></p>

<p>You can proceed to the celebration sites either by private vehicles or by using public transportation. The Dubai Metro is a convenient option considering there might be street closures in the areas surrounding the designated celebration sites. It is advisable to head to the venues early before road closures take effect to avoid traffic congestion and ensure a comfortable, safe, and secure experience<span dir="RTL">.</span></p>

<p><strong>Which roads will be closed in Dubai in preparation for the celebrations? And what are the closure timings</strong><strong><span dir="RTL">?</span></strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Al Asayel Street will be closed to traffic at exactly 4:00 pm, notably the stretch from Oud Metha Street towards the Burj Khalifa area.</li>
	<li>Mohammed Bin Rashid Boulevard, Burj Khalifa Street, and Future Street will be closed starting from 4:00 pm as the parking spaces in these areas reach full capacity. Members of the public who have reserved places at establishments in the Boulevard area or Dubai Mall are advised to arrive before 4:00 pm on Tuesday.</li>
	<li>Lower Financial Center Street will be closed around 4:00 pm. On Upper Financial Center Street and Sukuk Street, traffic restrictions will be enforced from 8:00 pm.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>What are the alternative routes that can be used to access other areas near the celebration sites during the closure of the roads leading to those sites?</strong></p>

<p>Sheikh Zayed Road will remain fully open until a partial closure takes effect at 11:00 pm. Alternatively, the public can use Jumeirah Street, Al Wasl Street, Sheikh Mohammed Bin Zayed Road, and Al Khail Road.</p>

<p><strong>Where can I park my private vehicle on arriving at a celebration site?</strong></p>

<p>Park your vehicle in one of the designated parking areas so that you can enjoy the events and festivities undisturbed. Be mindful of others&rsquo; safety and comfort while parking your vehicle. Avoid parking in the middle of the road, which causes traffic obstruction and inconvenience to others.</p>

<p><strong>Can I bring my children to the celebration sites?</strong></p>

<p>Celebrating with family and friends makes the festivities even more enjoyable, but please be mindful of children&#39;s safety, especially in crowded areas. Always keep a close eye on the children in your group and ensure they stay by your side right through. It is preferable for children to wear safety wristbands.</p>

<p><strong>What should I do if myself, a family member, or someone present at the location, experiences an injury or a medical emergency?</strong></p>

<p>You should call the emergency number 998 to report any medical emergencies, or promptly contact a Dubai Police officer or security personnel present at the location. They will take the necessary steps to summon one of the ambulance teams present at the location to provide the necessary medical assistance.</p>

<p><strong>Are ambulance services available across all New Year&#39;s celebration sites?</strong></p>

<p>Dubai always ensures the comfort, safety, and security of everyone during all major events and occasions by providing all services that guarantee the swiftest response during emergencies of any kind. Specialised teams are available at all New Year&#39;s celebration sites to provide first aid services, in addition to which ambulance teams are always at hand to deal with cases that require urgent medical intervention.</p>

<p><strong>Are all celebration sites secured in the event of a fire?</strong></p>

<p>Preparedness for all kinds of emergencies, including fire, is a top priority for Dubai&#39;s Events Security Committee (ESC). Civil Defense teams are stationed at various celebration sites, as is the case with all major events hosted by Dubai throughout the year. Ensuring everyone&rsquo;s safety and security is a responsibility Dubai takes very seriously and always places topmost amongst its priorities.</p>

<p><strong>What should I do if I find a lost bag or personal belongings at celebrations sites?</strong></p>

<p>Please inform the police or security personnel present at the location. Your cooperation is key in ensuring that lost items are returned to their owners.</p>

<p><strong>What should I do if I lose my bag or some of my belongings during the festivities?</strong></p>

<p>You should inform Dubai Police or any security personnel present at the location, leave your contact information, and provide a detailed description of the lost items. You will be contacted to come and collect them as soon as they are found.</p>

<p><strong>Can I bring family picnic items to the celebration site?</strong></p>

<p>Avoid carrying large bags or items to the celebration sites to ensure smooth entry and movement within the venue. This ensures everyone&#39;s comfort and allows for an enjoyable and hassle-free experience for all attendees.</p>

<p><strong>What are the general guidelines that I should observe when present at any of the celebration sites?</strong></p>

<p>Follow the instructions provided by security personnel at the celebration site as well as the instructional signs at the location.</p>

<p>Adhere to traffic rules and regulations and give priority to pedestrians crossing at designated areas.</p>

<p>Avoid crowding or pushing and use designated pedestrian areas.</p>

<p>Be considerate of others and avoid behaviours that may cause distress or spoil the festive mood<span dir="RTL">.</span></p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 18:42:25 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735994.1735483586!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735994.1735483586!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[2025 New Year's Celebrations in Dubai – FAQs]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Lifestyle</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Lifestyle</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Meet the Faces of DXB Today: A Dynamic Team Bringing Dubai to Life]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/meet-the-faces-of-dxb-today-a-dynamic-team-bringing-dubai-to-life-2024-12-27-1.735977</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/meet-the-faces-of-dxb-today-a-dynamic-team-bringing-dubai-to-life-2024-12-27-1.735977</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Hosted on Dubai One, the flagship English-language channel under Dubai Media Incorporated (DMI), <em>DXB Today</em> is the ultimate showcase of Dubai&rsquo;s dynamic spirit. The show captures the heartbeat of this ever-evolving city, spotlighting its vibrant culture, innovative initiatives, and fascinating people. With a fresh perspective and a team of charismatic presenters, <em>DXB Today</em> brings viewers stories that celebrate Dubai as a global hub for opportunity, diversity, and ambition.</p>

<p>At the heart of the show lies its exceptional team of presenters&mdash;a mix of homegrown talent, global adventurers, and seasoned storytellers. Together, they weave a captivating tapestry of voices that reflect the energy and diversity of Dubai. From cultural deep dives to adrenaline-pumping adventures, the <em>DXB Today</em> team ensures every episode offers something for everyone. Let&rsquo;s get to know the faces behind the show and discover the passion they bring to your screens.</p>

<p><strong>The Explorers of Stories and Perspectives</strong></p>

<p>Dubai-born <strong>Maitha Alawadi</strong> brings a uniquely local lens to <em>DXB Today</em>, but her storytelling reflects her global curiosity. As a filmmaker, foodie, and proud Emirati, Maitha approaches every segment with an open mind. &ldquo;The show encapsulates Dubai&rsquo;s essence&mdash;a melting pot of cultures and traditions,&rdquo; she explains. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m always fascinated by how people from different backgrounds find home here.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>Ahmad Alfalasi</strong> shares Maitha&rsquo;s passion for discovery. Whether uncovering hidden gems or diving into complex topics like AI, Ahmad&rsquo;s relaxed, conversational style helps viewers see Dubai through fresh eyes. &ldquo;Every story is a chance to learn,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;And if I&rsquo;m curious about something, I know the audience will be too.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>Fares Alraqqad</strong>, a Jordanian with seven years in Dubai, is another explorer at heart. &ldquo;Dubai constantly surprises me,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;There&rsquo;s something here for everyone, no matter your interests.&rdquo; Fares&rsquo; segments often highlight the city&rsquo;s hidden communities and lesser-known treasures, bringing an adventurous edge to the show.</p>

<p><strong>The Dreamers Who Broke the Mold</strong></p>

<p>For <strong>Nimishi Neha</strong>, presenting has always been about breaking boundaries. Born in London, Nimishi defied societal expectations to pursue her dream of broadcasting. After earning her journalism degree, she became the face of MTV UK, interviewing A-list celebrities and attending the hottest events. Now in Dubai, she&rsquo;s a familiar voice and face as a radio host, podcast creator, and TV presenter.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I grew up idolizing Oprah, Jameela Jamil, and Davina McCall,&rdquo; she shares. &ldquo;Their ability to connect with people inspired me to use my voice to make a difference.&rdquo; Nimishi&rsquo;s curiosity and authenticity are at the core of her presence on <em>DXB Today</em>, where she thrives on meeting people from all walks of life.</p>

<p>Similarly, <strong>Khalid Abdulghani</strong> brings a story of reinvention to the team. Born in Cyprus to an Irish mother and Emirati father, Khalid&rsquo;s life has been a whirlwind of global experiences, from Germany to the USA. Starting as a banker, then becoming Etihad Airways&rsquo; first Emirati cadet pilot, Khalid flew across the world for over 15 years. But the pandemic made him pause and reflect.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I realized it was time to chase my childhood dream of acting,&rdquo; he recalls. That dream eventually led him to TV presenting, where he brings his adventurous spirit and unshakable positivity to the screen. &ldquo;I love sharing stories that inspire and energize,&rdquo; Khalid says, &ldquo;and being part of a dynamic team like this makes it even more rewarding.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>The Connectors of Heart and Humor</strong></p>

<p>For <strong>Katie Overy</strong>, connection is key. Originally from the UK, Katie&rsquo;s meticulous preparation and warm personality make her a trusted anchor for the show. &ldquo;There&rsquo;s always space for warmth and personality,&rdquo; she explains. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s just about knowing when to use it.&rdquo; Her quick wit shines in interviews, like her unforgettable conversation with comedian John Cleese&mdash;about cats, no less!</p>

<p><strong>Dina Butti</strong>, an Egyptian-Canadian presenter, also excels at creating connections. Dina&rsquo;s journey from internships to Hollywood red carpets reflects her tenacity and love for storytelling. &ldquo;After 15 years, I still think presenting is the dream job,&rdquo; she says. Her relatable, bubbly personality makes her a favorite among viewers, especially as she seamlessly weaves her &ldquo;mom life&rdquo; into her on-screen presence.</p>

<p>Adding depth and experience, <strong>Tom Urqheart</strong>, a Scottish media veteran, brings a sage presence to the team. His calm demeanor and sharp humor balance the high-energy dynamics of his co-hosts. &ldquo;The can-do spirit of Dubai inspires me,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s a city that makes you believe anything is possible.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>The Team Reflecting Dubai&rsquo;s Diversity</strong></p>

<p>For <strong>Ayswayra Ajit</strong>, <em>DXB Today</em> represents the vibrant melting pot of Dubai. With over 14 years in the industry, this Indian presenter celebrates the diversity of her colleagues and the city itself. &ldquo;Our team&rsquo;s varied backgrounds make us a true reflection of Dubai,&rdquo; she says. Ayswayra&rsquo;s ability to connect with audiences is rooted in her preparation and passion for storytelling, bringing an unmatched vibrancy to the show.</p>

<p><strong>Dua Altoobi</strong>, an Emirati presenter, echoes this sentiment. &ldquo;Dubai&rsquo;s opportunities are endless,&rdquo; she says. Her segments reflect the city&rsquo;s boundless possibilities, and her approachable style ensures her stories resonate with viewers of all backgrounds. Her dream guest? Oprah Winfrey&mdash;a nod to her love for inspirational stories.</p>

<p>Together, the presenters of <em>DXB Today</em> form a kaleidoscope of talent, backgrounds, and perspectives. Their collective energy brings the city to life, making every episode an adventure. Whether they&rsquo;re uncovering hidden gems, sharing heartfelt stories, or diving into the pulse of Dubai&rsquo;s vibrant culture, this team captures the city&rsquo;s essence like no other.</p>

<p><strong>Tune in to <em>DXB Today</em> and let this incredible team take you on a journey through the magic of Dubai!</strong></p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:24:21 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735988.1735298502!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735988.1735298502!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735988.1735298502!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735987.1735298481!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735986.1735298459!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735985.1735298438!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735984.1735298341!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735983.1735298316!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735982.1735298299!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735981.1735298282!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735980.1735298265!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735979.1735298248!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735978.1735298224!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Meet the Faces of DXB Today: A Dynamic Team Bringing Dubai to Life]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Lifestyle</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Lifestyle</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Hatta Winter Festival greets visitors with an array of exciting activities across 140 workshops]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/hatta-winter-festival-greets-visitors-with-an-array-of-exciting-activities-across-140-workshops-2024-12-25-1.735965</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/hatta-winter-festival-greets-visitors-with-an-array-of-exciting-activities-across-140-workshops-2024-12-25-1.735965</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The Hatta Winter Festival, being held as part of the Hatta Winter initiative, has captured the public imagination with 140 workshops showcasing Emirati cultural and artistic traditions to thousands of visitors from across the country and beyond. Brand Dubai, the creative arm of the Government of Dubai Media Office, has organised the workshops as part of a diverse schedule of activities catering to visitors of varied interests and ages, with most of the activities designed to appeal to the whole family.</p>

<p>Set against the stunning backdrop of the Hatta mountains, the Festival scores high on the fun scale, inspiring visitors to make the most of the pleasant weather and celebrate the effusive community spirit. The number of workshops organised as part of the Festival has recorded a 40% increase from the previous edition&rsquo;s tally of 100.</p>

<p>Highlighting the diversity of workshops, Mahra Alyouha, a member of the organising committee for the Hatta Winter Festival, said: &ldquo;Workshops are key components of this year&#39;s festival since they allow for a wide variety of interactive activities and greater audience engagement irrespective of the age or interests of visitors.&rdquo;</p>

<p>She added: &ldquo;Given the immense interest generated by workshops during the previous edition of the Festival, the organising committee decided to increase their number this year, taking their total up to 140 workshops covering everything from diverse art forms and cultural themes to specialist sessions in honing a wide range of creative skills. Offering abundant opportunities to acquire new skills and foster creativity and skill development, the workshops also highlight unique aspects of the local environment to build conversations around sustainable development practices.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The Festival has also lined up an array of creative workshops. &lsquo;The Swing House&rsquo; is holding workshops for those keen on learning the art of embroidery on tote bags. In collaboration with &lsquo;MOFUN,&rsquo; the Festival also features workshops teaching mirror engraving and felting embroidery. Children can learn to design a variety of jewellery boxes, or master wood and mirror painting with Shaikha Obaid from &lsquo;NSSFMA&rsquo; holding dedicated sessions. Another workshop by &lsquo;The Embroidery House&rsquo; will revolve around techniques and skills for using felting needles.</p>

<p>Alya Lootah and Nora Kalban from &lsquo;Medaf&rsquo; will lead painting workshops besides sessions where they will explain how to use seashells and canvas to create distinctive art. Workshops focusing on glass painting, cake decoration, Islamic geometric engravings on metal, wax painting, and fabric bag painting are also part of the mix. Among other sessions, Aisha Johar offers tips on cup painting, while Shaikha Mohammed illustrates embroidery techniques, and Shaikha Al-Maqbali highlights the creative uses of beads.</p>

<p>Inspiring young ones<br />
There are also plenty of activities to keep the little ones interested. Brand Dubai, in collaboration with &lsquo;MOFUN,&rsquo; offers specialised workshops for children featuring activities such as tote bag painting, plant pot embellishment, acrylic painting on 3D models, and creating accessories using paracord ropes. Mirror decoration sessions using clay are another highlight.</p>

<p>Additionally, The Swing House is conducting workshops for children on everything from pillow embroidery, clay modelling, mosaic design inspired by Hatta&rsquo;s landscapes, as well as creative fabric designs on apparel. Jewellery and bead design workshops are also set to keep the little ones hooked. The exhaustive list of activities reflects the Festival&#39;s commitment to offering fun, hands-on learning experiences for visitors of all ages, fostering creativity in a beautiful, nature-inspired setting.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:13:53 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735966.1735128817!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735966.1735128817!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Hatta Winter Festival greets visitors with an array of exciting activities across 140 workshops]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Lifestyle</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Lifestyle</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Merchlist Redefines Custom Corporate Gifting and Branded Merchandise in the UAE with Sustainable and Eco-Friendly Solutions]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/merchlist-redefines-custom-corporate-gifting-and-branded-merchandise-in-the-uae-with-sustainable-and-eco-friendly-solutions-2024-12-25-1.735961</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/merchlist-redefines-custom-corporate-gifting-and-branded-merchandise-in-the-uae-with-sustainable-and-eco-friendly-solutions-2024-12-25-1.735961</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Merchlist, the UAE&rsquo;s premier provider of custom branded merchandise, corporate gifting, and uniforms, is transforming how businesses elevate their brand presence and build stronger relationships with clients and employees. With a proven track record of serving over 2,500 organizations across the UAE and Saudi Arabia, Merchlist has become the trusted partner for impactful corporate gifting, promotional products, and professional uniforms.</p>

<p>Offering over 1,000 customizable products, Merchlist combines innovation, sustainability, a</p>

<p>and convenience to help businesses create high-quality branded merchandise with ease.</p>

<p><strong>&ldquo;Our mission is to simplify corporate gifting and branding while helping companies create meaningful and lasting brand impressions,&rdquo;</strong> said <strong>Divesh</strong>, Co-Founder of Merchlist.</p>

<p><strong>Empowering Businesses with Custom Branded Products</strong></p>

<p>Merchlist offers an expansive range of customizable products to suit every business need. From eco-friendly gifts and promotional items to professional uniforms, Merchlist&rsquo;s diverse portfolio ensures that companies can find the perfect products to represent their brand.</p>

<p><strong>Top categories include:</strong></p>

<p>&bull; <strong>Promotional Giveaways</strong>: Custom branded pens, notebooks, and tote bags to enhance visibility at trade shows and events.</p>

<p>&bull; <strong>Corporate Gifting</strong>: High-end gift sets, custom gift boxes, and tech gadgets with company logos to strengthen client relationships.</p>

<p>&bull; <strong>Employee Recognition</strong>: Branded apparel and accessories for celebrating milestones and fostering employee loyalty.</p>

<p>&bull; <strong>Custom Branded Uniforms</strong>: Stylish and functional workwear, including shirts, caps, and jackets, that help employees represent their brand with confidence.</p>

<p><strong>Seamless Customization with Technology</strong></p>

<p>Merchlist&rsquo;s intuitive online platform is designed to make customization effortless. Businesses can upload their logos, add personalized designs, and preview products in real-time, ensuring every item reflects their brand identity perfectly.</p>

<p><strong>&ldquo;Our platform makes personalization quick and accessible, giving businesses complete control over their branded merchandise,&rdquo;</strong> said <strong>Divesh</strong>.</p>

<p>Whether businesses need small batches or large-scale orders, Merchlist&rsquo;s platform streamlines the process, ensuring quick turnaround times and unmatched precision.</p>

<p><strong>Driving Sustainability Through Eco-Friendly Solutions</strong><br />
&nbsp;</p>

<p>As businesses prioritize sustainability, Merchlist is leading the way with an extensive range of eco-friendly products. From reusable water bottles and bamboo-based stationery to biodegradable packaging, Merchlist helps companies align their branding efforts with their environmental values.</p>

<p><a href="https://themerchlist.com/product-category/eco-friendly/"><span style="color:#0000FF;"><strong>Custom Eco-friendly merchandise</strong></span></a><strong><span style="color:#0000FF;"> </span>options include:</strong></p>

<p>&bull; <strong>Reusable Drinkware</strong>: Bottles, mugs, and tumblers that reduce single-use plastic waste.</p>

<p>&bull; <strong>Sustainable Accessories</strong>: Bamboo pens, tech gadgets, and notebooks crafted from renewable materials.</p>

<p>&bull; <strong>Green Packaging</strong>: Minimal and recyclable packaging for gift sets and promotional items.</p>

<p><strong>&ldquo;Sustainability is a core value for us, and we&rsquo;re committed to providing products that help businesses make a positive environmental impact,&rdquo;</strong> added <strong>Divesh</strong>.</p>

<p><strong>A Trusted Partner for Over 2,500 Organizations</strong></p>

<p>Merchlist&rsquo;s <strong><a href="https://themerchlist.com/corporate-merchandise/"><span style="color:#0000FF;">Corporate Merchandise</span></a><span style="color:#0000FF;"> </span></strong>arm ensures a commitment to quality, reliability, and innovation has made it the preferred choice for businesses across the UAE and Saudi Arabia. Serving industries such as retail, finance, healthcare, and education, Merchlist offers tailored solutions to meet the unique needs of its clients.</p>

<p><strong>Industries served include:</strong></p>

<p>&bull; <strong>Finance and Banking</strong>: Executive gifts and branded items for client engagement.</p>

<p>&bull;&nbsp; <strong>Retail and E-commerce</strong>: Uniforms, branded packaging, and giveaways for customer loyalty.</p>

<p>&bull; <strong>Healthcare and Education</strong>: Branded merchandise and uniforms for employees, students, and stakeholders.</p>

<p style="margin-left:20.0pt;">&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Why Merchlist Stands Out</strong></p>

<p>Merchlist&rsquo;s success is built on its ability to deliver exceptional products and services that resonate with its clients. Key differentiators include:</p>

<p>&bull; <strong>Extensive Product Range</strong>: Over 1,000 customizable options to suit every need and budget.</p>

<p>&bull; <strong>Intuitive Customization</strong>: A user-friendly platform for seamless personalization.</p>

<p>&bull; <strong>Sustainability Commitment</strong>: Eco-friendly products that align with corporate environmental goals.</p>

<p>&bull; <strong>Fast Turnaround</strong>: Reliable production times and free delivery for tight deadlines.</p>

<p><strong>The Future of Corporate Gifting and Branding</strong></p>

<p>As businesses seek innovative ways to engage their audiences and enhance brand loyalty, Merchlist is at the forefront of the corporate gifting and branded merchandise industry. By combining cutting-edge technology, sustainability, and an unwavering commitment to quality, Merchlist is redefining what it means to make a lasting impression.</p>

<p><strong>For more information on how Merchlist can elevate your brand, visit<span style="color:#0000CD;"> </span><a href="https://themerchlist.com/"><span style="color:#0000CD;">themerchlist.com</span></a> or contact us at team@themerchlist.com.</strong></p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:09:45 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735962.1735128551!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735962.1735128551!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Merchlist Redefines Custom Corporate Gifting and Branded Merchandise in the UAE with Sustainable and Eco-Friendly Solutions]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Lifestyle</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Lifestyle</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai announces comprehensive security plan for 2025 New Year's Eve celebrations]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/dubai-announces-comprehensive-security-plan-for-2025-new-year-s-eve-celebrations-2024-12-24-1.735953</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/dubai-announces-comprehensive-security-plan-for-2025-new-year-s-eve-celebrations-2024-12-24-1.735953</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>- Plan covers fireworks displays at 36 locations<br />
- 8,530 police officers, and 1,145 patrols deployed to ensure safety and security<br />
- Dubai divided into four operational sectors to streamline safety measures and enhance public services, building on last year&rsquo;s success<br />
- Key road closures announced for New Year&rsquo;s Eve in Dubai<br />
- Dubai Metro (Red and Green lines) will operate continuously for 43 hours from 5:00 AM on 31 December 2024 until midnight on 1 January 2025<br />
- Emergency and non-emergency reports can be made on the toll-free numbers 999 and 901, respectively<br />
- Abdulla Khalifa Al Marri calls for public cooperation, adherence to guidelines, and the immediate reporting of suspicious behaviour to ensure safe and enjoyable New Year&#39;s Eve</p>

<p>The Events Security Committee in Dubai has confirmed its comprehensive preparations to ensure the safety and security of the 2025 New Year&rsquo;s Eve celebrations.</p>

<p>Building on the success of last year&rsquo;s plan, the emirate will once again be divided into four operational sectors&mdash;North, Central, West, and Maritime&mdash;to streamline safety measures and enhance public services in collaboration with strategic partners.</p>

<p>The committee, in coordination with the Permanent Committee for Labour Affairs, has also arranged dedicated viewing areas for workers.</p>

<p>These zones will feature large screens and meal services, allowing workers to enjoy the celebrations, including the fireworks, safely and conveniently while reducing the need for movement to crowded event locations.</p>

<p>Event overview and deployment<br />
The 2025 celebrations will feature fireworks displays at 36 locations across Dubai. Key sites include Burj Khalifa; Global Village; Bab Al Shams Desert Resort; Atlantis The Royal; Al Marmoom Oasis; Expo City; Dubai Frame; and Dubai Design District, among others.</p>

<p>To ensure safety, Dubai Police will deploy 8,530 officers and 1,145 patrols, supported by 33 marine rescue boats, Civil Defence vehicles, and ambulances. Six mobile operations rooms will monitor activities across the emirate.</p>

<p>Dedicated tents will be set up in Downtown Dubai, offering:<br />
&bull; Lost and found services<br />
&bull; First aid<br />
&bull; Logistical support<br />
&bull; Assistance for lost children<br />
&bull; Guidance for visitors</p>

<p>Security plan announcement<br />
During a press conference held at the InterContinental Dubai Festival City, Dubai officials announced the comprehensive security, organisational, and service plans for the New Year&#39;s Eve celebrations.</p>

<p>The press conference was attended by His Excellency Expert Major General Khalil Ibrahim Al Mansouri, Assistant Commander-in-Chief for Criminal Investigation Affairs; His Excellency Major General Saif Muhair Al Mazroui, Acting Assistant Commander-in-Chief for Operations and Chair of the Events Security Committee; His Excellency Mishal Abdul Karim Julfar, CEO of Dubai Corporation for Ambulance Services; His Excellency Expert Major General Ali Hassan Al Mutawa, Assistant Director-General for Fire and Rescue, Dubai Civil Defence; Hussain Al Banna, Executive Director, Roads and Transport Authority (RTA); Adel Al Marzouqi, Executive Director, Dubai Municipality; and representatives from 55 government and private entities.</p>

<p>Major General Khalil Ibrahim Al Mansouri commended the 55 entities&#39; collaborative efforts, highlighting their unified and coordinated approach to delivering the highest levels of safety. He emphasised that preparatory measures included coordination meetings, tabletop exercises, and on-site inspections at the 36 event locations.<br />
He further noted the success of dividing the emirate into operational sectors in 2024 and confirmed this strategy will continue.</p>

<p>&bull; North Sector: includes four event locations<br />
&bull; Central Sector: covers nine locations<br />
&bull; West Sector: comprises 23 locations<br />
&bull; Maritime Sector: ensures safety at all coastal and water-based events</p>

<p>Major General Al Mansouri added that six mobile operation rooms will provide additional support, ensuring seamless communication between entities.</p>

<p>Public Appeal<br />
Major General Al Mansouri urged the public to cooperate with Dubai Police, follow traffic instructions, and avoid congested areas. Emergency and non-emergency reports can be made via the toll-free numbers 999 and 901, respectively.</p>

<p>Public Transport<br />
Hussain Al Banna detailed the RTA&#39;s traffic and transport plan, especially for the Burj Khalifa area:</p>

<p>Traffic Management<br />
Road Closures:<br />
&bull; Al Asayel Street from Oud Metha Road to Burj Khalifa: from 4:00 PM<br />
&bull; Mohammed Bin Rashid Boulevard, Burj Khalifa Street, and Al Mustaqbal Street: from 4:00 PM, depending on parking availability<br />
&bull; Lower Financial Centre Street: from 4:00 PM<br />
&bull; Upper Financial Centre Street and Al Sukook Street: from 8:00 PM<br />
&bull; Public Advisory: Guests with bookings in the area must arrive before 4:00 PM.</p>

<p>Metro and tram services<br />
&bull; Dubai Metro (Red and Green lines) will operate continuously for 43 hours from 5:00 AM on 31 December 2024 until midnight on 1 January 2025.</p>

<p>Shuttle Services and Parking<br />
&bull; 260 buses (20 double-deckers, 240 standard) will transport guests to key locations.<br />
&bull; Additional parking (900 spaces) will be available at Al Wasl Club (500) and Al Jaffiliya (400), with shuttle buses running from 3:00 PM.</p>

<p>Crowd management<br />
Traffic lights near major areas will be monitored in real-time, and pedestrian routes to buses and metro stations will be clearly marked. Smart screens will alert drivers about road closures and alternative routes.</p>

<p>Dubai Municipality measures<br />
Adel Al Marzouqi confirmed Dubai Municipality&#39;s preparedness, with the deployment of 2,776 staff, including 242 supervisors and 2,534 sanitation workers, supported by 246 vehicles. The plan focuses on public health, food safety, and the cleanliness of public spaces.<br />
&bull; Food Safety: Inspections will be conducted at malls, hotels, restaurants, and public event sites.<br />
&bull; Park and Beach Management: Special teams will secure public parks, recreational areas, and beaches, with lifeguards on duty, particularly at night.<br />
&bull; Waste Management: Round-the-clock operations will ensure cleanliness at event sites.</p>

<p>Dubai Civil Defence preparedness<br />
Major General Ali Hassan Al Mutawa announced the deployment of 1,097 firefighters and 123 advanced vehicles across five sectors. Inspections of 257 critical facilities have ensured compliance with safety standards.</p>

<p>Dubai Civil Defence will send 500,000 safety messages to attendees via SMS and has urged the public to comply with safety guidelines.</p>

<p>Ambulance services<br />
Mishal Abdul Karim Julfar detailed Dubai Ambulance&#39;s exceptional readiness, including 224 emergency points and 593 paramedics. Strategic deployment covers key areas like Dubai Mall, Sheikh Mohammed Bin Rashid Boulevard, and Hatta. Resources deployed include:<br />
&bull; Five marine rescue boats<br />
&bull; Seven ambulances at Dubai Mall<br />
&bull; 19 ambulances and 38 paramedics near Burj Khalifa</p>

<p>Volunteer Programme: 42 trained volunteers will support medical teams in handling minor cases.<br />
Public guidance includes carrying necessary medications and contacting 998 or the Dubai Ambulance app in case of emergencies.</p>

<p>His Excellency Lieutenant General Abdulla Khalifa Al Marri, stated: &quot;As Dubai prepares to welcome the new year, Dubai Police and our key partners have stepped up the measures to deliver unmatched security and services during this global event. Over the years, our accumulated expertise has set benchmarks in event management, aligning with Dubai&#39;s position as a leader in hosting world-class celebrations.&quot;</p>

<p>Al Marri called for public cooperation, adherence to guidelines, and the immediate reporting of suspicious behaviour to ensure a safe and enjoyable New Year&#39;s Eve for all.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 18:38:34 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735954.1735051099!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735954.1735051099!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai announces comprehensive security plan for 2025 New Year's Eve celebrations]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai Welcomes the Winter Season with Festive Celebrations]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/dubai-welcomes-the-winter-season-with-festive-celebrations-2024-12-22-1.735934</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/dubai-welcomes-the-winter-season-with-festive-celebrations-2024-12-22-1.735934</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Dubai is set to welcome the winter season in a truly exceptional way, with its entertainment destinations adorned with festive decorations and filled with joy and excitement. These destinations offer a variety of unique events and activities, making them the perfect choice for families to create unforgettable holiday memories.</p>

<p>Visitors can enjoy dazzling fireworks displays, lively musical performances, and energetic parades featuring beloved holiday characters. Immersive experiences include visits to magical toy workshops, exploring festive-themed decorations, and engaging in fun-filled challenges and adventures.</p>

<p>Additionally, families can savor exceptional dining experiences, featuring seasonal menus and a wide range of international cuisines, as well as festive markets offering unique gifts and an enchanting shopping atmosphere.</p>

<p>With its diverse activities and celebrations, Dubai promises a unique winter experience that combines entertainment and festive cheer, ensuring unforgettable memories for everyone during the holiday season.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 12:55:05 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735936.1734857666!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735936.1734857666!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735936.1734857666!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735935.1734857649!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai Welcomes the Winter Season with Festive Celebrations]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Lifestyle</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Lifestyle</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Extraordinary Line-Up of Only-in-Dubai Experiences Keeps DSF's Third Week Dazzling!]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/extraordinary-line-up-of-only-in-dubai-experiences-keeps-dsf-s-third-week-dazzling-2024-12-20-1.735924</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/extraordinary-line-up-of-only-in-dubai-experiences-keeps-dsf-s-third-week-dazzling-2024-12-20-1.735924</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p align="center">&nbsp;</p>

<ul>
	<li><em>Third week of DSF brings a festive wonderland to life with must-visit attractions including themed plays, spectacular concerts, and delightful family friendly experiences</em></li>
	<li><em>First-ever edition of The Uncommon x DSF launches this week at Al Marmoon from 20 December to 12 January</em></li>
	<li><em>Live concerts continue to dazzle the city with Yara on 21 December, Hany Shaker and Sergei Makovetsky on 26 December, and electrifying X Factor Live Shows every Sunday of DSF</em></li>
	<li><em>The city comes alive with family-friendly festive magic with the Nutcracker, Barney, Dr. Seuss&#39; How The Grinch Stole Christmas, CoComelon, and more</em></li>
	<li><em>Iconic DSF landmarks continue to captivate visitors across the city at DSF Nights at Dubai Festival City Mall, DSF x Hatta, and CanteenX</em></li>
	<li><em>Brand new for this week, the city&rsquo;s most anticipated sales season launches on 26 December with up to 75 per cent off across leading brands and stores</em></li>
	<li><em>Plus, dazzling daily fireworks continue to illuminate the skies at Dubai Festival City Mall and Hatta along with spectacular twice-daily drone shows at Bluewaters Island and The Beach, JBR</em></li>
</ul>

<p style="margin-left:36.0pt;">&nbsp;</p>

<p>The iconic annual <strong>Dubai Shopping Festival (DSF) </strong>continues to dazzle in the third week of its monumental <strong>30th anniversary celebrations</strong>, showcasing the very best the city has to offer. Bringing a diverse range of activities across the city for all to enjoy, the city&rsquo;s biggest-ever celebration launches the first-ever edition of <strong>The Uncommon x DSF </strong>this week, promising an unforgettable desert experience for all. Visitors can also enjoy a thrilling start to the festive season with shows such as<strong> The Nutcracker</strong>, <strong>Dr. Seuss&#39; How The Grinch Stole Christmas</strong>, the <strong>Winter District</strong>, and much more. An exhilarating line-up of A-list concerts adds to the excitement this week with <strong>Yara </strong>on 21 December, <strong>Hany Shaker</strong> and <strong>Sergei Makovetsky</strong> on 26 December, as well as ongoing live <strong>XFactor </strong>shows every Sunday as part of <strong>DSF Nights and Dubai Festival City Mall</strong>.</p>

<p>Plus, organisers Dubai Festivals and Retail Establishment (DFRE) will continue to illuminate the city with <strong>free-to-watch daily fireworks</strong>, stunning photo-worthy <strong>Dubai Lights </strong>installations, and <strong>twice-daily free drone shows</strong> that have wowed audiences with their incredible artistry and innovation. Visitors can continue indulging in delicious delights at <strong>CanteenX</strong>, while immersing themselves in family-friendly attractions at <strong>Ripe Market</strong> and with the <strong>Aladdin in Dubai </strong>stage production. In addition, with the highly anticipated <strong>DSF Sales Season </strong>kicking off later this week, shoppers can bag unbeatable deals and discounts, while incredible <strong>raffles</strong> offer spectacular prizes.</p>

<p><strong>BRAND NEW THIS WEEK</strong></p>

<p><a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dubai-events-calendar/dsf-uncommon-desert-popup"><strong>The Uncommon x DSF</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: Until 12 January 2025</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: Al Marmoom</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>: The Uncommon x DSF transforms Al Marmoom into a sanctuary of creativity and tranquillity, every day from 4pm to 12am. Visitors can experience breathtaking lighting installations by an international artist, cosy firepit gatherings, an intriguing mirror maze, exciting arcade and play area, with an enchanting outdoor cinema nights and live oud performances on the weekends.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dubai-events-calendar/the-nutcracker"><strong>The Nutcracker</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: Until 22 December 2024</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: Dubai Opera</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>: The timeless tale of The Nutcracker enchants audiences this festive season with the renowned Astana Opera ballet and orchestra under the artistic direction of Yuri Grigorovich.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dubai-events-calendar/dr-seuss-musical"><strong>Dr. Seuss&#39; How The Grinch Stole Christmas</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: Until 24 December 2024</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: Zabeel Theatre, Jumeirah Zabeel Saray</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>:&nbsp; The enchanting world of Whoville takes centre stage at Zabeel Theatre with Dr. Seuss&#39; How the Grinch Stole Christmas! The Musical, a heartwarming tale of The Grinch&rsquo;s transformation from mischief to holiday cheer.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dubai-events-calendar/cocomelon-live"><strong>Cocomelon Live: Sing-a-long</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: 20 &ndash; 21 December</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: Coca-Cola Arena</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>: CoComelon LIVE: Sing-A-Long brings a vibrant musical adventure featuring cheerful preschool teacher Ms. Appleberry, JJ, and friends at 9am, 1pm and 5pm.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dubai-events-calendar/hany-shaker"><strong>Hany Shaker Live in Concert</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: 26 December 2024</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: Dubai Opera</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>: An unforgettable evening of chart-topping Egyptian melodies will take centre stage as star singer Hany Shaker delivers a live performance at <a href="https://dubai.platinumlist.net/event-tickets/94791/hany-shaker-concert-at-dubai-opera?utm_source=google&amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;utm_campaign=21824142193&amp;utm_content=174256037732-717557651254--p-&amp;utm_term=hany%20shaker%20dubai%20opera&amp;gad_source=1&amp;gclid=CjwKCAiA6aW6BhBqEiwA6KzDc5X-SHnLJxuyuAokt5lddfZHvrKBDLEpmOEa1m0Znni1avSAnMrFahoCeaYQAvD_BwE">Dubai Opera</a>.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://dubai.platinumlist.net/event-tickets/93395/non-accidentally-meeting-sergey-makovetsky-at-zabeel-theatre-dubai"><strong>Sergei Makovetsky &quot;Non-Accidentally Meeting&quot; Live in Concert</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: 26 December 2024</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: Zabeel Theatre, Jumeirah Zabeel Saray</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>: Sergei Makovetsky presents a captivating one-man show, blending personal reflections, vivid stage miniatures, and rare film footage.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>GameQuest Express</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: 20 - 29 December 2024</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: Ibn Battuta Mall</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>: The GameQuest Express offers an exhilarating gaming experience for all ages every day from 2pm to 10pm with free-to-play zones, tournaments, and interactive activities, located at Ibn Battuta Mall&rsquo;s Persian Court. Highlights include racing simulators, VR adventures, and console classics. Participants can compete for daily prizes, including the chance to win 30 gold coins.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Shop &amp; Win Like a Pro</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: Until&nbsp; 5 January 2025</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: City Centre Deira</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>: Shoppers can explore immersive, pixel-themed gaming experiences in celebration of DSF when spending AED 200 or more at City Centre Deira (excluding Carrefour) to gain access to the interactive activation, featuring fun zones, engaging gameplay, and chances to win instant prizes. Winners take home exciting prizes such as smartphones, smart TVs, laptops, PlayStations, and more.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>3 Days, 30 Winners with Centrepoint</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: 20 - 22 December</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: Citywide Centrepoint stores</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>: Centrepoint invites shoppers to experience the ultimate style upgrade when spending just AED 200 for the chance to win a fabulous AED 2,000 gift voucher.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>DSF Sale Season </strong></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date:</strong> 26 December 2024 - 2 February 2025</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: Citywide</li>
	<li><strong>About: </strong>The DSF Sale Season kicks off with unbeatable discounts of up to 75 per cent across Dubai&rsquo;s malls and shopping districts, with over 800 global brands participating across 3,500 outlets.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>RETURNING WEEKLY FAVOURITES</strong></p>

<p><a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dubai-events-calendar/dsf-fireworks-nights"><strong>Daily Free Fireworks</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: Until 12 January 2025</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: Dubai Festival City Mall and Hatta</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>: DSF&rsquo;s third week continues to dazzle with mesmerising fireworks lighting up the city skies. At 9pm each night, Dubai Festival City Mall is illuminated by vibrant displays of colour and light crafted by the Al Zarooni Group. Meanwhile, Hatta sets the stage for breathtaking shows every Friday and Saturday at 8pm.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dubai-events-calendar/dsf-drones-light-show"><strong>Twice-daily Drone Shows</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: Until 12 January 2025</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: Bluewaters Island and The Beach, JBR</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>: Dubai&rsquo;s skies continue to dazzle with extraordinary twice-daily drone shows presented by Emarat at 8pm and 10pm. As the longest-running performances in DSF history, these awe-inspiring displays feature 1,000 drones crafting breathtaking visuals that honour Dubai&rsquo;s vibrant heritage, dynamic present, and ambitious future. A spectacular brand-new theme launches from 27 December to 12 January, &lsquo;Celebrating Dubai&rsquo; while seamlessly blending tradition and modernity against the backdrop of powerful beats and cutting-edge soundscapes with 2D and 3D drone formations.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dubai-events-calendar/dsf-dubai-lights"><strong>Dubai Lights</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: Until 12 January 2025</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: Bluewaters Island, Palm Nakheel Mall, Palm West Beach, Al Seef, Dubai Design District, Al Marmoom, Hatta, and City Walk</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>: Dubai Lights shine brighter than ever for the 30th edition of DSF, unveiling a reimagined experience with captivating, interactive installations created by renowned international artists. This artistic showcase celebrates the harmony of the five elements&mdash;Water, Air, Fire, Energy and Connection&mdash;through innovative and immersive displays.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dubai-events-calendar/dsf-canteen-x-mushrif-park"><strong>CanteenX</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: Until 31 December 2024</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: Mushrif Park, Gate 1</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>: Returning for its second edition, the free-to-enter vibrant outdoor market is running daily from 4pm to midnight on weekdays and until 1am on weekends and features four unique zones. Guests can indulge in mouthwatering dishes while enjoying live DJ sets, high-energy performances, interactive activities and exclusive menus curated by renowned F&amp;B owners.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dubai-events-calendar/dsf-nights-dfcm"><strong>DSF Nights at Dubai Festival City Mall</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: Until 12 January 2025</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: Dubai Festival City Mall</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>: DSF Nights at Dubai Festival City Mall captivates visitors with an exciting line-up of daily activities and events, including an exceptional live concert from Yara on 21 December, Hams Fikri on 4 January 2025, and Ibrahim Al Sultan on 11 January 2025. A special ticketed performance on New Year&rsquo;s Eve from Mahmoud El Esseily will ring in the New Year in style, with tickets available on <a href="https://platinumlist.net/artist/3087/mahmoud-el-esseily">Platinumlist</a>. Visitors can look forward to lively performances by beloved characters such as Modesh &amp; Dana, Barney, and Bluey, indulge in culinary delights such as The Bay by Social, Sayf, Helipad by Frozen Cherry, and M&rsquo;OSHI, and enjoy the twice-daily brand-new IMAGINE shows.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dubai-events-calendar/dsf-nights-dfcm?query=imagine&amp;page=1&amp;configure=%5Bobject%20Object%5D"><strong>Live X Factor Shows</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: Every Sunday until 12 January 2025</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: Festival Bay, Dubai Festival City Mall</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>: Experience the thrill of being part of a live television audience as the world-famous <strong>X Factor</strong> live shows take the stage. This iconic singing competition is broadcasting live every Sunday from 10:30pm to 1am, featuring extraordinary talent and captivating musical performances. Don&rsquo;t miss the chance to witness unforgettable moments as rising stars take the stage in this globally celebrated show.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dubai-events-calendar/dsf-hatta"><strong>DSF x Hatta</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: Until 5 January 2025</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: Hatta Wadi Hub</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>: Hatta Wadi Hub transforms into the ultimate winter retreat for DSF x Hatta from 4pm to 10pm on weekdays and 12pm to 12am on weekends. Visitors can soar through stunning landscapes on a zipline, glide across calm waters while kayaking, enjoy live music performances and fireworks on weekends under the open sky and indulge in some of Dubai&rsquo;s most loved food pop-ups including Home Bakery and G.O.A.T Burger.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dubai-events-calendar/ripe-market"><strong>Ripe Market</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: Every Saturday and Sunday</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: Dubai Police Academy Park</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>: The Ripe Market features a vibrant bazaar of artisan stalls, unique small businesses, and handcrafted products, alongside fresh organic produce, baked goods, and tasty bites from food trucks, offering a lively community shopping and dining experience.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dubai-events-calendar/winter-district"><strong>Winter District</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: 20 &ndash; 22 December 2024</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: Dubai Media City Amphitheatre</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>: The Dubai Media City Amphitheatre becomes a festive wonderland as it transforms into a Winter District brimming with holiday magic with sparkling lights, cheerful decorations, a charming Christmas market, delicious seasonal treats, enchanting attractions, and a snow play area for children.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://dubai.platinumlist.net/event-tickets/93024/aladdin-in-dubai"><strong>Aladdin in Dubai</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: 20 &ndash; 29 December 2024</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: Jumeirah Beach Hotel</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>: The Dubai Panto returns to its home at Jumeirah Beach Hotel Auditorium for its 18th year with a magical new version of Aladdin. This enchanting British pantomime, infused with a Middle Eastern twist, promises a captivating mix of comedy, music, dancing, and dazzling visuals.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Sonic Stage Show</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: Until 7 January 2025</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: City Center Mirdif</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>: To celebrate the new Sonic movie, an exciting Sonic activation and stage show debuts during the 30th edition of DSF. The 12-minute stage show brings Sonic the Hedgehog to life in an action-packed adventure, complete with meet-and-greets and a fun activity zone. Entry to the zone requires a spend of AED 200 for two tokens, accessible by presenting a SHARE ID on the SHARE Rewards App.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>DSF VISA DIB Millionaire </strong></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date: </strong>Until 12 January 2025</li>
	<li><strong>Location: </strong>Citywide</li>
	<li><strong>About:</strong> Shoppers paying with a Dubai Islamic Bank Visa Debit or Credit Card can unlock the chance to win an incredible 1 million dirhams. Making cumulative purchases of AED 500 at participating DSF retailers will earn an entry into an exclusive draw&mdash;with unlimited chances to enter and turn dreams into a reality.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Celebrate 30 years of DSF with Dubai Jewellery Group </strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Date: Until 12 January 2025</li>
	<li>Location: participating Dubai Jewellery Group outlets citywide</li>
	<li>About: Every jewelry purchase of AED 1,500 earns a raffle coupon for the chance to win a share of an astounding AED 1.5 million in gold. With weekly draws on 20 and 27 December 2024, and 3 and 12 January 2025, four lucky winners each week will take home 250 grams of gold.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>DSF Raffles </strong></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Date</strong>: Until 12 January 2025</li>
	<li><strong>Location</strong>: Citywide</li>
	<li><strong>About</strong>: With DSF, everyone has the chance to win big this season, with an incredible array of daily rewards, grand raffles, mega prize draws, and unmatched retail promotions. From ENOC&rsquo;s daily prizes of up to AED 10,000 to the DSF Mega Raffle and Majid Al Futtaim&rsquo;s Biggest Prize of the Year, the excitement is non-stop. Highlights include Modesh and BLUE Rewards Millionaire at Dubai Festival City Mall, Dubai Jewellery Group&rsquo;s 1.5 million dirhams in gold raffle, DSMG&rsquo;s Shop, Spin, and Win promotion and 30 DSF Golden Ticket prizes worth AED 300,000, making this season a true celebration of dreams and surprises.</li>
</ul>

<p>Visitors can navigate through the endless excitement of this year&rsquo;s festival through the all-new <strong>digital </strong><a href="https://dsfmap.visitdubai.com/"><strong>DSF Map</strong></a> - an interactive online guide to explore all of the season&rsquo;s iconic and only-in-Dubai experiences, festival favourites, ever-popular signature events, and brand-new additions waiting to be discovered across the city.</p>

<p>Dubai Shopping Festival is supported by Key Partners Dubai Islamic Bank and VISA, and Strategic Partners which include: Al Futtaim Malls (Dubai Festival City Mall &amp; Festival Plaza), Al Zarooni Group (Mercato Shopping Mall), AW Rostamani Group, DHAM (Al Seef, Bluewaters, Ibn Battuta Mall, Nakheel Mall and The Outlet Village), Emirates Airline, ENOC, e&amp;, Majid Al Futtaim (Mall of the Emirates, City Centre Mirdif, City Centre Deira), Merex Investment (City Walk and The Beach, JBR),&nbsp;and&nbsp;talabat.</p>

<p>For more information, visit the <a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dsf">Dubai Shopping Festival</a> website and follow @DubaiFestivals on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/dubaifestivals/">Instagram</a> and <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@dubaifestivals">TikTok</a>.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 22:01:59 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735927.1734717653!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735927.1734717653!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735927.1734717653!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735926.1734717638!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735925.1734717621!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Extraordinary Line-Up of Only-in-Dubai Experiences Keeps DSF's Third Week Dazzling!]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Lifestyle</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Lifestyle</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[The 11th Camel Trek Nears Completion: A Celebration of UAE Heritage]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/the-11th-camel-trek-nears-completion-a-celebration-of-uae-heritage-2024-12-18-1.735899</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/the-11th-camel-trek-nears-completion-a-celebration-of-uae-heritage-2024-12-18-1.735899</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<ul>
	<li>
	<blockquote>
	<h3><strong>Abdullah Hamdan Bin Dalmouk: The Journey Embodies Our Historical and Cultural Values</strong></h3>
	</blockquote>
	</li>
</ul>

<p><br />
The 11th edition of the Camel Trek, organized by the Hamdan Bin Mohammed Heritage Center (HHC), is nearing its final destination in Dubai after covering over half of its 680 km journey across the UAE desert. Featuring 33 participants from 17 nationalities, the trek will culminate at the Heritage Village in Global Village on December 21, after 13 days of travel.</p>

<p>The expedition began on December 9 in the Rub&#39; al Khali desert and has passed key checkpoints, including Tel Marib, South Shah, the Arabian Oryx Sanctuary &ldquo;Bab Bin Mudhahiya,&rdquo; Al-Du&rsquo;aisiya, and North Al-Qaw&rsquo;a, among others. The caravan is now advancing towards Khaznah, Ajban, and Saih Al-Silm before reaching its final destination.</p>

<h3><strong>A Journey with a Message</strong></h3>

<p>Abdullah Hamdan Bin Dalmouk, CEO of the Hamdan Bin Mohammed Heritage Center, commended the participants&#39; dedication and resilience in facing natural challenges like cold weather and tough terrain. He highlighted the role of HHC trainers in preparing the participants for such hardships, stating:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;This journey was a real test of teamwork. With the increase in participants, we extended travel hours, often arriving after nightfall. This year&rsquo;s trek simulated historical journeys, with participants preparing their meals and adapting to conditions similar to those faced by our ancestors.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Bin Dalmouk emphasized that the trek carries a significant cultural message, aiming to raise awareness about the UAE&#39;s rich heritage:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Through this journey, we aim to reconnect with our history, preserving our national identity and introducing future generations to the essence of desert life&mdash;a key part of our ancestors&rsquo; lives.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>

<h3><strong>Traditions and Personal Stories</strong></h3>

<p>For some participants, the trek was a journey of self-discovery and cultural immersion. Emirati citizen Khaled Yahya Al-Balushi, inspired by Al-Oula Radio, shared:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;This experience allows me to honor my forefathers&#39; journeys and represent the UAE&rsquo;s traditions in the best light. Through cooperation and commitment, we showcase the beauty of Emirati customs alongside participants from diverse backgrounds.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Dutch horse trainer Harmke Westervelt also expressed her joy at participating:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;This journey was challenging yet deeply rewarding. As a horse trainer, I found bonding with my camel a unique and transformative experience, highlighting the incredible traits of these remarkable creatures.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>

<h3><strong>About the Hamdan Bin Mohammed Heritage Center</strong></h3>

<p>The Hamdan Bin Mohammed Heritage Center (HHC) is a leading organization dedicated to the preservation and promotion of Emirati culture and heritage. It serves as a hub for cultural and heritage initiatives, competitions, and research, fostering a deep sense of national identity among Emirati youth while promoting UAE traditions on a global stage.</p>

<p>For more information, visit <a href="http://www.hhc.gov.ae" rel="noopener" target="_new">www.hhc.gov.ae</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 12:56:18 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735903.1734512100!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735903.1734512100!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735903.1734512100!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735902.1734512029!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735901.1734511954!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735900.1734511936!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[The 11th Camel Trek Nears Completion: A Celebration of UAE Heritage]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Top Online Flower Delivery Services in UAE: Discover the Best Florists for Every Occasion]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/top-online-flower-delivery-services-in-uae-discover-the-best-florists-for-every-occasion-2024-12-17-1.735886</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/top-online-flower-delivery-services-in-uae-discover-the-best-florists-for-every-occasion-2024-12-17-1.735886</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The flourishing online flower delivery sector in the dynamic atmosphere of the United Arab Emirates has made sending flowers simpler than ever. Whether you&#39;re celebrating a birthday, expressing love, or simply wanting to brighten someone&#39;s day, these services offer the perfect combination of convenience, variety, and dependability. Let&#39;s look at the greatest <a href="https://myglobalflowers.com/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000CD;"><strong>online flower delivery services</strong></span></a> in the UAE, including the most popular blooms and top florists such as MyGlobalFlowers, flowers.ae, uaeflowers.com, florette.ae, and flowerstationdubai.com.</p>

<p><strong>Most Popular Flowers in the UAE</strong></p>

<p>The UAE&rsquo;s online flower market is flourishing, driven by a tech-savvy population and a love for luxury. From Dubai&#39;s skyscrapers to Abu Dhabi&#39;s charming places, internet florists are making it simple to send stunning arrangements throughout the country. Purchasing fresh flowers has never been easier or more elegant, thanks to user-friendly websites and quick delivery.</p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Roses: Timeless Elegance&nbsp;</strong></li>
</ul>

<p>Roses are the MVP of flowers in the UAE. Symbolizing love and respect, they come in a rainbow of colors. Red for romance, yellow for friendship, and white for purity&mdash;there&rsquo;s a rose for every vibe. Plus, their classic beauty never goes out of style, making them a top pick for any occasion.</p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Lilies: Grace and Beauty</strong></li>
</ul>

<p>Lilies add a touch of sophistication with their stunning blooms and enchanting fragrance. Perfect for weddings or elegant events, they&rsquo;re often paired with other flowers to create eye-catching arrangements. Their versatile look makes them a favorite among UAE florists.</p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Orchids: Exotic Sophistication</strong></li>
</ul>

<p>Orchids bring a dash of luxury and exotic flair to any bouquet. They&#39;re ideal for trendy bouquets and elegant decorations because of their unusual shapes and durability. Furthermore, with proper care, orchids can remain brilliant for weeks, making them an excellent gift choice.</p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Local Favorites: Desert-Inspired Blooms</strong></li>
</ul>

<p>Embracing native flora, many UAE florists incorporate desert-inspired flowers into their designs. Consider vivid desert roses and hardy succulents that reflect the region&#39;s heritage. These one-of-a-kind arrangements add a new touch while also celebrating the natural beauty of the UAE.</p>

<p><br />
<strong>Leading Online Flower Delivery Services in UAE</strong><br />
<strong>MyGlobalFlowers</strong></p>

<p>MyGlobalFlowers truly shines with its international flair and jaw-dropping arrangements. Whether you&#39;re sending love throughout the world or right here in the UAE, they&#39;ve got the skills to make your floral message shine. Their user-friendly internet platform makes it easy to order from anywhere.<br />
Customers rave about the impeccable freshness and vibrant colors of the flowers. Many people praise MyGlobalFlowers&#39; dependable and speedy delivery, making it a top choice for special occasions and last-minute gifts. With rave ratings across numerous platforms, it&#39;s easy to see why they&#39;re so popular among flower enthusiasts in the UAE.</p>

<p><strong>Flowers.ae</strong><br />
flowers.ae is all about letting your creativity bloom! If you enjoy personalizing every aspect, this is your go-to florist. Their vivid and customizable arrangements make each bouquet unique, making them ideal for anyone looking to personalize their floral presents.<br />
Frequent buyers love their loyalty perks, which include discounts, exclusive offers, and early access to new collections. Their user-friendly website and excellent customer support make the entire experience smooth and enjoyable.</p>

<p><strong>uaeflowers.com</strong><br />
uaeflowers.com has a large collection of elegant designs that cater to every taste. Whether you prefer classic elegance or modern flair, their vast collection offers something for everyone. Navigating their website is simple, making flower shopping stress-free.</p>

<p>Users love the intuitive website and the vast selection available. Positive reviews often mention the excellent customer service and the fresh, vibrant flowers that arrive promptly. Whether you&#39;re a first-time buyer or a returning customer, uaeflowers.com ensures a delightful shopping experience.</p>

<p><strong>Florette</strong><br />
Exclusive designs and excellent quality are what florette.ae is known for. Here you may find the most exquisite flower arrangements, perfect for making a lasting impression. Their dedication to perfection and meticulousness ensures that each arrangement is absolutely stunning.</p>

<p>Customers consistently praise the premium quality and stunning designs. The reliable delivery service and exceptional customer support further elevate the experience, making florette.ae a favorite among those seeking the best in floral arrangements.</p>

<p><strong>Flower Station</strong><br />
flowerstationdubai.com is your destination for unique and creative flower arrangements that make a statement. If you&rsquo;re looking to wow someone with something different, their innovative designs are sure to impress. Their flair for creativity sets them apart in the bustling Dubai flower scene.</p>

<p>Customers love the unique and creative designs that stand out from the typical bouquets. Many have praised the excellent customer service and dependable same-day delivery. The beautiful presentation of each arrangement and the use of fresh, colorful flowers are common themes in the positive comments.</p>

<p><strong>Most Common Advantages of Online Flower Delivery Services</strong></p>

<p>When it comes to sending flowers in the UAE, online delivery services totally steal the show. No matter where you are or what you&#39;re celebrating, they make gifting blossoms effortless and fun. Here are the main reasons why ordering flowers online is the best option:</p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Convenience:</strong> Order flowers from the comfort of your home or on the go, any time of day.</li>
	<li><strong>Variety:</strong> Access a vast selection of flowers and arrangements that cater to every taste and occasion.</li>
	<li><strong>Customization:</strong> Tailor your bouquet to suit your specific needs, whether it&rsquo;s color, type, or style.</li>
	<li><strong>Speed:</strong> Enjoy fast and reliable delivery options, including same-day delivery in many cases.</li>
	<li><strong>Reliability:</strong> Trustworthy services ensure your flowers arrive fresh and beautifully arranged.</li>
</ul>

<p>Online flower delivery is the preferred alternative for many in the UAE due to these amazing perks. Whether you&#39;re organizing ahead of time or in a pinch, these services will ensure that your floral presents are perfect and hassle-free.</p>

<p><strong>Your Perfect Bouquet Awaits</strong><br />
Choosing the right online flower delivery service in the UAE ensures that your floral gifts have a lasting impression. With a diverse assortment of gorgeous flowers and top-tier florists like MyGlobalFlowers, flowers.ae, uaeflowers.com, florette.ae, and flowerstationdubai.com, finding the perfect bouquet for any occasion is straightforward. Accept the ease and beauty of online flower delivery to make every occasion in the UAE unique and memorable.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 23:25:14 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735887.1734462894!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735887.1734462894!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735887.1734462894!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735888.1734462951!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Top Online Flower Delivery Services in UAE: Discover the Best Florists for Every Occasion]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Lifestyle</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Lifestyle</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Hatta Winter initiative launched as part of '#DubaiDestinations' campaign]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/hatta-winter-initiative-launched-as-part-of-dubaidestinations-campaign-2024-12-11-1.735823</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/hatta-winter-initiative-launched-as-part-of-dubaidestinations-campaign-2024-12-11-1.735823</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Under the directives and patronage of H.H. Sheikh Ahmed bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Second Deputy Ruler of Dubai and Chairman of the Dubai Media Council, the Hatta Winter initiative was launched today.</p>

<p>Organised under the supervision of the Supreme Committee to Oversee the Development of Hatta, and implemented by Brand Dubai, the creative arm of the Government of Dubai Media Office, the initiative invites residents and visitors to explore the unique experiences offered by the mountainous region during the cooler months of the year.</p>

<p>Running from 13th December 2024, to 22nd January 2025, the campaign seeks to showcase Hatta as a leading winter destination. The initiative will shine a spotlight on the region&rsquo;s cultural, tourism, and entertainment offerings, and dynamic entrepreneurial spirit.</p>

<p>Part of the #DubaiDestinations campaign, Hatta Winter features an extensive programme of activities designed to appeal to people of all ages &ndash; from families and adventurers to culture enthusiasts.</p>

<p>Organised in collaboration with key partners, including the Roads and Transport Authority, Dubai Municipality, Dubai Culture and Arts Authority (Dubai Culture), Dubai Sports Council, and the Dubai Department of Economy and Tourism (DET), the initiative will highlight Hatta&rsquo;s distinctive appeal as a region rich in natural beauty and heritage.</p>

<p>Speaking at a press conference today announcing Hatta Winter, Mona Ghanem Al Marri, Vice Chairperson and Managing Director of the Dubai Media Council and Director-General of the Government of Dubai Media Office, underscored the significance of the initiative.</p>

<p>Aligned with the Dubai 2040 Urban Master Plan&rsquo;s objectives for Hatta, the initiative seeks to consolidate the region&rsquo;s position as a leading tourist destination, unlock new opportunities for the private sector and entrepreneurs, and support community-led local projects, she said.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Hatta Winter showcases the region&rsquo;s charm as a winter destination and highlights the UAE&rsquo;s commitment to promoting sustainable tourism and supporting local communities in Hatta,&rdquo; said Al Marri. &ldquo;With its breathtaking mountain landscapes, refreshing winter weather, diverse wildlife, and rich cultural heritage, Hatta is an ideal destination for those seeking natural beauty and authentic local experiences. From its outdoor recreational activities to its rich traditions and the offerings of local entrepreneurs, Hatta offers something for everyone, including families, adventurers, and culture enthusiasts.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;This campaign has been made possible through exemplary collaboration with the Supreme Committee to Oversee the Development of Hatta as well as our partners, united by a shared commitment to ensuring the success of the event and supporting the Hatta Master Development Plan, the Dubai 2040 Urban Master Plan, and Dubai&rsquo;s broader economic and social agendas. As we continue to develop Hatta&rsquo;s offerings, this initiative reflects our sustained efforts to raise the region&rsquo;s profile as a must-visit winter destination on the global tourism map,&rdquo; she added.</p>

<p>Highlighting the success of the first edition of the initiative, Her Excellency said it attracted over 500,000 visitors from the UAE and Gulf countries in just two weeks. In response to this remarkable interest, the organising committee, under the supervision of the Supreme Committee to Oversee the Development of Hatta, has extended this year&rsquo;s activities to a full month. The extension will give more visitors the opportunity to enjoy Hatta&rsquo;s breathtaking landscapes and winter activities, she said.</p>

<p>Last year&rsquo;s initiative featured 50 activities, 100 workshops, and over 45 volunteers, mostly youth. This year, a comprehensive marketing campaign will spotlight Hatta&rsquo;s offerings, promote local projects, and support the region&rsquo;s economy through extensive media coverage and promotional efforts.</p>

<p>Spanning nearly 40 days, Hatta Winter will feature five festivals, each offering a variety of events and activities organised in collaboration with government and private sector partners. These include: the Hatta Winter Festival, organised by Brand Dubai; Hatta Cultural Nights, presented by Dubai Culture; the Hatta Honey Festival and the Hatta Agricultural Festival, both organised by Dubai Municipality; and Hatta x DSF, organised by DET. Each festival will feature a mix of community, cultural, and entertainment activities, offering unique experiences to people of all ages.</p>

<p>The Hatta Winter Festival will be held in the picturesque surroundings of Leem Lake, a three-hectare site nestled amidst the Hatta mountains. The idyllic setting enhances the festival&rsquo;s appeal, complemented by live entertainment, recreational activities, and cultural programmes.</p>

<p>Shaima Al Suwaidi, Director of Brand Dubai, said, &ldquo;The outstanding collaboration of our partners in the Hatta Winter initiative reflects our shared commitment to showcasing Hatta as a destination that offers rich experiences for citizens, residents, and visitors. Brand Dubai is committed to fostering strong partnerships with government, semi-government, and private sector entities in alignment with Dubai&rsquo;s strategic vision and its economic and social goals over the next decade.&quot;</p>

<p>&ldquo;A key objective of this initiative is to support small and emerging businesses, as it not only drives increased visitor engagement but also helps create new opportunities for entrepreneurs and traders in Hatta and across Dubai. We are proud to feature members of our &lsquo;Proudly from Dubai&rsquo; network in major events and activities throughout the year. This year&rsquo;s Hatta Winter Festival will showcase 30 entrepreneurial projects, with a particular emphasis on those based in Hatta, underscoring our commitment to fostering local talent and promoting entrepreneurship,&rdquo; she added.</p>

<p>She highlighted that the Hatta Winter Festival will include 120 workshops, 14 activities, and four innovative community events. The initiative will also feature 80 television episodes, produced in collaboration with Dubai Media; the Brand Dubai Store; as well as the mesmerising Hatta Mountain Light Shows. The Festival will also host a Majlis for senior Emirati citizens, sponsored by Camelisious, as well two pop-up restaurants, Salt and Sadeem.</p>

<p>Hussain Al Banna, CEO of Traffic and Roads Agency at Dubai&rsquo;s Roads and Transport Authority (RTA) and Head of the Executive Team to Oversee the Development of Hatta, stated, &ldquo;The Supreme Committee to Oversee the Development of Hatta, chaired by His Excellency Mattar Al Tayer, Director General, Chairman of the Board of Executive Directors of Dubai&rsquo;s Roads and Transport Authority (RTA), has completed 41 development projects in Hatta with 24 additional projects currently underway in collaboration with relevant government entities in the emirate. These efforts are aligned with the strategy aimed at enhancing infrastructure and achieving comprehensive development in the region, supporting Dubai&rsquo;s social agenda and enhancing its appeal as an exceptional touristic destination renowned for its natural beauty and wide array of recreational attractions that cater to diverse audiences.</p>

<p>&ldquo;RTA has prioritised enhancing the road and transport network, providing flexible and mass mobility solutions, and offering full support during festivals, activities, and events held in Hatta, particularly the &#39;Hatta Winter Festival.&#39;</p>

<p>&ldquo;RTA organises Hop On Hop Off bus services, operating 29 daily trips to key tourist landmarks in Hatta, as well as the Hatta Express service with 14 direct trips connecting Dubai to Hatta.</p>

<p>&ldquo;This year, RTA has allocated over 1,100 parking spaces to serve the public, alongside 17 buses for internal transportation from the parking areas to the event sites. Additional internal buses are available to transport visitors to the top of Hatta Dam. Furthermore, a dedicated team has been deployed to manage crowds and ensure smooth traffic flow throughout the festival period.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Commenting on the Hatta Honey Festival and Hatta Agricultural Festival, Ahmed Al Zarooni, Director of the Public Parks and Recreational Facilities Department at Dubai Municipality, said, &ldquo;Dubai Municipality will host the ninth edition of the Hatta Honey Festival, a flagship event held annually to support Emirati beekeepers and the honey production sector in the UAE. Running from 27 to 31 December 2024, the festival will feature 51 Emirati beekeepers as part of the Hatta Winter initiative. The event serves as a platform for beekeepers to showcase and market their products and exchange expertise in honey production. The Municipality has ensured that all preparations are complete to provide high-quality facilities and services for visitors and participants.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He added, &quot;The Hatta Agricultural Festival will take place from 18 to 22 January 2025 at the shores of the Leem Lake. The event supports Emirati farmers and the agricultural ecosystem by providing 25 booths for farmers and five accompanying activities. The festival aims to empower farmers and agricultural entrepreneurs by offering facilities and support to Hatta&rsquo;s farmers and farm owners, encouraging sustainable and high-quality agricultural production while contributing to the UAE&#39;s food security system.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Speaking about the cultural and creative activities featured in Hatta Winter, Mariam Dhain Al Tamimi, Manager of Al Shindagha Historical District and Acting Director of the Heritage Sites Department at Dubai Culture, commented, &ldquo;Hatta Cultural Nights is a celebration of the Hatta region&rsquo;s unique heritage, natural beauty, and cultural richness. Through this initiative, we aim to deepen the public&#39;s connection to the traditions and customs of the mountainous region while showcasing the artistic and creative talents that reflect the spirit of the community. As we welcome the fourth edition, we are proud to present a vibrant programme of heritage, artistic, and entertainment activities that not only highlight the region&rsquo;s historical significance but also contribute to its growing presence on the cultural tourism map. One of the key projects is the striking &lsquo;Deliberate Pauses&rsquo; installation by Shaikha Al Mazrou, and part of Dubai Culture&rsquo;s Public Art Strategy. By empowering local talent, supporting producers, and engaging families, Hatta Cultural Nights embodies Dubai Culture&rsquo;s mission to preserve and promote Emirati heritage while enriching the cultural and artistic fabric of Dubai.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Dr. Mohammed Abdul Wahab Al Ansari, Director of the Strategy Office at the Dubai Sports Council, said, &ldquo;The Dubai Sports Council is committed to enhancing Hatta&rsquo;s profile as a leading destination for sports and recreational activities. Since 2009, we have introduced various initiatives and hosted numerous local and international events, such as mountain biking, hiking, and cycling races under the Dubai Pulse Programme, which have drawn hundreds of participants from Hatta and neighbouring areas. In collaboration with key partners from the government and private sectors, including Dubai Municipality and the Roads and Transport Authority, we have significantly enhanced Hatta&rsquo;s sports infrastructure by developing interconnected mountain biking trails, hiking routes, and specialised cycling tracks to accommodate participants of all skill levels.</p>

<p>He added, &ldquo;Our vision for Hatta is to provide a diverse array of sporting events that appeal to all age groups and interests. These include cycling, mountain biking, long-distance running races, hiking, stand-up paddleboarding, kayaking, walking tours, obstacle races, and motorsport events like the Dubai International Baja and Hatta Ramadan Tournament. Signature events such as the Dubai International Hero and obstacle challenge races further highlight Hatta&rsquo;s unique sports offerings. We are also committed to increasing private sector participation by involving local companies in organising a variety of community events that cater to all segments of society, such as Hatta Outdoors, Hattan Investment, Harpers Mountain Bikes, Hatta Sports Club, and Wadi Hub. In collaboration with Brand Dubai and Hattan Investment, two football and basketball courts will be built during the Hatta Winter events, providing free access for residents and visitors of the Hatta region.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Ahmed Al Khaja, CEO of Dubai Festivals and Retail Establishment at the Dubai Department of Economy and Tourism, highlighted the significant impact of last year&rsquo;s edition of the initiative in promoting Hatta and its natural beauty. He noted the unprecedented number of events and activities organised with the participation of various government, semi-government, and private sector entities, which attracted a large number of visitors. This overwhelming response encouraged the organising committee to extend this year&rsquo;s event to a full month of activities.</p>

<p>He added that the Dubai Department of Economy and Tourism is committed to contributing to the Hatta Winter initiative by organising fireworks displays every Friday and Saturday. The Department will also promote the events and workshops through its platforms and guide visitors to activity locations to ensure they enjoy the full experience, he said.</p>

<p>Organised by DET as part of the Dubai Shopping Festival&#39;s 30th anniversary celebrations, Hatta x DSF invites visitors to immerse themselves in an exciting outdoor experience. Running until 5 January 2025, the event offers a blend of adventure and relaxation, featuring activities like mountain biking, zip-lining, and kayaking, amidst stunning views of Hatta&rsquo;s natural beauty. Visitors can also enjoy enchanting lighting displays, captivating fireworks every weekend, live music performances, and artisanal caf&eacute;s serving the finest seasonal beverages.</p>

<p>Hamda Mohammed Mubarak Albasata, Head of Sama Dubai, said, &ldquo;Dubai Media Incorporated is proud to cover the Hatta Winter initiative through Sama Dubai channel with five diverse programmes airing daily and weekly. These programmes blend social, cultural, entertainment, and historical themes, showcasing the unique beauty and landmarks of Hatta, along with highlights from Dubai. The content features engaging segments, including interviews with Hatta residents, festival visitors, and activities around Leem Lake. Additionally, Dubai Media Incorporated will provide comprehensive coverage of all festival events and participants, amplifying the experience across social media platforms. This includes conducting in-depth interviews with festival partners to bring the event to life for a wider audience.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 22:29:24 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735824.1733941711!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735824.1733941711!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Hatta Winter initiative launched as part of '#DubaiDestinations' campaign]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Lifestyle</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Lifestyle</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid approves Dubai Walk Master Plan to transform emirate into year-round pedestrian-friendly city]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-approves-dubai-walk-master-plan-to-transform-emirate-into-year-round-pedestrian-friendly-city-2024-12-07-1.735767</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-approves-dubai-walk-master-plan-to-transform-emirate-into-year-round-pedestrian-friendly-city-2024-12-07-1.735767</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister of the UAE and Ruler of Dubai, has approved the Dubai Walk Master Plan (Dubai Walk), a visionary initiative aimed at transforming Dubai into a pedestrian-friendly city. The plan was approved in the presence of H.H. Sheikh Maktoum bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, First Deputy Ruler of Dubai, and Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Finance of the UAE.<br />
The Dubai Walk Master Plan will establish an integrated network of walkways with a unique identity, focusing on accessibility, safety, and a comfortable walking experience, featuring uninterrupted pathways and expanded green spaces.<br />
His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum said that enhancing the quality of life in Dubai remains a key focus of the emirate&#39;s strategic vision. He emphasised that innovative infrastructure projects and the development of a distinctive, modern destination reflect Dubai&#39;s global stature, further strengthening its position as the preferred city to live, work, and visit.<br />
His Highness said: &ldquo;We have approved the Dubai Walk Master Plan, a 6,500 km network of modern walkways covering 160 areas across the emirate. The plan includes constructing 3,300 km of new walkways and rehabilitating 2,300 km of existing ones by 2040, in addition to more than 900 km of walkways planned beyond 2040. It also involves developing 110 pedestrian bridges and underpasses to enhance connectivity. This ambitious plan aims to increase pedestrian and soft mobility from 13% to 25% by 2040.&rdquo;<br />
His Highness added: &ldquo;Dubai is a city of the future, committed to creating a healthy and happy urban environment. The Dubai Walk Master Plan promotes active lifestyles and provides exercise opportunities for all, making walking a central part of our culture and daily lives. This vision will position Dubai as one of the world&rsquo;s healthiest and most sustainable cities.<br />
His Highness reviewed the Dubai Walk Master Plan, which outlines development strategies for walkways through 2040 and sets design standards to ensure seamless integration with the distinctive character of each area.<br />
The approval of the Dubai Walk Master Plan was attended by H.H. Sheikh Ahmed bin Saeed Al Maktoum, President of Dubai Civil Aviation Authority and Chairman and Chief Executive of Emirates Airline and Group; H.H. Sheikh Mansoor bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Chairman of Dubai Sports Council; H.H. Sheikha Latifa bint Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Chairperson of the Dubai Culture and Arts Authority; Mohammed Ibrahim Al Shaibani, Director General of His Highness The Dubai Ruler&rsquo;s Court;Mohamed bin Hadi Al Hussaini, Minister of State for Financial Affairs; Omar Sultan Al Olama, Minister of State for Artificial Intelligence, Digital Economy and Remote Work Applications, in addition to other senior officials.<br />
At the launch of the Master Plan near the Museum of the Future, His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum was received by Mattar Al Tayer, Director General and Chairman of the Board of Executive Directors of the Roads and Transport Authority (RTA). Al Tayer provided a detailed briefing on the Dubai Walk Master Plan and its role in strengthening Dubai&#39;s global competitiveness in pedestrian and soft mobility.<br />
Aligned with the Dubai 2040 Urban Master Plan&rsquo;s &lsquo;20-Minute City&rsquo; goal&mdash;enabling 80% of residents to access essential services within a 20-minute commute&mdash;and the Quality of Life Strategy 2033, the Dubai Walk Master Plan aims to transform Dubai into a pedestrian-friendly city. The plan focuses on enhancing pedestrian safety, connecting areas with existing walkways, and integrating creative and cultural elements into soft mobility infrastructure, reflecting the unique identity of each area. It also promotes collaboration with strategic partners to deliver innovative infrastructure solutions while engaging youth to contribute creative ideas for walkway design and amenities.<br />
The plan envisions a 6,500 km interconnected walkway network, constructing 3,300 km of new walkways and upgrading 2,300 km of existing ones. The pilot phase runs from 2025-2027, with full implementation in three stages from 2027-2040.<br />
The plan includes the development of 110 pedestrian bridges and underpasses to enhance connectivity across urban areas. Key projects include a bridge on Al Ittihad Road connecting Al Nahda and Al Mamzar, a bridge on Tripoli Street linking Al Warqa and Mirdif, a bridge on Al Khawaneej Street joining Mushrif and Al Khawaneej, and a bridge on Dubai-Al Ain Road connecting Dubai Silicon Oasis and Dubailand.<br />
The project will seamlessly link major landmarks such as Burj Khalifa, Dubai International Financial Centre, Dubai Marina, and Jumeirah Lakes Towers. Each route will feature distinctive designs, colours, lighting, and landscaping, reflecting the unique identity of its surrounding area.<br />
The walkways will incorporate greenery, shaded areas, misting systems, interactive digital screens, art displays, sports and entertainment equipment, rest areas, and commercial spaces. Accessibility and safety are prioritised through the use of signage, ground markings, lighting, integrated pavements, art displays, and integration with navigation systems and smart applications.<br />
H.H. Sheikh Mohammed reviewed plans for the 17 km first phase of pedestrian walkways, featuring two key routes. The 15 km Al Ras Historical Route in Al Ras and Al Souk Al Kabeer highlights the emirate&rsquo;s heritage, including 5 km along the revitalised waterfront with 25 rehabilitated public squares featuring shaded rest areas, green spaces, and art displays.<br />
His Highness also reviewed &lsquo;The Future Loop&rsquo; project which will be implemented at the Museum of the Future area. This iconic elevated walkway, spanning 2 km with a width ranging from 6 to 15 meters, seamlessly connects key landmarks, including the Dubai World Trade Centre, Museum of the Future, Emirates Towers, Dubai International Financial Centre, and nearby metro stations.<br />
His Highness then viewed the model of &lsquo;The Future Loop,&rsquo; highlighting its connection to 10 key locations, a 30,000-square-metre air-conditioned level for year-round walking, and an additional 30,000 square metres of shaded, green open spaces. The project, which will include commercial spaces, is set to be developed through a public-private partnership.<br />
His Highness also reviewed models for three types of pedestrian walkways. The Scenic-Leisure Walkways include 112 km of waterfront paths, 64 km in urban areas, 124 km of green paths, and 150 km of rural and mountain trails. The City Connectivity Walkways focus on first- and last-mile connections to public transport in 30 areas, including Al Rigga, Business Bay, Al Bada&rsquo;a, and the Trade Centre. The Community Walkways are designed to link residential areas to nearby attractions in 50 areas, beginning with Al Barsha 2, Al Khawaneej 2, and Al Mizhar 1.<br />
Additionally, His Highness reviewed three models for urban spaces. The first model, Plazas, will be implemented in four locations: Etihad Museum, 2nd of December Street, Al Mamzar, and Mushrif. The second model, Superblocks, will cover four areas in its initial phase: Al Fahidi, Al Quoz, Al Karama, and Abu Hail. The third model, Boulevards, will be executed on four streets: Jumeirah, Baniyas, Al Khaleej, and Al Muraqqabat, transforming them into pedestrian-friendly spaces.<br />
H.H. Sheikh Mohammed was briefed on road infrastructure developments in &lsquo;The Future Loop&rsquo; area, including enhancements to the Trade Centre Roundabout and Al Mustaqbal Street. The project will construct 6,200 metres of vehicle bridges and tunnels, transforming the roundabout into a surface-level intersection, improving traffic flow for seven surrounding areas and benefiting approximately 500,000 residents and visitors. These enhancements will increase road capacity by 30% (from 9,000 to 12,000 vehicles per hour) and reduce travel time from eight minutes to just over three.<br />
A global competition, attracting six renowned international consultancy firms, sought innovative walkway designs for Al Ras and the Museum of the Future area. LXA&#39;s first-place concept was selected for the Museum of the Future area, envisioning a 2 km iconic bridge reflecting the area&#39;s elegance and premium infrastructure, complementing landmarks like the Museum of the Future. Supporting the Dubai 2040 Urban Master Plan and the &lsquo;20-Minute City&rsquo; concept, the bridge provides seamless pedestrian and soft mobility access.<br />
The elevated walkway integrates with the area&#39;s futuristic vision, creating a new tourist landmark and ensuring smooth pedestrian and traffic flow. Adopting global best practices, the project promotes walking and soft mobility. The design includes air-conditioned sections, shaded areas, green spaces for temperature reduction, and interactive spaces for recreation and events. The bridge connects major attractions and integrates three Red Line metro stations to encourage metro use.<br />
The Al Ras area design preserves its historical character using minimalist interventions for walkways and plazas. Simple designs, materials, and harmonious colours are emphasised. Public spaces between historical buildings will be rehabilitated to create shaded rest areas, green spaces, and areas for art and cultural displays. Innovative microclimate control, leveraging the area&#39;s natural layout, will ensure pedestrian comfort. Diverse flooring materials will guide visitors to key attractions, and the complete street concept will redesign roads to prioritize pedestrians and soft mobility.<br />
A smart application will be launched which will promote walking by enabling users to track and share their walking data (routes, steps, duration, distance). It will provide information on walkway features, facilities, user reviews, and allow users to save favourite routes. The app will also include a database of Dubai&#39;s pedestrian network, highlighting points of interest, art displays, rest areas, and nearby events. A reward system will award points for distances walked, redeemable for discounts or digital wallet credits.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sat, 7 Dec 2024 19:29:50 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735771.1733585487!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735771.1733585487!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735771.1733585487!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735770.1733585467!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735769.1733585433!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735768.1733585165!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid approves Dubai Walk Master Plan to transform emirate into year-round pedestrian-friendly city]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[A Hidden Gem Opens Its Doors in Dubai]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/a-hidden-gem-opens-its-doors-in-dubai-2024-12-06-1.735762</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/a-hidden-gem-opens-its-doors-in-dubai-2024-12-06-1.735762</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<div class="flex max-w-full flex-col flex-grow">
<div class="min-h-8 text-message flex w-full flex-col items-end gap-2 whitespace-normal break-words text-start [.text-message+&amp;]:mt-5" data-message-author-role="assistant" data-message-id="b25bc71d-2f2d-4024-8733-8e91a7e12fdc" data-message-model-slug="gpt-4o" dir="auto">
<div class="flex w-full flex-col gap-1 empty:hidden first:pt-[3px]">
<div class="markdown prose w-full break-words dark:prose-invert light">
<p>Tucked away on Bluewaters Island, a newly opened venue offers a serene and sophisticated retreat for those seeking a unique dining and cultural experience in Dubai. This hidden gem, located within the newly launched Delano Dubai, is a harmonious blend of artistic design, refined gastronomy, and tranquil surroundings.</p>

<p><strong>A Space Steeped in Charm</strong><br />
Inspired by the elegance of Parisian townhouses and the opulence of Slavic aristocratic estates, the space features a timeless yet contemporary design. Velvet textures, floral linens, and stained glass create an atmosphere that feels intimate and inviting. Thoughtfully designed verandas bring natural light into the interiors, with one extending into a winter garden and another connecting to a private dining area perfect for small gatherings.</p>

<p><strong>A Culinary Escape</strong><br />
The menu here is a tribute to Slavic culinary traditions, offering rich yet elegant flavors. From delicate smoked salmon and salmon coulibiac to artisanal caviars and pavlovas, each dish is carefully crafted for sharing and savoring.</p>

<p><strong>More to Discover</strong><br />
Beyond its dining experience, this destination offers a boutique filled with handpicked items that reflect the artistry and craftsmanship of its culinary heritage. Guests can browse gourmet delicacies, elegant tableware, and home d&eacute;cor or enjoy a quiet moment with tea and pastries.</p>

<p><strong>A Tranquil Retreat</strong><br />
The venue&rsquo;s pool area is a quiet oasis, with mosaic tiles, jasmine-covered pergolas, and private cabanas offering seclusion and relaxation. Overlooking the sea, this space provides a peaceful escape from the bustle of city life.</p>

<p>Discreet and unassuming, this new spot offers a blend of culture, cuisine, and tranquility, making it a destination for those in the know. Its understated charm invites exploration, offering moments of discovery in every corner.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 6 Dec 2024 23:10:42 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735764.1733512181!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735764.1733512181!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735764.1733512181!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735763.1733512161!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[A Hidden Gem Opens Its Doors in Dubai]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Lifestyle</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Lifestyle</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[The 30th edition of the Dubai Shopping Festival kicks off today]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/the-30th-edition-of-the-dubai-shopping-festival-kicks-off-today-2024-12-06-1.735748</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/the-30th-edition-of-the-dubai-shopping-festival-kicks-off-today-2024-12-06-1.735748</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The iconic annual Dubai Shopping Festival (DSF) takes citywide celebrations to dazzling new heights today, kick-starting the festival&rsquo;s greatest, most phenomenal, and out-of-this-world 30th anniversary edition. An exhilarating line-up of world-class entertainment, awe-inspiring adventures, and unforgettable experiences will bring together the entire emirate like never before. This year promises to be the most extraordinary season ever in the festival&rsquo;s incredible history with an action-packed calendar brimming with non-stop, day-in-day-out, fun-filled moments for everyone, every day, in every corner of the city from 6 December 2024 to 12 January 2025.</p>

<p>Organised by Dubai Festivals and Retail Establishment (DFRE), this season kicks off today with epic DSF opening weekend celebrations, featuring the spectacular 321 Festival with show-stopping Arab and South Asian performances, twice-daily drone shows, dazzling fireworks, and exciting family-friendly entertainment with DSF Nights at Dubai Festival City Mall, DSF x Hatta, and the season&rsquo;s biggest shopping deals and grand raffles.</p>

<p>Kicking off a season of electrifying entertainment is the highly anticipated return of the 321 Festival. Music aficionados can enjoy two opening weekend concerts at the Coca-Cola Arena. Starting tonight on 6 December, iconic Arabic music legends Georges Wassouf and Kadim Al Sahir will set the stage ablaze with their greatest hits from 9pm. Later this weekend on 8 December, Coke Studio Live will deliver a mesmerising night of South Asian music, specially curated by the visionary Zulfiqar (Xulfi) Khan. For families, City Walk transforms into an unmissable carnival destination starting today, 6 December, from 12pm, with street performers, dancing classes, creative workshops, street games, glitter face painting, and countless photo opportunities.</p>

<p>The opening weekend of DSS also sees the launch of DSF Nights at Dubai Festival City, presented by talabat, featuring an extraordinary mix of free-to-attend non-stop family-friendly entertainment every single day of DSF that promises something magical for everyone. The season will launch in spectacular style with Ahmed Saad performing live tonight as part of free-to-attend Saturday night concerts at 9:30pm, with spots up for grabs through the Blue Rewards app. Adding to the excitement, the daily IMAGINE shows will dazzle audiences twice every evening (except Sundays), before the night skies light up with stunning daily fireworks. What&rsquo;s more; this, and every Sunday night at 10:30pm, the world-renowned X Factor will take over Festival Bay in partnership with Dubai TV as part of DSF, allowing visitors the unique opportunity to witness aspiring talents from across the region make it to the stage before celebrity judges Ragheb Alama, Rahma Riad, and Fayez Alsaeed, in a thrilling competition to crown the next superstar.</p>

<p>The excitement doesn&rsquo;t stop there! The opening weekend of DSF also sees the launch of free-to-attend daily fireworks by Al Zarooni Group at Dubai Festival City Mall every day starting tonight, 6 December, at 9:00pm, while Hatta&rsquo;s skies will sparkle every Friday and Saturday at 8:00pm.</p>

<p>Across the city, Bluewaters Island and The Beach, JBR will begin hosting twice-daily drone shows presented by Emarat and AO Drones at 8pm and 10pm, featuring a total of 1,000 drones weaving captivating tales of Dubai&rsquo;s legacy and future over the ocean and beachfront at this iconic location.</p>

<p>The captivating Dubai Lights will also take over the city starting today, 6 December, transforming iconic locations into mesmerising canvases for one-of-a-kind art installations celebrating after the five elements - including Energy at Bluewaters Island; Water at Al Seef; Air at Dubai Design District; Fire at Al Marmoom and Connection at Kite Beach. Further enchanting lights can be explored at Palm Nakheel Mall, Palm West Beach,City Walk and DSF x Hatta.</p>

<p>Nature enthusiasts and adventure seekers alike will find their perfect escape with DSF x Hatta as Hatta Wadi Hub transforms into a festive haven of tranquility and excitement for DSF, running from 6 December to 5 January 2025. This picturesque destination offers a unique fusion of outdoor entertainment, immersive activities, and family-friendly experiences, coupled with dazzling fireworks every Friday and Saturday at 8pm. Thrill-seekers will be treated to exhilarating adventures like mountain biking and hiking, while those seeking serenity can unwind in the breathtaking beauty of Hatta&rsquo;s surroundings. Food lovers will delight in a diverse array of culinary options to satisfy every craving, while automotive enthusiasts will have thrilling opportunities to participate in exclusive Nissan test drives to experience Hatta&rsquo;s rugged terrain in unparalleled style.</p>

<p>Shopping in Dubai will transform into an exhilarating experience during DSF, with vibrant mall experiences and exclusive promotions. From malls to markets and homegrown hidden gems to top designer labels, every corner of the city promises unforgettable retail moments for all. Adding to the magic of DSF&rsquo;s opening weekend, the DSF Amber Millionaire from 6 to 8 December will offer an unparalleled opportunity for 30 Amber Members to win one million Amber points each (equivalent to AED 10,000), by spending AED 500 on full-price merchandise in a single transaction. Shoppers can also look forward to many more rewards and life-changing prizes, such as the DIB Visa Millionaire promotion which brings incredible chances to win an incredible prize of one million dirhams when using a Dubai Islamic Bank Visa Debit or Credit Card at participating DSF stores.</p>

<p>Paving the way for a season of incredible offers and unbeatable deals, shoppers can stand the chance to win phenomenal raffles and draws kicking off today. From winning cash prizes to extraordinary experiences, DSF promises something for everyone.</p>

<p>These are just a few of the endless out-of-this-world experiences being specially curated for the most sensational 30th edition of DSF yet. An action-packed calendar of 38 wonder-filled days will deliver many more non-stop, day-in-day-out thrills for everyone, every day, in every corner of the city, with several other spectacular celebrations, A-list concerts, and awe-inspiring events in the coming weeks.</p>

<p>To help visitors navigate through the endless excitement of this year&rsquo;s festival, the all-new digital DSF Map - an interactive online guide to explore all of the season&rsquo;s iconic and only-in-Dubai experiences, festival favourites, ever-popular signature events, and brand-new additions waiting to be discovered across the city has launched. The dynamic tool has been specially designed to help users plan a seamless DSF journey across the city with just the click of a button.</p>

<p>Dubai Shopping Festival is supported by Key Partner VISA Dubai Islamic Bank and Strategic Partners which include: Al Futtaim Malls (Dubai Festival City Mall &amp; Festival Plaza), Al Zarooni Group (Mercato Shopping Mall), AW Rostamani Group, DHAM (Al Seef, Bluewaters, Ibn Battuta Mall, Nakheel Mall and The Outlet Village), Emirates Airline, Enoc, e&amp;, Majid Al Futtaim (Mall of the Emirates, City Centre Mirdif, City Centre Deira), Merex Investment (City Walk and The Beach, JBR) and talabat.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 6 Dec 2024 18:13:42 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735749.1733494396!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735749.1733494396!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[The 30th edition of the Dubai Shopping Festival kicks off today]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Lifestyle</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Lifestyle</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[The 30th edition of the Dubai Shopping Festival is set to kick off in 6 December]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/the-30th-edition-of-the-dubai-shopping-festival-is-set-to-kick-off-in-6-december-2024-12-05-1.735746</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/the-30th-edition-of-the-dubai-shopping-festival-is-set-to-kick-off-in-6-december-2024-12-05-1.735746</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>- Iconic and only in Dubai: DSF returns this weekend with citywide spectacular experiences, epic concerts, and exclusive retail events &amp; promotions for 30th anniversary edition<br />
- The monumental 30th edition of DSF kicks off from 6 December 2024 to 12 January 2025 as the city&rsquo;s greatest, most memorable and out-of-this-world celebration ever<br />
- Incredible new DSF additions will take over the city this weekend, including DSF Nights at Dubai Festival City Mall, DSF x Hatta, and a brand-new breathtaking 1,000-drone display twice daily non-stop for 38 days<br />
- Incredibly popular festival favourites will make their highly anticipated return with new and enhanced 30th anniversary editions, including dazzling daily firework shows, a star-studded lineup at 321 Festival, mesmerising Dubai Lights, and astounding raffles paired with unbeatable retail events and promotions<br />
- Plus, Dubai&rsquo;s one-of-a-kind citywide entertainment returns bigger and better than ever with electrifying live X Factor shows, the iconic Thirty Seconds to Mars concert, and the adrenaline-fueled Dubai Racing Carnival<br />
- A-list Arabic entertainment is back and bigger than ever before this DSF with performances by Kadim Al Sahir and Georges Wassouf at 321 Festival and Ahmed Saad on opening night of DSF Nights in Dubai Festival City Mall</p>

<p><br />
The 30th edition of the iconic Dubai Shopping Festival (DSF) is set to kick off this weekend, transforming the emirate into a hub of magic, excitement, and endless adventures from 6 December 2024 to 12 January 2025. Organised by Dubai Festivals and Retail Establishment (DFRE), this season promises a non-stop celebration for 38 back-to-back days, creating unmissable moments for everyone to treasure together. From incredible A-list concerts and non-stop fireworks to dazzling twice-nightly drone shows, world-class retail adventures, and astounding raffles, DSF&rsquo;s eagerly anticipated season will dazzle with only-in-Dubai city-wide experiences for everyone, every day, in every corner of the city, from sunrise to sunrise.</p>

<p>Check out the lineup of events and experiences taking place in the first week of the most extraordinary programme in DSF history.</p>

<p>321 FESTIVAL - DSF OPENING WEEKEND CONCERTS AT COCA-COLA ARENA<br />
● Date: 6 and 8 December<br />
● Location: Coca-Cola Arena<br />
● About: The highly anticipated 321 Festival lights up Dubai on 6 December with Georges Wassouf and Kadim Al Sahir. On 8 December, the energy will soar even higher with Coke Studio Live. Tickets are now available and selling fast for Kadim Al Sahir and Georges Wassouf and Coke Studio Live &mdash; don&rsquo;t miss this electrifying opening weekend.</p>

<p>321 FESTIVAL - FAMILY CARNIVAL &amp; ENTERTAINMENT AT CITY WALK<br />
● Date: 6 to 8 December<br />
● Location: City Walk<br />
● About: A dazzling array of carnival-themed activities, immersive workshops, and captivating roaming entertainment will head to the heart of Dubai for DSF&rsquo;s epic opening weekend. This vibrant, family-friendly celebration will run daily from 12pm until late evening, creating an atmosphere filled with endless fun, excitement, and magical moments for all ages.</p>

<p>DSF DAILY FIREWORK AT DUBAI FESTIVAL CITY MALL AND HATTA<br />
● Date: 6 December 2024 - 12 January 2025<br />
● Location: Dubai Festival City Mall and Hatta<br />
● About: Dazzling shows by Al Zarooni Group will illuminate Dubai Festival City Mall every day at 9:15pm, while Hatta will light up the skies every Friday and Saturday at 8pm.</p>

<p>DSF TWICE-DAILY DRONE SHOW AT BLUEWATERS ISLAND AND THE BEACH, JBR<br />
● Date: 6 December 2024 - 12 January 2025<br />
● Location: Bluewaters Island and The Beach, JBR<br />
● About: Dubai skies will come alive with spectacular twice-daily drone shows presented by Emarat at 8pm and 10pm. The longest in DSF history, these mesmerising performances will feature a total of 1,000 drones creating all-new breathtaking displays that celebrate Dubai&rsquo;s rich past, dynamic present, and visionary future. From 6 to 26 December, the first theme of the show will captivate audiences with vibrant visuals and stunning drone formations, paying tribute to three decades of iconic DSF moments.</p>

<p>DUBAI LIGHTS<br />
● Date: 6 December 2024 - 12 January 2025<br />
● Location: Bluewaters Island, Palm Nakheel Mall, Palm West Beach, Al Seef, Dubai Design District, Al Marmoom, Kite Beach, Hatta, and City Walk<br />
● About: Dubai Lights will transform the city into a radiant showcase of creativity through immersive light installations designed by renowned international artists, turning the city into a glowing hub of artistic brilliance.</p>

<p>DSF NIGHTS AT DUBAI FESTIVAL CITY MALL<br />
● Date: 6 December 2024 - 12 January 2025<br />
● Location: Dubai Festival City Mall<br />
● About: The mall&rsquo;s Festival Bay will come alive with free-to-attend Saturday night concerts by top Arab stars including Ahmed Saad on 6 December and Shamma Hamdan on 7 December for DSF&rsquo;s epic opening weekend. One-of-a-kind retail pop-ups and trendy dining concepts will bring even more excitement to the experience, while the IMAGINE show will deliver a breathtaking spectacle twice every evening, concluding with awe-inspiring fireworks. Families will delight in a vibrant array of entertainment, with engaging activities and performances designed for all ages, including daily meet-and-greets with the city&rsquo;s beloved characters, Modesh &amp; Dana, and a dazzling experience by the spectacular Pluma Circus. Adding to the thrill, shoppers will have the unique chance to witness DSF&rsquo;s daily raffle draws live and get the chance to win one Million Blue Rewards (equivalent to AED 10,000) with DSF Modesh &amp; Blue Rewards Millionaire raffle.</p>

<p>X FACTOR LIVE SHOW AT DUBAI FESTIVAL CITY MALL<br />
● Date: Every Sunday from 6 December 2024 - 12 January 2025<br />
● Location: DSF Nights at Dubai Festival City Mall<br />
● About: The world-renowned X Factor live show will bring electrifying talent and unforgettable performances every Sunday as part of DSF Nights at Dubai Festival City Mall. In partnership with Dubai TV as part of DSF, this iconic singing competition will transform Dubai Festival City Mall into a hub of musical brilliance from 10:30pm to 1:00am. A dazzling production and star-studded judges including Ragheb Alama, Rahma Riad, and Fayez AlSaeed will ensure each show showcases jaw-dropping talent and thrilling performances.</p>

<p>DSF x HATTA<br />
● Date: 6 December 2024 - 5 January 2025<br />
● Location: Hatta Wadi Hub<br />
● About: Hatta Wadi Hub will come alive with enchanting light displays, dazzling firework displays on the weekend, a vibrant mix of live music performances, outdoor experiences, iconic dining options, immersive lights, and fireworks. Free entry for all from 12pm to 12am on weekends and 4pm to 10pm on weekdays.</p>

<p>THIRTY SECONDS TO MARS<br />
● Date: 12 December 2024<br />
● Location: Coca-Cola Arena<br />
● About: The legendary band promises an electrifying performance, with tickets starting at AED 295 and available for purchase now on the Coca-Cola Arena website.</p>

<p>WINTER CITY<br />
● Date: 6 December 2024 - 12 January 2025<br />
● Location: Expo City Dubai, Al Wasl Plaza<br />
● About: Join Mrs. Claus for festive fun, including sorting the naughty and nice list, decorating cookies, and creating holiday crafts. Brimming with surprises and holiday cheer, the factory will be open daily from 2pm to 10pm, with tickets priced at AED 40 online and AED 50 at the box office.</p>

<p>DUBAI RACING CARNIVAL<br />
● Date: 6 December 2024 onwards<br />
● Location: Meydan Racecourse<br />
● About: The Dubai Racing Carnival will make its grand return for the 2024-2025 season, offering an impressive prize purse and a line-up of world-class events. The season will feature thrilling horse races, vibrant live entertainment, and exquisite five-star dining every Friday, making it one of the most prestigious gatherings in the region.</p>

<p>DSF VISA DIB MILLIONAIRE<br />
● Date: 6 December 2024 - 12 January 2025<br />
● Location: Citywide<br />
● About: By spending AED 500 cumulatively with a Dubai Islamic Bank Visa Debit or Credit Card at participating DSF stores, shoppers will gain entries into a draw to win an incredible 1 million dirhams, with no limit on the number of entries.</p>

<p>DSF AMBER MILLIONAIRE<br />
● Date: 6 - 8 December 2024<br />
● Location: Participating Al Tayer brands citywide<br />
● About: This DSF, Amber Millionaire presents an extraordinary chance for 30 Amber Members to win one million Amber points each, equivalent to AED 10,000, by spending AED 500 on full-price merchandise in a single transaction during the offer period. Customers who meet the qualifying spend will automatically be entered into the raffle draw.</p>

<p>DSF RAFFLES<br />
● Date: 6 December 2024 - 12 January 2025<br />
● Location: Citywide<br />
● About: DSF brings 38 back-to-back days of incredible daily rewards, epic grand raffles, mega prize draws, and out-of-this-world retail promotions. Each day will bring countless chances for residents and visitors to turn their dreams into reality and take home thrilling prizes like DSF Mega Raffle, incredible prizes with ENOC, Emirates Skywards Everyday Millionaire campaign, Biggest Prize of the Year promotion at Majid Al Futtaim malls, Modesh and BLUE Rewards Millionaire at Dubai Festival City Mall, Dubai Jewellery Group&rsquo;s grand raffle of 1.5 million dirhams in gold, the Shop, Spin, and Win promotion by Dubai Shopping Malls Group (DSMG), and 30 DSF Golden Tickit prizes totalling a whopping AED 300,000 this season.</p>

<p>Dubai Shopping Festival is supported by Key Partner VISA Dubai Islamic Bank and Strategic Partners which include: Al Futtaim Malls (Dubai Festival City Mall &amp; Festival Plaza), Al Zarooni Group (Mercato Shopping Mall), AW Rostamani Group, DHAM (Al Seef, Bluewaters, Ibn Battuta Mall, Nakheel Mall and The Outlet Village), Emirates Airline, ENOC, e&amp;, Majid Al Futtaim (Mall of the Emirates, City Centre Mirdif, City Centre Deira), Merex Investment (City Walk and The Beach, JBR), and talabat.</p>

<p>For more information, visit the Dubai Shopping Festival website and follow @DubaiFestivals on Instagram and TikTok.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 5 Dec 2024 22:37:46 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735747.1733423827!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735747.1733423827!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[The 30th edition of the Dubai Shopping Festival is set to kick off in 6 December]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Lifestyle</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Lifestyle</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai Safari Park to offer novel night safari experience from 13 December]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/dubai-safari-park-to-offer-novel-night-safari-experience-from-13-december-2024-12-05-1.735740</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/dubai-safari-park-to-offer-novel-night-safari-experience-from-13-december-2024-12-05-1.735740</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Dubai Safari Park has announced that, starting 13th December, it will be extending its timings, enabling visitors to enjoy night safaris.</p>

<p>The novel experience will offer residents and visitors a chance to appreciate wildlife by nighttime.</p>

<p>Combined with a host of other activities, the night safari will welcome visitors for a limited period &ndash; from 13th December 2024 to 12th January 2025.</p>

<p>The extended hours will allow visitors to engage with wildlife in new ways. During the course of two nightly safaris led by expert wildlife guides, visitors can expect to catch a glimpse of the nighttime routines of over 90 species besides participating in interactive activities involving animals. In addition, an array of live performances, including an African fire show and a neon show, will mesmerise visitors.</p>

<p>Guests will leave with a greater understanding of the natural adaptations, such as enhanced night vision, echolocation, and a heightened sense of smell and hearing, that enable animals in the wild to thrive at night. The highlights for nighttime visitors include the changes in the animals&rsquo; behaviour as the evening deepens; this includes the increased roaring of lions, the heightened activity of the usually elusive pygmy hippos, and the intensified predatory instincts of carnivores primed for nocturnal hunting.</p>

<p>Ahmad Al Zarouni, Director of Public Parks and Recreational Facilities at Dubai Municipality, said, &ldquo;At Dubai Safari Park, we aim to educate our visitors about the marvels of the animal kingdom. With the introduction of the unique night safari, we are excited to reveal a new perspective on the world of wildlife after dark. This experience offers a rare opportunity to explore hidden aspects of life in the wild and learn about our constant efforts to enhance animal welfare, by day and by night. We hope to inspire a deeper appreciation for wildlife and encourage a new generation of animal welfare advocates across the region.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He added, &ldquo;Furthermore, coinciding with the country&rsquo;s peak tourist season, this unique experience &ndash; which can be enjoyed by residents and visitors to Dubai alike &ndash; not only builds on the city&#39;s vibrant lifestyle offerings but also reinforces the emirate&rsquo;s position as a global travel destination. This initiative is yet another example of how Dubai consistently exceeds expectations in delivering memorable moments for everyone.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Dubai Safari Park places animal welfare at the forefront of its operations. Well-considered measures are in place to ensure that the ecosystem and animals&rsquo; natural routines remain undisturbed for the entire period when the night safaris are conducted. Only nocturnally active species will be part of the safari experience, allowing guests to observe them in their most natural state.</p>

<p>The night safari, along with the evening experiences, will run exclusively from 13th December 2024 to 12th January 2025, from 18:00 to 20:00. Tickets will be sold starting from 11th December and visitors are encouraged to secure their night safari tickets from https://dubaisafari.ae as availability is limited.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 5 Dec 2024 22:23:54 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735741.1733423020!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735741.1733423020!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai Safari Park to offer novel night safari experience from 13 December]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Lifestyle</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Lifestyle</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Beauty Tips Inspired by SHEGLAM]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/beauty-tips-inspired-by-sheglam-2024-12-05-1.735729</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/beauty-tips-inspired-by-sheglam-2024-12-05-1.735729</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Beauty Tips Inspired by SHEGLAM</p>

<p><strong>Hydrate and Refresh Your Eyes:</strong><br />
Tired eyes can dull your entire look. Use hydrating under-eye patches, like the Clowning Around Under-Eye Patches, to brighten your under-eye area. Infused with refreshing ingredients, these patches help you look awake, radiant, and ready to conquer the day. They are perfect before makeup application or as part of your skincare routine.</p>

<p><strong>Experiment with Bold Hair Colors Without Commitment:</strong><br />
Want to make a bold statement without the hassle of permanent dye? Try temporary hair color like the Dye Hard Temporary Hair Dye Powder. Available in Chaos Blue and Mad Love Pink, it&rsquo;s a fun way to add a pop of color to your look for special events, cosplay, or even a casual night out. Simply apply and wash out when you&rsquo;re done!</p>

<p><strong>Find Your Perfect Shade:</strong><br />
Whether it&rsquo;s foundation, lipstick, or eyeshadow, don&rsquo;t be afraid to experiment with shades that highlight your unique skin tone and personality. SHEGLAM offers a diverse range of colors to help you find products that truly resonate with your style.</p>

<p><strong>Create a Bold Look with Confidence:</strong><br />
Channel your inner Harley Quinn with daring makeup. Pair vibrant eyeshadows with bold lipstick for an edgy, rebellious vibe. Keep the rest of your look simple to let your statement features shine.</p>

<p><strong>Prep Your Skin for a Flawless Base:</strong><br />
Great makeup starts with great skin. Ensure your face is well-moisturized and primed before applying foundation. Use lightweight, hydrating skincare products to create a smooth canvas. SHEGLAM&rsquo;s cruelty-free skincare options make this step both ethical and effective.</p>

<p><strong>Take Time for Self-Care:</strong><br />
Embrace beauty as part of your self-care routine. Applying under-eye patches, trying new makeup, or playing with hair colors makes beauty fun and empowering. The key is to feel your best in your own skin.</p>

<p><strong>Embrace Creativity:</strong><br />
Makeup and beauty are all about self-expression. Don&rsquo;t shy away from playful or unconventional looks. Use colors and techniques that inspire you, and don&rsquo;t worry about perfection. Let your personality shine through your beauty choices.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 5 Dec 2024 16:21:41 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735731.1733401646!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735731.1733401646!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735731.1733401646!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735730.1733401581!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Beauty Tips Inspired by SHEGLAM]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Lifestyle</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Lifestyle</category>
										
					</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
