<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
	<title>Mobile Business</title>
	<link>http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-business-1.512830?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout</link>	
	<atom:link href="http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-business-1.512830?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" ></atom:link>
	<description>Business</description>
			        <language>en</language>
    				<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai ranks among world’s top 10 cities in Global Power City Index for second consecutive year]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/business/economy-finance/dubai-ranks-among-world-s-top-10-cities-in-global-power-city-index-for-second-consecutive-year-2025-01-05-1.736051</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/business/economy-finance/dubai-ranks-among-world-s-top-10-cities-in-global-power-city-index-for-second-consecutive-year-2025-01-05-1.736051</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Dubai has been ranked eighth worldwide and first in the Middle East in the Global Power City Index 2024 (GPCI) for the second year in a row.</p>

<p>In an annual study released by Japan&rsquo;s Mori Memorial Foundation, the index highlights Dubai&rsquo;s role as a leader in innovation, economic dynamism, and global connectivity.</p>

<p>This achievement makes Dubai the only city in the Middle East to feature in the top 10, reaffirming its position as a major global hub for business, talent, and investment.</p>

<p>H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister, Minister of Defence, and Chairman of The Executive Council of Dubai, attributed this achievement to the visionary leadership of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President, Prime Minister and Ruler of Dubai.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Dubai continues to redefine what is possible, combining innovation, sustainability, and a focus on nurturing talent,&rdquo; said Sheikh Hamdan. &ldquo;The city has created one of the world&rsquo;s best environments for businesses to thrive, creative ideas to take shape, and individuals to realise their aspirations while enjoying an exceptional quality of life. This achievement reflects not only visionary leadership but also the collective contributions of countless individuals who share a commitment to excellence.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The Crown Prince highlighted the key drivers behind Dubai&#39;s success, including its world-class infrastructure, which continues to attract global investment and top talent. He highlighted the city&rsquo;s flexible and progressive legislative framework, designed to foster innovation and adapt to evolving global trends.</p>

<p>He also underscored the importance of Dubai&rsquo;s strong public-private sector partnerships, which have created a dynamic ecosystem for collaboration and growth.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Dubai&rsquo;s high ranking on global indices shows that we are not just keeping pace with the world, we are setting new benchmarks for excellence,&rdquo; he added.</p>

<p>Reaffirming Dubai&#39;s commitment to sustainable growth, Sheikh Hamdan said, &ldquo;We remain steadfast in our efforts to consolidate Dubai&rsquo;s global status as a city of the future. By embracing strategic innovation and maintaining a strong commitment to excellence, we are creating new opportunities across industries.&rdquo;</p>

<p>With a strong focus on improving quality of life and fostering economic opportunities, Dubai continues to attract the world&rsquo;s leading minds, businesses, and investors. One of the fastest-growing cities in the index, Dubai is also constantly establishing new benchmarks for urban innovation, connectivity, and resilience.</p>

<p>The Global Power City Index (GPCI) evaluates and ranks the major cities of the world according to their &ldquo;magnetism,&rdquo; or their comprehensive power to attract people, capital, and enterprises from around the world. It does so by measuring six functions&mdash;Economy, Research and Development, Cultural Interaction, Livability, Environment, and Accessibility&mdash;providing a multidimensional ranking.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 5 Jan 2025 18:45:28 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736053.1736088390!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736053.1736088390!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai ranks among world’s top 10 cities in Global Power City Index for second consecutive year]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Business</category>
										
																			
											<category>Economy and Finance</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Business/Economy_Finance</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Fuel Prices Remain Stable in the UAE for January 2025]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/business/energy/fuel-prices-remain-stable-in-the-uae-for-january-2025-2024-12-31-1.736012</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/business/energy/fuel-prices-remain-stable-in-the-uae-for-january-2025-2024-12-31-1.736012</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The UAE&#39;s Fuel Price Committee has announced the gasoline and diesel prices for January 2025, which remain stable compared to previous rates. The prices are as follows:</p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Diesel:</strong> AED 2.68 per liter</li>
	<li><strong>Super 98 Gasoline:</strong> AED 2.61 per liter</li>
	<li><strong>Special 95 Gasoline:</strong> AED 2.50 per liter</li>
	<li><strong>E-Plus 91 Gasoline:</strong> AED 2.43 per liter</li>
</ul>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 10:59:10 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736013.1735628316!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736013.1735628316!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Fuel Prices Remain Stable in the UAE for January 2025]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Business</category>
										
																			
											<category>Energy</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Business/Energy</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[GCAA adopts Protocol for Autopsy and Aviation Medicine in Air Accident Investigations]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/gcaa-adopts-protocol-for-autopsy-and-aviation-medicine-in-air-accident-investigations-2024-12-27-1.735991</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/gcaa-adopts-protocol-for-autopsy-and-aviation-medicine-in-air-accident-investigations-2024-12-27-1.735991</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Abdullah bin Touq Al Marri, Minister of Economy and Chairman of the Board of Directors of the General Civil Aviation Authority (GCAA), has approved the &quot;Protocol for Autopsy and Aviation Medicine in Air Accident Investigations,&quot; a new step toward improving air accident investigation practices.</p>

<p>This protocol represents a significant and distinctive addition to the aviation sector in the UAE by enhancing national capabilities in air accident investigations and fostering collaboration among various relevant entities.</p>

<p>It marks a critical development in investigation methodologies by enabling investigators to consult experts in forensic medicine and aviation medicine to analyse the health status of flight crew members as one of the investigative aspects. This is in addition to other elements related to the aircraft&rsquo;s condition, flight operations, and human factors. Together, these analyses integrate to yield the most precise conclusions regarding the causes of accidents and the contributing factors.</p>

<p>Abdullah bin Touq Al Marri stated, &ldquo;The adoption of this protocol, designed to provide more enablers for fostering a safer and more sustainable aviation environment, reflects our commitment to the wise leadership&#39;s directives to enhance aviation safety and develop innovative tools to improve air accident investigations and prevent their recurrence.</p>

<p>We take pride in the advanced status of the UAE in aviation security and safety, as well as its swift and sophisticated capabilities in dealing with air incidents.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Saif Mohammed Al Suwaidi, Director-General of the GCAA, explained that the protocol, with its policies and procedures developed in coordination and collaboration with the relevant entities in the country, represents a qualitative leap in the field of air accident investigations. It establishes a culture of multidisciplinary cooperation and strengthens joint national efforts to ensure the application of the best global standards in the aviation sector, identifying the causes of air accidents and preventing their recurrence.</p>

<p>Captain Aysha Mohammed Al Hamil, Assistant Director-General in Air Accident Investigations, stated, &ldquo;This protocol is a valuable technical development that enhances the effectiveness of investigations by incorporating advanced forensic methods. By utilising the expertise available in the UAE, we aim to build a more accurate and efficient investigations framework that helps identify accident causes and prevent their recurrence.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The protocol emphasises the importance of collaboration between public and private sector entities, contributing to the long-term safety and sustainability of aviation, while reinforcing the UAE&#39;s position in the global aviation community.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:32:49 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735992.1735299146!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735992.1735299146!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[GCAA adopts Protocol for Autopsy and Aviation Medicine in Air Accident Investigations]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed issues Resolution pertaining to foreign banks operating in Dubai]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/business/economy-finance/hamdan-bin-mohammed-issues-resolution-pertaining-to-foreign-banks-operating-in-dubai-2024-12-27-1.735971</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/business/economy-finance/hamdan-bin-mohammed-issues-resolution-pertaining-to-foreign-banks-operating-in-dubai-2024-12-27-1.735971</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>In his capacity as Chairman of The Executive Council of Dubai, H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, and Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defence of the UAE, has issued Executive Council Resolution No. (101) of 2024 approving measures to flag foreign banks found to be in breach of administrative guidelines while operating in the Emirate of Dubai and stipulating penalties for such violations.</p>

<p>The Resolution, which specifies administrative violations and applicable fines for foreign banks, aims to enhance compliance among banking sector institutions by establishing robust standards for responsible governance within the banking system.</p>

<p>The Resolution will be published in the Official Gazette and will be effective from the date of its publication.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:38 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735972.1735243196!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735972.1735243196!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed issues Resolution pertaining to foreign banks operating in Dubai]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Business</category>
										
																			
											<category>Economy and Finance</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Business/Economy_Finance</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed forms interim steering committee to oversee transfer of commercial control operations in Dubai]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/business/economy-finance/hamdan-bin-mohammed-forms-interim-steering-committee-to-oversee-transfer-of-commercial-control-operations-in-dubai-2024-12-24-1.735955</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/business/economy-finance/hamdan-bin-mohammed-forms-interim-steering-committee-to-oversee-transfer-of-commercial-control-operations-in-dubai-2024-12-24-1.735955</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>- Committee specialises in approving the timeline and stages of transferring commercial control tasks and operations from regulatory bodies to the Dubai Corporation for Consumer Protection and Fair Trade</p>

<p>In his capacity as Chairman of the Executive Council of Dubai, His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister, and Minister of Defence of the UAE, has issued Executive Council Resolution No. (99) of 2024, forming the Steering Committee for Overseeing the Transfer of Commercial Control Operations in the Emirate of Dubai.</p>

<p>The resolution stipulates the formation of an interim committee called the &lsquo;Steering Committee for Overseeing the Transfer of Commercial Control Operations in the Emirate of Dubai&rsquo;, chaired by the Secretary-General of the Supreme Legislation Committee. Members include: a representative from the Department of Finance, a representative from the Dubai Government Human Resources Department, the CEO of Dubai Corporation for Consumer Protection and Fair Trade, the CEO of the Regulatory Policies and Governance Sector and the CEO of the Legislation and Disputes Sector at the Department of Economy and Tourism in Dubai, and a representative from the government entity authorised under current legislation to carry out commercial control activities in Dubai.</p>

<p>Committee&rsquo;s responsibilities<br />
According to the resolution, the Steering Committee&rsquo;s powers and responsibilities include:<br />
&bull; Approving the timeline and stages for transferring commercial control tasks and operations from regulatory bodies to the Dubai Corporation for Consumer Protection and Fair Trade.<br />
&bull; Unifying and organising commercial control operations in local markets by identifying and classifying all types and forms of commercial control carried out by regulatory bodies and the Authority.<br />
&bull; Reviewing commercial inspection and control procedures, proposing amendments, unification, and simplification, and submitting these proposals to The Executive Council of Dubai.</p>

<p>The Steering Committee is also responsible for:<br />
&bull; Establishing controls and mechanisms for coordination between regulatory bodies and the Dubai Corporation for Consumer Protection and Fair Trade regarding the implementation of inspection procedures within their respective jurisdictions, including regulating the exchange of information and data among them.<br />
&bull; Consulting with whomever it deems appropriate with relevant expertise to assist in performing its duties.<br />
&bull; Ensuring the integration of roles, coordination of efforts, exchange of information, and cooperation between government and regulatory bodies in all matters that enable the Steering Committee to carry out the tasks entrusted to it under the provisions of this resolution.</p>

<p>The Steering Committee is also responsible for:<br />
&bull; Making necessary decisions regarding any issues or disputes that may arise between the Authority and regulatory bodies in the event that appropriate consensual solutions are not reached between the concerned parties, referring such matters or disputes to The Executive Council of Dubai when necessary.<br />
&bull; Following up on the implementation of the plan to transfer commercial control tasks and operations, monitoring progress, and issuing necessary directives regarding obstacles and difficulties that may hinder the implementation of the plan at all stages.</p>

<p>Cooperation with the Committee<br />
The resolution mandates all government entities in the emirate, including regulatory bodies and supervisory authorities in special development zones and free zones, including the Dubai International Financial Centre, to fully cooperate with the Steering Committee, its subcommittees, and its work teams. They must provide data, information, statistics, documents, and studies requested by the Steering Committee within the specified timeframe, which the Steering Committee deems necessary to enable it to perform the tasks entrusted to it under the provisions of this resolution, subsequent resolutions, and applicable legislation in the Emirate.</p>

<p>The Chairman of the Steering Committee for Overseeing the Transfer of Commercial Control Operations in the Emirate of Dubai shall issue the necessary decisions, instructions, and directives to implement the provisions of this resolution. The resolution will be effective from the date of its publication in the Official Gazette.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 18:43:14 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735956.1735051380!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735956.1735051380!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed forms interim steering committee to oversee transfer of commercial control operations in Dubai]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Business</category>
										
																			
											<category>Economy and Finance</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Business/Economy_Finance</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAEV announces adoption of recently introduced EV tariffs effective January 2025]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/business/energy/uaev-announces-adoption-of-recently-introduced-ev-tariffs-effective-january-2025-2024-12-19-1.735918</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/business/energy/uaev-announces-adoption-of-recently-introduced-ev-tariffs-effective-january-2025-2024-12-19-1.735918</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>UAEV, the UAE&#39;s first government-owned electric vehicle (EV) charging network, announced the adoption of the recently introduced EV tariffs by the Ministry of Energy and Infrastructure, effective January 2025.</p>

<p>While these tariffs mark an important step towards enhancing the sustainability and scalability of the network, it is worth noting that EV charging services have remained free of charge since the tariffs were first announced last May. This milestone initiative reflects UAEV&rsquo;s commitment to ensuring service quality, equitable access to its network, and alignment with the UAE&rsquo;s vision for a sustainable future.</p>

<p>From January 2025, EV users will benefit from transparent and standardised charging fees. The tariff is set at 1.2 DHS/kWh + VAT for DC chargers and 0.70 DHS/kWh + VAT for AC chargers, ensuring fair and consistent pricing while supporting the operational excellence of the network.</p>

<p>To enhance the EV driving experience, UAEV is introducing its user-friendly mobile application. The app will provide features such as easily finding your next charging station, live status updates, and simple payments, empowering EV users with essential tools to navigate the charging network effectively.</p>

<p>Complementing the app, UAEV is launching a dedicated 24/7 call centre to provide instant support and assistance, ensuring seamless user experiences at all times.</p>

<p>&ldquo;This marks a transformative step in the UAE&rsquo;s journey towards sustainable transportation,&rdquo; said Sharif al Olama, Chairman of UAEV. &ldquo;The implementation of standardised charging tariffs and the launch of innovative solutions like the UAEV app and 24/7 support reflect our ongoing commitment to enhancing the EV driver experience. By expanding our network and aligning with the UAE&rsquo;s Net Zero 2050 Strategy, we are driving a cleaner, greener future for all.&rdquo;</p>

<p>By 2030, UAEV&rsquo;s network will include 1,000 chargers strategically located across urban hubs, highways, and transit points within the UAE. Key locations will span all emirates, ensuring accessibility for both inter-city and intra-city EV users alike.</p>

<p>Aligned with the UAE&rsquo;s Net Zero 2050 Strategy, UAEV is committed to advocating for sustainable transport and reducing carbon emissions. By delivering high-speed charging solutions, real-time network uptime monitoring, and strategically placed charging stations, UAEV empowers EV drivers and promotes green mobility across the nation.</p>

<p>UAEV delivers an integrated charging solution ecosystem designed to meet diverse user needs. With a focus on reliability, accessibility, and innovation, UAEV reinforces its role as a key enabler of the UAE&rsquo;s green transition.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 23:01:05 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735919.1734634805!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735919.1734634805!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAEV announces adoption of recently introduced EV tariffs effective January 2025]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Business</category>
										
																			
											<category>Energy</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Business/Energy</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Explore magical Christmas markets with flydubai]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/business/travel/explore-magical-christmas-markets-with-flydubai-2024-12-18-1.735906</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/business/travel/explore-magical-christmas-markets-with-flydubai-2024-12-18-1.735906</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Basel Christmas market on Barf&uuml;sserplatz and M&uuml;nsterplatz is considered to be one of the prettiest and largest in Switzerland.<br />
&nbsp;right in the centre of the city and at the heart of the festively decorated Old Town. A magnificent Christmas tree stands on M&uuml;nsterplatz, with ornaments by the well-known decorator Johann Wanner.<br />
While enjoying an evening stroll through the stands on M&uuml;nsterplatz, you shouldn&rsquo;t miss a quick walk to the Pfalz. Here you can enjoy your mulled wine with an amazing view over the Rhine and the glowing lights of the city.</p>

<p>Budapest is also renowned for its delightful festive markets held in V&ouml;r&ouml;smarty Square and at the Basilica, where visitors can explore beautifully decorated stalls offering traditional Hungarian crafts, festive decorations, and an array of delicious seasonal foods such as chimney cake (k&uuml;rtőskal&aacute;cs) and goulash. These markets attract both locals and tourists, making Budapest a popular destination for holiday travelers seeking a magical holiday experience.<br />
Prague is also famous for its enchanting festive markets, which are among the most beautiful and popular in Europe. The city&#39;s main festive markets are held in the Old Town Square and Wenceslas Square, featuring beautifully decorated wooden huts selling traditional Czech products, handcrafted goods, festive decorations, and delicious seasonal foods.&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:40:24 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735908.1734518360!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735908.1734518360!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735908.1734518360!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735907.1734518344!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Explore magical Christmas markets with flydubai]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Business</category>
										
																			
											<category>Travel</category>
										
																								
										
													
				 									<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/General</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE ranks first globally in 223 competitiveness indicators]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/business/economy-finance/uae-ranks-first-globally-in-223-competitiveness-indicators-2024-12-17-1.735883</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/business/economy-finance/uae-ranks-first-globally-in-223-competitiveness-indicators-2024-12-17-1.735883</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The United Arab Emirates has maintained its upward trajectory in global competitiveness reports in 2024, securing top positions in key indicators thanks to the wise leadership and forward-thinking vision aimed at human development as the foundation and primary goal of development.</p>

<p>The UAE ranked first globally in 223 indicators, compared to 215 in 2023, and was among the top five countries globally in 444 indicators, compared to 406 in 2023. It also ranked among the top 10 globally in 661 indicators, compared to 604 in 2023 and 508 in 2022.</p>

<p>The UAE&#39;s progress is a tangible reflection of ongoing modernisation efforts in the legislative framework, the launch of proactive initiatives supporting the economic system and investment, the rule of law, the utilisation of advanced technology, and the development of various sectors to enhance the quality of life for all citizens and residents.</p>

<p>In the IMD World Competitiveness Yearbook 2024, the UAE climbed three places to seventh globally, following its achievement last year of entering the top 10 countries in the report.</p>

<p>The UAE&#39;s performance was outstanding across all report dimensions, ranking second globally in the economic performance, fourth in the government efficiency, and tenth in the business environment efficiency.</p>

<p>The UAE&#39;s positive performance has contributed to its leading position globally in over 90 indicators in the report, which fall under its main and sub-factors.</p>

<p>The UAE ranked first regionally in the 2023/2024 Human Development Index report issued by the United Nations Development Programme and ranked 17th globally out of 193 countries included in the report.</p>

<p>For the third consecutive year, the UAE ranked first globally in the 2023/2024 Global Entrepreneurship Monitor report, recording a rate of 7.7, a record high since the report&#39;s launch.</p>

<p>The UAE ranked first in the Middle East and North Africa and 18th globally in the Travel &amp; Tourism Development Index issued by the World Economic Forum.</p>

<p>The UAE achieved fifth place globally and first in the Arab world in road quality and tenth globally and second in the Arab world in the efficiency of public transport services, in addition to ninth place globally and first in the Arab world in the efficiency of port services, according to the Travel &amp; Tourism Development Index 2024, issued in May by the World Economic Forum.</p>

<p>Throughout 2024, the UAE topped the world in a number of competitiveness indicators related to the civil aviation sector. It ranked first globally in the Quality of Air Transport Infrastructure Index within the 2024 Travel &amp; Tourism Development Index and third globally in the efficiency of air transport services and number of seats for weekly international departures/kilometre indices.</p>

<p>According to the United Nations Conference on Trade and Development (UNCTAD) report issued in June, the UAE ranked second globally after the United States in the number of new FDI projects in 2023, with 1,323 new projects, representing a growth rate of around 33% compared to the previous year.</p>

<p>The report indicated that the UAE recorded inflows of foreign direct investment projects in 2023 amounting to $30.688 billion (approximately AED112.6 billion), while the UAE&#39;s foreign investments at the end of the same year amounted to $262.208 billion (approximately AED 962 billion).</p>

<p>The UAE achieved outstanding results in a number of indicators related to government and digital services, as issued in the United Nations E-Government Survey 2024. It ranked first globally in the ICT Infrastructure Index and achieved a full score of 100%, while the country advanced 34 points in the Human Capital Index, moving from 44th to 10th place and achieving first place in Asia and the Arab world in this index.</p>

<p>The UAE reached fifth place globally in the Quality Infrastructure Index for Sustainable Development in 2024, issued by the United Nations Industrial Development Organisation (UNIDO), within the category of countries with a gross domestic product ranging from $100 billion to $1 trillion.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 13:50:05 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735884.1734428951!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735884.1734428951!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE ranks first globally in 223 competitiveness indicators]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Business</category>
										
																			
											<category>Economy and Finance</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Business/Economy_Finance</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[DMCC Crypto Centre Metaverse launched to drive Web3 engagement]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/business/economy-finance/dmcc-crypto-centre-metaverse-launched-to-drive-web3-engagement-2024-12-17-1.735881</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/business/economy-finance/dmcc-crypto-centre-metaverse-launched-to-drive-web3-engagement-2024-12-17-1.735881</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>DMCC, the international business district that drives the flow of global trade through Dubai, has launched the DMCC Crypto Centre Metaverse, representing a landmark application of the technology for one of the world&rsquo;s leading Web3 ecosystems.</p>

<p>Developed with Infinite Reality, the Metaverse will feature engaging gamified zones and allow users to interact directly with the DMCC Crypto Centre team. Additionally, users will have access to dedicated service clinics covering essential areas such as banking, compliance and insurance.</p>

<p>Belal Jassoma, Director of Ecosystems at DMCC, said, &ldquo;Even under a moderate scenario, the global metaverse market is projected to exceed US$3.1 trillion by 2030. In launching the DMCC Crypto Centre Metaverse, we are not only providing a cutting-edge digital experience for our ecosystem members, but also demonstrating a real pragmatic use case of next-gen technology at the intersection of blockchain and AI.</p>

<p>This latest milestone drives global AI applications forward, reinforcing Dubai&rsquo;s status as one of the world&rsquo;s leading innovation hubs, and paving the way for a future where the Metaverse is scaled up and becomes a dynamic, open and interoperable space for the benefit of many industries.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The creation of the DMCC Crypto Centre digital twin aligns with the ambitious Dubai Metaverse Strategy, aiming to position the emirate as one of the top 10 metaverse economies globally and establish Dubai as a leading hub for immersive technologies.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 13:47:58 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735882.1734428865!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735882.1734428865!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[DMCC Crypto Centre Metaverse launched to drive Web3 engagement]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Business</category>
										
																			
											<category>Economy and Finance</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Business/Economy_Finance</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[flydubai unveils new Business Class Lounge at Dubai International (DXB)]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/business/travel/flydubai-unveils-new-business-class-lounge-at-dubai-international-dxb-2024-12-16-1.735874</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/business/travel/flydubai-unveils-new-business-class-lounge-at-dubai-international-dxb-2024-12-16-1.735874</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p align="center">The new Business Class Lounge underscores the carrier&rsquo;s commitment to investing in enhancing customer experience</p>

<ul>
	<li>The lounge will be available to flydubai Business Class passengers for flights departing from Terminal 2</li>
</ul>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p><a href="https://www.flydubai.com/en-ae/">flydubai</a>, the Dubai-based carrier, has unveiled its new Business Class Lounge at Terminal 2, Dubai International (DXB). The carrier&rsquo;s dedicated lounge opened its doors earlier today to welcome Business Class passengers, underscoring the carrier&rsquo;s commitment to offering an enhanced travel experience for its customers.</p>

<p>The official opening of the lounge was attended by Hamad Obaidalla, Chief Commercial Officer at flydubai, H.E. Major-General Obaid Muhair bin Suroor, Deputy Director-General of the General Directorate of Residence and Foreigners Affairs (GDRFA), Major-General Talal Ahmed Al Shanqiti, General Director Assistant of the GDRFA, Major-General Ali Atiq bin Lahej, Acting Assistant Commandant for Ports Affairs, H.E. Jamal Al-Hai, Deputy Chief Executive Officer at Dubai Airports and Majed Al Joker, Chief Operating Officer at Dubai Airports, along with other key stakeholders and members of the media.</p>

<p>The modern 900-square-metre Business Class Lounge can accommodate more than 200 passengers. The lounge is conveniently located after the passport control and security lanes at Dubai International&rsquo;s Terminal 2 Departure area. The boarding gate for Business Class passengers is located in the lounge where passengers can board the dedicated Business Class buses for their flights.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Commenting on the opening of the new Business Class Lounge, Hamad Obaidalla, Chief Commercial Officer at flydubai, said: &ldquo;this year, flydubai is celebrating a milestone in its journey marking 15 years of operations.&nbsp;We remain committed to constantly evolving and investing in enhancing customer experience whether in the air or on the ground. The new lounge will provide an enjoyable and seamless travel experience for our Business Class passengers from Terminal 2 in Dubai. We would like to thank the airport authorities for their support to officially welcome customers to the new beautifully designed space.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The new lounge features modern aesthetics incorporating natural light in its simple and elegant design that draws inspiration from the serene and timeless beauty of desert dunes. The warm tones and minimalist aesthetics feature some of Dubai&rsquo;s most iconic skylines and create a comfortable space both for relaxation and productivity.</p>

<p>The lounge features a glass facade offering uninterrupted tarmac views and inviting natural light. The welcoming space offers a variety of seating configuration areas including dining, lounging and a quiet space for relaxation. Inside the lounge, customers can look forward to a wide range of dining options whether from an internationally inspired buffet or an &agrave; la carte option. The lounge also has shower facilities, a thoughtfully designed prayer room and other practical amenities such as complimentary Wi-Fi, workstations and multiple charging stations.</p>

<p>Mohamed Hassan, Senior Vice President of Airport Services &amp; Cargo at flydubai, said: &ldquo;lounges are a key component for the seamless and comfortable travel experience we aim to provide to our customers. The new flydubai Business Class Lounge and boarding gate provide added convenience to our passengers who are looking for a more personalised and efficient travel experience, whether they are travelling for business or leisure. We are looking forward to welcoming many of our passengers just in time for the busy holiday travel period.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Emirates Skywards members can also enjoy select benefits of the new Business Class Lounge depending on their membership tier.</p>

<p>Earlier in October this year, the carrier officially opened its new Business Class check-in at Terminal 2, Dubai International (DXB). The dedicated space offers flydubai&rsquo;s Business Class passengers a unique and smooth check-in experience with a personalised Meet and Assist service, seated check-in and a Fast Track service through passport control and security lanes.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:31:24 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735875.1734345000!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735875.1734345000!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[flydubai unveils new Business Class Lounge at Dubai International (DXB)]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Business</category>
										
																			
											<category>Travel</category>
										
																								
										
													
				 									<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/General</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Parkin and Batic sign MoU to explore smart city parking solutions across Saudi Arabia]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/business/corporate/parkin-and-batic-sign-mou-to-explore-smart-city-parking-solutions-across-saudi-arabia-2024-12-16-1.735872</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/business/corporate/parkin-and-batic-sign-mou-to-explore-smart-city-parking-solutions-across-saudi-arabia-2024-12-16-1.735872</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Parkin Company PJSC (&ldquo;Parkin&rdquo; or the &ldquo;Company&rdquo;), the largest provider of paid public parking facilities and services in Dubai announces that it has entered into a Memorandum of Understanding (&ldquo;MoU&rdquo;) with BATIC Investment and Logistics Company (&ldquo;BATIC&rdquo;), a Saudi Arabian conglomerate listed on the Saudi Exchange (TADAWUL), with investments in logistics, transportation, parking, real estate, private and civil security services, cash solutions and facilities management.</p>

<p><br />
Key Takeaways</p>

<p>&nbsp;&bull; The partnership aims to combine Parkin&#39;s renowned operational capabilities with the extensive local public parking network managed by Smart City Solutions Co. (&ldquo;SCSC&rdquo;), a BATIC subsidiary and Saudi Arabia&rsquo;s largest paid public parking provider.</p>

<p>&bull; The proposed collaboration will focus on the implementation of cutting-edge digital technologies to optimise traffic flow and enhance the end-user experience.</p>

<p>&bull; This MoU represents a key step in Parkin&#39;s international growth strategy and aligns seamlessly with BATIC&#39;s commitment to maintain market share while advancing smart city initiatives under Saudi Vision 2030.</p>

<p>The MoU, signed during a recent visit by Parkin&rsquo;s CEO to BATIC&rsquo;s headquarters in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia, provides a framework for Parkin and BATIC to evaluate potential synergies and explore a strategic partnership with a focus on SCSC.</p>

<p>The companies will assess opportunities to expand paid parking services in the Saudi market, collaborating with municipalities, real estate developers, operators of shopping centres, hotels, and other venues. The envisaged collaboration will prioritise the adoption of advanced digital technologies, including AI, real-time data analysis, digital gates, sensors and smart cameras to simplify parking, improve utilisation, reduce congestion and create a seamless parking experience for customers.</p>

<p>The agreement enables both parties to fully evaluate collaboration opportunities, identify synergies between Parkin&rsquo;s operational expertise in Dubai and BATIC&rsquo;s strong Saudi presence through SCSC, and to seek any legal or regulatory necessary approvals.</p>

<p>Eng. Mohamed Abdulla Al Ali, CEO of Parkin, commented:</p>

<p>&nbsp;&ldquo;As the largest public paid parking provider in the MENA region, the proposed technology driven partnership between BATIC and Parkin is a significant milestone, underscoring our market leading capabilities in the GCC, commitment to international growth outside the Emirate of Dubai and shared vision to continue enhancing seamless mobility. By combining our operational excellence, cutting-edge technology and industry know-how with BATIC&#39;s strong presence, the partnership is poised to deliver innovative, scalable, customer-focused parking solutions that stand to benefit both residents and visitors to the Kingdom, supporting economic growth.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>Eng. Mohammed Alzamil, Managing Director and Group CEO of BATIC, added:</p>

<p>&ldquo;This landmark partnership brings together two clear market leaders with complementary operations, technology and expertise. Collaborating with the pre-eminent parking operator in the UAE will enable us to optimise the delivery of parking services across our asset base, reducing congestion, driving efficiencies and improving the overall customer journey. With an extensive parking portfolio of 195,000 parking spaces across five cities, we will achieve greater mobility in the Kingdom, aligned to the aspirations of Saudi Vision 2030.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:16:38 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735873.1734344186!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735873.1734344186!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Parkin and Batic sign MoU to explore smart city parking solutions across Saudi Arabia]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Business</category>
										
																			
											<category>Corporate</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Business/Corporate</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Drydocks World awarded ostwind 4 project to support Germany’s renewable energy goals]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/business/energy/drydocks-world-awarded-ostwind-4-project-to-support-germany-s-renewable-energy-goals-2024-12-16-1.735869</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/business/energy/drydocks-world-awarded-ostwind-4-project-to-support-germany-s-renewable-energy-goals-2024-12-16-1.735869</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Drydocks World, in partnership with GE Vernova, has secured a landmark project to build and install Ostwind 4, a 2 gigawatt (GW) offshore wind grid connection that will power nearly two million German households.</p>

<p>Awarded by 50Hertz, the Transmission System Operator for eastern Germany, including Berlin and Hamburg, the project is a major step in the country&rsquo; commitment to renewable energy.</p>

<p>Ostwind 4 will connect Baltic Sea wind farms to the national grid using cutting-edge High-Voltage Direct Current (HVDC) technology. This will mark Germany&rsquo;s first deployment of a 525 kilovolts HVDC transmission system in Baltic, setting new standards for efficiency in transporting energy over long distances.</p>

<p>Located 30 kilometers northeast of R&uuml;gen Island, the project includes the construction of offshore and onshore converter stations and a 110-kilometer DC cable system linking land and sea.</p>

<p>Drydocks World, part of the DP World Group, will manage the Engineering, Procurement, Construction, and Installation of the of the wind energy converter stations&rsquo; topsides and jacket structures. The topside, fabricated at Drydocks World&#39;s Dubai facility, will integrate advanced equipment designed and manufactured in Europe. Once completed, the platform will be transported and installed in German waters.</p>

<p>GE Vernova will supply the HVDC technology, including Voltage-Sourced Converters (VSC), transformers, SF6-free Gas Insulated Switchgear, civil works for the onshore converter station, and Grid Automation equipment.</p>

<p>Sultan Ahmed bin Sulayem, Group Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer, DP World, said: &quot; Drydocks World&rsquo;s pivotal role in the Ostwind 4 Project underscores its technical excellence and commitment to advancing sustainable infrastructure. This award reflects DP World&rsquo;s broader mission to drive clean energy transitions and economic growth. As the global energy landscape evolves, we remain dedicated to leveraging our expertise and innovative capabilities to support initiatives that drive clean energy transitions and economic development.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Captain Rado Antolovic, CEO of Drydocks World, said: &quot;The Ostwind 4 project exemplifies the power of international collaboration in advancing renewable energy solutions. Drydocks World is honoured to support Germany&#39;s transition to sustainable energy by delivering cutting-edge offshore infrastructure that embodies engineering excellence and environmental stewardship. This achievement reaffirms our unwavering commitment to innovation and sustainability, setting new benchmarks for offshore wind projects and supporting global efforts to build a greener future.&quot;</p>

<p>Stefan Kapferer, CEO of 50Hertz Transmission, commented: &ldquo;The awarding of the contract to GE Vernova and Drydock World marks the beginning of a new chapter in the use of wind energy in the Baltic Sea. 50Hertz is the first transmission system operator to deploy 2 GW / 525 kV technology in this sea area.</p>

<p>This is pioneering work. We want to ensure that the entirety of the technically and economically viable offshore wind energy potential in the Baltic Sea is exploited, primarily with the help of direct current technology. To do this, we need to think and act in an even more networked way across national borders. One prerequisite for this is the creation of legal and regulatory conditions that enable wind farms in the waters of other EU states to be connected to the German transmission grid.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Philippe Piron, CEO of GE Vernova&#39;s Electrification business, added: &ldquo;Ostwind 4 represents a crucial milestone in our mission to electrify and decarbonize with the energy to change the world. By leveraging our advanced HVDC technology, this key infrastructure project underscores the essential role of offshore wind to ensure European energy security and to accelerate the global energy transition. This order also highlights the rapid growth in GE Vernova&#39;s Electrification segment, our fastest growing business, as our customers invest in the grid. We are very proud to collaborate with 50Hertz and Drydocks World to advance Germany&rsquo;s renewable energy goals and set a new standard for a resilient and sustainable grid infrastructure.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The innovative design of the offshore converter station includes a U-shaped jacket substructure supporting offshore wind energy production for decades. Drydocks World&#39;s involvement in the Ostwind 4 project underscores its reputation for executing complex offshore infrastructure projects while reinforcing its commitment to advancing sustainable energy solutions.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:11:59 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735870.1734343893!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735870.1734343893!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Drydocks World awarded ostwind 4 project to support Germany’s renewable energy goals]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Business</category>
										
																			
											<category>Energy</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Business/Energy</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Exceptional year for global airport industry in 2024]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/business/travel/exceptional-year-for-global-airport-industry-in-2024-2024-12-16-1.735864</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/business/travel/exceptional-year-for-global-airport-industry-in-2024-2024-12-16-1.735864</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>As infrastructure and operations are reshaped, the global airport industry, whose revenues are set to reach US$194.4 billion in 2024, will continue exploring and acquiring the best-in-class technology and automation solutions throughout 2025. This will also include qualitative improvements to passenger experiences and sustainability practices, including LEED certification acquisitions.</p>

<p>The Airports Council International (ACI) World, in its annual World Airport Traffic Report, forecasts global passenger traffic to increase by 10 percent, reaching 9.5 billion passengers in 2024, based on data from over 2,700 airports across 180 countries. In 2023, it stood at 8.7 billion, reaching 95 percent of pre-pandemic levels. By the end of 2024, international passenger traffic will reach 4.1 billion, accounting for 43 percent of total passengers. The domestic passenger traffic is expected to reach 5.4 billion, making up 57 percent of the total.</p>

<p>ACI World further projects that the global airport investment is set to reach US$2,404 billion in 2040 while the Middle East aviation market is due to reach US$33.70 billion size by 2029. Middle Eastern airports are due to spend US$151 billion on the expansion of their capacity and enhancing passenger and cargo facilities.</p>

<p>The best and most effective ways for airports to handle the fast-rising air traffic and the effective deployment of the newest technologies and innovations will be under the spotlight at the Airport Show, the 24th edition of which will be held in 2025 at the Dubai World Trade Centre (DWTC) from May 6 to 8. Unparalleled networking and business opportunities await the industry stakeholders and professionals with a big number of exhibitors coming from all over the world and four major co-located knowledge-enhancing conferences taking place over three days.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Ahmed bin Saeed Al Maktoum, President of Dubai Civil Aviation Authority, Chairman of Dubai Airports, Chairman and Chief Executive of Emirates Airline and Group, and Patron of Airport Show, remarked: &ldquo;Airports are vital connectors and economic engines for communities and countries.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He added that Dubai, a key hub at the crossroads of global travel, is investing US$35 billion in the second phase of development of the Al Maktoum International &ndash; Dubai World Central (DWC) to become the world&rsquo;s largest airport with a capacity of up to 260 million passengers annually, Sheikh Ahmed said airports across the region are also modernizing and expanding to meet growing demand, with a combined project value of over US$1.3 trillion across the Middle East, Africa and South Asia.&rdquo; He asserted that the Airport Show, organized by RX, continues to be a vital stage for business growth and expansion in the airport industry.</p>

<p>By the mid-2030s, ICAO predicts that over 200,000 flights will take off and land daily all over the world. By 2036, the air transport industry will contribute US$1.5 trillion to global GDP. By 2040, airports in the Middle East will handle 1.1 billion passengers, with the Middle East and Asia-Pacific accounting for 58 percent of global air passenger demand.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The Airport Show is the Middle East, Africa and South Asia&rsquo;s leading airport exhibition for 110-odd airport operators and their associates in the Middle East. The 2025 edition is expected to have a total of 160 exhibitors from 20+ countries along with more than 6,000 participants from 30+ countries. The show will feature four insightful conferences on its sidelines - the Global Airport Leaders Forum (GALF), Airport Security Middle East, the ATC Forum, and Women in Aviation (WIA). The annual multi-events platform is being supported among others by the Dubai Civil Aviation Authority, Dubai Airports, Dubai Aviation Engineering Projects, Emirates Airlines, Dubai Air Navigation Services, and the Dubai-based global airline and dnata.</p>

<p>May Ismail, Event Manager at RX, a global company that organizes about 400 events across 42 industry sectors in 22 countries including Airport Show, said: &ldquo;The airport industry&rsquo;s growth is very bright with ample growth opportunities for almost every stakeholder. Airports have remained steadfast in their commitment to a safe, sustainable, and thriving air travel sector. In the technology-driven era, the focus for airport operators is on thriving rather than simply surviving. The Airport Show will remain a crucial platform in 2025 too for the Middle East, Africa, and South Asia region as US$1.3 trillion in airport development projects are readying to take off. The B2B platform will facilitate global companies to showcase their cutting-edge technologies and innovations designed to enhance airport operations, facility expansion, safety enhancement, improve passenger experiences and sustainability, and widen automation.&rdquo;</p>

<p>A Market Outlook report by Beumer Group, says the airport industry is further optimizing airport processes and the passenger experience to &ldquo;radically change the way we fly.&rdquo; Airports in 2025, according to the multinational intra-logistic solutions company, will face &ldquo;increasing capacity challenges&rdquo; to accommodate the &ldquo;surge&rdquo; in global air travel. They added: &ldquo;Current bottlenecks, like security checks, will add even more stress to the travel experience unless airports deploy innovative solutions in their processes. At the same time, increased automation is needed to meet the high passenger capacity demands. Latest technology and automation solutions are reshaping airport operations and improving passenger experience while sustainability strategies are under the spotlight to meet the passenger need for improved Environmental, Social, and Governance (ESG) performance.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Passenger experience at airports is becoming crucial in 2025, which will be a record-breaking year for passenger volume, revenue generation, and setting standards higher. The airport industry is moving from a pre-digital to a post-digital age. The use of technology during travel will have a profound impact on how passengers interact with airports with demand focused more on automation and hands-on control over each step of their journey. Geneva-based SITA, the world&rsquo;s leading specialist in air transport communications and Information Technology, says 83 percent of airport and airline IT leaders it surveyed believe that the demographic shift will be the most important influence on their passenger solutions strategy from 2025 onwards.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:02:32 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735865.1734343334!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735865.1734343334!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Exceptional year for global airport industry in 2024]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Business</category>
										
																			
											<category>Travel</category>
										
																								
										
													
				 									<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/General</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Estancia Capital Redrawing the Lines of Luxury Real Estate in Dubai]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/business/real-estate/estancia-capital-redrawing-the-lines-of-luxury-real-estate-in-dubai-2024-12-16-1.735861</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/business/real-estate/estancia-capital-redrawing-the-lines-of-luxury-real-estate-in-dubai-2024-12-16-1.735861</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p data-pm-slice="1 1 []">In a move set to disrupt the status quo, Estancia Capital has officially launched its luxury real estate brokerage services in Dubai. This bold new player is poised to redefine the city&#39;s high-end property landscape with unwavering commitment, innovation, exclusivity, and its promise to provide &#39;Insurance for Capital - Without Premium.&#39;</p>

<p>At an exclusive launch event held on December 14, 2024, Estancia Capital&#39;s CEO and Co-Founder, Mujtaba Lakhiya, and Co-Founder, Usama Ehtesham, unveiled their vision for a new era in luxury real estate. &quot;We&#39;re not just another brokerage firm,&quot; Lakhiya emphasized. &quot;We&#39;re curators of exceptional experiences, matchmakers for the world&#39;s most discerning buyers and sellers, and guardians of the highest standards in the industry.&quot;</p>

<p>Ehtesham added, &quot;Dubai is more than just a city &ndash; it&#39;s a symbol of innovation, luxury, and progress. We&#39;re thrilled to be a part of this vibrant ecosystem and to contribute to its continued growth and success.&quot;</p>

<p>Estancia Capital&#39;s bespoke services cater to the most refined tastes, offering access to Dubai&#39;s most coveted luxury properties, from opulent residences to cutting-edge commercial spaces. With strong ties to the region&#39;s top developers, the firm provides unparalleled insights and opportunities for its clients.</p>

<p>As Dubai continues to evolve as a global hub for luxury and innovation, Estancia Capital is perfectly positioned to play a leading role in shaping the city&#39;s future. With its launch, the firm sets a new benchmark for excellence in luxury real estate, one that will undoubtedly resonate throughout the industry.</p>

<h3><strong>About Estancia Capital</strong></h3>

<p>Estancia Capital is a luxury real estate brokerage firm that embodies the spirit of innovation and exclusivity. With a passion for delivering exceptional experiences and a commitment to the highest standards, Estancia Capital is poised to redefine the art of luxury real estate in Dubai with its premise: Affordable High-End Luxury.</p>

<p>For media inquiries, please contact: +971 4 548 8755 or email: <a disabled="true">info@estanciacapital.ae</a></p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:45:36 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735863.1734335092!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735863.1734335092!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735863.1734335092!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735862.1734335072!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Estancia Capital Redrawing the Lines of Luxury Real Estate in Dubai]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Business</category>
										
																			
											<category>Real Estate</category>
										
																								
										
													
				 									<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/General</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[5.2 million to travel through DXB between 13, 31 December]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/business/travel/5-2-million-to-travel-through-dxb-between-13-31-december-2024-12-12-1.735829</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/business/travel/5-2-million-to-travel-through-dxb-between-13-31-december-2024-12-12-1.735829</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Dubai International (DXB) is set to welcome a surge in travellers as the winter holiday season unfolds, with over 5.2 million guests expected between 13th and 31st December.</p>

<p>The daily average is projected at 274,000 guests, with Friday, 20th December, anticipated to be the busiest day of the period, hosting nearly 296,000 guests.</p>

<p>The weekend from 20th to 22nd December will also see peak activity, with an estimated 880,000 guests passing through.</p>

<p>Essa Al Shamsi, Senior Vice President of Terminal Operations at Dubai Airports, said, &quot;Delivering the exceptional experience that DXB is known for during peak travel periods is always a challenge, but one we are well-prepared to meet with collaboration across the oneDXB family. This year, we are excited to welcome millions of guests while also creating moments of joy through festive activations. The Family Zone at Terminal 3 will transform into a winter wonderland featuring a unique fusion performance of carollers and beatboxers, a Magic Station offering gift-wrapping and photo opportunities, a Nutcracker marching band, and more. These activities are designed to surprise and delight, making every journey through DXB truly memorable.&quot;</p>

<p>This season&rsquo;s traffic surge reflects Dubai&rsquo;s global appeal, with visitors drawn to its vibrant shopping, dining, and entertainment offerings, as well as the city&rsquo;s amazing winter weather. Of the projected traffic, 1.7 million guests will arrive in Dubai, and 1.5 million will depart, underscoring Dubai&rsquo;s rising position as a premier destination for international travellers.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 15:56:55 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735830.1734004591!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735830.1734004591!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[5.2 million to travel through DXB between 13, 31 December]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Business</category>
										
																			
											<category>Travel</category>
										
																								
										
													
				 									<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/General</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE President endorses appointment of Board of Directors of XRG]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/uae-president-endorses-appointment-of-board-of-directors-of-xrg-2024-12-12-1.735827</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/uae-president-endorses-appointment-of-board-of-directors-of-xrg-2024-12-12-1.735827</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan has endorsed the Board of Directors for XRG, a transformative international energy investment company.</p>

<p>Launched by ADNOC in November 2024 with an enterprise value exceeding $80 billion (AED290 billion), XRG will prioritise strategic investments that capitalise on the transformation of global energy systems, enable sustainable economic growth, and enhance long-term value creation.</p>

<p>XRG is uniquely positioned to drive this transformation, addressing the increase in global energy demand by 2050, alongside a surge in the demand for advanced artificial intelligence (AI) systems that will use as well as optimise energy production, distribution, and efficiency. The company will also advance lower-carbon energy and technologies.</p>

<p>The newly appointed Board of Directors brings world-class expertise across energy, chemicals, infrastructure, investment, technology, sustainability and economic development. Their expertise positions XRG to execute its ambitious growth strategy.</p>

<p>&bull; H.E. Dr. Sultan Ahmed Al Jaber</p>

<p>- Role: Executive Chairman</p>

<p>- Background: UAE Minister of Industry and Advanced Technology and ADNOC Managing Director and Group CEO. Dr. Al Jaber has over 25 years&rsquo; experience spanning the energy, industrial, investments, infrastructure, sustainability and advanced technology sectors and has been instrumental in helping to advance the UAE&rsquo;s energy diversification.</p>

<p>&bull; H.E. Mohamed Hassan Alsuwaidi</p>

<p>- Role: Board Member</p>

<p>- Background: UAE Minister of Investment and Managing Director and CEO of ADQ. H.E. Alsuwaidi brings extensive investment experience across multiple sectors, including utilities, metals and mining, infrastructure, technology, and agriculture.</p>

<p>&bull; H.E. Dr. Ahmed Mubarak Al Mazrouei</p>

<p>- Role: Board Member</p>

<p>- Background: Chairman of the President&rsquo;s Office for Strategic Affairs and Chairman of the Abu Dhabi Executive Office, H.E. Dr Al Mazrouei is a pivotal figure in the UAE&rsquo;s financial and economic governance.</p>

<p>&bull; H.E. Jasem Al Zaabi</p>

<p>- Role: Board Member</p>

<p>- Background: Chairman of the Abu Dhabi Department of Finance, Chairman of the Board of e&amp; and Vice Chairman of the UAE Central Bank. H.E. Al Zaabi&rsquo;s expertise spans finance, investment, technology, real estate and infrastructure.</p>

<p>&bull; Jon Gray</p>

<p>- Role: Board Member</p>

<p>- Background: President and Chief Operating Officer of Blackstone. Mr. Gray is a globally recognised investor and long-serving leader at the largest alternative asset management firm. With more than $1 trillion in Assets Under Management, Blackstone invests broadly across private equity, real estate, infrastructure, energy, secondaries, credit and insurance.</p>

<p>&bull; Nassef Sawiris</p>

<p>- Role: Board Member</p>

<p>- Background: Executive Chair of OCI Global. Mr. Sawiris is a globally recognised investor and business leader with decades of experience in steering businesses across sectors including investment, commodities, construction, and infrastructure.</p>

<p>&bull; Bernard Looney</p>

<p>- Role: Board Member</p>

<p>- Background: Chairman of Prometheus Hyperscale and former CEO of bp. Mr. Looney brings vast expertise across the global energy supply chain as well as investing in traditional and renewable energies.</p>

<p>H.E. Dr. Sultan Al Jaber commented, &ldquo;Under the guidance of the UAE&rsquo;s leadership, XRG is a transformative investment company, uniquely positioned to unlock value across high-growth sectors, geographies, and value chains that are underpinned by strong market fundamentals. Building on over half a century of Abu Dhabi&rsquo;s global leadership in energy and investment, XRG combines unparalleled knowledge, access to smart capital, building and nurturing strong partnerships, expanding into new markets, and leveraging advanced technologies, with an agile approach to strategic investments across the full energy value chain.</p>

<p>&quot;Initially focused on the energy, low carbon and chemicals sectors, XRG is committed to delivering innovative, sustainable, and disruptive solutions that create long-term value for partners, customers, and stakeholders and supporting the accelerated need for Energy in AI. I look forward to working closely with my colleagues on the XRG Board and our international partners to create new opportunities and lasting value and socio-economic impact.&rdquo;</p>

<p>XRG underscores ADNOC&rsquo;s commitment to accelerating its international growth in response to the significant global energy investment opportunity. The company will focus on addressing megatrends, including the exponential growth of artificial intelligence (AI), the transformation of global energy systems, and the rising energy demands of emerging economies, where population growth and urbanisation are reshaping energy markets.</p>

<p>XRG&rsquo;s diversified, flexible approach ensures it can strategically pivot to identify and invest in high- return opportunities, initially focusing on three strategic growth platforms:</p>

<p>1. The International Gas Platform plans to collaborate with international stakeholders to address significant energy challenges of the 21st century. It aims to develop an extensive integrated gas portfolio to meet the projected 20% increase in global gas demand and a 65% rise in LNG demand by 2050. This platform is intended to enhance global energy security and supply reliable, lower-carbon solutions.</p>

<p>2. The Global Chemicals Platform aims to be among the top five global leaders in producing essential chemical and specialty products, to meet the anticipated 70% increase in global demand by 2050. This platform will facilitate growing urbanisation and industrialisation in emerging economies, thereby generating employment opportunities and promoting advancements in healthcare, agriculture, and technology through the provision of key chemical products.</p>

<p>3. The Low-Carbon Energies Platform aims to accelerate energy transformation and drive sustainable economic growth. It will invest in scalable solutions for hydrogen, ammonia, biofuels and decarbonisation technologies, to meet demand for low carbon fuels that is expected to grow by more than 150% to 2050. XRG will formally begin operations in Q1 2025.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 15:55:12 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735828.1734004447!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735828.1734004447!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE President endorses appointment of Board of Directors of XRG]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Maktoum bin Mohammed reviews Dubai Securities and Exchange Higher Committee’s 2024 accomplishments, future projects]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/maktoum-bin-mohammed-reviews-dubai-securities-and-exchange-higher-committee-s-2024-accomplishments-future-projects-2024-12-09-1.735797</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/maktoum-bin-mohammed-reviews-dubai-securities-and-exchange-higher-committee-s-2024-accomplishments-future-projects-2024-12-09-1.735797</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>His Highness Sheikh Maktoum bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, First Deputy Ruler of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Finance of the UAE, and Chairman of the Dubai Securities and Exchange Higher Committee, chaired a meeting of the Committee to review its significant accomplishments in 2024 and strategic priorities aimed at reinforcing Dubai&rsquo;s position as a dynamic capital market and global financial centre.</p>

<p>Dynamic financial ecosystem<br />
HH Sheikh Maktoum bin Mohammed said: &ldquo;We remain steadfast in our efforts to realise the vision of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister of the UAE and Ruler of Dubai, to establish Dubai as the epicentre of global finance and secure its position among the world&#39;s top four financial hubs, in alignment with the Dubai Economic Agenda D33.&rdquo;</p>

<p>His Highness commended the Committee&rsquo;s sustained efforts to implement innovative approaches to keep pace with the latest developments and meet the needs of local and international investors.<br />
Sheikh Maktoum said: &quot;Dubai&rsquo;s sustained achievements in the capital markets sector stand as testament to its position as a leader in financial innovation and global investment. These milestones reflect the leadership&rsquo;s unwavering commitment to fostering growth and creating a dynamic financial ecosystem that offers diverse opportunities and boosts investor confidence, while driving sustainable economic growth.&rdquo;</p>

<p>IPO successes<br />
His Highness reviewed the accomplishments of the Dubai Financial Market (DFM), highlighting three significant IPOs this year, including Parkin, Spinneys and Talabat, the UAE&rsquo;s largest private sector IPO. These achievements underscore Dubai&rsquo;s appeal as a premier market for public listings. Since the establishment of the Higher Committee, the DFM has hosted a total of 10 listings, raising over AED43 billion and generating demand exceeding AED1.2 trillion.</p>

<p>Strong market index performance<br />
For the second consecutive year, the DFM General Index outperformed all regional indices, increasing by 19%, reflecting the market&rsquo;s sustained growth trajectory. DFM&rsquo;s market capitalisation grew by over 100% from AED394 billion in 2022 to AED801 billion early December 2024.</p>

<p>International investors accounted for 47% of DFM&rsquo;s trading activity, with the market attracting over 132,000 new investors in 2024, 85% of them foreign investors. Notably, 35% of new international investors came from the Asia Pacific region.</p>

<p>Global leadership in Sukuk listings<br />
Nasdaq Dubai emerged as the leading global venue for Sukuk listings in terms of value, and first regionally in debt instrument listings, with 51 listings of sukuk and bonds, and a total value of AED360 billion in listed sukuk, while the aggregate value of fixed income securities stood at AED528 billion. About 45% of issuers hailed from outside the UAE, including sovereign issuance from China, Hong Kong, Indonesia, Turkey, the Philippines, and the Maldives.</p>

<p>Advancements in virtual assets<br />
During the meeting, HH Sheikh Maktoum was also briefed on the ongoing efforts of the Virtual Assets Regulatory Authority (VARA) to solidify Dubai&rsquo;s leadership in the virtual assets sector. VARA continues to focus its efforts on enhancing its infrastructure and extending the reach and resilience of the virtual asset ecosystem, while committing to offering a safe, innovative space for service providers and users alike.</p>

<p>Since its inception, the Dubai Securities and Exchange Higher Committee has played a pivotal role in reinforcing Dubai&rsquo;s position as a global capital market and financial hub. Its efforts align with the emirate&rsquo;s broader economic vision to attract global investments, foster innovation, and enable sustainable growth across all sectors of the financial ecosystem.</p>

<p>The Committee&rsquo;s key accomplishments include establishing the Financial Markets Law Enforcement Committee, and the Virtual Assets Regulatory Authority, a specialised court for the resolution of securities-related disputes, apart from legislation and incentives to support local markets and listed firms.</p>

<p>The Committee also launched several projects including the xCube market maker and xCube trading app, green bonds and sukuk valued at $27 billion, a pilot for carbon credit trading and the IPO Accelerator programme.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 9 Dec 2024 18:03:33 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735798.1733752945!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735798.1733752945!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Maktoum bin Mohammed reviews Dubai Securities and Exchange Higher Committee’s 2024 accomplishments, future projects]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE hosts 102nd meeting of Permanent Committee for Arab Media]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/business/economy-finance/uae-hosts-102nd-meeting-of-permanent-committee-for-arab-media-2024-12-09-1.735791</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/business/economy-finance/uae-hosts-102nd-meeting-of-permanent-committee-for-arab-media-2024-12-09-1.735791</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The UAE hosted the 102nd meeting of the Permanent Committee for Arab Media in Abu Dhabi today, attended by Ahmed Rashid Khattabi, Assistant Secretary-General and Supervisor of the Media and Communication Sector at the Arab League, Abdulrahman bin Nasser Al Obaidan, Chairperson of the Permanent Committee for Arab Media, along with heads and members of delegations from Arab countries.</p>

<p>Mohammed Saeed Al Shehhi, Secretary General of the UAE Media Council, affirmed that the meeting reflects the strong ties among Arab nations and a shared commitment to enhancing the role of Arab media to keep pace with rapid developments while serving Arab communities and protecting their interests.</p>

<p>Al Shehhi added that media is a powerful force in building informed societies, fostering international ties based on mutual understanding, and highlighting shared human values. &quot;Our aim is for Arab media to become a platform for effective communication and a significant force on the global stage,&quot; he said.</p>

<p>He stressed that the world is witnessing major transformations driven by the digital revolution, highlighting how modern technologies, such as artificial intelligence, are shaping the future of media. He called for innovative media policies and strategies to enable Arab media to transition from merely adapting to global changes to leading positive influence, leveraging outstanding Arab resources and talents.</p>

<p>Al Shehhi also emphasised that despite technological advancements, media remains fundamentally a humanitarian message. &quot;Our mission as Arab nations should focus on promoting values of tolerance, coexistence, and mutual respect, while countering threats to our societies such as hate speech, violence, and extremism,&quot; he noted.</p>

<p>He pointed out that today&rsquo;s media industry is an interconnected global enterprise, with content swiftly crossing borders via digital platforms.</p>

<p>&quot;This new reality necessitates enhanced coordination and cooperation among our nations to develop joint mechanisms enabling Arab media to leave its unique mark on the global media landscape, reflecting our communities&rsquo; aspirations, preserving our identity, and contributing to a global dialogue that promotes shared values and addresses global challenges with a responsible Arab spirit,&quot; he added.</p>

<p>He further stated that today&#39;s meeting serves as an important opportunity to exchange ideas and expertise, shaping a collective future for Arab media through practical recommendations that bolster its developmental role and ensure its active presence on the global stage.</p>

<p>Ahmed Rashid Khattabi praised the organisational efforts that contributed to the success of the 102nd meeting of the Permanent Committee for Arab Media, describing these efforts as part of enhancing joint Arab action in the media field, which is a cornerstone in fostering societal vitality and strengthening national cohesion.</p>

<p>He affirmed that media is an indispensable tool in achieving development, promoting good governance, and reinforcing the rule of law, alongside spreading values of peace, tolerance, and coexistence while rejecting extremism and exclusion, appreciating the richness and diversity of societal values with a spirit of openness and innovation.</p>

<p>Khattabi noted that the Arab League has recently worked on advancing the Arab media system through innovative approaches and ambitious projects tailored to current challenges.</p>

<p>He explained that these efforts include combating terrorism, keeping pace with rapid developments in electronic media and artificial intelligence, promoting media literacy and environmental journalism, building partnerships with major digital companies, encouraging media talent, and enhancing professional performance while fostering experience exchange and strengthening Arab representation in the international media arena.</p>

<p>Khattabi expressed gratitude to the UAE for its warm hospitality and professionalism, commending the constructive collaboration of its team with the Arab League&rsquo;s General Secretariat. He hoped that the session&rsquo;s outcomes would result in practical and comprehensive recommendations to be presented to the Executive Office of the Council of Arab Information Ministers for adoption.</p>

<p>Maitha Majid Al Suwaidi, CEO of the Media Strategy and Policy Sector at UAE Media Council, reviewed the UAE&rsquo;s efforts to promote joint Arab action through the Arab Electronic Media Committee, chaired by the UAE. She highlighted the importance of collective efforts in response to the rapid transformations in digital media.</p>

<p>The Permanent Committee for Arab Media discussed updates on the Arab Media Action Plan abroad, the Arab Electronic Media Committee website, and the role of Arab media in addressing terrorism.</p>

<p>The meeting also examined the Arab Media Map for Sustainable Development 2030, measures to advance negotiations with international media companies, ongoing efforts to promote environmental media literacy, and steps to enhance professional excellence and develop the skills of Arab media professionals.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 9 Dec 2024 17:05:20 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735792.1733749506!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735792.1733749506!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE hosts 102nd meeting of Permanent Committee for Arab Media]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Business</category>
										
																			
											<category>Economy and Finance</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Business/Economy_Finance</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai south signs agreement with bt properties to develop a unique master community at the golf district]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/business/real-estate/dubai-south-signs-agreement-with-bt-properties-to-develop-a-unique-master-community-at-the-golf-district-2024-12-06-1.735750</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/business/real-estate/dubai-south-signs-agreement-with-bt-properties-to-develop-a-unique-master-community-at-the-golf-district-2024-12-06-1.735750</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Dubai South, the largest urban master development focusing on aviation, logistics, and real estate, has announced the signing of an agreement with BT Holding LLC, Dubai. The agreement entails the development of a gated-master community within Dubai South&rsquo;s Golf District, located near Al Maktoum International Airport.</p>

<p>The agreement was signed by HE Khalifa Al Zaffin, Executive Chairman of Dubai Aviation City Corporation and Dubai South, and Ahmed Ali Riaz Malik, Group Chief Executive Officer, in the presence of Nabil Al Kindi, CEO of Dubai South Properties, Malik Riaz Hussain, Founder and Chairman of Bahria Town, as well as other senior executives from both entities.</p>

<p>The master community will feature villas, townhouses, apartments, educational facilities, hospitals, retail spaces, mosques, and entertainment venues. It will also include green spines, water streams, a central park, dancing fountains, iconic monuments, wide boulevards, and numerous other attractions, offering a serene yet vibrant living experience.</p>

<p>In his comments on the agreement, HE Khalifa Al Zaffin said: &ldquo;We are pleased to sign this agreement with one of the most reputable developers in Asia. Dubai South is poised to become the city of the future, and the increasing demand for properties in the area underscores its immense potential in the years ahead. We remain steadfast in our commitment to supporting the government&rsquo;s vision of attracting 1 million residents to Dubai South upon the completion of Al Maktoum International Airport. This unique project, which reiterates Dubai&rsquo;s appeal to global investors, will set new benchmarks in luxury community living and meet the expectations of discerning investors and residents alike.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Malik Riaz Hussain said: &ldquo;Dubai, with its rapid growth and global prominence, represents a key market for our international expansion. We are thrilled to partner with Dubai South to launch a master development that embodies the essence of a forward-thinking and progressive community. Leveraging our extensive expertise in developing vast, master-planned communities across hundreds of square kilometres in Pakistan, we are eager to replicate this success in Dubai by creating a holistic, self-sustaining community. We look forward to work closely with Dubai South to transform this ambitious vision into reality.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Dubai South was launched as a Dubai Government project in 2006, representing an emerging 145 square-kilometre, master-planned city. Positioned as a global commercial and residential hub and a major contributor to the social and economic growth of Dubai and the United Arab Emirates, Dubai South offers business-friendly free-zone benefits and a living environment with a diverse range of mixed-use and residential communities to suit different lifestyles.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 6 Dec 2024 18:16:11 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735751.1733494522!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735751.1733494522!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai south signs agreement with bt properties to develop a unique master community at the golf district]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Business</category>
										
																			
											<category>Real Estate</category>
										
																								
										
													
				 									<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/General</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Bitcoin $100,000 after Trump wins US election]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/business/gold-currency/bitcoin-100-000-after-trump-wins-us-election-2024-12-05-1.735734</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/business/gold-currency/bitcoin-100-000-after-trump-wins-us-election-2024-12-05-1.735734</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin approached $90,000 on Tuesday, riding a wave of optimism following Donald Trump&rsquo;s election as U.S. president, with expectations that his administration will be more supportive of cryptocurrency.</p>

<p>The world&rsquo;s largest cryptocurrency has become one of the most prominent performers since the election, reaching $89,637 in Asia&mdash;a surge of more than 25% since November 5.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://www.avatrade.com/cryptocurrencies/bitcoin"><span style="color:#0000CD;">Bitcoin trading</span></a></strong> price rise mirrors the performance of Tesla (TSLA.O), Elon Musk&rsquo;s automaker, which has gained nearly 40% since the election results, as investors bet that Trump&rsquo;s allies and interests will thrive during his presidency.</p>

<p>&quot;This is clearly a Trump-driven rally, as he&rsquo;s very supportive of the industry, which will likely increase demand for both crypto-related stocks and the cryptocurrencies themselves,&quot; said Nick Twidale, chief market analyst at ATFX Global in Sydney.</p>

<p>&quot;Bitcoin was already near all-time highs when the election results came in, so it had a clear path to rise even further.&quot;</p>

<p>Trump has been a vocal advocate for digital assets during his campaign, promising to make the U.S. the &quot;crypto capital of the planet&quot; and to amass a national bitcoin reserve.</p>

<p>Although the specifics and timeline remain unclear, the prospect has sparked a speculative surge in crypto mining and trading stocks.</p>

<p>&quot;I think Trump&rsquo;s win raises the possibility that other countries may start buying bitcoin in anticipation of the U.S. doing so,&quot; said Matthew Dibb, chief investment officer at cryptocurrency asset manager Astronaut Capital. &quot;It could also be a huge catalyst for U.S.-listed Bitcoin miners, particularly if there&#39;s a chance of them being nationalized.&quot;</p>

<p>Shares of crypto miner Riot Platforms surged nearly 17% on Wall Street overnight, and continued to rise in after-hours trading. Other miners, such as MARA Holdings (MARA.O) and CleanSpark (CLSK.O), saw gains of nearly 30%.</p>

<p>Software company MicroStrategy (MSTR.O), a major bitcoin investor, revealed it had spent about $2 billion on bitcoin between October 31 and November 10. Its shares rose 26%, with continued gains in after-hours trading.</p>

<p>The enthusiasm extended beyond Bitcoin to smaller tokens, including ether and even the once-joke currency dogecoin, both seeing significant increases.</p>

<p>Crypto <strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Investor"><span style="color:#0000CD;">investors</span></a><span style="color:#0000CD;"> </span></strong>are also anticipating less regulatory scrutiny under U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission Chair Gary Gensler, whom Trump has indicated he will replace. In September, Trump launched a new crypto business, World Liberty Financial.</p>

<p>&quot;What we&rsquo;re witnessing isn&rsquo;t just a milestone in price, but a signal that the market is warming up to bitcoin as a more stable and politically favored asset,&quot; said Justin D&#39;Anethan, head of Asia-Pacific business development at digital assets market maker Keyrock.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 5 Dec 2024 17:46:00 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735735.1733406320!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735735.1733406320!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Bitcoin $100,000 after Trump wins US election]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Business</category>
										
																			
											<category>Gold and Currency</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/5900/business24-7/Business/gold-currency</category>
										
					</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
