<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
	<title>Mobile - Law and Order</title>
	<link>http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-law-and-order-1.635430?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout</link>	
	<atom:link href="http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-law-and-order-1.635430?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" ></atom:link>
	<description>Law and Order</description>
			        <language>en</language>
    				<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Sharjah EPAA arrests, fines Kalba poachers]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/crime/local/sharjah-epaa-arrests-fines-kalba-poachers-2020-07-29-1.695535</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/crime/local/sharjah-epaa-arrests-fines-kalba-poachers-2020-07-29-1.695535</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Sharjah&rsquo;s Environment and Protected Areas Authority, EPAA, recently arrested four people accused of taking protected wildlife from the Alqurm Protected Area at Khor Kalba, on the UAE&rsquo;s East Coast, it has been announced. They were accused of violating several protocols and regulations.</p>

<p>Hana Saif Al Suwaidi, the EPAA Chairwoman, said that despite the instructions on signs distributed throughout the reserve, which stipulate that entry to the sanctuary is forbidden without prior official permission, and laws and instructions not to harm wildlife directly and indirectly within the reserve, the people were found to have entered the reserve, ignoring the guidelines and putting the wildlife in the reserve at risk.</p>

<p>She said that when they were apprehended they were carrying large quantities of fish and crabs. Following legal questioning, they were each fined a total of AED10,000 for the offence.</p>

<p>The penalties are prescribed by the Sharjah Executive Council for individuals found to be causing harm to nature and wildlife in the Emirate. Offences include any damage to the soil and vegetation, and the cutting of perennial and annual vegetation. The Council also issues fines for the disposal of waste from construction sites into areas of reserves and for the dumping of wastewater and oil from sewage networks.</p>

<p>Those following unfair fishing practices, killing and harming wild creatures and destroying geological formations, in addition to polluting the environment, also face severe penalties.</p>

<p>The Alqurm Protected Area includes diverse ecosystems, including the only forest of mangroves on the UAE&rsquo;s East Coast, swamps and salt marshes (sabkhas) and mudflats. It is also home to one of the rarest birds in the world, the local sub- species of the Collared Kingfisher, while endangered marine turtles breed on its beaches.</p>

<p>The Sharjah Environment and Protected Areas Authority seeks to protect the environment, nature reserves, wildlife and their biological diversity by conducting scientific studies and research and implementing measures for pollution control. In addition, the Authority seeks to increase awareness through educational programmes on the principles of sustainable development.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 11:07:57 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.695536.1596006458!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.695536.1596006458!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
											<media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Photo: WAM]]></media:title>
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Sharjah EPAA arrests, fines Kalba poachers]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Law_Order</category>
										
																			
											<category>Local</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Law_order/Local</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Federal Public Prosecution warns public against circulating information on drugs]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/crime/local/federal-public-prosecution-warns-public-against-circulating-information-on-drugs-2020-07-22-1.695438</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/crime/local/federal-public-prosecution-warns-public-against-circulating-information-on-drugs-2020-07-22-1.695438</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The UAE Federal Public Prosecution has warned the public against publishing any information for the purposes of trafficking in or promoting narcotic drugs.</p>

<p>On its social media platforms, the Public Prosecution affirmed its ongoing efforts and keenness to support the fight against this scourge by heightening the awareness of the public on the risks of this crime.</p>

<p>&quot;Eliminating this plague will not only protect our young people but will also enhance the sense of safety and stability of our community, the Public Prosecution said.</p>

<p>It emphasised that the UAE law, including the Federal Law no. 14 of 1995, and its amendments; has illegalized the possession of narcotic drugs and psychotropic substances for trafficking in, or promoting purposes, an offence which carries the death penalty.</p>

<p>It further noted that the Federal Decree-Law No. 5 of 2012 on Combating Cyber Crimes has addressed the crime of publishing information for trafficking in, or promoting narcotics via information technology means.</p>

<p>According to Article (36) of this Decree-Law, whoever establishes, manages or runs a website or publishes information on the computer network or any information technology means for trafficking in or promoting narcotics or psychotropic substances and the like or the manner for their use or facilitates such dealing in instances other than those permitted by the law shall be punished by temporary imprisonment and a fine not less than five hundred thousand dirhams and not in excess of one million dirhams or either of these two penalties.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 11:06:06 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.623482.1457360683!/image/image.gif_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.gif" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.623482.1457360683!/image/image.gif_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.gif" type="image/jpeg">
											<media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[(Shutterstock)]]></media:title>
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Federal Public Prosecution warns public against circulating information on drugs]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Law_Order</category>
										
																			
											<category>Local</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Law_order/Local</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Operation Fox Hunt 2: Dubai Police take down "Hushpuppi" , "Woodberry", ten international cybercriminals]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/crime/local/operation-fox-hunt-2-dubai-police-take-down-hushpuppi-woodberry-ten-international-cybercriminals-2020-06-28-1.695146</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/crime/local/operation-fox-hunt-2-dubai-police-take-down-hushpuppi-woodberry-ten-international-cybercriminals-2020-06-28-1.695146</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="color: #000000;">The Dubai Police have recently arrested Raymond Igbalode Abbas, also known as &quot;Hushpuppi&quot; and Olalekan Jacob Ponle aka &quot;Woodberry&quot; along with ten African cybercriminals in a special operation.&nbsp; </span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span dir="RTL" style="color: #000000;">Dubbed &quot;Fox Hunt 2&quot;, the operation took down the suspects for committing crimes outside the UAE, including money-laundering, cyber fraud, hacking, criminal impersonating, scamming individuals, banking fraud and identity theft. </span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="color: #000000;">Lt. General Abdullah Khalifa Al Marri, the Commander-in-chief of Dubai Police, said the arrest of &#39;Hushpuppi&#39;, &#39;Woodberry&#39; and ten gang members involved in money laundry and cyber fraud activities, is another achievement added to the proud record of Dubai police in ensuring the emirate&#39;s security and safety as well as preserving people&#39;s money and property. &quot;Similar to operation &#39;Fox Hunt 1&#39; that took down an African gang of nine online scammers last February, Op &#39;Fox Hunt 2&#39; is another painful hit to cybercriminals who try to mess with the world&#39;s security and safety,&quot; he said. </span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="color: #000000;">Al Marri further reaffirmed the force&#39;s commitment to foiling cyber fraud and online scams using the latest technology. &quot;As criminals constantly change their criminal methods, Dubai Police work tirelessly to qualify elites of officers and employees specialised in facilitating the latest technologies to tackle emerging and transnational organised crime,&quot; he said.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="color: #000000;">The commander-in-chief of Dubai Police also praised the tremendous efforts made by the force&#39;s teams who arrested the suspects and mastered the use of modern technologies. </span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="color: #000000;"><strong>Synchronised Raids</strong></span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="color: #000000;">According to Expert Major General Khalil Ibrahim Al Mansouri, Assistant Commander-in-Chief for Criminal Investigation Affairs, the suspects were caught in a series of synchronised raids by six SWAT teams from Dubai Police. &quot;The operation was carried out in a highly professional manner in terms of planning and execution as well as setting a zero hour to take down all gang members in the same time,&quot; Al Mansouri said. </span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="color: #000000;">Al Mansouri said the operation foiled the gang&#39;s bid to deceive many people from around the world and steal their money. He also lauded the efforts of the task force assigned to the case. &quot;The investigation teams at Dubai Police have done a great job in utilising AI-based technologies, including the Criminal Data Analysis Centre at Dubai Police, to track down the cyber fraudsters,&quot; Al Mansouri said.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="color: #000000;"><strong>Fox Hunt 2</strong></span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span dir="RTL" style="color: #000000;">Revealing the operation&#39;s details, Brigadier Jamal Salem Al Jallaf, Director of Criminal Investigation Department (CID) at Dubai Police, said that upon receiving the security intel about an African gang involved in money-laundering and cyber fraud, an investigation team was formed to track down the suspects, make the arrest and put an end to the gang&#39;s illegal activities that have been badly affecting individuals and companies overseas and targeting their bank accounts and credit cards. </span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span dir="RTL" style="color: #000000;">&quot;After verifying available information, the team has started to track the gang including &quot;Hushpuppi&quot;, who celebrated his wealth via social media platform, under a businessman fa&ccedil;ade, in an attempt to lure victims from all over the world,&quot; Al Jallaf said. </span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span dir="RTL" style="color: #000000;">Al Jallaf said the anti-cybercrime task force was able to track the gang members and detect their criminal activities including creating fake accounts on social media website with fake nicknames, hacking corporate emails to deceive clients into making money transfers to the gang&#39;s bank accounts. </span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span dir="RTL" style="color: #000000;">&quot;The suspects also targeted victims overseas by creating fake websites for well-known companies and banks in a bid to steal victims&#39; credit card information and then launder the stolen money,&quot; Al Jallaf continued. </span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="color: #000000;">The director of Dubai CID said the raid resulted in confiscating incriminating documents of a planned fraud on a global scale worth AED 1.6 billion ($ 435 million). </span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span dir="RTL" style="color: #000000;">&quot;The team also seized more than AED 150 million ($40.9 million) in cash, 13 luxury cars with an estimated value of AED 25 million ($6.8 million) obtained from fraud crimes, and confiscated 21 computer devices, 47 smartphones, 15 memory sticks, five hard disks containing 119,580 fraud files as well as addresses of 1,926,400 victims&quot;, he said.&nbsp; </span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span dir="RTL" style="color: #000000;">After conducting further investigations and analysing confiscated electronic devices, Dubai Police investigators uncovered sensitive information mined by the suspects on individuals and companies overseas including bank accounts and fake credit cards as well as documents and files condemning the gangs&#39; illegal activities. </span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="color: #000000;"><strong>Fox Hunt 1</strong></span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span dir="RTL" style="color: #000000;">Last February, Dubai Police arrested an African gang of nine fraudsters specialised in cyber scam after they had run 81 fake business across 18 countries around the world. </span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span dir="RTL" style="color: #000000;">Dubbed &quot;Fox Hunt 1&quot; the operation revealed a hidden online fraud network that deceived victims into transferring money in return of job opportunities. The gang used multiple bank accounts to make money transfers and deposits totalling more than AED 32 million ($8.7 million) </span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="color: #000000;">The operation prevented the gang from abusing 800,000 email addresses and foiled their bid to steal 4 billion dirhams ($1.08 billion).&nbsp; </span></p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 11:16:04 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.695147.1593328528!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.695147.1593328528!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
											<media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Photo: Dubai Media Office]]></media:title>
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>Dubai Media Office </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Operation Fox Hunt 2: Dubai Police take down "Hushpuppi" , "Woodberry", ten international cybercriminals]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Law_Order</category>
										
																			
											<category>Local</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Law_order/Local</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Public Prosecution calls on public not to use, deal with display fireworks to ensure public safety, avoid legal accountability]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/news/emirates/public-prosecution-calls-on-public-not-to-use-deal-with-display-fireworks-to-ensure-public-safety-avoid-legal-accountability-2020-05-11-1.694405</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/news/emirates/public-prosecution-calls-on-public-not-to-use-deal-with-display-fireworks-to-ensure-public-safety-avoid-legal-accountability-2020-05-11-1.694405</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The Public Prosecution has called upon the public to abide by the Law of the land and not to use fireworks in any way whatsoever in order to ensure public safety and avoid legal accountability.</p>

<p>Pursuant to the Federal Decree Law No 17 of 2019 on arms, munition, explosives, military hardware and hazardous material, explosives may consist of a chemically pure compound or a mixture of different chemical compounds that interact with each other when exposed to predisposing factors, such as a stimulating force in the production of pressure and heat at a certain speed that leads to affecting or damaging the surroundings, said the Public Prosecution, noting that &quot;display fireworks&quot; are considered to be explosive material.</p>

<p>Under the Article 3 of the Federal Decree Law, the acquisition, possession, transport, illicit carriage, manufacturing, and repair of explosives or explosive devices are prohibited without a regulatory approval, added the prosecution.</p>

<p>Under Article 54, any person trading in, importing, exporting, or manufacturing fireworks or getting them into or out of the country without a license shall be sentenced a jail sentence of not less than one year and be find not less than AED100,000, or either of the said punishments.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 01:20:37 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.694406.1589145609!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.694406.1589145609!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
											<media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Photo: WAM]]></media:title>
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Public Prosecution calls on public not to use, deal with display fireworks to ensure public safety, avoid legal accountability]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>News</category>
										
																			
											<category>Emirates</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/News/Emirates</category>
										
					</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
