<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
	<title>Mobile Technology</title>
	<link>http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-technology-1.512834?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout</link>	
	<atom:link href="http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-technology-1.512834?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" ></atom:link>
	<description>Technology</description>
			        <language>en</language>
    				<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Yapiee App Sets New Standards in Influencer-Brand Partnerships for UAE Businesses]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/yapiee-app-sets-new-standards-in-influencer-brand-partnerships-for-uae-businesses-2025-01-04-1.736043</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/yapiee-app-sets-new-standards-in-influencer-brand-partnerships-for-uae-businesses-2025-01-04-1.736043</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<ul>
	<li><strong><em>Yapiee transforms influencer marketing in the UAE, fostering impactful collaborations between brands and influencers. </em></strong></li>
</ul>

<p>Yapiee App, an influencer marketing platform, has been innovative, mainly in the space of the influencer marketing apps. It changes how brands would get in touch with influencers across the UAE. Being different from others, this platform provides a path for companies of all sorts to team up with an influencer to reduce the influence marketing process while at the same time making it easier to promote businesses, allowing companies to gain visibility along with interacting with customers via meaningful engagement.</p>

<p>At the core is the AI-powered matching system which links a brand with its influencer based on their audience&#39;s demographics and interest. It means marketing campaigns would not only be effective but customized: because the needs of each business will be different. Businesses can create a unique offer to a niche audience, and that results in increased customer loyalty and sales. Importantly, Yapiee also provides an opportunity to offer the brand&#39;s goods or services in exchange for influencer collaborations instead of money, and this seems to be very cost-efficient and beneficial to both parties.</p>

<p>One of the most significant value propositions that has been there for Yapiee is its real-time collaboration functions. These help influencers as well as brands coordinate with each other in a seamless manner without causing any issues, so that the campaigns reach the right time frame and maximize the effectiveness of every marketing campaign. Thus, it&#39;s a tool crucial for any business looking to drive success in the competitive digital market.</p>

<p>Achievement in cost-effective marketing can be realized through the acquisition of this app by businesses anywhere in the UAE. This initiative not only contributes to the development of the local economy but also enhances brand engagement through influencer marketing. The app offers multilingual support in six languages: Arabic, English, German, Spanish, French, and Italian. This feature ensures that people from diverse backgrounds can connect easily, facilitating effective communication between brands and consumers, regardless of cultural and linguistic differences.</p>

<p>With flexible social media integration, Yapiee is able to connect businesses to their target audience across all the major platforms like Instagram, X, YouTube, TikTok, and Facebook. And that goes with the scope of engagement and visibility, the requirements to thrive in this competitive market today.</p>

<p>Very recently, Yapiee exhibited at GITEX/North Star 2024 held in Dubai. It marked a difference among the many 6,500 participants with regard to showcasing its unique value proposition in front of international spectators. This platform helped grab the attention of visitors and clients, as well as influencers, toward the new product.</p>

<p>It&#39;s free to download and use, and thus the application is even more attractive for brands and their influencers. Yapiee is also planning to expand its operations internationally by early 2025.</p>

<p>Summed up in a nutshell, it can be said that Yapiee is not merely a marketing tool but is something that can change the face of business entities within the UAE. It helps in bringing people closer to forming a community and increasing visibility; they are engaging the audience to a great extent by bringing forward these innovative features and continuous collaborations.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zz1OE8hfYLg"><span style="color:#0000FF;">Click here to know how Yapiee works for Businesses</span></a><span style="color:#0000FF;"> or </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T6JQ6xqe-pU"><span style="color:#0000FF;">get an overview of the Yapiee App here</span></a><span style="color:#0000FF;">.</span></strong></p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sat, 4 Jan 2025 13:35:46 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736044.1735983268!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736044.1735983268!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Yapiee App Sets New Standards in Influencer-Brand Partnerships for UAE Businesses]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Technology</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Technology</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai Culture and Google launch open call for 2nd MENA Creatives Bootcamp – AI & Innovation Edition]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/dubai-culture-and-google-launch-open-call-for-2nd-mena-creatives-bootcamp-ai-innovation-edition-2024-12-24-1.735957</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/dubai-culture-and-google-launch-open-call-for-2nd-mena-creatives-bootcamp-ai-innovation-edition-2024-12-24-1.735957</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p style="box-sizing: border-box; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 1.25em; font-size: 1.375em; color: rgb(113, 120, 125); line-height: 1.375em; font-family: flamabook, Roboto, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, Arial, sans-serif; background-color: rgb(247, 247, 247);">Dubai Culture and Arts Authority (Dubai Culture) has launched the open call for the second &lsquo;MENA Creatives Bootcamp &ndash; AI &amp; Innovation Edition,&rsquo; organised in collaboration with Google. The programme aims to support creative community members, enhance their skills, and empower them to leverage technology and AI solutions to advance their creative projects. It also focuses on boosting digital presence and encouraging experiential learning. This initiative reflects Dubai Culture&rsquo;s commitment to strengthening the cultural and creative industries, positioning Dubai as a global centre for culture, an incubator for creativity, and a thriving hub for talent.<br style="box-sizing: border-box;" />
<br style="box-sizing: border-box;" />
The Authority has invited all creatives in UAE and MENA region to register for the bootcamp, with applications open until to 10 January, 2025. Spaces are limited to gain access to the four-day event, which offers participants opportunities to network, collaborate with outstanding talent and gain tailored one-on-one mentorship from Google&rsquo;s AI experts. Google&rsquo;s office in Dubai will host the bootcamp activities, while Al Quoz Creative Zone will host the last day with a specialised programme covering innovation, digital art and artificial intelligence.<br style="box-sizing: border-box;" />
<br style="box-sizing: border-box;" />
Shaima Rashed Al Suwaidi, Director of the Marketing &amp; Corporate Communication Department at Dubai Culture, affirmed the significance of the &lsquo;MENA Creatives Bootcamp &ndash; AI &amp; Innovation Edition&rsquo; and its role in fostering innovation and encouraging the harnessing of digital tools, in line with the UAE National Innovation Strategy, saying: &ldquo;Through this bootcamp, Dubai Culture seeks to open new horizons for creatives and provide them with access to experts, tools and knowledge to explore technology and advanced AI applications that can be applied to their creative practices and projects. These applications possess unique capabilities in content creation and generating original ideas for their projects, contributing to Dubai&rsquo;s global leadership as one of the most future-ready cities in the world.&rdquo;<br style="box-sizing: border-box;" />
<br style="box-sizing: border-box;" />
The first edition of the &lsquo;MENA Creatives Bootcamp &ndash; Sustainability Edition&rsquo; aligned with the UAE Year of Sustainability as well as the hosting of COP 28 and succeeded in attracting over 88 applications from creatives locally and regionally. Of these, 21 creatives from 10 countries were selected to join the bootcamp, guided by 41 mentors and specialists across various fields. The programme also featured one-on-one mentoring sessions led by 19 Google experts, as well as a wide range of workshops and sessions on achieving sustainability and discovering eco-friendly design practices.</p>

<p style="box-sizing: border-box; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 1.25em; font-size: 1.375em; color: rgb(113, 120, 125); line-height: 1.375em; font-family: flamabook, Roboto, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, Arial, sans-serif; background-color: rgb(247, 247, 247);">To register in the bootcamp, visit&nbsp;<a href="https://dubaiculture.gov.ae/en/about-us/special-projects/our-projects-events/Dubai-Culture-and-Google-launch-open-call-for-2nd-MENA-Creatives-Bootcamp" style="box-sizing: border-box; color: rgb(0, 174, 242); text-decoration-line: none; word-break: break-all; background-color: transparent;">this link</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 18:45:28 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735958.1735051516!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735958.1735051516!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai Culture and Google launch open call for 2nd MENA Creatives Bootcamp – AI & Innovation Edition]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Technology</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Technology</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed issues directives for organising the Dubai AI Week initiative to drive AI adoption]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/hamdan-bin-mohammed-issues-directives-for-organising-the-dubai-ai-week-initiative-to-drive-ai-adoption-2024-12-19-1.735913</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/hamdan-bin-mohammed-issues-directives-for-organising-the-dubai-ai-week-initiative-to-drive-ai-adoption-2024-12-19-1.735913</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defence of the UAE, Chairman of The Executive Council of Dubai, and Chairman of the Board of Trustees of the Dubai Future Foundation (DFF), today issued directives for the &lsquo;Dubai AI Week&rsquo; to be organised from 21 to 25 April, 2025. In its inaugural edition, the event will bring together global AI experts, thought leaders and decision-makers for a week-long series of conferences, initiatives, and exhibitions to explore advancements, share insights, and address real-world challenges. The first-of-its-kind initiative aligns with the Dubai Universal Blueprint for Artificial Intelligence.</p>

<p>Dubai AI Week will feature a diverse range of events with extensive global participation from AI thought leaders, specialists, and executives representing leading AI-focused organisations. The primary events will be held at the Museum of the Future and AREA 2071 in the Emirates Towers, Dubai.</p>

<p>The initiative will showcase key events, including the &lsquo;AI Retreat&rsquo;, &lsquo;Dubai Assembly for Generative AI&rsquo;, &lsquo;Global Prompt Engineering Championship&rsquo;, &lsquo;Machines Can See&rsquo; Summit, and the &lsquo;Dubai AI Festival&rsquo;.</p>

<p>HH Sheikh Hamdan stated: &ldquo;Under the leadership of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister of the UAE and Ruler of Dubai, we are creating an integrated ecosystem that is shaping the future of AI and solidifying Dubai&rsquo;s position as a global hub for AI innovation. AI is integral to future advancements, and Dubai stands as a platform where experts and innovators can come together to unlock its vast potential.&rdquo;</p>

<p>His Highness added: &ldquo;Dubai has always been at the forefront of identifying AI&rsquo;s transformative opportunities and fostering strong public-private partnerships to drive investment in this critical field. With a clear and focused strategy, we aim to accelerate AI adoption to achieve our goals. Dubai AI Week will gather global experts to deliver solutions that benefit humanity, create new opportunities for progress, and establish best practices for AI innovation and application.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Driving global impact<br />
The Dubai AI Week builds on the success of the inaugural &lsquo;AI Retreat&rsquo;, hosted by DFF in June 2024 as a main event under the Dubai Universal Blueprint for Artificial Intelligence. The 2025 AI Retreat, a highlight of AI Week, will take place at the Museum of the Future, bringing together over 1,000 global experts, policymakers, and industry leaders. Featuring four roundtable discussions, the retreat will explore global and local AI opportunities, outline strategies to expand AI applications across various sectors, and launch ten strategic AI initiatives.</p>

<p>The &lsquo;Dubai Assembly for Generative AI&rsquo;, hosted at AREA 2071, will bring together 1,800 participants, including ministers, officials, CEOs, decision-makers, experts, and global speakers. The assembly will feature 25 main sessions and 12 immersive experiences led by major global tech companies, offering a dynamic platform to explore emerging AI technologies through discussions, exhibitions, and live demonstrations.</p>

<p>The &lsquo;Global Prompt Engineering Championship&rsquo; received 2,000 applications, with 40 finalists to be selected to showcase creative solutions evaluated by a panel of 12 experts. Taking place at the Museum of the Future and AREA 2071, the competition will focus on optimising AI solutions for speed, accuracy, and efficiency. A total prize pool of AED1 million will be awarded across four competition categories.</p>

<p>The &lsquo;Dubai AI Festival&rsquo;, held at Madinat Jumeirah, will attract 5,000 business leaders, 500 investors, and 100 exhibitors from 100 countries. Organised by the Dubai AI Campus in partnership with the Dubai International Financial Centre (DIFC), the festival will serve as a platform for global leaders to exchange ideas, form partnerships, and showcase groundbreaking AI projects.</p>

<p>The &lsquo;Machines Can See&rsquo; Summit, making its debut during Dubai AI Week, will welcome 5,000 visitors for its exhibitions, 850 participants, and 40 global experts and speakers. This event will bring together executives, researchers, and startups to foster collaboration and showcase advancements in machine vision technologies, a key area of AI innovation.</p>

<p>Premier regional showcase<br />
The Machines Can See 2025 Summit, organised by Polynome Events in collaboration with the Artificial Intelligence, Digital Economy and Remote Work Applications office (UAE), and DFF, stands out as a premier AI event in the Middle East. The summit will bring together 5,000 industry leaders, including 100 senior executives from top technology companies, 300 startups, and leading academic researchers. The event will offer opportunities for networking and growth, enabling organisations to strengthen their presence in the region&#39;s thriving AI ecosystem and attract top talent.</p>

<p>Dubai AI Week will also feature the launch of a comprehensive week-long programme in Dubai&rsquo;s schools, in collaboration with the Knowledge and Human Development Authority (KHDA). The initiative aims to educate students about Artificial Intelligence concepts and its future applications, inspiring them to actively participate in shaping the future of various industries.</p>

<p>Dubai AI Week is set to become a cornerstone event on the Dubai calendar, uniting global experts across a week of activations to showcase innovations, tackle sector challenges, and establish best practices for AI integration, further cementing Dubai&rsquo;s leadership in AI innovation.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 14:36:54 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735914.1734604569!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735914.1734604569!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed issues directives for organising the Dubai AI Week initiative to drive AI adoption]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Technology</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Technology</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed launches Middle East’s first-of-its-kind drone delivery system at Dubai Silicon Oasis]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/hamdan-bin-mohammed-launches-middle-east-s-first-of-its-kind-drone-delivery-system-at-dubai-silicon-oasis-2024-12-17-1.735894</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/hamdan-bin-mohammed-launches-middle-east-s-first-of-its-kind-drone-delivery-system-at-dubai-silicon-oasis-2024-12-17-1.735894</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defence of the UAE, and Chairman of the Board of Trustees of the Dubai Future Foundation (DFF), today launched the Middle East&rsquo;s first-of-its-kind drone delivery system at Dubai Silicon Oasis (DSO), the special economic zone for knowledge and innovation and a member of the Dubai Integrated Economic Zones Authority (DIEZ).</p>

<p>The launch event was attended by H.H. Sheikh Ahmed bin Saeed Al Maktoum, President of the Dubai Civil Aviation Authority, Chairman of Dubai Airports, Chairman and Chief Executive of Emirates Airline and Group, and Chairman of the Dubai Integrated Economic Zones Authority.</p>

<p>He placed the first order using the drone delivery system through the platform from the Rochester Institute of Technology-Dubai (RIT-Dubai), one of the landing points within DSO&rsquo;s drone delivery network. The order was successfully delivered from one of the take-off points in the community.</p>

<p>H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed reaffirmed Dubai&rsquo;s commitment to developing advanced infrastructure and fostering an innovative environment to enhance smart logistics and cutting-edge air transport solutions, aligned with the vision of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President, Prime Minister and Ruler of Dubai, to establish Dubai as a leader among future-ready cities.</p>

<p>His Highness said, &ldquo;We continue to support projects that drive a diversified, flexible digital economy by leveraging advanced technology in Dubai and empowering the aviation and air transport sectors. Our strategy places a high priority on strengthening public-private partnerships to catalyse research and development (R&amp;D), sustainable growth, and smart mobility. This aligns with the Dubai Economic Agenda D33, which aims to position Dubai among the world&rsquo;s top three urban economies.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Highlighting the importance of economic growth driven by R&amp;D and innovation, H.H. Sheikh Hamdan said, &ldquo;Over the past years, we have launched a series of programmes in Dubai aimed at promoting the development of smart city solutions, enhancing economic integration between various sectors, and employing technology in the service of society, such as the Dubai Programme to Enable Drone Transportation, the Dubai Robotics and Automation Programme, the Dubai Research and Development Program, and Dubai&rsquo;s annual plan to accelerate the adoption of artificial intelligence. Today, we are reaping the impressive results of these initiatives and continuing the transformational projects that will double the size of Dubai&rsquo;s economy by 2033.&rdquo;</p>

<p>H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed further said, &ldquo;The future of robotic technologies and self-driving systems for retail services, and knowledge-based economic applications, innovation, digital transformation and the use of artificial intelligence have all become a reality in Dubai.&rdquo;</p>

<p>His Highness emphasised Dubai&rsquo;s pioneering role in driving innovation and creating new opportunities. &ldquo;Dubai has consistently led the way in advancing research, innovation, and the adoption of transformative technologies. A decade ago, we introduced the UAE Drones for Good Award to encourage the positive use of drone technology. Today, we have reached a significant milestone with operational readiness to commence drone delivery operations. Through strong collaboration between the public and private sectors, we aim to further raise the quality of services, enhance quality of life, and accelerate economic growth.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The launch was also attended by Omar bin Sultan Al Olama, Minister of State For Artificial Intelligence, Digital Economy and Remote Work Applications; Mattar Al Tayer, Director General and Chairman of the Board of Executive Directors of Dubai&rsquo;s Roads and Transport Authority (RTA); Lieutenant General Talal Belhoul Al Falasi, President of Dubai&rsquo;s State Security Department; and several senior officials.</p>

<p>His Highness&rsquo; comments were made during the completion of a joint project between Dubai Civil Aviation Authority, the Dubai Integrated Economic Zones Authority (DIEZ), and the Dubai Future Foundation (DFF), to finalise preparations for launching drone delivery services in DSO. Their efforts resulted in the creation of dedicated air routes aligned with existing airspace usage in DSO.</p>

<p>H.H. Sheikh Ahmed bin Saeed Al Maktoum emphasised that Dubai&rsquo;s global leadership in aviation, logistics, and future mobility stems from the visionary leadership of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum. This vision has established Dubai as one of the most advanced hubs for air transport and aviation solutions. Dubai also leads in excellence in research, development, and testing of cutting-edge technologies, including drones and related services, leveraging these innovations to drive development and serve communities worldwide.</p>

<p>The pilots at Dubai Silicon Oasis were the culmination of the Dubai Programme to Enable Drone Transportation, launched by H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum in 2021. The MoU to initiate the programme&rsquo;s operations was signed by several government and private sector entities, including Dubai Silicon Oasis, Dubai Future Foundation, Dubai Civil Aviation Authority, the Roads and Transport Authority, Fakeeh University Hospital, Majid Al Futtaim, and Emirates SkyCargo.</p>

<p>Over the past few months, Dubai Silicon Oasis hosted a series of pilot operations for drone delivery operations to ensure the highest aviation safety and security standards. This was done in cooperation with the DCAA and Keeta Drone, a pioneer in this field and the most well-known drone delivery platform in China. This is the company&rsquo;s first venture outside the Greater China region.</p>

<p>Dr. Mohammed Al Zarooni, Executive Chairman of DIEZ, said, &ldquo;DIEZ is committed to supporting initiatives that utilise advanced technologies to facilitate people&rsquo;s daily lives, and provide a conducive environment to pilot smart solutions ahead of implementation. We are proud to be a key partner of the Dubai Program to Enable Drone Transportation, launched by H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, in 2021.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He added, &ldquo;We are delighted to launch drone delivery operations at DSO, which has become an internationally recognised lab for the latest smart technologies. The launch marks a new milestone in the shift towards a future of technological innovation. We are committed to working with both, the private and public sectors, to test and implement projects and initiatives in the smart mobility field, in a bid to offer the emirate&rsquo;s residents the most advanced smart services as part of the emirate&rsquo;s broader strategy to make Dubai the world&rsquo;s best place to live.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Mohammed Abdullah Linjawi, Director General of DCAA, said, &ldquo;We are committed to making a vital contribution to enhancing Dubai&rsquo;s position as one of the cities best prepared for the future and a global hub for innovation in the aviation sector. This new achievement in the field of drone delivery reflects the continuous efforts made by the emirate under the guidance of the wise leadership, which has always attached great importance to developing safe and efficient transportation solutions that contribute to improving quality of life, strengthening Dubai&rsquo;s future economy and making it a leading model in developing and implementing smart solutions in the field of aviation.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He added, &ldquo;Drone delivery will reach 33% of Dubai by 2030, positioning the emirate as a pioneer in smart mobility. We will continue our pioneering role in creating new opportunities by regulating and operating drones and paving the way for the introduction of various emerging and promising technologies in the field of aviation in cooperation with government and private entities, and applying the best international practices to ensure the safety of air operations and using the latest technologies to enhance the efficiency of advanced logistics services.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Khalfan Belhoul, CEO of Dubai Future Foundation, stressed that this achievement embodies the forward-thinking vision of the leadership and Dubai&rsquo;s commitment to design and execute the future. It also reflects Dubai&rsquo;s remarkable successes in developing advanced infrastructure and creating integrated systems to support the growth of smart mobility, delivery, and logistics services over the past years.</p>

<p>Belhoul noted, &ldquo;The Dubai Future Foundation is committed to collaborating with public and private entities, in line with H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed&rsquo;s directives to accelerate progress in vital economic and future sectors.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;We will continue to work with our partners through various projects, programmes, and initiatives, such as the &#39;Dubai Program to Enable Drone Transportation,&#39; the &#39;Dubai Robotics and Automation Program,&#39; and the &#39;Dubai Research, Development, and Innovation Programme&#39;. This aligns with our mission to reinforce Dubai&rsquo;s position as one of the world&rsquo;s most future-ready cities,&rdquo; Belhoul added.</p>

<p>Dr. Yinian Mao, VP of Meituan and President of Keeta Drone, the overseas arm of the drone delivery unit of Meituan, a leading tech-driven retail company in China, said, &ldquo;Our venture in the Middle East aligns with the parent company&rsquo;s growth strategy. We are excited to have an ideal partner such as Dubai Integrated Economic Zones Authority that offers businesses and investors three economic zones of choice to ensure the right platform to establish and grow in this region. Through our presence in Dubai Silicon Oasis, we are keen to bring drone delivery solutions to its community and look forward to expanding the initiative across Dubai, and the wider region.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Dr. Yousef Al-Assaf, President of Rochester Institute of Technology in Dubai, said, &ldquo;We are proud to forge a unique partnership with diverse public and private sector entities in the project to test, implement and launch the first drone delivery system in the Middle East, from Dubai Silicon Oasis, which consolidates its position as a hub for future technologies. The participation of RIT-Dubai, headquartered in DSO, in this pioneering project enables it to develop its academic competencies, empower local talent, and provide a world-class academic and research laboratory environment.&rdquo;</p>

<p>With the aid of cutting-edge flight control algorithms and multi-sensor fusion positioning technology, the drone is designed to operate in various city landscapes. It is equipped with low-noise propellers, a parachute, and a flight control system, all developed in-house.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 23:32:50 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735895.1734463957!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735895.1734463957!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed launches Middle East’s first-of-its-kind drone delivery system at Dubai Silicon Oasis]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Technology</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Technology</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[INOI Unveils Three New Smartphones at Semi-Annual Conference]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/inoi-unveils-three-new-smartphones-at-semi-annual-conference-2024-12-15-1.735848</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/inoi-unveils-three-new-smartphones-at-semi-annual-conference-2024-12-15-1.735848</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>INOI, a leading European mobile technology brand, unveiled three new smartphones during its semi-annual partner&rsquo;s conference.</p>

<p>The A35 ADVENTURE, A55 SPECTRE 5G, and A75 ELEGANCE are designed to meet the diverse needs of smartphone users, offering the perfect balance of performance, image quality, distinctive design, and long-lasting power.</p>

<p>&quot;These new models truly emphasize our brand philosophy of combining functionality with distinctive design features. A prime example is the launch of our signature purple-colored power button, which also doubles as the fingerprint sensor,&quot; said Per Ekman, Chief Commercial Officer. &quot; &#39;Purple Power&#39; will be the motto of the new line-up.&quot;</p>

<p>Each smartphone comes with a market-first 777- day international warranty, underscoring INOI&#39;s commitment to reliability.</p>

<p><strong>A35 ADVENTURE: The Mid-Range Game Changer</strong></p>

<p>Targeting the mid-range market, the A35 ADVENTURE offers exceptional value with high-end features. Equipped with a powerful 50MP AI rear camera and a display boasting a 90Hz refresh rate, this device guarantees stunning photos and smooth visuals.</p>

<p><strong>A55 SPECTRE 5G: Budget-friendly 5G Connectivity</strong></p>

<p>The A55 SPECTRE 5G offers fast and reliable 5G connectivity at an accessible price. The 50MP AI camera supports 4K video recording at 60FPS, ensuring high-quality content creation.</p>

<p><strong>A75 ELEGANCE: Premium Performance for Power Users</strong></p>

<p>For those seeking premium performance, the A75 ELEGANCE combines luxury with functionality. Powered by the flagship MediaTek G99 platform, this device offers extraordinary speed and multitasking capabilities. With up to 512GB of internal storage, users can store more photos, videos, and files without compromise. Additionally, 33W fast charging and a long-lasting 5000mAh battery ensure the A75 ELEGANCE keeps users powered up and ready for anything. With a 50MP AI main camera and a 24MP front camera featuring AI capabilities, users can capture breathtaking shots in any lighting or environment.</p>

<p>The A35 ADVENTURE, A55 SPECTRE 5G, and A75 ELEGANCE will be available starting January 2025 at retailers and online stores.</p>

<p><strong>About INOI</strong></p>

<p>INOI is a European electronics brand focused on the development and production of modern mobile devices. It offers a wide range of innovative smartphones, tablets, and feature phones, all running Android.</p>

<p>INOI&rsquo;s operational headquarters are in Dubai, UAE, with its marketing and design center based in Nice, France. The company believes in the transformative power of innovation and technology, constantly striving to provide its customers with the best products and an exceptional user experience.</p>

<p>With over 30 years of experience in the market, INOI understands the needs of both distributors and end customers, offering favorable conditions and comprehensive support to ensure seamless, professional collaboration.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:52:48 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735850.1734256347!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735850.1734256347!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735850.1734256347!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735849.1734256332!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[INOI Unveils Three New Smartphones at Semi-Annual Conference]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Technology</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Technology</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[How The HONOR X9c Brings Superior Durability and Performance to Tackle Everyday Challenges]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/how-the-honor-x9c-brings-superior-durability-and-performance-to-tackle-everyday-challenges-2024-11-29-1.735673</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/how-the-honor-x9c-brings-superior-durability-and-performance-to-tackle-everyday-challenges-2024-11-29-1.735673</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p><strong><em>From sophisticated design and engineering to innovative AI experiences, the HONOR X9c breaks new ground for mid-tier smartphones</em></strong></p>
</blockquote>

<p>HONOR&rsquo;s latest flagship, <strong><a href="https://www.honor.com/ae-en/phones/honor-x9c/buy/?utm_source=PRLEN&amp;utm_medium=pr&amp;utm_campaign=honorx24c&amp;utm_content=PRL">the HONOR X9c</a></strong>, is a pinnacle of innovation that redefines smartphone durability in incredible new ways. Designed with performance and survivability in mind, the HONOR X9c delivers a smartphone experience like no other, serving as a testament to the pioneering features that define HONOR&rsquo;s Series X smartphones. With impressive new durability features, the HONOR X9c is ready to accompany you wherever life takes you, and delivers outstanding performance and battery life to ensure that you&rsquo;re always connected to the world around you and beyond.</p>

<p>The HONOR X9c speaks volumes of HONOR&rsquo;s commitment to innovation in the mid-range smartphone segment by introducing features that would normally be found on high-end, flagship models. In doing this, the HONOR X9c positions itself as a truly reliable and versatile smartphone that delivers exceptional performance even in the most challenging conditions.</p>

<p><strong>Built To Overcome Life&rsquo;s Challenges</strong></p>

<p>Durability is key for the HONOR X9c, and its precision engineering and innovative safety features make it an ideal smartphone for users who want complete peace of mind with their smartphones. An example is HONOR&rsquo;s Anti-Drop Display, which is engineered to withstand drops from heights up to 2 meters. It also offers 60% greater glass impact resistance and a 52% increase in corner impact resilience over previous models, ensuring that any accidental drops never jeopardize the integrity of the smartphone.</p>

<p>The HONOR X9c is also engineered to withstand extreme conditions that would otherwise be problematic for regular smartphones. From intense temperatures to hazards such as dust and water, most smartphones would stop functioning properly or begin to experience performance issues. However, since the HONOR X9c is equipped with IP65M water and dust resistance and a three-layer waterproof structure, neither accidental water exposure nor environmental elements can compromise this smartphone. In fact, the HONOR X9c can be submerged in up to 25cm of water for a short period without compromising its performance, and can even handle extreme temperatures ranging from 30C to -55C.</p>

<p>It&#39;s common to think that a durable smartphone requires a rugged or bulky design to be effective, but the HONOR X9c dispels that myth with its sleek and attractive design. Weighing just 189g and measuring 7.98mm in thickness, the HONOR X9c is ultra-slim, making it easy to carry and comfortable to hold. It fits easily into pockets or bags without being cumbersome, and the sleek titanium finish gives it a premium look and feel.</p>

<p><strong>Battery Life That Never Lets You Down</strong></p>

<p>One of the most crucial features of any smartphone is its battery life, and here too the HONOR X9c sets a new standard in its segment. Equipped with the industry&rsquo;s first 6600mAh Silicon-carbon battery, the HONOR X9c can provide up to 3 days of usage on a single charge and is a game-changer for users who use their smartphones throughout the day. Whether it&rsquo;s streaming content, gaming, or staying connected longer, the HONOR X9c is able to provide unmatched battery life without having to reach for a charger. When it does come time for a recharge, the 66W wired HONOR SuperCharge can quickly bring the phone battery up to a full charge, and also supports an ultra-fast charging mode for quicker recharging.</p>

<p><strong>An Unmatched User Experience With MagicOS 8.0</strong></p>

<p>Beyond its remarkable design and durability, the HONOR X9c offers an intuitive user experience, thanks to AI-powered MagicOS 8.0. A variety of unique features work together to streamline everyday tasks, allowing users to focus on what matters most. For example, Magic Portal can understand the context of what is on a user&rsquo;s screen and offer helpful suggestions and shortcuts. By simply dragging content onto Magic Portal, users can get directions or product recommendations without having to go through multiple manual steps.</p>

<p>When it comes to photography, the HONOR X9c&rsquo;s world-class hardware is further enhanced by AI features, capturing timeless moments that redefine smartphone photography. The powerful, 108MP Ultra-sensing Camera is capable of capturing vivid and well-exposed images under any lighting conditions, even in challenging low-light environments. To further capture remarkable photos, the HONOR X9c is equipped with AI Motion Sensing to identify diverse scenarios using an AI network trained on a database of over 8 million images. It can then automatically detect movement in a scene and adjust camera settings automatically to capture blur-free and crisp images every time.</p>

<p>In addition to this, the AI Eraser feature allows users to quickly edit their photos to remove any unwanted elements from their photos. With a single click, users can remove people, objects, or other distractions from the background to create a professional-looking image in seconds. This is especially useful for travellers wanting to capture stunning vistas as cleanly as possible. Whether you&rsquo;re a professional at smartphone photography or a novice, the camera and AI tools on the HONOR X9c make it extremely easy to make every photograph a stunning masterpiece.</p>

<p><strong>Exceptional Visuals On A Stunning Display</strong></p>

<p>The HONOR X9c is designed to offer an elevated viewing experience, starting with its vivid 6.78-inch Eye-comfort OLED Display. With an industry-leading peak HDR brightness of 4000nits, the HONOR X9c can be viewed comfortably even in bright sunlight, offering outstanding visibility. Supporting 1.07 billion colors and a 1.5K resolution, images and content look bright and crisp, providing an immersive viewing experience for gaming, watching videos, and much more.</p>

<p>To ensure that eye fatigue is minimized, the HONOR X9c&rsquo;s display provides a high refresh rate of 120Hz, ensuring smooth motion and enhanced responsiveness throughout the interface. The 3840Hz Risk-free PWM Dimming also helps to minimize screen flickering, further reducing eye strain during extended periods of use. Lastly, the Circadian Night Display automatically adjusts the display to a warmer tone to decrease blue light emission and enhance sleep quality. In conjunction with Dynamic Dimming technology to promote effective ciliary muscle engagement, the HONOR X9c puts user safety and comfort above all, ensuring a comfortable viewing experience throughout the day.</p>

<p>The HONOR X9c confirms HONOR&rsquo;s commitment to crafting innovative and stylish products that continue to add value to users&rsquo; lives. With a host of intelligent AI features and a durable yet lightweight design, the HONOR X9c challenges all the norms of a mid-range smartphone, and offers exceptional features that effortlessly balances functionality with style. For users who need a smartphone that can keep up with their rigorous lifestyles and demanding routines, the HONOR X9c is an easy investment to make, and will no doubt be the benchmark for other smartphones to aspire to.</p>

<p>The HONOR X9c is available in four captivating colors - Titanium Purple, Titanium Black, Sunrise Orange, and Jade Cyan <a href="https://www.honor.com/ae-en/phones/honor-x9c/buy/?utm_source=PRLEN&amp;utm_medium=pr&amp;utm_campaign=honorx24c&amp;utm_content=PRL">at a price of AED 1299. Upon purchase, consumers will get free gifts worth AED 398 including HONOR Choice Earbuds X5, HONOR Care 12-month Accidental Damage Protection.</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 10:51:17 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735676.1732863113!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735676.1732863113!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735676.1732863113!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735675.1732863089!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735674.1732863048!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[How The HONOR X9c Brings Superior Durability and Performance to Tackle Everyday Challenges]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Technology</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Technology</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[HONOR Announces Pre-Orders for HONOR X9c – The Unbreakable AI Smartphone]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/honor-announces-pre-orders-for-honor-x9c-the-unbreakable-ai-smartphone-2024-11-21-1.735537</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/honor-announces-pre-orders-for-honor-x9c-the-unbreakable-ai-smartphone-2024-11-21-1.735537</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<ul>
	<li><strong>With unmatched durability, all-day battery life, and AI-powered photography, the HONOR X9c delivers a user experience without compromise</strong></li>
</ul>

<p>Global technology brand HONOR is announced the pre-order of the latest addition to the HONOR X Series, <a href="https://www.honor.com/ae-en/phones/honor-x9c/buy/?utm_source=Emirates247&amp;utm_medium=pr&amp;utm_campaign=honorx11c&amp;utm_content=general" target="_blank"><strong>the HONOR X9c. This Unbreakable AI Smartphone</strong></a> builds on the success of its predecessor while also introducing several industry-first features, HONOR X9c and innovative drop, water and heat resistance features, making the HONOR X9c a compelling investment for anyone seeking a smartphone that can withstand the wear and tear of daily life.</p>

<p>In addition, HONOR X9c is designed to elevate the user experience with a host of innovative AI features powered by MagicOS 8.0. With AI Magic Portal, users can enjoy seamless navigation as the device intelligently directs them to the right apps.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Furthermore, the camera is enhanced with AI Motion Sensing, allowing for precise capture of dynamic moments. The AI Eraser further simplifies photo editing by effortlessly removing unwanted elements from images. Together, these features make the HONOR X9c an ideal choice for users who value cutting-edge technology and a more intuitive smartphone experience.</p>

<p>The HONOR X9c is available for pre-order in four captivating colors - Titanium Purple, Titanium Black, Sunrise Orange, and Jade Cyan. Consumers can pre-order HONOR X9c via HONOR Online Store, HONOR Experience Store, Sharaf DG, Emax, Jumbo, Noon, Amazon, Virgin Megastore, Etisalat by e&amp;, Carrefour, Ecity and other retail shops at a price of AED 1299. Upon pre-order, consumers will get free gifts worth AED 497 including HONOR Choice Earbuds X5, HONOR Care 12-month Accidental Damage Protection and HONOR Talents Case.</p>

<p><strong>Durability Without Compromise That Built to Last</strong></p>

<p>The HONOR X9c raises the bar for smartphone durability with its next generation of HONOR Drop-Resistant Design. Enhanced with ultra-tempered glass and advanced protective shields, the HONOR X9c can withstand drops from heights up to 2 meters . This makes the HONOR X9c the perfect choice for users looking for a durable, everyday device that offers flagship durability features but on a friendly budget.&nbsp;</p>

<p>With an impressive operational range, the battery can perform exceptionally well even in temperatures spanning from -30&deg;C to 55&deg;C . Adding to this, it also features IP65M water and dust resistance&nbsp; and a three-layer waterproof structure to keep out dust and dirt. Capable of remaining fully functional even after submersion in water up to 25cm deep for 5 minutes , the HONOR X9c easily resists water damage and accidental splashes, making it the perfect companion for outdoor explorers who need a smartphone that can keep up with their adventures.</p>

<p>Achieving the Five-Star comprehensive reliability certification from Switzerland&rsquo;s SGS , the HONOR X9c is distinguished by its outstanding smartphone protection, highlighting HONOR&rsquo;s dedication to quality and durability in every device.</p>

<p><strong>Intelligent Smartphone Photography, Enhanced by AI</strong></p>

<p>Equipped with incredible AI features, the HONOR X9c redefines the smartphone photography experience, giving users powerful tools to refine their photographs into stunning shots every time. HONOR AI Motion Sensing helps to capture sharp, dynamic photographs of subjects in motion with incredible precision, and intelligently identifies scenes using an AI network trained on over 8 million images. From sports days to gatherings with friends, it&rsquo;s never been easier to capture life&rsquo;s moments in vivid detail.</p>

<p>For moments when a captured photograph contains unintended distractions, HONOR&rsquo;s AI Eraser can be used to quickly remove unwanted elements with a single click. Whether it&rsquo;s background pedestrians or unappealing graffiti on a building, AI Eraser can seamlessly erase objects while intelligently filling in the background to complete the image. These AI features not only improve photographs, but also simplify the editing process, ensuring that every special moment is captured in the best way possible.</p>

<p><strong>All-Day Battery Life for Ultimate Endurance</strong></p>

<p>The HONOR X9c introduces the industry&rsquo;s first 6600mAh Silicon-carbon battery, which provides users with extended power for all of their needs throughout the day. On a single charge, users can enjoy up to 48.4 hours of music streaming and 25.8 hours of online video playback , making the HONOR X9c the perfect choice for those who enjoy consuming content on the go. When the battery drops to 2%, the AI Superpower Saving Mode maintains continuous calls for up to 50 minutes , ensuring essential communication is not interrupted. When it&rsquo;s time to recharge, the 66W wired HONOR SuperCharge&nbsp; can quickly bring the phone battery up to a full charge, and users can activate the ultra-fast charging mode for even faster recharging.&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 11:26:16 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735540.1732173842!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735540.1732173842!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735540.1732173842!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735539.1732173826!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735538.1732173802!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[HONOR Announces Pre-Orders for HONOR X9c – The Unbreakable AI Smartphone]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Technology</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Technology</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Latifa bint Mohammed opens ‘Dubai Future Solutions – Prototypes for Humanity’ initiative]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/latifa-bint-mohammed-opens-dubai-future-solutions-prototypes-for-humanity-initiative-2024-11-18-1.735485</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/latifa-bint-mohammed-opens-dubai-future-solutions-prototypes-for-humanity-initiative-2024-11-18-1.735485</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Her Highness Sheikha Latifa bint Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Chairperson of Dubai Culture and Arts Authority (Dubai Culture), officially opened the &lsquo;Dubai Future Solutions &ndash; Prototypes for Humanity&rsquo; initiative. This transformative programme, approved by His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defence of the UAE, and Chairman of the Board of Trustees of the Dubai Future Foundation, reflects the emirate&rsquo;s commitment to excellence, creativity, and innovation in the service of humanity.<br />
The initiative, held in partnership with the Dubai Future Foundation, seeks to drive positive societal change by leveraging innovative projects initiated by enterprising university students and distinguished academics to address complex global challenges. Bringing together one of the most diverse assemblies of academic talent and innovation, the initiative will witness participation from elite professors and university students from leading institutions worldwide, who presented the top 100 projects offering practical solutions to critical challenges facing our planet and societies. The event is taking place on the sidelines of the 2024 Dubai Future Forum at the Museum of the Future on 19 and 20 November, bringing together over 2,500 experts and 100 international institutions specialising in future foresight and design.</p>

<p>Her Highness Sheikha Latifa expressed her pride in the groundbreaking achievements and creative solutions for global challenges that came about courtesy of the &lsquo;Prototypes for Humanity&rsquo; initiative over the past decade. She highlighted that expanding the initiative, an Art Dubai Group enterprise, through &lsquo;Dubai Future Solutions &ndash; Prototypes for Humanity,&rsquo; further strengthens its contribution to nurturing innovation and serving societies.</p>

<ul>
	<li>Empowering forum</li>
</ul>

<p>Her Highness said: &ldquo;Today, we celebrate a decade of innovation &ndash; a journey defined by continuing efforts to advance scientific research, mobilise visionary ideas, and transform them into impactful, pioneering solutions to address some of the world&rsquo;s most pressing challenges. This initiative reflects our dedication to shaping the future, providing a global platform for creators and innovators to drive meaningful change. It also inspires the development and acceleration of transformative technologies, supports entrepreneurship, empowers individuals, and harnesses talent to serve humanity, all while contributing to the overarching goals of comprehensive and sustainable development.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Her Highness added: &ldquo;I am proud to witness generations of young innovators from international universities and institutions across academic, cultural, technological, and creative fields who have harnessed knowledge to develop innovative solutions aimed at serving humanity, and we hope to support their growth from Dubai.&rdquo;<br />
The initiative attracted 2,700 applications from over 800 universities worldwide. During the event, the top five exceptional innovators will be announced and honoured with awards totalling AED 360,000, enabling them to further advance their research in vital fields.</p>

<p><strong>Exhibition celebrates pioneers</strong></p>

<p>Sheikha Latifa inaugurated the &lsquo;Dubai Future Solutions &ndash; Prototypes for Humanity&rsquo; 2024 exhibition, which showcases cutting-edge innovations and breakthrough projects in key domains such as healthcare, energy, society, nature, and data science. These creative projects lay the foundation for a robust infrastructure that supports Dubai&rsquo;s status as a global hub for innovation and future opportunities.</p>

<p>Her Highness also hosted a meeting, bringing together government officials, decision-makers and experts, including His Excellency Saeed Al Tayer &ndash; Managing Director and CEO of Dubai Electricity and Water Authority; His Excellency Dawood Al Hajri &ndash; Director General of Dubai Municipality; His Excellency Awad Saqr Al Ketbi &ndash; Director General of the Dubai Health Authority; His Excellency Dr. Amer Sharif &ndash; CEO of Dubai Health and President of Mohammed bin Rashid University of Medicine and Health Sciences; Her Excellency Hala Badri &ndash; Director General of Dubai Culture and Arts Authority; His Excellency Khalfan Belhoul &ndash; CEO of Dubai Future Foundation; as well as investors, entrepreneurs, and pioneers who advanced groundbreaking concepts. The discussions focused on adopting and transforming these creative solutions into successful, impactful projects.</p>

<ul>
	<li>Key partners</li>
</ul>

<p>Key partners in the &lsquo;Dubai Future Solutions &ndash; Prototypes for Humanity&rsquo; initiative include Dubai Culture and Arts Authority, the Dubai Future Foundation, the Dubai International Financial Centre, and the Hussain Sajwani &ndash; DAMAC Foundation, which has committed<br />
AED100 million to advance innovation and technology in Dubai, further driving progress and impact.</p>

<p>His Excellency Khalfan Belhoul, CEO of Dubai Future Foundation, said: &ldquo;The Dubai Future Solutions &ndash; Prototypes for Humanity programme offers an unparalleled platform for young innovators to showcase their transformative ideas alongside the annual Dubai Future Forum, reinforcing Dubai&rsquo;s commitment to fostering global solutions. With the invaluable leadership of Her Highness Sheikha Latifa and the support of a diverse network of partners, we&rsquo;re driving impactful change through collaboration, empowering the next generation to address critical challenges with creativity and vision.&rdquo;<br />
Arif Amiri, Chief Executive Officer of the DIFC Authority and Chairman of the Board of Art Dubai said: &ldquo;This year&rsquo;s Prototypes for Humanity programme is truly inspirational and demonstrates how young innovators are creating a better world by developing creative solutions to global challenges. As a founding partner, DIFC&rsquo;s longstanding support for Prototypes for Humanity underscores our commitment to solidifying Dubai&rsquo;s reputation as a global hub for innovation, where the brightest minds can come together to build a more responsible and sustainable future.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Hussain Sajwani, Founder and Chairman of DAMAC, said: &ldquo;Our partnership with the Dubai Future Foundation aligns with the vision of the emirate&rsquo;s leadership to establish the city as a global hub for creativity and technology. The &lsquo;Dubai Future Solutions &ndash; Prototypes for Humanity&rsquo; initiative is a significant milestone in realising these aspirations, and at DAMAC, we are honoured to collaborate with the Foundation on programmes that attract top talent and expertise towards unlocking their potential to serve humanity, reflecting our commitment to enhancing quality of life and addressing the needs of future generations. We firmly believe that innovation and technology are the keys to advancing nations and shaping a sustainable, prosperous future.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Taddeu Baldani Caravieri, Director of the &lsquo;Prototypes for Humanity&rsquo; initiative, said: &lsquo;Whilst the Prototypes for Humanity programme has grown significantly over the past ten years, its guiding principle has always been to shine a light and empower the best ideas that help make for a better tomorrow. We are delighted to have so many innovators present here today and with the support of our invaluable network of partners we look forward to seeing them thrive in Dubai and beyond.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The &lsquo;Dubai Future Solutions &ndash; Prototypes for Humanity&rsquo; initiative aims to identify and enable projects that can comprehensively address critical issues and seeks to collaborate with distinguished graduates and professors from more than 800 global universities. Students and academics across diverse disciplines showcased innovations in agriculture, healthcare, energy, civil society, mobility, water and the environment.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 19:30:00 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735486.1731990611!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735486.1731990611!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Latifa bint Mohammed opens ‘Dubai Future Solutions – Prototypes for Humanity’ initiative]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed meets with Linda Yaccarino, CEO of X Corp]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/hamdan-bin-mohammed-meets-with-linda-yaccarino-ceo-of-x-corp-2024-11-14-1.735416</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/hamdan-bin-mohammed-meets-with-linda-yaccarino-ceo-of-x-corp-2024-11-14-1.735416</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong>His Highness: Dubai and the UAE continue to build mutually beneficial cooperation with leading players in the digital media industry&nbsp;</strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defence of the UAE, and Chairman of The Executive Council of Dubai, held a meeting with Linda Yaccarino, CEO of X Corp. (formerly Twitter), at The Executive Office in Emirates Towers in Dubai.</p>

<p>His Highness&rsquo;s meeting with the CEO of one of the world&rsquo;s largest social media platforms underlines the UAE and Dubai&rsquo;s commitment to forging partnerships with leading global technology companies, as part of its goal of consolidating its status as an international hub for future-focused innovations.</p>

<p>HH Sheikh Hamdan said Dubai and the UAE continue to build mutually beneficial cooperation with leading players in the digital media industry and explore synergies that align with the country&rsquo;s goal to bring about digital transformation across various spheres of life. Highlighting the goal of the Dubai Economic Agenda D33 to generate AED100 billion in annual economic value through digital transformation over the next decade, His Highness said X is a valuable partner in the country&rsquo;s efforts to drive innovation and adoption of new technologies.&nbsp;</p>

<p>HH Sheikh Hamdan further said X&#39;s vision to transform itself into an all-in-one digital hub creates unique complementarities with the UAE&rsquo;s focus on AI and other advanced technologies. Having established itself as the region&rsquo;s media epicentre over two decades, Dubai offers a unique platform for international companies seeking to innovate and expand their business. With around 4,000 media and tech companies forming a vibrant industry ecosystem, Dubai not only provides a supportive infrastructure but also serves as a launchpad for pioneering initiatives. The city offers the ideal base for the world&rsquo;s leading companies to introduce groundbreaking services, drive technological advancements, and set new benchmarks in digital engagement in the region and beyond, His Highness said.</p>

<p>The meeting explored potential partnerships aligned with the UAE and X&rsquo;s shared commitment to innovation and digital transformation. As the UAE looks toward the future with ambitious growth and digital transformation goals, HH Sheikh Hamdan expressed confidence in having X as a long-term partner. &ldquo;We are excited to explore how this partnership can create lasting value for both the UAE and X, setting an example for impactful collaboration between a global technology leader and one of the world&rsquo;s most future-ready nations,&rdquo; he added.</p>

<p>X (formerly Twitter) opened its first office in the Middle East and North Africa region in Dubai in 2015. The region is home to some of the company&rsquo;s largest markets. The company had 250 million daily active users as of mid-2024.</p>

<p>The meeting was attended by His Excellency Omar Sultan Al Olama, Minister of State for Artificial Intelligence, Digital Economy, and Remote Work Applications, and Director General of the Dubai Crown Prince&#39;s Office.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 19:10:10 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735417.1731596892!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735417.1731596892!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed meets with Linda Yaccarino, CEO of X Corp]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Technology</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Technology</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE hosts global cyber diplomacy training programme for women]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/uae-hosts-global-cyber-diplomacy-training-programme-for-women-2024-11-14-1.735413</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/uae-hosts-global-cyber-diplomacy-training-programme-for-women-2024-11-14-1.735413</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;The General Women&#39;s Union (GWU), in collaboration with the International Telecommunication Union and the UAE Cybersecurity Council, on Wednesday wrapped up a two-day international training programme aimed at empowering women in cybersecurity governance and diplomacy.</p>

<p>The programme, held at GWU&#39;s headquarters, was held under the patronage of H.H. Sheikha Fatima bint Mubarak (Mother of the Nation), Chairwoman of the General Women&#39;s Union, President of the Supreme Council for Motherhood and Childhood, and Supreme Chairwoman of the Family Development Foundation (FDF).</p>

<p>The &quot;International Programme for Training Women Trainers in the Arab Region and the World&quot; brought together women participants from 22 countries across the Arab region and beyond.</p>

<p>The initiative targeted female policymakers in cybersecurity, professionals involved in peace and security initiatives, and women in technical fields seeking to broaden their skills to transition into strategic roles in cybersecurity policy and cyber diplomacy.</p>

<p>Through theoretical and hands-on training, the programme provided essential tools and facilitation techniques to equip women with the knowledge needed to become trainers and leaders in national cybersecurity governance.</p>

<p>Topics covered included an overview of current cybersecurity threats, the implications of AI risks, and guidelines on national resilience strategies addressing legal, regulatory, and technical dimensions.</p>

<p>Participants also gained insights into developing national cybersecurity strategies, engaging key stakeholders, and understanding the international landscape of cyber diplomacy. The programme reviewed ongoing UN discussions on cybersecurity and explored global standards for state conduct in cyberspace.</p>

<p>Noura Al Suwaidi, GWU&#39;s Secretary-General, highlighted the UAE&#39;s leading role in cybersecurity at regional and global levels, stressing the importance of empowering women in technology and policy to build a secure digital environment that protects national achievements. She attributed this progress to the UAE&#39;s visionary leadership and the support of Sheikha Fatima bint Mubarak.</p>

<p>Dr. Mohammed Hamad Al-Kuwaiti, Chairman of the UAE Cybersecurity Council, commended the programme&#39;s success, calling it a milestone in the shared mission to empower women in cybersecurity. He thanked H.H. Sheikha Fatima for her unwavering support and emphasised that her guidance continues to drive advancements in the field.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 11:52:45 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735414.1731570723!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735414.1731570723!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE hosts global cyber diplomacy training programme for women]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Technology</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Technology</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Get Ready for the Next Evolution in Durability with The Unbreakable AI Smartphone Soon]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/get-ready-for-the-next-evolution-in-durability-with-the-unbreakable-ai-smartphone-soon-2024-11-14-1.735404</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/get-ready-for-the-next-evolution-in-durability-with-the-unbreakable-ai-smartphone-soon-2024-11-14-1.735404</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>HONOR has always been at the forefront of smartphone innovation, and the HONOR X9 Series is a testament to this commitment. The HONOR X9b series was a breakthrough for HONOR, introducing the world to an unbreakable smartphone that set new standards in durability. This hero product allowed HONOR to significantly increase its market share globally, with an impressive +80% sale out increase in the Middle East and Africa (MEA) compared to the X9a.</p>

<p>The success of the HONOR X9b series not only solidified HONOR&#39;s reputation for quality and innovation but also significantly boosted its market share. The X9b&#39;s unbreakable design captured the attention of consumers worldwide, particularly in the MEA region, where the demand for robust and reliable devices is high. This success has strengthened HONOR&#39;s brand presence and loyalty among consumers, positioning it as a leader in the durable mid-range smartphone segment.</p>

<p><strong>Introducing the HONOR X9c: The Unbreakable AI Smartphone</strong></p>

<p>Building on this legacy, the HONOR X9c is set to take durability to new heights. The new addition to the series, the Unbreakable AI Smartphone HONOR X9c, not only increases drop resistance but also offers extreme temperature and water resistance. With a better screen, a bigger battery, and faster supercharge capabilities. Powered with Ai, the HONOR X9c is designed to meet the demands of modern life.</p>

<p><strong>Triple-Resistant Durability</strong></p>

<p>A survey by <a href="https://www.statista.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Statista </strong></a>found that 68% of smartphone users consider durability as a key factor when purchasing a new device. The HONOR X9c 5G is triple-resistant to drops, heat, and water, earning the prestigious SGS Gold Label certification for durability. This certification ensures that the HONOR X9c provides a more reliable and trustworthy smartphone experience against accidental damages. Whether you are an adventurer, a professional, or an everyday user, the HONOR X9c is engineered to withstand life&#39;s toughest challenges.</p>

<p><strong>Revolutionary AI Features</strong></p>

<p>The HONOR X9c also brings a host of incredible AI features that make life easier by addressing users&#39; pain points. From the HONOR AI Motion Sensing feature that captures the perfect photo every time to the AI Eraser function that removes unwanted background distractions, the HONOR X9c is designed to enhance your daily life.</p>

<p>The introduction of the HONOR X9c is expected to further solidify HONOR&#39;s position in the mid-range smartphone segment. By offering a device that combines exceptional durability with cutting-edge AI features, HONOR aims to attract a broader audience, including professionals, adventurers, and everyday users who require a reliable and robust smartphone.</p>

<p>The HONOR X9c&#39;s competitive pricing and innovative features are designed to appeal to cost-conscious consumers without compromising on quality. This strategy is expected to drive higher sales volumes and increase market penetration, particularly in emerging markets where durability and affordability are key factors in purchasing decisions.</p>

<p>Catering to users&rsquo; diverse style preferences, the HONOR X9c will be available in four captivating colourways: Titanium Purple, Sunrise Orange, Titanium Black, and Jade Cyan. Pre-orders in the UAE will start November 22nd, and exciting gifts will be available for early buyers, to be the first to experience the incredible durability and innovative AI features of the HONOR X9c.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 10:44:27 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735406.1731566633!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735406.1731566633!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735406.1731566633!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735405.1731566613!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Get Ready for the Next Evolution in Durability with The Unbreakable AI Smartphone Soon]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Technology</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Technology</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Digital Dubai receives the Certificate of Excellence in Ideas and Innovation Management from the British IdeasUK Foundation]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/digital-dubai-receives-the-certificate-of-excellence-in-ideas-and-innovation-management-from-the-british-ideasuk-foundation-2024-11-14-1.735384</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/digital-dubai-receives-the-certificate-of-excellence-in-ideas-and-innovation-management-from-the-british-ideasuk-foundation-2024-11-14-1.735384</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>- In Recognition of Establishing a Culture of Innovation and Creative Thinking ..Digital Dubai receives the Certificate of Excellence in Ideas and Innovation Management from the British IdeasUK Foundation</p>

<p>&quot;Digital Dubai has added a new milestone to its record of achievements in adopting innovative work systems that align with future requirements and contribute to strategic goals. The Authority has been awarded the Gold Level Certificate of Excellence in Idea Management and Innovation by IdeasUK, a British institution renowned for assessing organizational capabilities in idea management and fostering a culture of innovation globally. This recognition underscores Digital Dubai&rsquo;s commitment to fostering innovation and integrating its principles to enhance operations and services.&quot;</p>

<p>&nbsp;The award follows a rigorous evaluation process, comparing Digital Dubai&rsquo;s innovation approach with global best practices, and assessing Dubai&rsquo;s strengths, successes, and achievements in the field of innovation. The evaluation also recognized Digital Dubai&rsquo;s proactive approach in leveraging experiences and formulating development plans and programs to achieve its objectives, especially in establishing Dubai as a model for future cities&mdash;one that encourages creative thinking and innovation to deliver solutions and enhance the happiness of its residents.<br />
Commenting on this achievement, Maryam Almehrzi &ndash; Institutional Development Advisor at Digital Dubai, said, &ldquo;Receiving the Certificate of Excellence in Innovation Management reflects Dubai Digital&rsquo;s efforts in adopting creativity and innovation systems and encouraging the generation of ideas to develop products and projects that contribute to achieving its vision of digitizing life in Dubai by leading the digital transformation in the emirate. This accomplishment also highlights the dedication of our teams who strive tirelessly to achieve the goals of the Digital Dubai Strategy by integrating the latest technology with creative, forward-thinking ideas&quot;.</p>

<p>&quot;This achievement adds to the Authority&rsquo;s extensive record of accomplishments in innovation, including the Stevie Awards, the World Intelligence Summit, the Emirates Artificial Intelligence Award, and many others.</p>

<p>Notably, Digital Dubai remains committed to delivering innovative initiatives and projects that meet the needs of Dubai&#39;s citizens and residents, contributing to an integrated and pioneering experience in digital transformation that reinforces Dubai&rsquo;s position as a leading global city in this field.&quot;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 06:29:16 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735385.1731551320!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735385.1731551320!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Digital Dubai receives the Certificate of Excellence in Ideas and Innovation Management from the British IdeasUK Foundation]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Technology</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Technology</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Bitcoin breaks $81,000 as Trump's election turbocharges cryptocurrencies]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/bitcoin-breaks-81-000-as-trump-s-election-turbocharges-cryptocurrencies-2024-11-11-1.735287</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/bitcoin-breaks-81-000-as-trump-s-election-turbocharges-cryptocurrencies-2024-11-11-1.735287</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Cryptocurrencies rally on de-regulation expectations</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Bitcoin hits record high over $81,000</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Ether, dogecoin surge</strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>soared to a record high above $81,000 on Monday on expectations that cryptocurrencies will boom in a favourable regulatory environment following the election of Donald Trump as U.S. president and pro-crypto candidates to Congress.</p>

<p>The world&#39;s biggest and best-known cryptocurrency , has now more than doubled from the year&#39;s low of $38,505 and was last at $81,572 having earlier touched a record high of $81,899.</p>

<p>Trump embraced digital assets during his campaign, promising to make the United States the &quot;crypto capital of the planet&quot; and to accumulate a national stockpile of bitcoin.</p>

<p>Other so-called &#39;Trump trades&#39; - from U.S. stocks to shorting bonds have lost some steam since the election, but cryptocurrencies haven&#39;t paused for breath.</p>

<p>&quot;Bitcoin&#39;s Trump-pump is alive and well... with Republicans on the cusp of taking the house to confirm a red wave in Congress, it seems the crypto crowd are betting on digital-currency deregulation,&quot; said Matt Simpson, senior market analyst at City Index, referring to Republican control of both houses.</p>

<p>While Simpson warned Trump&#39;s near-term priorities are likely to lie elsewhere, crypto investors see an end to stepped-up scrutiny under U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission Chair Gary Gensler whom Trump has said he will fire.</p>

<p>The cryptocurrency industry spent more than $119 million backing pro-crypto congressional candidates and has, by and large, succeeded.</p>

<p>In Ohio, one of the crypto industry&#39;s biggest foes in Congress - Senate Banking Committee Chair Sherrod Brown was ousted, while pro-crypto candidates from both the Democratic and Republican parties won in Michigan, West Virgina, Indiana, Alabama and North Carolina.</p>

<p>Trump also unveiled a new crypto business, World Liberty Financial in September, and although details about the business, opens new tab have been scarce, investors have taken his personal interest in the sector as a friendly signal.</p>

<p>Billionaire Elon Musk, a major Trump ally, is also a proponent of cryptocurrencies.</p>

<p>Eric Trump, one of the president-elect&#39;s sons and executive vice president of his private conglomerate, The Trump Organization, is a keynote speaker at a bitcoin conference in Abu Dhabi next month, according to the event organisers.</p>

<p>Gains in cryptocurrencies have been broad. Ether rose above $3,200 for the first time in over three months on Monday and was last fetching $3,192. Dogecoin , an alternative cryptocurrency that began as a satirical critique of the 2013 crypto frenzy, was at a three-year high.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 09:46:30 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735288.1731304025!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735288.1731304025!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>Reuters </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Bitcoin breaks $81,000 as Trump's election turbocharges cryptocurrencies]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Technology</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Technology</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Nvidia surpasses $3.6 trillion market value after Trump win]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/nvidia-surpasses-3-6-trillion-market-value-after-trump-win-2024-11-08-1.735236</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/nvidia-surpasses-3-6-trillion-market-value-after-trump-win-2024-11-08-1.735236</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Shares of Nvidia (NVDA.O), opens new tab rallied to a record high on Thursday, making the chipmaker the first company in history to surpass a stock market value of $3.6 trillion as Wall Street extended a rally sparked by Donald Trump&#39;s return to the White House.<br />
The dominant AI chipmaker&#39;s shares rose 2.2%, lifted by broad investor optimism about tax cuts and lower regulations after the Republican candidate&#39;s Tuesday election victory.<br />
Nvidia&#39;s stock market value ended the day at $3.65 trillion, beating Apple&#39;s (AAPL.O), opens new tab record closing market capitalization of $3.57 trillion reached on Oct. 21, before the chipmaker on Tuesday overtook the iPhone maker as the world&#39;s most valuable company, according to LSEG data.<br />
Apple&#39;s stock rose 2.1% on Thursday, leaving it with a market value of $3.44 trillion.<br />
The S&amp;P 500 technology index (.SPLRCT), opens new tab has surged over 4% in the two sessions since Trump won the election on Tuesday.<br />
Nvidia has been the U.S. stock market&#39;s biggest winner from a race between Microsoft (MSFT.O), opens new tab, Alphabet (GOOGL.O), opens new tab and other heavyweights to build out their AI computing capacity and dominate the emerging technology.<br />
The Silicon Valley chip designer&#39;s stock has climbed 12% in November, with its value tripling so far in 2024.<br />
Following this year&#39;s surge, Nvidia now exceeds the combined value of Eli Lilly (LLY.N), opens new tab, Walmart (WMT.N), opens new tab, JPMorgan (JPM.N), opens new tab, Visa (V.N), opens new tab, UnitedHealth Group (UNH.N), opens new tab and Netflix (NFLX.O), opens new tab.<br />
Analysts on average see Nvidia increasing its quarterly revenue by over 80% to $32.9 billion when it reports its results on Nov. 20, according to LSEG.<br />
In June, Nvidia briefly became the world&#39;s most valuable company before it was overtaken by Microsoft (MSFT.O), opens new tab and Apple. The tech trio&#39;s market capitalizations have been neck-and-neck for several months.<br />
Microsoft&#39;s market value stood at nearly $3.16 trillion, with its stock up 1.25% on Thursday.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 8 Nov 2024 08:44:48 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735237.1731040966!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735237.1731040966!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>Reuters </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Nvidia surpasses $3.6 trillion market value after Trump win]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Technology</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Technology</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Cyber Security Council, Immersive Labs strengthen national defence of 25 organisations]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/cyber-security-council-immersive-labs-strengthen-national-defence-of-25-organisations-2024-11-05-1.735137</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/cyber-security-council-immersive-labs-strengthen-national-defence-of-25-organisations-2024-11-05-1.735137</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The Cyber Security Council and Immersive Labs, the leader in people-centric cyber resilience, has announced the successful completion of their recent Dubai Cyber Drill that reinforced UAE enterprises&#39; cybersecurity posture against Critical National Infrastructure (CNI) threats.</p>

<p>The event included attendees from 25 major organisations representing various sectors &ndash; from financial services and telecommunications to healthcare and government &ndash; and closed with an awards ceremony.</p>

<p>Led by world-class cyber crisis experts and featuring a keynote address by Dr. Mohamed Al Kuwaiti, Head of the UAE Cyber Security Council, the event offered executive and technical teams an unforgettable hands-on learning experience, along with best practices for building resilience against threats.</p>

<p>&quot;Our partnership with Immersive Labs to deliver dynamic, realistic cyber drills like this one supports our goal of fortifying cybersecurity and essential infrastructure throughout the nation,&quot; said Al Kuwaiti. &quot;The importance of measurable, hands-on learning across private and public sectors cannot be overstated.&quot;</p>

<p>Eyas Hawari, Immersive Labs Senior Managing Director, stated, &quot;To navigate rapidly evolving threats, we must prioritise human-centric cyber resilience and empower our people to defend critical national infrastructure. This is why our work with the Cyber Security Council and like-minded organisations is so timely and relevant.&quot;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 5 Nov 2024 15:27:50 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735138.1730806028!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735138.1730806028!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Cyber Security Council, Immersive Labs strengthen national defence of 25 organisations]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Technology</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Technology</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[ATRC Entity Unveils SteerAI: New Tech Venture Set to Transform Industrial Vehicles into Autonomous Powerhouses]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/atrc-entity-unveils-steerai-new-tech-venture-set-to-transform-industrial-vehicles-into-autonomous-powerhouses-2024-11-05-1.735135</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/atrc-entity-unveils-steerai-new-tech-venture-set-to-transform-industrial-vehicles-into-autonomous-powerhouses-2024-11-05-1.735135</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p><strong>&bull; SteerAI&rsquo;s advanced software stack and hardware kit make industrial vehicles autonomous.<br />
&bull; New venture, powered by VentureOne, the ATRC&rsquo;s commercialization arm, will begin with ground vehicles and expand to sea.</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<p>The Advanced Technology Research Council&rsquo;s (ATRC) commercialization arm, VentureOne, has officially launched SteerAI, an innovative mobility system powered by artificial intelligence designed to transform standard industrial vehicles into autonomous powerhouses.</p>

<p>Initially catering to the logistics and defense sectors, SteerAI integrates a cutting-edge hardware kit, software stack, and fleet management system, enabling autonomous ground vehicles to execute complex missions with unparalleled precision and efficiency. This technology not only saves time and resources but also enhances the safety of human workforces. SteerAI&rsquo;s advancements are the result of expertise from the Technology Innovation Institute (TII), the ATRC&rsquo;s applied research arm.</p>

<p>H.E. Faisal Al Bannai, Adviser to the UAE President and Secretary General of ATRC, remarked, &ldquo;The launch of SteerAI marks a significant milestone in establishing the UAE&rsquo;s leadership in autonomous technology. At ATRC, our vision is to continuously push the boundaries of innovation, and SteerAI exemplifies how we are translating groundbreaking research into real-world solutions that drive tangible impact.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Dr. Najwa Aaraj, CEO of TII, emphasized, &ldquo;We have not simply created an autonomous vehicle&mdash;we have developed its &lsquo;brain.&rsquo; The advanced navigation algorithms work in conjunction with cutting-edge sensors as part of an efficient, modular system that can be adapted to any vehicle, potentially transforming the way we move.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Vehicles equipped with SteerAI&rsquo;s system will operate consistently and accurately between navigation points, minimizing downtime. The software stack collaborates with corresponding sensors, enabling vehicles to swiftly respond to hazards, navigate obstacles, and function seamlessly in challenging environments and unmapped areas.</p>

<p>Beyond enabling fully autonomous mobility, SteerAI&rsquo;s software also supports remote fleet management, offering mission planning, monitoring, and data-driven analytics to optimize vehicle deployment and performance.</p>

<p>&quot;SteerAI represents a major milestone in our journey toward driving positive impact through advanced technologies,&rdquo; stated Reda Nidhakou, Acting CEO of VentureOne. &ldquo;The mobility needs in logistics and defense are intense, complex, and costly. Our vehicle-agnostic autonomous system redefines operational efficiency and precision while safeguarding companies&rsquo; most valuable assets&mdash;their people. Our mission is to leverage technology to help our partners transform their operations.&rdquo;</p>

<p>SteerAI is the second venture launched by VentureOne, following the introduction of AI71 in November 2023, which develops business solutions utilizing TII&rsquo;s Falcon generative AI models.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 5 Nov 2024 10:30:10 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735136.1730788076!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735136.1730788076!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[ATRC Entity Unveils SteerAI: New Tech Venture Set to Transform Industrial Vehicles into Autonomous Powerhouses]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Technology</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Technology</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[World's first wooden satellite, developed in Japan, heads to space]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/world-s-first-wooden-satellite-developed-in-japan-heads-to-space-2024-11-05-1.735133</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/world-s-first-wooden-satellite-developed-in-japan-heads-to-space-2024-11-05-1.735133</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The world&#39;s first wooden satellite, built by Japanese researchers, was launched into space on Tuesday, in an early test of using timber in lunar and Mars exploration.</p>

<p>LignoSat, developed by Kyoto University and homebuilder Sumitomo Forestry, will be flown to the International Space Station on a SpaceX mission, and later released into orbit about 400 km (250 miles) above the Earth.</p>

<p>Named after the Latin word for &quot;wood&quot;, the palm-sized LignoSat is tasked to demonstrate the cosmic potential of the renewable material as humans explore living in space.</p>

<p>&quot;With timber, a material we can produce by ourselves, we will be able to build houses, live and work in space forever,&quot; said Takao Doi, an astronaut who has flown on the Space Shuttle and studies human space activities at Kyoto University.</p>

<p>With a 50-year plan of planting trees and building timber houses on the moon and Mars, Doi&#39;s team decided to develop a NASA-certified wooden satellite to prove wood is a space-grade material.</p>

<p>&quot;Early 1900s airplanes were made of wood,&quot; said Kyoto University forest science professor Koji Murata. &quot;A wooden satellite should be feasible, too.&quot;</p>

<p>Wood is more durable in space than on Earth because there&#39;s no water or oxygen that would rot or inflame it, Murata added.</p>

<p>A wooden satellite also minimises the environmental impact at the end of its life, the researchers say.</p>

<p>Decommissioned satellites must re-enter the atmosphere to avoid becoming</p>

<p><strong>space debris</strong></p>

<p>. Conventional metal satellites create aluminium oxide particles during re-entry, but wooden ones would just burn up with less pollution, Doi said.</p>

<p>&quot;Metal satellites might be banned in the future,&quot; Doi said. &quot;If we can prove our first wooden satellite works, we want to pitch it to Elon Musk&#39;s SpaceX.&quot; INDUSTRIAL APPLICATION</p>

<p>The researchers found that honoki, a kind of magnolia tree native in Japan and traditionally used for sword sheaths, is most suited for spacecraft, after a 10-month experiment aboard the International Space Station.</p>

<p>LignoSat is made of honoki, using a traditional Japanese crafts technique without screws or glue.</p>

<p>Once deployed, LignoSat will stay in the orbit for six months, with the electronic components onboard measuring how wood endures the extreme environment of space, where temperatures fluctuate from -100 to 100 degrees Celsius every 45 minutes as it orbits from darkness to sunlight.</p>

<p>LignoSat will also gauge wood&#39;s ability to reduce the impact of space radiation on semiconductors, making it useful for applications such as data centre construction, said Kenji Kariya, a manager at Sumitomo Forestry Tsukuba Research Institute.</p>

<p>&quot;It may seem outdated, but wood is actually cutting-edge technology as civilisation heads to the moon and Mars,&quot; he said. &quot;Expansion to space could invigorate the timber industry.&quot;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 5 Nov 2024 10:25:37 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735134.1730787773!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735134.1730787773!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>Reuters </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[World's first wooden satellite, developed in Japan, heads to space]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Technology</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Technology</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Advancing Space Travel: The Promise of Multimode Propulsion]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/advancing-space-travel-the-promise-of-multimode-propulsion-2024-11-05-1.735131</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/advancing-space-travel-the-promise-of-multimode-propulsion-2024-11-05-1.735131</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<h3>Researchers at the University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign have made significant strides in enhancing spacecraft efficiency for lunar missions through a cutting-edge propulsion approach known as multimode propulsion. This innovative method combines both chemical high-thrust and electric low-thrust propulsion using the same propellant, aiming to optimize spacecraft operations on missions to the Moon. Funded by NASA, the team examined four real mission scenarios to demonstrate the practical applications of this technology.</h3>

<p>Aerospace engineering Ph.D. student Bryan Cline emphasized the project&#39;s groundbreaking nature: &ldquo;This is the first high-fidelity analysis of multimode mission design for lunar missions relevant to NASA, particularly utilizing CubeSats.&rdquo; By employing a standard 12-unit CubeSat, the team was able to explore various mission profiles effectively.</p>

<p>One of the primary benefits of multimode propulsion lies in its ability to significantly reduce the spacecraft&#39;s dry mass. Cline explained that utilizing a single fuel tank streamlines mass and volume, which is a distinct advantage over traditional hybrid systems that require multiple propellants. &ldquo;With multimode systems, the flexibility to switch between high-thrust and low-thrust modes allows for better maneuverability and reduced fuel consumption,&rdquo; he noted.</p>

<p>Cline&#39;s team manually determined when to employ high-thrust or low-thrust during their mission simulations, which resulted in suboptimal trajectories. To enhance this process, he developed an algorithm that automatically identifies the optimal moments to switch thrust modes, ensuring the most efficient flight path. &ldquo;We created the first indirect optimal control technique tailored for multimode mission design, enabling us to achieve specific objectives such as minimizing fuel use and transfer time,&rdquo; Cline stated.</p>

<p>The researchers successfully tested this method on both two-dimensional transfers between Earth and Mars and three-dimensional transfers to geostationary orbit. Cline highlighted the versatility of the approach: &ldquo;The method is adaptable to a wide range of mission design challenges, ensuring optimal solutions through variational calculus.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Cline remarked on the potential of multimode propulsion as an emerging technology that enhances mission capabilities. &ldquo;This advancement provides greater flexibility and adaptability, allowing for missions that were previously unattainable,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;We are at an exciting juncture for multimode propulsion, working to translate our laboratory research into practical applications that will benefit the broader space community.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 5 Nov 2024 08:57:25 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735132.1730782620!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735132.1730782620!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Advancing Space Travel: The Promise of Multimode Propulsion]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Technology</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Technology</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Seoul National University Pioneers Ultra-Low Power Neuromorphic Hardware for Advanced AI]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/seoul-national-university-pioneers-ultra-low-power-neuromorphic-hardware-for-advanced-ai-2024-11-05-1.735129</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/seoul-national-university-pioneers-ultra-low-power-neuromorphic-hardware-for-advanced-ai-2024-11-05-1.735129</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<div class="flex max-w-full flex-col flex-grow">
<div class="min-h-8 text-message flex w-full flex-col items-end gap-2 whitespace-normal break-words [.text-message+&amp;]:mt-5" data-message-author-role="assistant" data-message-id="9747b63a-a1a1-4c3e-ba26-0adde61ac212" data-message-model-slug="gpt-4o" dir="auto">
<div class="flex w-full flex-col gap-1 empty:hidden first:pt-[3px]">
<div class="markdown prose w-full break-words dark:prose-invert light">
<p>A research team from the College of Engineering at Seoul National University (SNU), headed by Professor Ho Won Jang, has achieved a breakthrough in ultra-low power neuromorphic hardware designed for artificial intelligence (AI) computation. The team&#39;s innovative hardware, which significantly reduces power consumption, is set to advance AI technology across various industries.</p>

<p>This research addresses core issues in semiconductor materials and neuromorphic devices, showing potential for large-scale, array-level technology applications. The findings were recently published in <em>Nature Nanotechnology</em>, a leading journal in the field, marking a major achievement for the research community.</p>

<p>As AI-powered applications like the Internet of Things (IoT), generative AI, and autonomous vehicles increasingly rely on massive data processing, current silicon-based computing faces challenges such as high energy demands and processing limitations. This makes the development of next-generation neuromorphic hardware&mdash;a technology that emulates the human brain&rsquo;s neural processing&mdash;a critical step forward. Unlike traditional computing, neuromorphic systems use synapse-like components to perform complex computations with energy efficiency and accuracy.</p>

<p>The SNU team focused on halide perovskite materials, previously notable for their role in solar cells and LEDs, to develop neuromorphic devices with unprecedentedly uniform ion distribution. These advanced materials, designed with hybrid organic-inorganic structures, enabled the team to achieve ultra-linear and symmetric synaptic weight control, enhancing computation accuracy and efficiency.</p>

<p>Performance testing revealed that the device could handle large datasets with an error margin below 0.08%, achieving high precision on tasks ranging from basic image recognition to complex AI inference. Collaborative studies with the University of Southern California further demonstrated that the technology could operate on ultra-low power, both at the individual device level and in arrays, reinforcing its scalability and potential impact.</p>

<p>This innovative neuromorphic hardware offers a promising solution to the escalating energy demands of AI computation. The technology is anticipated to have broad applications in fields like autonomous driving, medical diagnostics, and AI-driven industries, while fostering advancements in AI hardware and semiconductor innovations.</p>

<p>The research builds on a previous study by Dr. Seung Ju Kim and Prof. Ho Won Jang, published in <em>Materials Today</em>, with patent applications underway in South Korea and the U.S. Dr. Kim, a distinguished researcher and Seoul National University alumnus, is currently advancing this technology at the University of Southern California, working alongside American research labs to develop intelligent semiconductors for aerospace applications.</p>

<p>Seoul National University, established in 1946, is South Korea&rsquo;s premier national university and a key player in global engineering advancements, with the College of Engineering driving innovation through cutting-edge research and international collaborations.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 5 Nov 2024 08:48:57 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735130.1730782064!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735130.1730782064!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Seoul National University Pioneers Ultra-Low Power Neuromorphic Hardware for Advanced AI]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Technology</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Technology</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid attends ‘AI Retreat’]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/mohammed-bin-rashid-attends-ai-retreat-2024-11-04-1.735117</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/mohammed-bin-rashid-attends-ai-retreat-2024-11-04-1.735117</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister of the UAE and Ruler of Dubai, attended part of the &lsquo;Artificial Intelligence Retreat&rsquo; held on Day 0 of the UAE Government Annual Meetings 2024 in Abu Dhabi.</p>

<p>Setting the tone for deliberations during the retreat, His Highness stated, &ldquo;The UAE has firmly established its leadership among the world&rsquo;s most future-focused nations, securing a prominent position at the forefront of Artificial Intelligence advancements that will transform all sectors. We are committed to not only maintaining but reinforcing this leadership by building our capacities. This can be realised by strengthening infrastructure, data preparedness, and legislative frameworks, while intensifying the training and development of our national workforce, the backbone of our country&rsquo;s future.</p>

<p>&ldquo;The UAE&rsquo;s foresight and strategic planning have led to extraordinary achievements in this rapidly evolving field. We are positioned as one of the best prepared nations to seize opportunities within the sector, leveraging these advancements to elevate quality of life and accelerate economic growth and all-round development. As we have the resources and a globally competitive talent pool, our ambitions are boundless in spearheading future trends and pioneering this sector,&rdquo; His Highness added.</p>

<p>Sheikh Mohammed commended the efforts of national entities that have contributed to the success of the UAE&rsquo;s Artificial Intelligence Strategy and praised the retreat for bringing together diverse entities under one umbrella to share insights and align frameworks and plans, aiming to amplify impact and achievements in this critical domain.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mansour bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Vice President, Deputy Prime Minister and Chairman of the Presidential Court; His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defence of the UAE; His Highness Sheikh Maktoum bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, First Deputy Ruler of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Finance of the UAE; and Lieutenant General His Highness Sheikh Saif bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Prime Minister And Minister of Interior, attended the retreat.</p>

<p>Mohammed bin Abdullah Al Gergawi, Minister of Cabinet Affairs; and His Excellency Omar bin Sultan Al Olama, Minister of State for Artificial Intelligence, Digital Economy, and Remote Work Applications, were also in attendance.<br />
Chaired by Sheikh Mohammed, the meetings brought together over 500 officials from federal and local government entities, the private sector, and community institutions.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 4 Nov 2024 21:06:42 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735118.1730739907!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735118.1730739907!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid attends ‘AI Retreat’]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Technology</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Technology</category>
										
					</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
