<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
	<title>Mobile - Varieties</title>
	<link>http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-varieties-1.708781?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout</link>	
	<atom:link href="http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-varieties-1.708781?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" ></atom:link>
	<description>Varieties</description>
			        <language>en</language>
    				<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Summer Storm Sweeps through Balkan Region]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/summer-storm-sweeps-through-balkan-region-2024-07-02-1.733360</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/summer-storm-sweeps-through-balkan-region-2024-07-02-1.733360</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>A powerful storm struck several Western Balkan countries on Tuesday following days of intense heatwaves, resulting in damaged homes, uprooted trees, and streets flooded with torrential rainwaters.</p>

<p>The storm, accompanied by heavy rains, hail, and strong winds, first hit Slovenia on Monday before moving eastward to impact Croatia, Bosnia, and Serbia. Within hours, the storm caused a significant drop in temperatures.</p>

<p>Experts attribute such volatile weather patterns and unexpected storms, along with heatwaves, to human-induced climate change.</p>

<p>Footage from the affected region depicted rooftops and facades pockmarked by hail, fallen trees crushing cars, and roads transformed into rivers in Serbia&#39;s capital, Belgrade, and other cities.</p>

<p>Authorities in Slovenia reported emergency teams responding to dozens of distress calls, with winds and hailstones, some as large as eggs, shattering car windshields and damaging power lines, homes, gardens, and farms.</p>

<p>In Croatia, eastern regions suffered severe damage, prompting about 1,000 firefighters to join emergency response efforts elsewhere. A lightning strike ignited a house fire in the village of Bosnias.</p>

<p>The storm in northwest Bosnia caused power outages in several villages, while cars and homes sustained damage across the country.</p>

<p>In Belgrade, heavy rains late Monday covered streets with debris and fallen branches. Firefighters rescued stranded individuals and extinguished six lightning-caused fires.</p>

<p>State television channel RTS described a major highway segment between the north and south remaining closed until Tuesday morning.</p>

<p>Belgrade&#39;s mayor, Aleksandar Sapić, described the storms and floods as a &quot;new reality in weather,&quot; while critics blamed poor sewer maintenance and infrastructure neglect amid rampant construction.</p>

<p>Police reported one person rescued unharmed after a tree fell on their car in the town of Pe&scaron;en in northern Serbia.</p>

<p>Serbia&#39;s national airline, Air Serbia, announced flight delays due to fueling operations being suspended amidst potential lightning strikes.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 2 Jul 2024 15:51:25 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733361.1719921008!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733361.1719921008!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Summer Storm Sweeps through Balkan Region]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai Police Surprise Honest Student Among His Peers]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/dubai-police-surprise-honest-student-among-his-peers-2024-06-13-1.733233</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/dubai-police-surprise-honest-student-among-his-peers-2024-06-13-1.733233</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Al Qusais Police Station surprised a student at Omar Bin Al Khattab School with a special honour among his peers in appreciation of his honesty after he had returned a wallet containing a sum of money to its owner after finding it in the Al Muhaisnah 4 area within the jurisdiction of Al Qusais Police Station.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Colonel Jamal Ibrahim Ali, Deputy Director of Al Qusais Police Station, honoured the student, Ahmad Saleh Ali Muhammad, in the presence of Lieutenant Colonel Nasser Abdulaziz Al Khaja, Head of the Administrative Affairs Department, Lieutenant Dana Al Muhairi from the Customer Happiness Department, and the school principal, Huda Yusuf, and members of the school&#39;s teaching staff.</p>

<p>Colonel Jamal Ibrahim stated that the honouring comes within the &quot;We Reach You to Thank You&quot; initiative, which aims to honour external collaborators and partners in their places and among their peers. He praised Ahmad&#39;s honesty, good conduct, and eagerness to communicate with the police station to return the wallet and money to its owner, calling on community members to take him as a role model for honesty and integrity.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The student&#39;s mother expressed her happiness with Dubai Police honouring her son and their eagerness to do so at his school. She indicated that Ahmad did his duty by handing over the wallet to Al Qusais Police Station after her son found it so its owner could retrieve it.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the honest young boy expressed his sincere gratitude to the Dubai Police, represented by Al Qusais Police Station, stressing that this honour is a badge of pride for him among his peers at school.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 18:23:18 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733234.1718288574!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733234.1718288574!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai Police Surprise Honest Student Among His Peers]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Massive fire breaks out at oil refinery in Iraq's Erbil]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/massive-fire-breaks-out-at-oil-refinery-in-iraq-s-erbil-2024-06-13-1.733214</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/massive-fire-breaks-out-at-oil-refinery-in-iraq-s-erbil-2024-06-13-1.733214</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>A massive fire broke out at the asphalt storage facility of an oil refinery in Erbil province, northern Iraq, last night.</p>

<p>According to security sources and eyewitnesses, ten firefighting teams were deployed to control the blaze.</p>

<p>Sources at the scene indicated that thick smoke rose hundreds of metres into the air, covering a large area. Civil defence teams have cordoned off the site to prevent the fire from spreading.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 09:10:00 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733215.1718276984!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733215.1718276984!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Massive fire breaks out at oil refinery in Iraq's Erbil]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Varieties</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Varieties</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Tragic Fire in Mangaf, Kuwait: Over 35 Dead and Dozens Injured]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/tragic-fire-in-mangaf-kuwait-over-35-dead-and-dozens-injured-2024-06-12-1.733188</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/tragic-fire-in-mangaf-kuwait-over-35-dead-and-dozens-injured-2024-06-12-1.733188</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>More than 35 people have been killed in a devastating fire at a building in Mangaf, Kuwait. Dozens of injured individuals are receiving treatment at various Ministry of Health hospitals.</p>

<p>Major General Eid Rashid from the Kuwaiti Ministry of Interior stated that emergency teams, including fire services and forensic specialists, were dispatched to the scene to identify the deceased and the injured, according to Al-Qabas newspaper.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Major General Eid Al-Awaihan, Director General of Forensic Evidence, confirmed that the death toll at the fire site in Mangaf has exceeded 35. He added that 15 injured individuals were transported to hospitals, where four of them have succumbed to their injuries.</p>

<p>The Ministry of Health announced that they have been providing full medical care to 43 individuals affected by the fire in the Mangaf building, including several severe cases, with four victims pronounced dead upon arrival.</p>

<p>The ministry reported that the injured have been distributed among various hospitals in the country: 21 cases at Adan Hospital, six at Farwaniya Hospital, one at Amiri Hospital, 11 at Mubarak Hospital, and four cases at Mubarak Hospital for necessary treatment. Medical teams are exerting all efforts to offer the required care immediately.</p>

<p>The ministry is closely monitoring the condition of the injured and coordinating with relevant hospitals and authorities to ensure all necessary resources are available for optimal medical services. Specialized medical teams have been formed to oversee the treatment of the injured and provide psychological and moral support to them and their families. Updates will be provided as new information becomes available. The ministry expressed its condolences, praying for mercy for the deceased and a swift recovery for the injured.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 13:09:07 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733189.1718183256!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733189.1718183256!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Tragic Fire in Mangaf, Kuwait: Over 35 Dead and Dozens Injured]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Varieties</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Varieties</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE to experience earliest Summer Solstice with longest day: 13 Hours, 48 Minutes on June 20-22]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/uae-to-experience-earliest-summer-solstice-with-longest-day-13-hours-48-minutes-on-june-20-22-2024-06-08-1.733059</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/uae-to-experience-earliest-summer-solstice-with-longest-day-13-hours-48-minutes-on-june-20-22-2024-06-08-1.733059</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The UAE will experience an earlier summer solstice this year. Occurring on June 20th at 20:51 UTC, this marks the earliest solstice since 1796 for most countries around the world. This celestial event will usher in the longest day of the year for the UAE, with daylight hours reaching 13 hours and 48 minutes. It&#39;s important to note that similar variations in solstice timing can be expected in future leap years.</p>

<p>Ibrahim Al Jarwan, Board Chairman of the Emirates Astronomical Society and member of the Arab Union for Space and Astronomy Sciences, explained that during the summer solstice, the sun is directly overhead at the Tropic of Cancer, its northernmost point. In areas directly below the sun, such as the southern regions of the UAE, there will be no shadow at noon. Shadows at noontime will also be shorter across the Arabian Peninsula, with the shortest shadow occurring in the entire Northern Hemisphere.</p>

<p>Al Jarwan added that temperatures are expected to range between 41 and 43 degrees Celsius during the day and 26 and 29 degrees Celsius at night, with generally dry conditions and active winds. This is expected to be the case during the first half of summer, which runs from June 21 to August 10.</p>

<p>The second half of summer, spanning from August 11 to the autumnal equinox on September 23, is characterised by an influx of high humidity, persistent high temperatures, and the activation of moist Kos winds. These winds invigorate the formation of cumulonimbus clouds over mountainous regions and their surroundings, leading to thunderstorms.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sat, 8 Jun 2024 22:49:08 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733073.1717913742!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733073.1717913742!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733073.1717913742!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733060.1717872504!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE to experience earliest Summer Solstice with longest day: 13 Hours, 48 Minutes on June 20-22]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA["Dubai Residency" Seizes 366 Fake Travel Documents in 3 Months]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/dubai-residency-seizes-366-fake-travel-documents-in-3-months-2024-06-04-1.732974</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/dubai-residency-seizes-366-fake-travel-documents-in-3-months-2024-06-04-1.732974</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The General Directorate of Residency and Foreigners Affairs in Dubai announced the seizure of 366 fake documents and travel papers from passengers passing through Dubai airports during the first quarter of this year. This success is attributed to the readiness of its trained national personnel and the possession of advanced technologies capable of detecting fake documents within 30 to 60 seconds.</p>

<p>Aqeel Ahmed Al-Najjar, an expert advisor in the Document Examination Department at &quot;Dubai Residency,&quot; explained that the total number of forgery cases detected by the Document Examination Center in the first quarter of this year was 366, compared to 355 cases in the same period in 2023. Last year, 16,127 documents were examined, of which 1,232 were found to be fake, leading to 443 cases being referred to the Public Prosecution.</p>

<p>He noted that the administration established the Document and Paper Examination Center, which has been accredited by the courts and judicial bodies in the country since its launch in 2018. The center focuses solely on examining travel documents and related papers, including passports, travel documents, identity cards, entry permits, and residency cards (such as the U.S. Green Card). The examination process involves all security features, stamps, and electronic chips associated with these documents. The center boasts a fully equipped laboratory with the latest precision technologies in this field.</p>

<p>National Workforce</p>

<p>Al-Najjar emphasized that the center operates with 100% national workforce, who have acquired sufficient expertise through continuous training and qualification. This includes 1,500 passport officers at Terminal 1, Terminal 2, and Terminal 3 (for entry and exit), and 30 document examiners, all of whom are nationals.</p>

<p>He confirmed that the center provides services to all relevant state entities, including training services for some airlines and their employees responsible for verifying passenger identities and managing boarding. The center also assists any entity wishing to verify the authenticity of documents and papers, including individuals needing such services, such as those acquiring foreign passports through intermediaries and wishing to verify their authenticity, or passports referred to the center by the general residency and foreigners affairs administrations in the state or various entities. These documents belong to individuals who have changed their nationalities and obtained new passports from certain countries, seeking to update their identity and residency data recorded with those administrations. The center examines the passports to verify their authenticity.</p>

<p>Furthermore, the examination process includes outgoing passengers referred to the judicial authorities if found carrying fake or counterfeit travel documents, whether they were aware of it or were victims misled by someone. The prosecution, courts, and judicial authorities handle their cases. Incoming passengers with fake travel documents or passports are denied entry and immediately returned to the authorities and countries they came from.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 4 Jun 2024 16:03:30 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.732975.1717502558!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.732975.1717502558!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA["Dubai Residency" Seizes 366 Fake Travel Documents in 3 Months]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[27, including children killed in massive fire at gaming zone in India]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/27-including-children-killed-in-massive-fire-at-gaming-zone-in-india-2024-05-26-1.732739</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/27-including-children-killed-in-massive-fire-at-gaming-zone-in-india-2024-05-26-1.732739</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;A massive fire broke out at a gaming zone in Gujarat&#39;s Rajkot city, India, on Saturday evening, leaving in its wake a death toll of 27, police said on Sunday.</p>

<p>Asian News International (ANI) reported that a massive fire broke out at a gaming zone in Rajkot city, resulting in the loss of lives including children. Meanwhile, Gujarat Home Minister Harsh Sanghvi said that he is heading to Rajkot and SIT will start its investigation tonight only in the Rajkot fire tragedy which claimed 27 lives.</p>

<p>&quot;Many families have lost their children in this incident. I am going to Rajkot right now. The SIT will start its investigation tonight. The administrator and the manager have been arrested. A meeting will take place after visiting the fire spot and the action will start tonight. Prime Minister Narendra Modi has also taken the details from the Chief Minister. Members of the SIT are ordered to reach Rajkot by 3:00 IST. The CM will be provided with the details tonight itself,&quot; Harsh Sanghvi told ANI.</p>

<p>Two people, including the owner and manager of the TRP game zone in Rajkot, have been taken to a police station for interrogation into the fire incident at the gaming facility. According to officials, the fire broke out at around 4:30 IST.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 21:10:07 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.732740.1716743376!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.732740.1716743376!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[27, including children killed in massive fire at gaming zone in India]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Varieties</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Varieties</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[American Rapper Ends His Life in Live Stream]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/american-rapper-ends-his-life-in-live-stream-2024-05-22-1.732635</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/american-rapper-ends-his-life-in-live-stream-2024-05-22-1.732635</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<div class="flex flex-grow flex-col max-w-full">
<div class="min-h-[20px] text-message flex flex-col items-start whitespace-pre-wrap break-words [.text-message+&amp;]:mt-5 juice:w-full juice:items-end overflow-x-auto gap-2" data-message-author-role="assistant" data-message-id="5a1689b3-fc92-4655-93fd-66a7fbae62d6" dir="auto">
<div class="flex w-full flex-col gap-1 juice:empty:hidden juice:first:pt-[3px]">
<div class="markdown prose w-full break-words dark:prose-invert light">
<h3>A rapper in the state of Virginia, USA, has died while filming a video on social media after a bullet from a gun he was holding struck his head.</h3>

<p>Police reported that the young rapper, aged 17, succumbed to a gunshot wound to the head.</p>

<p>Although the police have not confirmed the young man&#39;s identity, separate footage circulating on social media showed rapper Rilo Hansho singing in front of the camera during a live stream while holding a gun equipped with a laser sight, according to the American newspaper &quot;New York Post.&quot;</p>

<p>According to investigations, the young rapper apparently fired a bullet into his head by accident while filming the video, causing his immediate death.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 08:51:02 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.732636.1716353444!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.732636.1716353444!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[American Rapper Ends His Life in Live Stream]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Varieties</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Varieties</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Inventor of the iPod Turns Cow Burps into Diamonds]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/inventor-of-the-ipod-turns-cow-burps-into-diamonds-2024-05-22-1.732633</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/inventor-of-the-ipod-turns-cow-burps-into-diamonds-2024-05-22-1.732633</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>American-Lebanese engineer and inventor, Tony Fadell, known for creating the iPod, has significantly contributed to identifying and reducing methane emissions in recent years. His focus is on how to convert methane gas produced by cow &quot;burps and flatulence&quot; into diamonds, according to &quot;Metro.&quot;</p>

<p>It is well-known that fossil fuel fields are not the only source of methane gas. Cows, and more specifically their burps, and to a lesser extent their flatulence, also produce significant amounts of methane. Methane traps much more heat in the atmosphere than carbon dioxide.</p>

<p>Tony Fadell explains: &quot;I have a company called Diamond Foundry that takes biogenic methane, either from the ground, manure, or animals, and converts it into diamonds using green energy, wind power, and solar power.&quot; Like carbon dioxide, the methane molecule contains carbon, which the company extracts and crystallizes to form diamonds, currently used mainly in electronics.</p>

<p>It is worth noting that although methane does not last in the atmosphere as long as carbon dioxide, it is, according to the United Nations Environment Programme, 80 times more harmful over a 20-year period after its release.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 08:33:44 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.732634.1716352271!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.732634.1716352271!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Inventor of the iPod Turns Cow Burps into Diamonds]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Varieties</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Varieties</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Seven dead after powerful storms slam Houston, Texas]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/seven-dead-after-powerful-storms-slam-houston-texas-2024-05-18-1.732521</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/seven-dead-after-powerful-storms-slam-houston-texas-2024-05-18-1.732521</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Thunderstorms have killed seven people and left more than half a million homes and businesses without power in south-eastern Texas.</p>

<p>Residents in the area could be without power for weeks after Thursday&#39;s storm, which packed 110mph (177km/h) winds, BBC reported.</p>

<p>The deaths were mostly caused by downed trees and power lines and lightning. The storm has moved on to neighbouring Louisiana with flood warnings in place for the Gulf Coast.</p>

<p>In an update on Friday night, officials announced the deaths of three more people, taking the toll to seven.</p>

<p>In Friday&#39;s news conference, Texas Judge Lina Hidalgo, the top government executive in Harris County, said that at least two tornados hit the region on Thursday night.</p>

<p>In Houston, traffic lights were out on Friday, office windows blown through and glass strewn across the city&#39;s streets.</p>

<p>The Houston Independent School District district cancelled school on Friday.</p>

<p>Flash floods and severe thunderstorm warnings were issued for multiple counties, according to Houston&#39;s National Weather Service office.</p>

<p>On Friday evening, about 600,000 homes and businesses were without electricity, down from nearly one million customers one day earlier.</p>

<p>This is the second time in six weeks that a deadly storm has swept through the Houston area. Last month a tornado hit the suburb of Katy, killing one person and injuring 10.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 22:00:42 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.732522.1716055199!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.732522.1716055199!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Seven dead after powerful storms slam Houston, Texas]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Varieties</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Varieties</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Abu Dhabi Police Warns Public of Fraudulent Transactions When Selling Vehicles and Goods Online]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/abu-dhabi-police-warns-public-of-fraudulent-transactions-when-selling-vehicles-and-goods-online-2024-05-17-1.732481</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/abu-dhabi-police-warns-public-of-fraudulent-transactions-when-selling-vehicles-and-goods-online-2024-05-17-1.732481</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The General Command of Abu Dhabi Police has issued a warning regarding fraudulent purchases made through the internet and social media platforms. These scams often involve counterfeit and delayed payment receipts, allowing fraudsters to take immediate possession of vehicles or other goods listed for sale.</p>

<p>Brigadier General Muslim Mohammed Al Ameri, Acting Director of the Criminal Security Sector, emphasized the commitment of Abu Dhabi Police to educate the public about these fraudulent activities, assist them in reporting such incidents, and enhance preventive measures to avoid falling victim to scams.</p>

<p>Al Ameri explained that the fraudulent process typically begins when a seller advertises their goods on social media or specialized applications. After the parties agree on the terms, the fraudster examines the item and sends the seller fake bank receipts, convincing them that the transfer will take several days. The fraudster then takes possession of the item based on these deceptive receipts.</p>

<p>He stressed the importance of sellers verifying receipt of the actual payment before proceeding with the transaction to avoid becoming victims of cunning fraudsters who deceitfully assure them that the sale is being conducted legally.</p>

<p>Al Ameri also highlighted the importance of contacting the relevant authorities if individuals encounter fraud and urged them to report to the nearest police station. Additionally, information can be shared through the Abu Dhabi Police&#39;s &quot;Aman&quot; service, which operates around the clock and allows community members to help prevent crimes confidentially. Reports can be made via the toll-free number <code>8002626</code> (<code>AMAN2626</code>), text messages (<code>2828</code>), email (<a href="mailto:aman@adpolice.gov.ae"><code>aman@adpolice.gov.ae</code></a>), or the smart app of the Abu Dhabi Police General Command.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 10:13:27 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.732482.1715926354!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.732482.1715926354!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Abu Dhabi Police Warns Public of Fraudulent Transactions When Selling Vehicles and Goods Online]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Syrian filmmaker Abdellatif Abd al-Hamid has passed away at the age of 70]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/syrian-filmmaker-abdellatif-abd-al-hamid-has-passed-away-at-the-age-of-70-2024-05-16-1.732449</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/syrian-filmmaker-abdellatif-abd-al-hamid-has-passed-away-at-the-age-of-70-2024-05-16-1.732449</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The Artists Union in Syria, along with several cinema institutions, mourned the director Abdellatif Abd al-Hamid, who passed away late Wednesday night at the age of 70.</p>

<p>In a joint statement by the Syrian Ministry of Culture and the General Cinema Corporation, it was stated that the late director &quot;left behind a rich cinematic legacy that holds great value in the history of Syrian and Arab cinema as a whole.&quot;</p>

<p>Abd al-Hamid was born in 1954 and studied Arabic literature at Tishreen University before receiving a scholarship to study cinema in Russia. He then returned to Syria to begin his career with the General Cinema Corporation.</p>

<p>He presented a series of films that left a mark on Syrian cinema, most of which he both wrote and directed, including &quot;Nights of Ibn Awiyah,&quot; &quot;Verbal Messages,&quot; &quot;The Rise of Rain,&quot; &quot;Breeze of the Soul,&quot; &quot;Two Moons and an Olive Tree,&quot; &quot;What Listeners Ask For,&quot; &quot;September Rain,&quot; &quot;The Road of Bees,&quot; and &quot;Solo Performance.&quot; He also played roles in some films, such as &quot;Waiting for Autumn&quot; directed by Joud Saeed, and &quot;Ma&#39;ward&quot; directed by Ahmed Ibrahim Ahmed.</p>

<p>Several Syrian artists expressed their sadness at the loss of the prominent director through their social media accounts, including Kinda Hanna, Taim Hasan, and Mustafa Al Khani.</p>

<p>Actor Karam al-Sharani wrote on his Facebook account, &quot;His exceptional laughter... exceptional facial expressions that you cannot truly understand because he looks at you but he&#39;s lost in another world... exceptional way of speaking... his exceptional films like &#39;Verbal Messages,&#39; &#39;Nights of Ibn Awiyah,&#39; and &#39;What Listeners Ask For.&#39; The exceptional lover in his love for his late wife Larisa... a very big loss for everyone who knew you and for Syrian cinema in particular, and Arab cinema in general.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 06:31:55 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.732450.1715826695!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.732450.1715826695!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Syrian filmmaker Abdellatif Abd al-Hamid has passed away at the age of 70]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Tragedy Strikes: India Billboard Collapse Claims 12 Lives, Leaves 60 Injured]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/tragedy-strikes-india-billboard-collapse-claims-12-lives-leaves-60-injured-2024-05-14-1.732353</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/tragedy-strikes-india-billboard-collapse-claims-12-lives-leaves-60-injured-2024-05-14-1.732353</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Twelve people were killed and at least 60 injured in Mumbai after a billboard collapsed during a fierce storm. The signage collapsed at a petrol station in the city&rsquo;s east, trapping dozens of people underneath. An excavator was brought in to dig through the wreckage as rescuers worked to find any survivors.</p>

<p>Eight bodies had already been removed from the wreckage, according to Gaurav Chauhan, an inspector with the National Disaster Response Force (NDRF). Four more bodies are still buried inside the debris, with rescuers having located them but unable to remove them due to the hazardous situation at the petrol pump.</p>

<p>Authorities stated that 60 people had been rescued and admitted to hospital earlier. The incident has raised questions about the safety of billboards and other structures in Mumbai, as such collapses are unfortunately not uncommon in the city. The incident serves as a tragic reminder of the importance of ensuring the stability and integrity of structures in a densely populated urban area like Mumbai.</p>

<p>As the rescue operation continued, emergency responders and medical personnel worked tirelessly to care for the injured and recover the bodies of those who had lost their lives in the tragedy. The collapse of the billboard during the storm has highlighted the need for stronger safety regulations and enforcement measures to prevent such incidents from occurring in the future.</p>

<p>The incident has sparked a debate about the responsibility of authorities and private companies in maintaining the safety of structures like billboards, which can pose a significant danger to public safety when they collapse. It has also raised concerns about the impact of severe weather events on infrastructure in Mumbai, a city that is often vulnerable to heavy rains and storms during the monsoon season.</p>

<p>As the people of Mumbai mourned the loss of those killed in the billboard collapse, questions were raised about the need for stricter building codes and regular safety inspections to prevent similar tragedies from happening again. The city&rsquo;s authorities will likely face pressure to take action to improve the safety of structures like billboards and ensure that such incidents are not repeated in the future.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 07:11:41 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.732354.1715656274!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.732354.1715656274!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>DPA </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Tragedy Strikes: India Billboard Collapse Claims 12 Lives, Leaves 60 Injured]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Varieties</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Varieties</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Teenage boy killed in London sword attack]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/teenage-boy-killed-in-london-sword-attack-2024-05-01-1.731931</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/teenage-boy-killed-in-london-sword-attack-2024-05-01-1.731931</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>A 14-year-old boy was killed and four other people were injured after a stabbing in London on Tuesday involving a man with a sword.</p>

<p>Police said they did not believe the incident was terrorism-related and there was no ongoing threat to the wider community.</p>

<p>Police tasered and arrested the man after the incident near Hainault in east London. Video footage showed a man wielding what appeared to be a sword.</p>

<p>&quot;It is with great sadness that I confirm one of those injured, a 14-year-old boy, has died. He was taken to hospital after being stabbed and sadly died shortly afterwards,&quot; London&#39;s Metropolitan Police Chief Superintendent Stuart Bell said.</p>

<p>He said it was not believed to be a targeted attack.</p>

<p>London&#39;s Metropolitan Police Assistant Commissioner Louisa Rolfe told reporters a 36-year-old man had been arrested on suspicion of murder and was currently in hospital, having suffered injuries when his van collided with a building.</p>

<p>Two members of the public and two police officers were in hospital with non-life threatening injuries. The two police officers had stab wounds requiring surgery.</p>

<p>Britain&#39;s King Charles paid tribute to those affected and praised the courage of the emergencies services that helped to contain the incident.</p>

<p>&quot;His (King Charles) thoughts and prayers are with all those affected - in particular, the family of the young victim who has lost his life,&quot; a Buckingham Palace spokesperson said.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 1 May 2024 08:47:07 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.731932.1714538667!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.731932.1714538667!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>Reuters </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Teenage boy killed in London sword attack]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Varieties</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Varieties</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Pyramids of Love: Tech Mogul Ankur Jain's Extravagant Wedding with Former WWE Wrestler Erika Hammond]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/pyramids-of-love-tech-mogul-ankur-jain-s-extravagant-wedding-with-former-wwe-wrestler-erika-hammond-2024-04-30-1.731896</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/pyramids-of-love-tech-mogul-ankur-jain-s-extravagant-wedding-with-former-wwe-wrestler-erika-hammond-2024-04-30-1.731896</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Tech mogul Ankur Jain tied the knot with former WWE wrestler Erika Hammond in a lavish ceremony set against the stunning backdrop of the Great Pyramids of Egypt.</p>

<p>Despite considering out-of-this-world options like space for their nuptials, the couple settled on Egypt. Renowned Egyptologist and family friend Dr. Zahi Hawass officiated the ceremony.</p>

<p>Jain, 33, founder and CEO of Bilt Rewards, met Hammond, 32, at Rumble Boxing. They opted for an exotic location, prioritizing the experience over traditional wedding details.</p>

<p>&quot;We&#39;re New Yorkers, and there&#39;s something magical about immersing ourselves in a completely different environment,&quot; Jain shared with People magazine.</p>

<p>Forgoing a bridal party and a conventional wedding cake, the couple entrusted most planning to their wedding coordinators.</p>

<p>&quot;We&#39;re not about the typical wedding customs. Why spend thousands on flowers?&quot; Jain questioned.</p>

<p>Despite smooth festivities, a hiccup arose with their South Africa safari plans, leading to a last-minute scramble. Yet, they made it to Cairo for a star-studded celebration at the Muhammed Ali Palace.</p>

<p>Guests, including Lance Bass and Robin Thicke, danced till dawn, embracing the delayed arrival of the couple.</p>

<p>The following day, a private tour of the Pyramids and an Ancient Egypt-themed dinner at the Grand Egyptian Museum awaited. Hammond&#39;s attire, a gold-embroidered gown by designer Rahul Mishra, blended Indian and Egyptian influences.</p>

<p>Jain reflected on their unforgettable wedding, filled with emotion and spectacular moments, culminating in a breathtaking fireworks display.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 07:29:17 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.731898.1714447396!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.731898.1714447396!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.731898.1714447396!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.731897.1714446913!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Pyramids of Love: Tech Mogul Ankur Jain's Extravagant Wedding with Former WWE Wrestler Erika Hammond]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Lifestyle</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Lifestyle</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai Police Apprehend Over 900 in Anti-Begging Campaign]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/dubai-police-apprehend-over-900-in-anti-begging-campaign-2024-04-28-1.731808</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/dubai-police-apprehend-over-900-in-anti-begging-campaign-2024-04-28-1.731808</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The Criminal Investigation Department at Dubai Police, in collaboration with police stations across the emirate, has apprehended 967 individuals involved in begging, street vending, and illegal labour since the start of the Ramadan campaign &quot;Combat Begging&quot;.</p>

<p>The arrests include 396 beggars, 292 street vendors, and 279 illegal workers.</p>

<p>Brigadier Ali Salem Al Shamsi, Director of the Suspicious Persons and Criminal Phenomena Department of the General Department of Criminal Investigations in Dubai Police, said that Dubai Police constantly strive to raise community members&#39; awareness about the dangers of begging, intensifying their efforts during Ramadan and the festive seasons.</p>

<p>&quot;During these times, beggars seek to evoke sympathy by increasing their presence in residential, commercial, and worship areas. Street vendors also try to elicit sympathy differently but pose a real threat to community safety, especially when they offer food and supplies of unknown origin, presented in poor conditions,&quot; he said.</p>

<p>Al Shamsi emphasised that the campaign aims to combat various negative phenomena foreign to the Emirati community and to educate the public about donating through official and trustworthy channels to ensure aid reaches those who truly deserve it.</p>

<p>He added that the phenomena of begging, street vending, and the presence of illegal workers threaten community security and tarnish the state&#39;s image, sometimes linked to severe consequences like theft, pickpocketing, and the exploitation of children and the sick in begging.</p>

<p>Al Shamsi urged the community to distribute alms and zakat personally through state-approved charitable organisations and called for the public not to respond to beggars or deal with illegal workers and to assist the police by immediately reporting any observed beggars through the contact centre (901) or via the &quot;Police Eye&quot; service on the Dubai Police smart app, along with the e-Crime service for reporting cybercrimes smoothly through <a href="http://www.ecrime.ae/">www.ecrime.ae</a>.</p>

<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.albayan.ae/uae/news/2024-04-28-1.4862880" target="_blank">Al-Bayan newspaper</a></em></p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 11:39:17 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.731809.1714289912!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.731809.1714289912!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai Police Apprehend Over 900 in Anti-Begging Campaign]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai Customs Unveils Smuggler's Ingenious Ploy: 4.25 Kilograms of Marijuana Concealed in Vehicle Engine Filters]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/dubai-customs-unveils-smuggler-s-ingenious-ploy-4-25-kilograms-of-marijuana-concealed-in-vehicle-engine-filters-2024-04-28-1.731799</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/dubai-customs-unveils-smuggler-s-ingenious-ploy-4-25-kilograms-of-marijuana-concealed-in-vehicle-engine-filters-2024-04-28-1.731799</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>In a groundbreaking move to uncover concealed narcotics, Dubai Customs officers successfully intercepted an attempt by a female African traveler to smuggle 4.25 kilograms of marijuana through Dubai International Airport. The illicit substance was ingeniously hidden within the engine air filter compartments. Upon suspicion, the traveler&#39;s luggage underwent meticulous inspection, revealing the presence of the hidden compartments, prompting a thorough examination that revealed the illicit substance within. Subsequently, the traveler, along with the confiscated materials, was handed over to the Dubai Police General Directorate for Narcotics Control to take necessary legal actions.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Khaled Ahmed, Acting Director of Passenger Operations Department, emphasized that safeguarding the community against harmful and prohibited substances remains a top priority for Dubai Customs. To fulfill this mission effectively, the department is committed to providing professional expertise supported by security awareness, accumulated experience, and advanced knowledge of smuggling techniques in all forms. These capabilities are continuously enhanced through workshops, training courses on inspection methods, drug detection techniques, as well as courses on body language techniques, empowering inspectors with valuable experience in dealing with smugglers.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Ahmed highlighted that this seizure demonstrates the seamless coordination among various customs units and their swift response in apprehending anyone attempting to smuggle or traffic prohibited or hazardous materials. Providing insight into the operation, he stated, &quot;During a routine shift, a Dubai Customs officer noticed suspicious luggage from a flight arriving from an African country. The officer alerted customs officials at the inspection point near the departure gate, who intercepted the bag&#39;s owner, leading to a manual inspection of the luggage and seizure of the narcotics.&quot;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Acting Director of Passenger Operations Department praised the efficiency and experience of Dubai Customs officers, affirming that, in line with its national duty and strategy for global customs leadership, Dubai Customs spares no effort in protecting the community from drug smuggling and illicit activities, thus reinforcing Dubai&#39;s position as the world&#39;s premier city for safe living and working.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 11:18:30 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.731800.1714288578!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.731800.1714288578!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai Customs Unveils Smuggler's Ingenious Ploy: 4.25 Kilograms of Marijuana Concealed in Vehicle Engine Filters]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dorset Couple Unearths 17th-Century Treasure Hoard During Kitchen Renovation]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/dorset-couple-unearths-17th-century-treasure-hoard-during-kitchen-renovation-2024-04-27-1.731789</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/dorset-couple-unearths-17th-century-treasure-hoard-during-kitchen-renovation-2024-04-27-1.731789</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Renovating a kitchen can be a costly endeavor, but for Betty and Robert Fooks from Dorset, it turned out to be a highly profitable one. While renovating their farmhouse, they stumbled upon an unexpected windfall: over **1,000 17th-century coins** concealed beneath the kitchen floor.</p>

<p>Robert Fooks, an agricultural engineer, made the remarkable discovery when he was removing the concrete floor to create more ceiling height. Hidden within a smashed glazed pottery bowl were these ancient coins, dating back 400 years.</p>

<p>The Fooks promptly reported their find to the local finds liaison officer, who sent the treasure to the British Museum for cleaning and identification. Known as the **&#39;Poorton coin hoard&#39;**, these coins are now slated for auction at Duke&rsquo;s auctioneers in Dorchester, Dorset, with an estimated value of around **&pound;35,000**.</p>

<p>Betty Fooks, an NHS health visitor, shared her excitement: &ldquo;Our house is centuries old, so there was plenty of work to be done. As we stripped away floors and ceilings, revealing the original stone walls, we decided to lower the ground floor for more ceiling space.&quot;</p>

<p>&quot;One evening,&quot; she continued, &quot;while I was with the children, my husband was digging with a pickaxe. He called out to say they&rsquo;d found something extraordinary. He gathered all the coins into a bucket. Had we not lowered the floor, they might still be hidden there. I imagine the original owner intended to retrieve them but never had the chance.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The hoard, discovered in October 2019, boasts an assortment of coins, including James I and Charles I gold coins, silver half crowns, shillings, and sixpences. Additionally, there are silver shillings and sixpences from the reigns of Elizabeth I and Philip and Mary.</p>

<p>Julian Smith, a specialist at Duke&rsquo;s auctioneers, shed light on the historical context: &ldquo;The cottage, nestled in a small hamlet in west Dorset, is a 17th-century long-house. The current owners purchased the property in 2019 and embarked on an extensive renovation project. During this process, the modern concrete floor was removed, and the ground was excavated nearly 2 feet deeper, revealing this remarkable treasure.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 05:10:53 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.731790.1714180221!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.731790.1714180221!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dorset Couple Unearths 17th-Century Treasure Hoard During Kitchen Renovation]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Varieties</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Varieties</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[A UAE citizen stumbled upon a rare sealed Pepsi-Cola bottle bearing the name 'Dubai' in the Al Dhaid]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/a-uae-citizen-stumbled-upon-a-rare-sealed-pepsi-cola-bottle-bearing-the-name-dubai-in-the-al-dhaid-2024-04-24-1.731667</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/a-uae-citizen-stumbled-upon-a-rare-sealed-pepsi-cola-bottle-bearing-the-name-dubai-in-the-al-dhaid-2024-04-24-1.731667</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The heavy rains that swept across various parts of the country last week revealed this vintage gem, which dates back to the sixties.. The bottle, found by heritage enthusiast and researcher Ali Rashid Muhyan Al Katbi, was nestled in a crevice among rocks in Al Dhaid, Sharjah. Upon closer examination, it was identified as an edition from Dubai Refreshments Company, established in 1958. The bottle&#39;s production date was traced to 1962 based on the production and expiration codes.</p>

<p>Ali Rashid Muhyan, who holds a bachelor&#39;s degree in International Relations from the University of Sharjah and a master&#39;s degree in Islamic History and Civilization, is currently pursuing his doctorate in the same field. His passion for heritage, weather, and the history of the Al Dhaid region led him to explore the area after heavy rains. As he followed the course of a wadi (seasonal river), he noticed a portion of the land had been eroded, revealing buried artifacts. Among these finds were five ancient wells concentrated within a one-kilometer area. Ali continued his exploration, moving from one well to another until he reached a rocky area with a cavity. It was there that he discovered the sealed Pepsi-Cola bottle, a relic from Dubai Refreshments Company.</p>

<p>The remarkable aspect of this find is that the bottle remained sealed, preserving its contents and the inscription on its base despite decades of weather fluctuations, river flow, and floods. This durability speaks to the quality of the product at the time. The bottle&#39;s historical significance sheds light on Dubai&#39;s early trade endeavors and the visionary economic outlook of its founder, the late Sheikh Rashid bin Saeed Al Maktoum. Dubai has since become a hub for startups, fueled by innovation, technology, and a supportive ecosystem of business incubators, accelerators, and motivated investors.</p>

<p>Ali Muhyan&#39;s interest in history and archaeology extends beyond this discovery. He collects various heritage artifacts during his research and travels to culturally significant regions. Additionally, he values translated British documents and diverse sources. To him, heritage is an essential part of human identity, both material and spiritual. Preserving and nurturing heritage remains a strategic choice for all nations, allowing them to take pride in the civilizations of their ancestors.</p>

<p>Source: <a href="https://www.albayan.ae/uae/news/2024-04-23-1.4860138" target="_blank"><strong>Al-Bayan newspaper</strong></a></p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 07:21:04 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.731670.1713928845!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.731670.1713928845!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.731670.1713928845!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.731669.1713928830!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.731668.1713928814!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[A UAE citizen stumbled upon a rare sealed Pepsi-Cola bottle bearing the name 'Dubai' in the Al Dhaid]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Varieties</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Varieties</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Rare Case: Pakistani Woman Gives Birth to Sextuplets Within an Hour in Rawalpindi]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/rare-case-pakistani-woman-gives-birth-to-sextuplets-within-an-hour-in-rawalpindi-2024-04-22-1.731560</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/varieties/rare-case-pakistani-woman-gives-birth-to-sextuplets-within-an-hour-in-rawalpindi-2024-04-22-1.731560</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>In a remarkable and extremely rare incident, 27-year-old Zeenat Waheed, a woman from Pakistan, delivered six babies at the District Headquarters Hospital in Rawalpindi. The newborns consist of four boys and two girls, each weighing less than two pounds. Despite the unusual circumstances, all six babies and their mother are in good health, according to Dr. Farzana, the hospital&#39;s medical superintendent.</p>

<p>Zeenat&#39;s first childbirth was anything but ordinary. She experienced labor pain on Thursday night and was promptly brought to the hospital. Within an hour, she gave birth to the sextuplets, with the first two babies being boys. The delivery sequence also included a baby girl, making it an extraordinary event.</p>

<p>The medical team placed the babies in an incubator to ensure their well-being. Although Zeenat faced complications after delivery, her condition is expected to normalize in the coming days. Family members expressed their joy over the birth of these six precious babies.</p>

<p>Sextuplet pregnancies are incredibly rare, occurring in just one out of every 4.5 million pregnancies. Such live births represent a remarkable achievement in the field of obstetrics. Multiple pregnancies can result from various factors, including the fertilization of separate eggs by different sperm (fraternal twins) or the splitting of a fertilized egg before implantation (identical twins). In recent years, reproductive technologies like ovulation-stimulating medicines and In Vitro Fertilization (IVF) have contributed to the occurrence of multiple pregnancies.</p>

<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.albayan.ae/varieties/2024-04-22-1.4859155" target="_blank"><strong>Al-Bayan newspaper</strong></a></em></p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 08:08:42 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.731561.1713758854!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.731561.1713758854!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Rare Case: Pakistani Woman Gives Birth to Sextuplets Within an Hour in Rawalpindi]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Varieties</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Varieties</category>
										
					</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
