<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
	<title>Mobile - Health</title>
	<link>http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-health-1.708773?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout</link>	
	<atom:link href="http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-health-1.708773?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" ></atom:link>
	<description>Health</description>
			        <language>en</language>
    				<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE Government issues Federal Decree-Law on medical products, pharmacy profession, pharmaceutical establishments]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/uae-government-issues-federal-decree-law-on-medical-products-pharmacy-profession-pharmaceutical-establishments-2024-12-29-1.735997</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/uae-government-issues-federal-decree-law-on-medical-products-pharmacy-profession-pharmaceutical-establishments-2024-12-29-1.735997</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The UAE Government has issued a Federal Decree-Law to regulate medical products, the pharmacy profession, and pharmaceutical establishments.</p>

<p>The objectives include solidifying the UAE&rsquo;s position as a globally trusted hub for pharmaceutical and medical industries, enhancing pharmaceutical security, and streamlining the development, approval, manufacturing, marketing, and distribution of medical products, all in adherence to international standards and competitive costs and timelines.</p>

<p>The provisions of the Decree-Law apply to all medical products, including drug products, medical devices, pharmaceutical products, healthcare products, biological products, dietary supplements, cosmetics, and genetically modified organism products intended for medical use. It also covers chemical precursors, controlled substances, semi-controlled substances, and hazardous or toxic materials for human and veterinary use.</p>

<p>The Decree-Law governs all pharmaceutical establishments and biobanks within the UAE, including those located in free zones. It applies to pharmacies, pharmacy chains, compounding pharmacies, medical warehouses, medical storage facilities, manufacturing facilities, contract-based manufacturing companies, marketing firms, pharmaceutical consulting firms, pharmaceutical laboratories, pre-clinical and clinical research entities, bioequivalence centres, biobanks, contract-based research and development companies, and other pharmaceutical establishments specified by the UAE Cabinet.</p>

<p>Additionally, the law encompasses practitioners of the pharmacy profession operating across the UAE, including within free zones.</p>

<p>The Decree-Law regulates all aspects of licencing, monitoring, and supervising pharmaceutical establishments and biobanks. It includes provisions for ownership transfers, temporary suspensions, precautionary closures, and licence revocations. The legislation outlines the roles and responsibilities of the Emirates Drug Establishment, the Ministry of Health and Prevention, and local health authorities.</p>

<p>Under the law, manufacturing facilities, contract-based manufacturing companies, medical warehouses, medical storage facilities, marketing firms, pharmaceutical consulting firms, and pharmaceutical laboratories are subject to licencing and monitoring by the Emirates Drug Establishment.</p>

<p>Biobanks, pre-clinical and clinical research entities, contract-based research and development companies, and bioequivalence centres fall under the jurisdiction of either the Emirates Drug Establishment or the relevant local health authorities, each within its jurisdiction.</p>

<p>Pharmacies, pharmacy chains, compounding pharmacies, blood storage units in hospitals, and medical stores in government health facilities with activities limited to storage are regulated by the ministry or the relevant local health authorities, each within its jurisdiction.</p>

<p>The Decree-Law prioritises fostering investment in the pharmaceutical sector by introducing an incentive framework to attract investments and encourage innovation and development within the medical industries. The Cabinet will issue a decision to establish this framework based on a proposal by the Chairman of the Emirates Drug Establishment in consultation with relevant health authorities and other stakeholders.</p>

<p>The Decree-Law also includes provisions to protect innovation by implementing a regulated protection mechanism for documents and data related to innovative medical products or those containing at least one new active ingredient, whether developed domestically or imported.</p>

<p>For the first time, the Emirates Drug Establishment is authorised to develop, publish, and update the UAE Pharmacopeia, approve reference pharmacopeias, and issue guidelines and standards for good practices aligned with internationally recognised principles.</p>

<p>The Decree-Law establishes clear conditions for granting marketing authorisations for medical products, including exclusive marketing authorisations, conditional marketing authorisations, and emergency use authorisations.</p>

<p>It introduces a fast-track approval pathway for innovative medical products of therapeutic importance and other qualifying medical products, ensuring compliance with international standards of quality, safety, and efficacy.</p>

<p>The legislation regulates all aspects of managing medical products, encompassing development, manufacturing, registration, pricing, import, export, circulation, distribution, possession, marketing, sale, use and safe disposal.</p>

<p>It includes general provisions for developing and manufacturing medical products in compliance with good practice guidelines issued by the Emirates Drug Establishment and aligned with international standards. For the first time, the law permits the transfer of excipients and solvents between licenced manufacturing facilities within the UAE, subject to approval by the Emirates Drug Establishment.</p>

<p>The Decree-Law also regulates the advertising, promotion, import, export, and re-export of medical products under the supervision of the Emirates Drug Establishment.</p>

<p>Moreover, the Decree-Law defines the provisions regulating the pricing of medical products and establishes the &ldquo;Pharmaceutical Policies Committee&rdquo;, working under the Chairperson of the Board of Directors of the Emirates Drug Establishment. The new law also requires pharmacy practitioners in the UAE to obtain a licence from the Ministry of Health and Prevention or the competent local health authority and specifies the duties of pharmacists and the activities that a clinical pharmacist is authorised to practice.</p>

<p>The Decree-Law regulates the provisions tied to the pharmacovigilance system in the UAE, ensuring the safe use of medical products and reducing side effects and adverse reactions. Additionally, it regulates, for the first time, the provisions for establishing and managing national databases for medical products, pharmaceutical facilities, and biobanks in the UAE.</p>

<p>The Decree-Law prescribes disciplinary measures for violations, including written warnings and financial fines ranging from AED1,000 to AED1 million for pharmaceutical establishments and biobanks and up to AED500,000 for practitioners of the pharmacy profession.</p>

<p>Penalties may also include temporary suspension of licences for up to six months or license revocation for severe breaches.</p>

<p>Entities and individuals covered under the law are granted a one-year grace period to comply with its provisions, with the possibility of an extension through a Cabinet decision.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 18:56:01 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735998.1735484149!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735998.1735484149!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE Government issues Federal Decree-Law on medical products, pharmacy profession, pharmaceutical establishments]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[GCAA adopts Protocol for Autopsy and Aviation Medicine in Air Accident Investigations]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/gcaa-adopts-protocol-for-autopsy-and-aviation-medicine-in-air-accident-investigations-2024-12-27-1.735991</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/gcaa-adopts-protocol-for-autopsy-and-aviation-medicine-in-air-accident-investigations-2024-12-27-1.735991</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Abdullah bin Touq Al Marri, Minister of Economy and Chairman of the Board of Directors of the General Civil Aviation Authority (GCAA), has approved the &quot;Protocol for Autopsy and Aviation Medicine in Air Accident Investigations,&quot; a new step toward improving air accident investigation practices.</p>

<p>This protocol represents a significant and distinctive addition to the aviation sector in the UAE by enhancing national capabilities in air accident investigations and fostering collaboration among various relevant entities.</p>

<p>It marks a critical development in investigation methodologies by enabling investigators to consult experts in forensic medicine and aviation medicine to analyse the health status of flight crew members as one of the investigative aspects. This is in addition to other elements related to the aircraft&rsquo;s condition, flight operations, and human factors. Together, these analyses integrate to yield the most precise conclusions regarding the causes of accidents and the contributing factors.</p>

<p>Abdullah bin Touq Al Marri stated, &ldquo;The adoption of this protocol, designed to provide more enablers for fostering a safer and more sustainable aviation environment, reflects our commitment to the wise leadership&#39;s directives to enhance aviation safety and develop innovative tools to improve air accident investigations and prevent their recurrence.</p>

<p>We take pride in the advanced status of the UAE in aviation security and safety, as well as its swift and sophisticated capabilities in dealing with air incidents.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Saif Mohammed Al Suwaidi, Director-General of the GCAA, explained that the protocol, with its policies and procedures developed in coordination and collaboration with the relevant entities in the country, represents a qualitative leap in the field of air accident investigations. It establishes a culture of multidisciplinary cooperation and strengthens joint national efforts to ensure the application of the best global standards in the aviation sector, identifying the causes of air accidents and preventing their recurrence.</p>

<p>Captain Aysha Mohammed Al Hamil, Assistant Director-General in Air Accident Investigations, stated, &ldquo;This protocol is a valuable technical development that enhances the effectiveness of investigations by incorporating advanced forensic methods. By utilising the expertise available in the UAE, we aim to build a more accurate and efficient investigations framework that helps identify accident causes and prevent their recurrence.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The protocol emphasises the importance of collaboration between public and private sector entities, contributing to the long-term safety and sustainability of aviation, while reinforcing the UAE&#39;s position in the global aviation community.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:32:49 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735992.1735299146!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735992.1735299146!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[GCAA adopts Protocol for Autopsy and Aviation Medicine in Air Accident Investigations]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Burjeel Holdings Expands Healthcare Services for Industrial Workers with New LLH Medical Center in Dubai]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/burjeel-holdings-expands-healthcare-services-for-industrial-workers-with-new-llh-medical-center-in-dubai-2024-12-13-1.735839</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/burjeel-holdings-expands-healthcare-services-for-industrial-workers-with-new-llh-medical-center-in-dubai-2024-12-13-1.735839</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p><em>T<strong>he center in Dubai Investment Park-2 is the Group&rsquo;s second facility, after the launch of the LLH Medical Center in Al Quoz.</strong></em></p>
</blockquote>

<p>LLH Hospital, part of Burjeel Holdings&mdash;a leading super-specialty healthcare provider in the MENA region&mdash;has launched a new medical center in Dubai Investment Park-2 to cater to the healthcare needs of the industrial workforce. This facility, following the successful launch of the LLH Medical Center in Al Quoz, further strengthens the Group&rsquo;s commitment to providing high-quality, accessible healthcare to the industrial workforce across key locations in Dubai.</p>

<p>Located in Mango Mall, Dubai Investment Park-2, the center, which caters to the significant population of industrial workers residing in the area, was inaugurated by Mr. Abdullah Lashkari, General Coordinator, Permanent Committee for Labour Affairs, Dubai. Equipped with specialty clinics, radiology services, laboratory services, physical rehabilitation, and a pharmacy, the medical center functions as a primary healthcare hub, offering a comprehensive range of services in one location. The center&rsquo;s board-certified doctors ensure every patient receives timely, high-quality care.&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>

<p>&ldquo;It is a significant milestone in our efforts to enhance the quality of life for workers in Dubai. This center is part of our commitment to providing integrated and comprehensive medical services, ensuring that workers receive the healthcare they deserve in an easy and convenient manner. At the Permanent Committee for Labour Affairs, we strive to promote a healthy and safe work environment, and we will continue our efforts to support initiatives that contribute to the workers&rsquo; well-being. We would like to thank Burjeel Holdings for this remarkable initiative, a valuable addition to the healthcare system in the Emirate,&rdquo; said Mr. Abdullah Lashkari.</p>

<p>In 2023, LLH opened its medical center in Al Quoz to provide accessible, high-quality care. The two strategically located centers are designed to serve the unique needs of the industrial workforce by offering a wide range of healthcare services. Together, they boost Burjeel Holdings&rsquo; capacity to deliver comprehensive care, ensuring that thousands of workers have access to essential medical services.</p>

<p>These centers enhance Burjeel Holdings&rsquo; established hub-and-spoke network, facilitating seamless care delivery. Complex cases or those needing specialized care are referred to Burjeel&rsquo;s secondary and tertiary facilities to ensure that all patients receive comprehensive medical services. Both centers also engage their communities through telehealth services, wellness campaigns, and preventive health programs, further emphasizing the Group&rsquo;s holistic approach to healthcare delivery.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Our goal is to make quality healthcare more accessible, particularly in communities that need it the most. By bringing healthcare services closer to the people, we ensure they can access essential care conveniently, whether near their homes or workplaces,&rdquo; said Mr. Bruno Dsouza, COO &ndash; Dubai &amp; Northern Emirates at Burjeel Holdings.</p>

<p>The medical centers significantly enhance LLH&rsquo;s existing network, which supports industrial health and caters to individuals from diverse socio-economic backgrounds. Established in 2007, LLH Hospital has been providing cost-effective, specialized, and quality healthcare services, meeting the needs of the growing population in Abu Dhabi through over 15 medical centers.&nbsp;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Being closer to our patients allows us to better understand their needs and provide tailored care. From primary care to advanced diagnostics and rehabilitation, our facility is designed to support patients throughout their healthcare journey, with a strong emphasis on prevention and wellness,&rdquo; said Dr. Mitali Dhawal Modi, Medical Director, LLH Medical Center in Dubai Investment Park-2.</p>

<p>This expansion underscores Burjeel Holdings&rsquo; dedication to inclusivity and equity in healthcare, ensuring that all individuals, regardless of socio-economic background, receive the care they deserve.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 16:20:46 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735840.1734092430!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735840.1734092430!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Burjeel Holdings Expands Healthcare Services for Industrial Workers with New LLH Medical Center in Dubai]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Burjeel-Aasandha Partnership Brings Complex Care Closer to Maldivians, Boosts Medical Tourism in Abu Dhabi]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/burjeel-aasandha-partnership-brings-complex-care-closer-to-maldivians-boosts-medical-tourism-in-abu-dhabi-2024-12-11-1.735816</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/burjeel-aasandha-partnership-brings-complex-care-closer-to-maldivians-boosts-medical-tourism-in-abu-dhabi-2024-12-11-1.735816</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<div><strong>&bull;<span style="white-space:pre"> </span>The collaboration will provide Maldivian patients access to specialized medical care, including multi-organ transplants, oncology, and endometriosis treatments, at the Group&rsquo;s flagship facility Burjeel Medical City</strong></div>

<div><strong>&bull;<span style="white-space:pre"> </span>This partnership will significantly strengthen the healthcare ties between the UAE and the Maldives, attracting more international patients seeking world-class treatments.&nbsp;</strong></div>
</blockquote>

<div>&nbsp;</div>

<div>In a significant move to strengthen medical tourism ties and broaden healthcare options for Maldivians, Burjeel Holdings, a leading super-specialty healthcare provider in the MENA region, listed on the Abu Dhabi Securities Exchange, has partnered with Aasandha Company Ltd, the administrator of the Maldives&rsquo; National Social Health Insurance Scheme. This strategic partnership opens the doors for Maldivian patients to access advanced medical treatments, including multi-organ transplants and complex medical care in key specialties including oncology, at Burjeel Medical City (BMC), the Group&rsquo;s flagship quaternary hospital in Abu Dhabi.&nbsp;</div>

<div>The collaboration agreement was signed at Aasandha Headquarters in Male by Mr. John Sunil, Group CEO of Burjeel Holdings, and Ms. Aminath Zeeniya, Managing Director/CEO of Aasandha, in the presence of senior officials from both organizations.&nbsp;&nbsp;</div>

<div><strong>A Hub for Complex Care</strong></div>

<div>This collaboration provides the patients covered under the Maldives&rsquo; National Social Health Insurance Scheme with access to advanced care across specialties like cardiology and advanced orthopedics, and treatments for conditions like endometriosis at BMC, a growing hub for international patients in the region. Most notably, Maldivian patients now have access to life-saving transplant services, a critical addition to their healthcare options.</div>

<div>Mr. John Sunil, Group CEO of Burjeel Holdings, said, &ldquo;This collaboration reflects our commitment to bridging healthcare gaps and extending our expertise beyond borders, underscoring Abu Dhabi&rsquo;s growing status as a global hub for medical excellence. We are honored to provide Maldivian patients with access to advanced care, cutting-edge technology and renowned specialists at BMC.&rdquo;&nbsp;</div>

<div><strong>Boosting Medical Tourism</strong></div>

<div>Abu Dhabi&rsquo;s strategic location as a gateway to Europe, Asia, and Africa positions it as a prime destination for international healthcare. With direct flights from Abu Dhabi to Male taking just over four hours, the Emirate offers Maldivians convenient access to advanced medical care. This collaboration not only enhances healthcare accessibility but also significantly boosts medical tourism between the UAE and the Maldives, attracting more international patients seeking world-class treatments.&nbsp;</div>

<div>This partnership streamlines the care journey for Maldivian patients through an efficient pre-authorization process and dedicated international patient coordinators. At BMC, patients benefit from a full spectrum of inpatient and outpatient services, state-of-the-art technology, internationally accredited standards, and a multidisciplinary approach to managing complex medical conditions. This comprehensive care model ensures Maldivians receive a seamless, high-quality healthcare experience in Abu Dhabi.&nbsp;&nbsp;</div>

<div>Ms. Aminath Zeeniya, Managing Director/CEO of Aasandha, said, &ldquo;We are delighted to collaborate with Burjeel Holdings to enhance the healthcare options available to Maldivians. This partnership ensures our citizens can access the best treatments in a world-class facility, strengthening the Maldives&rsquo; National Social Health Insurance Scheme.&rdquo;</div>

<div>Aasandha Company Ltd, established in 2011, provides comprehensive healthcare services to all Maldivian citizens. Funded by the government, the insurance scheme covers inpatient, outpatient, and emergency services, as well as medical care abroad. Through this partnership with Burjeel, Aasandha expands its ability to offer Maldivians high-end treatments like organ transplants and other specialized services.</div>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 13:55:25 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735818.1733910890!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735818.1733910890!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735818.1733910890!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735817.1733910875!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Burjeel-Aasandha Partnership Brings Complex Care Closer to Maldivians, Boosts Medical Tourism in Abu Dhabi]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Burjeel Hospital Abu Dhabi Opens Digestive Health Institute]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/burjeel-hospital-abu-dhabi-opens-digestive-health-institute-2024-11-29-1.735671</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/burjeel-hospital-abu-dhabi-opens-digestive-health-institute-2024-11-29-1.735671</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong><em>Equipped with cutting-edge technology and an expert team, the institute sets new standards in gastrointestinal care across the UAE, offering fast-track services for diagnostic and therapeutic endoscopy </em></strong></li>
	<li><strong><em>The services are tailored to meet the unique needs of patients of all ages, including women and children, providing comprehensive, family-oriented care</em> &nbsp;</strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>In a step towards meeting the increasing healthcare needs of the region, Burjeel Hospital Abu Dhabi, the leading super specialty hospital under Burjeel Holdings, has officially launched the Burjeel Digestive Health Institute. Equipped with state-of-the-art technology and a multidisciplinary approach, the institute caters to patients of all ages, including children, offering a wide range of advanced gastrointestinal (GI) services. The launch event was attended by Dr. Shamsheer Vayalil, Founder and Chairman of Burjeel Holdings, alongside Mr. Omran Al Khoori, Executive Board Member at Burjeel Holdings, Mr. John Sunil, Group CEO of Burjeel Holdings, and Mr. Safeer Ahamed, Group COO of Burjeel Holdings.<br />
<strong>Advanced Diagnostic and Therapeutic Care</strong><br />
The institute specializes in advanced diagnostic and therapeutic care across a wide range of conditions. It offers tailored treatment plans for Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS) and comprehensive diagnostics and management for Gastroesophageal Reflux Disease (GERD). Liver health services focus on addressing fatty liver and other chronic liver diseases, while dedicated clinics for Crohn&rsquo;s disease, ulcerative colitis, and other forms of Inflammatory Bowel Diseases (IBD) provide multidisciplinary care. The institute also treats pancreaticobiliary disorders, including gallstones and pancreatitis, and utilizes advanced diagnostics for complex gastrointestinal motility disorders.<br />
GI cancer screening and early detection are prioritized through endoscopic diagnostics and treatment, supported by a multidisciplinary tumor board for cancer treatment planning. Women&rsquo;s GI health is addressed through culturally sensitive care led by female gastroenterologists and supported by an all-female medical team. Pediatric gastroenterology services cater to children with digestive disorders, while AI-assisted endoscopy leverages artificial intelligence and advanced imaging for early tumor detection and improved outcomes. Additionally, the institute focuses on gut microbiome health through advanced testing and personalized strategies to optimize gut microbiota for enhanced digestive health.<br />
Dr. Khalid Osman Elamin Elsayed, Head of Department of Gastroenterology and Director of Endoscopy, said, &ldquo;Burjeel Digestive Health Institute reflects our commitment to patient-centered care, with a focus on personalized medicine. By combining cutting-edge technology and a team of multidisciplinary experts, we aim to set a new benchmark for gastrointestinal healthcare in the UAE. Our fast-track diagnostic and therapeutic services ensure that patients receive timely and effective care.&rdquo;<br />
<strong>Multidisciplinary Team</strong><br />
The institute adopts a collaborative approach to care, integrating expertise from gastroenterologists, hepatologists, surgeons, radiologists, dietitians, and allied health professionals to deliver holistic and personalized treatment plans. Services are also tailored to meet the unique needs of women and children, providing comprehensive, family-oriented care.<br />
The clinical team led by Dr. Khalid at the Burjeel Digestive Health Institute includes a highly experienced group of experts: Dr. Fatma Alshamsi, Consultant, Gastroenterology; Prof. Hassan Siegfried Abou-Rahma, Consultant, Gastroenterology; Dr. Sacha Sidani, Consultant, Gastroenterology; Dr. Khalid Barakat, Consultant, Gastroenterology; Dr. Hameed Raina, Specialist, Gastroenterology and Hepatology; Dr. Eman Al Atrash, Consultant Pediatric Gastroenterology, and Dr. Sofia Hanif, General Practitioner, Gastroenterology. This team&rsquo;s expertise and collaboration ensure that patients benefit from comprehensive care tailored to their unique needs.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 10:20:59 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735672.1732861169!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735672.1732861169!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Burjeel Hospital Abu Dhabi Opens Digestive Health Institute]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[How Many Years Can Exercise Add to Your Life?]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/how-many-years-can-exercise-add-to-your-life-2024-11-18-1.735454</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/how-many-years-can-exercise-add-to-your-life-2024-11-18-1.735454</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>With the pressures of daily life and the challenge of balancing work with health, many find it difficult to engage in physical activities, negatively affecting their health and life expectancy. However, a recent study reported by CNN reveals that regular exercise can extend life expectancy by at least five years.</p>

<p>Dr. Lennert Veerman, a public health professor at Griffith University in Australia, remarked: &quot;I was surprised to discover that the loss of life expectancy in the United States due to low physical activity could rival the damage caused by smoking and high blood pressure.&quot;</p>

<p>Veerman&#39;s research builds on a 2019 study, which showed that the risk of premature death decreases as physical activity increases. The latest study analyzed data from participants over the age of 40, a stage where mortality rates related to inactivity are more stable.</p>

<p>Using a life table&mdash;a tool that predicts the likelihood of individuals reaching a certain age&mdash;the researchers found that increasing daily physical activity by 111 minutes could add up to 11 years to the life expectancy of those with the lowest activity levels.</p>

<p>Veerman emphasized the need for collective efforts to achieve this goal, such as reducing reliance on cars and implementing long-term planning: &quot;We must work together to realize this vision, especially since the current healthcare system cannot sustain the rising costs associated with physical inactivity.&quot;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 07:09:07 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735455.1731899302!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735455.1731899302!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[How Many Years Can Exercise Add to Your Life?]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Global Diabetes Crisis: Over 800 Million Adults Affected, Half of Those Over 30 Are Untreated, New Study Reveals]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/global-diabetes-crisis-over-800-million-adults-affected-half-of-those-over-30-are-untreated-new-study-reveals-2024-11-14-1.735396</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/global-diabetes-crisis-over-800-million-adults-affected-half-of-those-over-30-are-untreated-new-study-reveals-2024-11-14-1.735396</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>A new study published in <em>The Lancet</em> has revealed a startling increase in the global prevalence of diabetes, with more than 800 million adults affected worldwide&mdash;almost double previous estimates. The research, conducted by the NCD Risk Factor Collaboration and the World Health Organization (WHO), also highlights a concerning gap in treatment, with over half of individuals aged 30 and above who have diabetes not receiving proper care.</p>

<p>According to the study, in 2022, approximately 828 million adults aged 18 and older were living with either type 1 or type 2 diabetes. Alarmingly, 445 million of those aged 30 and older, accounting for 59% of cases, were not receiving treatment. This trend paints a grim picture of a rising global health issue that remains largely underaddressed.</p>

<p>The WHO had previously estimated that around 422 million people were affected by diabetes, a chronic condition that can lead to severe health complications if left untreated. The disease, which involves elevated blood sugar levels, can damage vital organs such as the heart, blood vessels, and nerves, leading to life-threatening complications.</p>

<p>The study&rsquo;s findings point to a significant rise in the global diabetes rate, which has doubled since 1990, now affecting 14% of the global adult population compared to just 7% in 1990. The increase is especially pronounced in low- and middle-income countries, where rising cases have not been matched with an increase in treatment access. In contrast, treatment rates in higher-income countries have improved, contributing to a growing disparity in care.</p>

<p>In some regions, particularly sub-Saharan Africa, access to treatment remains severely limited. Professor Jean Claude Mbanya from the University of Yaounde I in Cameroon pointed out that only 5-10% of individuals with diabetes in the region are receiving the necessary treatment. He emphasized that the lack of access to insulin or other essential medications&mdash;often due to high costs&mdash;leaves millions at risk of serious health complications.</p>

<p>This global study, the first of its kind to include treatment data from all countries, is based on over 1,000 studies involving more than 140 million people. To ensure accurate estimates, the study utilized both fasting plasma glucose levels and glycated hemoglobin tests, common diagnostic criteria for diabetes. This comprehensive approach was particularly important in regions like South Asia, where relying solely on fasting plasma glucose measurements may have missed numerous undiagnosed cases.</p>

<p>While the study could not distinguish between type 1 and type 2 diabetes, it is widely believed that type 2 diabetes, which is often linked to obesity and poor diet, accounts for the majority of adult cases.</p>

<p>With diabetes rates soaring globally and treatment gaps widening, the need for urgent action to improve access to care and prevent further health complications has never been more critical. This comprehensive study highlights the gravity of the situation and calls for intensified global efforts to tackle the diabetes crisis.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 09:36:16 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735397.1731562487!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735397.1731562487!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>Reuters </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Global Diabetes Crisis: Over 800 Million Adults Affected, Half of Those Over 30 Are Untreated, New Study Reveals]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai Health's Board meeting, chaired by Ahmed bin Saeed, approves plans for a new Diabetes Centre]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/dubai-health-s-board-meeting-chaired-by-ahmed-bin-saeed-approves-plans-for-a-new-diabetes-centre-2024-11-13-1.735373</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/dubai-health-s-board-meeting-chaired-by-ahmed-bin-saeed-approves-plans-for-a-new-diabetes-centre-2024-11-13-1.735373</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>- First meeting of the board&rsquo;s second term also attended by Mansoor bin Mohammed<br />
- New 53,000 sq. ft. Diabetes Centre, scheduled to open in 2026, will double patient capacity over next decade<br />
- Project underscores Dubai Health&#39;s commitment to contributing to the goals of the Dubai Social Agenda 33&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ahmed bin Saeed: Dubai Health remains committed to establishing Dubai as a global leader in healthcare, medical education, and scientific research<br />
Mansoor bin Mohammed: Dubai Health will spare no effort to achieve the vision of the leadership to transform Dubai into a leading global model for healthcare excellence</p>

<p>The first meeting of the second term of Dubai Health&rsquo;s Board of Directors, chaired by His Highness Sheikh Ahmed bin Saeed Al Maktoum, approved plans for a new Diabetes Centre. Set to open in 2026, the new centre will offer services in alignment with the highest global standards. The project underscores Dubai Health&#39;s commitment to contributing to the goals of the Dubai Social Agenda 33 to promote a healthy lifestyle and enhance the quality of health and preventive services.</p>

<p>The meeting, held at Dubai Health&#39;s headquarters, was also attended by His Highness Sheikh Mansoor bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice Chairman of the Board of Directors of Dubai Health, and members of the board including Her Excellency Dr. Raja Easa Al Gurg, His Excellency Abdullah Abdul Rahman Al Shaibani, Professor Sir Ian Andrew Greer, Mohammed Hassan Al Shehhi, Walid Saeed Al Awadhi, CEO of Dubai Health Dr. Amer Sharif, and the representative of the Mohammed Bin Rashid University of Medicine and Health Sciences (MBRU) Professor Alawi Al-Sheikh Ali.</p>

<p>Creating a sustainable healthcare sector<br />
His Highness Sheikh Ahmed bin Saeed Al Maktoum reaffirmed Dubai Health&#39;s dedication to establishing Dubai as one of the world&rsquo;s best cities in healthcare, medical education and scientific research, guided by the emirate&#39;s visionary leadership. His Highness thanked Dubai Health teams and encouraged them to continue championing the &#39;Patient-First&#39; value.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mansoor bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice Chairman of the Board of Directors, highlighted that Dubai Health will spare no effort to achieve the vision of the leadership to transform Dubai into a leading global model in advancing health for humanity, and how sustained investments in health and well-being have strengthened the healthcare ecosystem and reinforced public trust.</p>

<p>During its meeting, the board discussed Dubai Health&#39;s key achievements in the first term and reviewed several upcoming strategic projects and programmes aimed at enhancing care. The Board also reviewed progress on the Hamdan Bin Rashid Cancer Hospital.</p>

<p>New Diabetes Centre<br />
Scheduled to open in 2026, Dubai Health&rsquo;s new Diabetes Centre embodies the integrated academic health system&rsquo;s commitment to delivering care that evolves alongside continuous research and learning, in accordance with the highest international standards. The new centre builds on the continuous service provided through the existing Diabetes Centre, which celebrated 15 years of providing healthcare services to patients this year. Dubai Health&#39;s Diabetes Centre has been a cornerstone of specialised diabetes care, having served over 15,000 patients since its establishment in 2009.</p>

<p>The new centre will cover more than 53,000 square feet, double the size of the current facility, and will enable Dubai Health to treat twice as many patients in the next 10 years. The centre will also offer a broad range of services and advanced therapeutic programmes, enhancing the comprehensive healthcare experience. The new location is also easily accessible from various areas of Dubai.</p>

<p>Her Excellency Dr. Raja Easa Al Gurg, Member of the Dubai Health Board of Directors and Chair of the Steering Committee of the new Diabetes Centre, said: &quot;The new facility with its patient centred design will strengthen the integrated healthcare ecosystem in Dubai. Through a sharp focus on medical innovation and the adoption of the latest technologies, we aim to continuously develop services that provide the highest levels of specialised care for diabetes patients.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Supporting patients<br />
Dr. Mohamed Farooqi, Director of the Diabetes Centre and Consultant Endocrinologist at Dubai Health, emphasised the importance of the new centre and its role in supporting diabetes patients, stating: &quot;The new centre builds on Dubai Health&#39;s years of experience and commitment to exceptional care, offering both specialised treatment and prevention service to meet the needs for comprehensive care of patients across Dubai. With the addition of specialties such as cardiology, nephrology, and ophthalmology, we will be able to offer an advanced level of care.&quot;</p>

<p>He further remarked: &quot;The new centre demonstrates our dedication to incorporating the latest technologies into our academic health system, with an emphasis on integrating endocrinology specialties within paediatric care. We aim to deliver comprehensive treatment that meets patients&#39; needs and helps to enhance their long-term health outcomes.&quot;</p>

<p>Dubai Health&#39;s new diabetes centre aims to harness the promise of artificial intelligence alongside traditional methods of healthcare delivery. The facility will be equipped with advanced medical technology, and examination rooms will feature technologies designed to provide patients with a smooth and efficient experience.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:15:42 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735374.1731507297!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735374.1731507297!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai Health's Board meeting, chaired by Ahmed bin Saeed, approves plans for a new Diabetes Centre]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Emirates Dermatology Society Annual Conference 2024 kicks off Friday]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/emirates-dermatology-society-annual-conference-2024-kicks-off-friday-2024-11-06-1.735196</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/emirates-dermatology-society-annual-conference-2024-kicks-off-friday-2024-11-06-1.735196</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The 8th Emirates Dermatology Society Annual Conference 2024, organised by the Emirates Dermatology Society at the InterContinental Dubai &ndash; Festival City Hotel, will be launched on 8th November.</p>

<p>The event will attract 500 doctors from leading experts and international and local specialists from dermatologists, cosmetologists and lasers from different countries.</p>

<p>Dr. Muna Al Murrawi, President of the Emirates Dermatology Society and Chair of the Conference, said that the three-day conference will discuss more than 85 expert talks on dermatology and aesthetics.</p>

<p>She explained that the scientific programme includes a number of various scientific workshops that discuss the most important dermatological and aesthetic diseases and treatment methods.</p>

<p>Dr. Al Murrawi added that the conference will also discuss hair and nail disorders, acne, skin cancer, women&#39;s health in dermatology, and the latest scientific findings in diseases and imbalances of hair and its transplantation, skin tumours and their treatments and laser, which now takes a large space in the treatment of skin diseases such as skin pigmentation, melisma, the effects of burns, blood birthmarks, varicose veins, tattoos, psoriasis, vitiligo, eczema and fungi of all kinds.</p>

<p>She explained that the conference, which is the largest of its kind in the Middle East, seeks to enhance awareness efforts, enable the local medical community to learn about the latest international medical practices proven by scientific evidence and highlight the most important success stories in this field.</p>

<p>She highlighted that the accompanying exhibition, in which more than 29 local and international companies participate, will display the latest technologies and devices used in diagnosing and treating skin diseases, laser treatment techniques and cosmetic treatment.</p>

<p>The conference will feature speakers from the USA, UK, Mexico, Spain, Italy, Singapore, India, Saudi Arabia, Bahrain, Egypt and the UAE.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 6 Nov 2024 14:07:59 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735197.1730887628!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735197.1730887628!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Emirates Dermatology Society Annual Conference 2024 kicks off Friday]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Burjeel Holdings and Response Plus Medical launch  $1mn Human Energy Health and Wellbeing Award]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/burjeel-holdings-and-response-plus-medical-launch-1mn-human-energy-health-and-wellbeing-award-2024-11-05-1.735143</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/burjeel-holdings-and-response-plus-medical-launch-1mn-human-energy-health-and-wellbeing-award-2024-11-05-1.735143</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<div data-block="true" data-editor="dimp6" data-offset-key="c1h83-0-0" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; color: rgb(36, 31, 33); font-family: &quot;Source Sans Pro&quot;, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, Helvetica, Arial; font-size: 16px; white-space-collapse: preserve; background-color: rgb(252, 252, 251);">
<div class="public-DraftStyleDefault-block public-DraftStyleDefault-ltr" data-offset-key="c1h83-0-0" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; position: relative; direction: ltr;">
<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong><em>Award aims to encourage innovators to identify solutions to inspire health and wellbeing initiatives for the global Energy sector</em></strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>Burjeel Holdings, a leading super-specialty healthcare provider in the MENA region, and Response Plus Medical Services (RPM), the largest pre-hospital care and emergency medical services provider in the region, have jointly launched the $1 million Human Energy Health and Wellbeing Award at ADIPEC 2024 to boost workplace wellness across the global Energy sector.</p>

<p>The global energy sector has made significant strides in prioritising the health and wellbeing of its workforce. Building on these efforts, Dr. Shamsheer Vayalil, Founder and Chairman of Burjeel Holdings, and Omran Al Khoori, Chairman of RPM Holding, announced the award during ADIPEC 2024, encouraging CEOs and senior executives from major global energy organisations to further advance holistic wellbeing across the industry.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Human Energy Health and Wellbeing Award that focuses on initiatives using AI to enhance mental and physical health, features two categories. A $1 million Wellbeing Investment supporting SMEs and startups to develop scalable health solutions. And an Excellence Recognition category celebrating large organisations for their innovative employee wellbeing initiatives.</p>

<p>The inaugural winners will be revealed at the next edition of ADIPEC in October 2025. Projects will be evaluated by an independent committee comprising global experts on three key criteria: creating supportive workplace environments, demonstrating innovative approaches, and showing measurable impact.</p>

<p>Dr. Shamsheer Vayalil, Founder and Chairman of Burjeel Holdings, said: &ldquo;The Energy sector, a cornerstone of global economies, has made significant strides in prioritising the physical and mental health of its workforce. As a trusted, long-standing healthcare partner to the sector, we believe it is our responsibility to foster a culture of holistic wellbeing across the global Energy sector. This award celebrates and inspires innovative and technology-driven solutions that address the diverse health challenges across some of the most challenging and rigorous work environments in the world. We are optimistic that these efforts will inspire impactful improvements in the overall health of Energy sector professionals worldwide.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Omran Al Khoori, Chairman of RPM Holding, commented: &ldquo;This award serves as recognition for the companies and innovators coming up with new ideas to promote physical and mental wellbeing in the Energy sector. It is also a platform for translating ideas into concrete solutions that can reinforce workforce resilience in a critical global sector at a time when energy is undergoing a profound transformation.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The initiative aligns with the &lsquo;We the UAE 2031&rsquo; vision and the UAE National Wellbeing Strategy 2031, reinforcing the nation&rsquo;s role as a hub for creating solutions to global challenges. Unveiled at the stand, the <strong><a href="https://hewaward.com/">https://hewaward.com/</a></strong> portal is now open for potential nominees. Further details on application dates, jury, and submissions will be shared later.</p>

<p><strong>About Burjeel Holdings</strong>&nbsp;</p>

<p>Founded in 2007, Burjeel Holdings is a leading super-specialty healthcare services provider in the UAE and Oman, and it operates a growing specialised healthcare segment in Saudi Arabia. The Group operates an integrated and multi-brand healthcare ecosystem across primary, secondary, tertiary, and quaternary medical care, ensuring complex care delivery to patients across all socioeconomic groups.</p>

<p>Burjeel Holdings&rsquo; network comprises 97 assets across the UAE, Oman, and Saudi Arabia, including 19 hospitals, 27 medical centers, 28 physiotherapy and wellness centers, 15 pharmacies, and other allied services. Its brands include Burjeel, Medeor, LLH, Lifecare, PhysioTherabia and Tajmeel.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>About Response Plus Medical Services (RPM)</strong></p>

<p>Founded in 2010, Response Plus Holding is the largest provider of onsite healthcare, medical emergency services and occupational health solutions in the UAE. RPM was listed as Response Plus Holding PJSC on the Abu Dhabi Securities Exchange in 2021 and is also currently listed on the FTSE GEIS as a global micro-cap company. Boasting the largest medical vehicle fleet in the region with 426 ambulances, RPM has become a trusted name and a partner of choice in its field of operation. It has conducted more than 1.2 million training sessions for healthcare and non- healthcare professionals, performed over 10,000 helicopter medical emergency evacuations, and offers reliable medical support for major sporting events in the region.&nbsp;</p>
</div>
</div>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 5 Nov 2024 18:42:49 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735144.1730819546!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735144.1730819546!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Burjeel Holdings and Response Plus Medical launch  $1mn Human Energy Health and Wellbeing Award]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai Health Authoritys NABIDH connects over 9.47 million patient records, more than 1,300 healthcare facilities]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/dubai-health-authority-s-nabidh-connects-over-9-47-million-patient-records-more-than-1-300-healthcare-facilities-2024-11-04-1.735113</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/dubai-health-authority-s-nabidh-connects-over-9-47-million-patient-records-more-than-1-300-healthcare-facilities-2024-11-04-1.735113</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The Dubai Health Authority&rsquo;s (DHA) NABIDH initiative has reached a significant milestone, unifying over 9.47 million patient records and connecting more than 1,300 healthcare facilities.</p>

<p>With 81% of Dubai&rsquo;s healthcare professionals actively connected to the system, NABIDH is transforming patient data management and enhancing healthcare delivery across the Emirate.</p>

<p>DHA in collaboration with Kyndryl, co-hosted a workshop to encourage the private sector to adopt this pioneering technology. The workshop discussed key topics including enhancing patient outcomes through modern technology, AI in healthcare and the importance of single digital medical record for every patient. The workshop was attended by His Excellency Awadh Seghayer Al Ketbi, Director-General of the Dubai Health Authority and senior health officials from the government and private sector.</p>

<p>NABIDH, which stands for Network &amp; Analysis Backbone for Integrated Dubai Health, is integral to DHA&rsquo;s strategy to digitise healthcare services, ensuring each patient has a single, comprehensive electronic medical file accessible across all healthcare providers. This initiative is aimed at improving efficiency, minimising errors, and providing a more personalised patient care experience.</p>

<p>During a specialised workshop organised recently by DHA to discuss progress on the &quot;Nabidh&quot; platform, Awadh Seghayer Al Ketbi, Director General of DHA, emphasised that the Authority draws inspiration for its continuous digital transformations from the vision of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President, Prime Minister of the UAE, and Ruler of Dubai. His Highness&#39; directives aim to make Dubai the smartest city in the world. Al Ketbi also highlighted the role of His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defence of the UAE and Chairman of The Executive Council of Dubai, whose guidance supports Dubai&rsquo;s international position and advancement.</p>

<p>Al Ketbi added that DHA has a portfolio of innovative projects and initiatives that serve the goals of digital and smart transformation in the Emirate of Dubai, including the rapidly advancing &quot;Nabidh&quot; platform. The platform&rsquo;s objectives include enhancing healthcare standards, ensuring effective communication between healthcare facilities, fostering better relationships between medical professionals and patients, and supporting decision-making processes. It also aims to integrate modern systems for disease prevention into the community.<br />
The workshop aimed to encourage the private sector to adopt this pioneering technology, while DHA provided an overview of the current progress of &quot;Nabidh.&quot; The discussions included improving patient outcomes through modern technology, the role of artificial intelligence in healthcare, and the importance of a unified digital medical record for each patient.</p>

<p>Mona Bajman CEO of Shared Support Services Sector at Dubai Health Authority stated that DHA spares no effort in acquiring the latest global smart solutions to support its development projects and programmes that align with Dubai&#39;s goals for health sustainability and well-being. She also stressed that DHA is committed to strengthening the efforts of Dubai&#39;s healthcare sector, helping it provide world-class services through a series of initiatives, including the &quot;Nabidh&quot; platform.</p>

<p>Bajman further added that the platform has successfully created a secure environment for exchanging reliable health data between healthcare facilities. It enables healthcare providers to share and securely access patients&#39; unified medical records from both public and private healthcare facilities across Dubai, maintaining the highest standards of privacy, accuracy, and speed.</p>

<p>Dr Mohammad Al Redha, Director of DHA&rsquo;s Health Informatics and Smart Health Department, elaborated, &ldquo;NABIDH&rsquo;s expansion to connect over 1,300 facilities and manage 9.47 million records is a notable achievement for Dubai&rsquo;s digital health ecosystem. This initiative provides a unified electronic medical record system that offers a comprehensive view of patients&rsquo; medical histories. It is integrated with the UAE&rsquo;s Riayati initiative, aiming for a single medical file for every individual in the country. We are pleased to see that 81% of Dubai&rsquo;s healthcare professionals are actively connected to the NABIDH system, and we are committed to ensuring that every healthcare provider benefits from this comprehensive platform.&rdquo;<br />
Kyndryl is a key managed infrastructure partner for the Dubai Health Authority. In this role, it supports the NABIDH initiative by managing the infrastructure that powers this system.</p>

<p>&ldquo;We are honoured to collaborate with DHA in transforming healthcare delivery through NABIDH. At Kyndryl, we are committed to leveraging our expertise in IT infrastructure to support innovative solutions that enhance citizen experiences and wellbeing,&rdquo; said Pieter Bil, Senior Vice President and Managing Director, Kyndryl Middle East and Africa. &ldquo;By ensuring NABIDH&rsquo;s secure and uninterrupted service, we are helping to create a more connected and efficient healthcare ecosystem, demonstrating our shared vision of a sustainable and advanced healthcare system for all.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 4 Nov 2024 20:57:19 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735114.1730814714!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735114.1730814714!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai Health Authoritys NABIDH connects over 9.47 million patient records, more than 1,300 healthcare facilities]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai wraps up Healthcare Future Summit 2024]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/dubai-wraps-up-healthcare-future-summit-2024-2024-10-31-1.735014</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/dubai-wraps-up-healthcare-future-summit-2024-2024-10-31-1.735014</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The Healthcare Future Summit concluded today at the Dubai World Trade Centre, held under the patronage of H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister, Minister of Defence, and Chairman of Dubai Executive Council.</p>

<p>The summit featured key international events, including the Dubai Otology, Neurotology, and Skull Base Surgery Conference &amp; Exhibition, the Annual Radiology Meeting, the International Family Medicine Conference &amp; Exhibition, and the inaugural School Health Conference.</p>

<p>Focusing on collaboration and knowledge-sharing across global health sectors, the summit reinforced the UAE&rsquo;s role as a leader in healthcare innovation and development.</p>

<p>Recognised as a landmark event, the summit promotes public health advancements, particularly in vaccination and infectious disease prevention.</p>

<p>This year, it attracted over 5,000 healthcare leaders, researchers, policymakers, and industry innovators who discussed the latest developments in vaccine technology, immunisation practices, and infectious disease control.</p>

<p>Dr Ramadan Al Blooshi, Advisor to the Director-General of the Dubai Health Authority and Chairman of the Scientific Committee for the Summit, said, &quot;The summit successfully brought together global health leaders to address vaccine advancements, immunisation practices, and pressing infectious disease challenges.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He added that the summit&#39;s strong attendance and high-level engagement helped create a vision for future infectious disease prevention.</p>

<p>The summit&rsquo;s agenda included discussions on adult vaccination programmes, highlighting the importance of vaccines for diseases such as respiratory syncytial virus (RSV), shingles, influenza, and pneumonia, which pose heightened risks to seniors. The shingles vaccine, noted for its effectiveness for adults over 50, was emphasised as vital in protecting older populations.</p>

<p>Dr Farida Al Hosani, Chair of the World Health Organisation&#39;s PIP Advisory Group, commented, &ldquo;Vaccination is essential throughout adulthood. Adult vaccines save lives, prevent complications from chronic illnesses, and support a healthier society.&rdquo;</p>

<p>She highlighted flu vaccination as an effective preventive measure, especially for high-risk adults, to ease the strain on healthcare systems.</p>

<p>A key theme was the establishment of a comprehensive adult vaccination schedule to reduce vaccine-preventable diseases, decrease healthcare costs, and improve quality of life.</p>

<p>The Healthcare Future Summit also addressed vaccination strategies as part of a proactive approach to managing health in an ageing population. By advancing vaccine technology and establishing routine adult immunisation programmes, the summit supports public health policies to reduce infectious diseases among adults globally.</p>

<p>The School Health Conference, with over 400 attendees from 200 UAE schools, addressed immunisation challenges, aiming to foster health awareness among students and parents.</p>

<p>Organised by the Dubai Health Authority, this conference focused on student health, mental wellness, nutrition, preventive care, and emergency preparedness in schools. It provided strategies and tools for creating safe, supportive school environments.</p>

<p>Dr Wafi Dawood, CEO of the Strategy and Planning Sector at the Knowledge and Human Development Authority (KHDA), highlighted the role of initiatives like the Dubai Fitness Challenge in encouraging physical activity for students and families.</p>

<p>Dawood noted that student wellbeing is integral to the Dubai Education 2033 (E33) Strategy, which emphasises a learner-centred approach from early education to lifelong learning.</p>

<p>Preventive healthcare and early interventions for student health were key topics, with discussions on nutrition, mental health, stress management, hygiene, and crisis response protocols. The conference also addressed the impact of technology and social media on health, alongside strategies for students with chronic conditions or special needs.</p>

<p>The Healthcare Future Summit featured participation from 206 doctors and specialists across 184 scientific sessions, sharing knowledge and innovation. Over 112 exhibiting brands joined, further strengthening connections within the healthcare sector.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 18:31:36 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735015.1730385042!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735015.1730385042!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai wraps up Healthcare Future Summit 2024]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai Health strengthens strategic partnership with Childrens National Hospital, USA, elevating paediatric care]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/dubai-health-strengthens-strategic-partnership-with-children-s-national-hospital-usa-elevating-paediatric-care-2024-10-23-1.734733</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/dubai-health-strengthens-strategic-partnership-with-children-s-national-hospital-usa-elevating-paediatric-care-2024-10-23-1.734733</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Dubai Health announced a strategic partnership between Al Jalila Children&rsquo;s Hospital and the Children&rsquo;s National Hospital in Washington, D.C., aiming to bring about a significant shift in paediatric healthcare.</p>

<p>The announcement follows a series of mutual visits. In the latest such visit, Dr. Amer Sharif, CEO of Dubai Health, led a delegation to the headquarters of Children&rsquo;s National Hospital. The visit included a tour of the Sheikh Zayed Institute for Pediatric Surgical Innovation and the Children&rsquo;s National Research Institute, during which both sides discussed ways to further strengthen their strategic collaboration.</p>

<p>Partnership of 8 years<br />
For over eight years, the partnership has focused on technology, specialised paediatric training, and improving healthcare quality for children. The expanded collaboration will now include several key areas, such as advanced systems development, data management, and increased access to paediatric care through innovations such as remote patient monitoring. Additionally, comprehensive and specialised training programmes will be launched for healthcare professionals at Al Jalila Children&rsquo;s Hospital. Starting next year, a cohort of medical professionals will receive advanced training, integrating best practices and innovative care models from Children&rsquo;s National Hospital to further elevate paediatric care standards.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Together, we are deepening our shared commitment to advancing paediatric healthcare,&rdquo; said Michelle Riley-Brown, President and CEO of Children&#39;s National Hospital. &ldquo;This collaboration is about more than just exchanging knowledge &ndash; it&#39;s about building sustainable, innovative solutions that will improve health outcomes for children, both in the UAE and globally. We want to ensure every child receives the highest quality of treatment, no matter where they live.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Leadership&rsquo;s support highlighted<br />
Dr. Amer Sharif, CEO of Dubai Health, said: &ldquo;We are honoured to visit the Children&rsquo;s National Hospital in Washington, D.C. and the Sheikh Zayed Institute for Pediatric Surgical Innovation, affiliated with the hospital, where the support of our wise leadership in fostering innovation and scientific research is evident both locally and internationally. I extend my deepest gratitude to the government of the UAE for providing us the opportunity to strengthen ties with the most prestigious health and scientific institutions in the world. This has opened new avenues for collaboration and created new opportunities for effective, impactful partnerships.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Strengthening our partnership with Children&rsquo;s National Hospital, one of the world&rsquo;s leading paediatric institutions, underscores our commitment to advancing children&rsquo;s health through our integrated academic health system. The collaboration aligns with the Dubai Social Agenda 33 and is aimed at building an efficient healthcare ecosystem that meets the highest global standards. It also reinforces Dubai&rsquo;s position as a global leader in healthcare, medical education, and scientific research.</p>

<p>&ldquo;We extend our gratitude to Children&rsquo;s National Hospital for their invaluable collaboration in strengthening this partnership. Through this alliance, we aim to enhance children&rsquo;s care with an evidence-based approach, aligning with Dubai Health&rsquo;s core value of putting the patient first throughout the healthcare journey,&rdquo; he added.</p>

<p>Dr. Mohammed Al Awadhi, Deputy CEO of Al Jalila Children&rsquo;s Hospital and Latifa Hospital, added: &ldquo;The strengthening of our partnership with Children&rsquo;s National Hospital will continue our work to elevate the standard of care for children in Dubai and beyond. Specifically, it will enable us to enhance operational efficiency, particularly in paediatric subspecialties, ensuring the best possible care for every child.</p>

<p>&ldquo;We will also work closely with the Children&rsquo;s National Hospital on leadership training, quality improvement, intensive care practices, and other areas to enhance the efficiency of paediatric care at Al Jalila Children&rsquo;s Hospital.&rdquo;</p>

<p>In 2018, Al Jalila Children&rsquo;s Hospital signed a health information technology (IT) agreement with Children&#39;s National Hospital. Leveraging its extensive expertise and resources, Children&rsquo;s National Hospital served as a strategic advisor, helping Al Jalila Children&rsquo;s Hospital expand its health IT capabilities to deliver the highest quality of care for children. Building on this collaboration, another agreement in 2022 focused on education and consulting services, resulting in Children&rsquo;s National Hospital conducting specialised training for cardiac ICU nurses, significantly enhancing Al Jalila Children&rsquo;s Hospital&rsquo;s clinical capabilities.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 17:11:58 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734734.1729689065!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734734.1729689065!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai Health strengthens strategic partnership with Childrens National Hospital, USA, elevating paediatric care]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Burjeel Holdings Unveils Innovative Mental Health and Ambulatory Care Solutions at Global Health Exhibition]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/burjeel-holdings-unveils-innovative-mental-health-and-ambulatory-care-solutions-at-global-health-exhibition-2024-10-23-1.734717</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/burjeel-holdings-unveils-innovative-mental-health-and-ambulatory-care-solutions-at-global-health-exhibition-2024-10-23-1.734717</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong><em>The brands &lsquo;Alkalma&rsquo; and &lsquo;Burjeel One&rsquo; mark a new era in healthcare innovation, enhancing accessibility and aligning with Saudi Arabia&rsquo;s Vision 2030.</em></strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>As part of its expansion in Saudi Arabia, Burjeel Holdings, a leading super-specialty healthcare provider in the MENA region, introduced two pioneering healthcare solutions at the Global Health Exhibition 2024. The Group unveiled Alkalma, a mental health and well-being platform, and Burjeel One, a specialized network of day surgery centers. Both initiatives align with Saudi Arabia&rsquo;s Vision 2030 and are set to revolutionize healthcare delivery in the region. Dr. Shamsheer Vayalil, Founder and Chairman of Burjeel Holdings, briefed His Excellency Fahad bin Abdurrahman Al-Jalajel, Minister of Health of Saudi Arabia, on the new initiatives at the Global Health Exhibition.</p>

<p>Alkalma, born from a strategic joint venture between Burjeel Holdings and Colombia-based healthcare leader Keralty, marks a new chapter in mental health services. Integrating value-based care with specialized primary centers and health risk management, Alkalma is debuting in Saudi Arabia with an ambitious goal of reaching nearly 30 million patients across MENA over the next decade. Alkalma will enhance preventive care, manage health risks, and reduce hospitalizations, all while delivering a comprehensive care ecosystem.</p>

<p>Burjeel One, a specialized network of day surgery centers, was also revealed at the exhibition, addressing the increasing demand for high-quality same-day medical services. These centers will offer minimally invasive procedures across key specialties such as oncology, advanced gynecology, orthopedics, and neurology. By incorporating advanced robotics and cutting-edge technologies, the first two Burjeel One centers, set to open in Riyadh by 2025, will ensure that patients receive world-class care without the need for prolonged hospital stays.</p>

<p>At the exhibition, visitors were given insight into how Alkalma and Burjeel One is supporting the Kingdom&rsquo;s shift towards a comprehensive healthcare model.&nbsp;</p>

<p>&ldquo;The launch of Alkalma and Burjeel One reflects our commitment to transforming healthcare in the region by integrating advanced technologies and value-based care models. These initiatives address the growing need for accessible mental health services and specialized ambulatory care while aligning with Saudi Arabia&rsquo;s Vision 2030,&rdquo; said Mr. John Sunil, CEO of Burjeel Holdings.</p>

<p>The unveiling of Alkalma and Burjeel One builds on the success of PhysioTherabia, Saudi Arabia&rsquo;s largest and fastest-growing physiotherapy network, which has expanded to 28 centers since its launch in 2023. These new services will enhance the network, offering integrated care from mental health to specialized surgery and rehabilitation.</p>

<p>Participating under the theme &lsquo;Making Space for Innovation,&rsquo; Burjeel Holdings showcased its commitment to advancing healthcare at the Global Health Exhibition. Attendees experienced live demos of advanced physiotherapy equipment, while Burjeel highlighted its expertise in complex care across specialties like fetal medicine, orthopedics, oncology, pediatrics, and cardiovascular care.</p>

<p>During their visit to Burjeel&rsquo;s booth, H.E. Dr. Majid Al-Fayyadh, CEO of King Faisal Specialist Hospital and Research Centre; &nbsp;H.E. Dr. Mohammed Al-Abd Al-Aali, Assistant Minister of Health; H.E. Dr. Ibrahim Alomar, Assistant Deputy Minister for Health Investment, Private Sector Participation (PSP), Ministry of Health; H.E. Dr. Khaled Alabdulkareem, Assistant Deputy Minister for Primary Health Care, Ministry of Health; and H.E. Dr. Shabab Al Ghamdi, General Secretary of CCHI, were introduced to the new brands the Group is launching in the Kingdom.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 10:16:13 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734720.1729664210!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734720.1729664210!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734720.1729664210!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734719.1729664191!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734718.1729664153!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Burjeel Holdings Unveils Innovative Mental Health and Ambulatory Care Solutions at Global Health Exhibition]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai to host Healthcare Future Summit 2024 from 29-31 October]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/dubai-to-host-healthcare-future-summit-2024-from-29-31-october-2024-10-21-1.734665</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/dubai-to-host-healthcare-future-summit-2024-from-29-31-october-2024-10-21-1.734665</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Under the patronage of His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defence of the UAE, and Chairman of The Executive Council of Dubai, Dubai will host the Healthcare Future Summit 2024 at the Dubai World Trade Centre from 29-31 October. Under the theme &lsquo;Vaccination, Research &amp; Development, Policy, and Delivery: Towards a Healthier Future&rsquo;, the event will bring together over 3,500 participants and 100 brands from more than 20 countries.</p>

<p>The Summit, hosted with the support of the Dubai Health Authority (DHA), will focus on cutting-edge innovations in vaccination and healthcare, including advancements in disease management and the application of advanced technologies like Artificial Intelligence (AI) to enhance vaccine distribution and develop new strategies for future pandemics.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Healthcare Future Summit 2024 will also explore the impact of modern technologies and AI on pharmaceutical research, with a special emphasis on vaccine development and innovations targeting respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) and &lsquo;immune ageing&rsquo;. The goal is to improve public health across all age groups.</p>

<p>Additionally, the Summit will feature several prominent international events, including the Dubai Otology, Neurotology &amp; Skull Base Surgery Conference &amp; Exhibition, the Annual Radiology Meeting Conference and Exhibition, and the International Family Medicine (IFM) Exhibition, all of which will have various scientific sessions and specialised workshops.</p>

<p>Strengthening Healthcare System Preparedness<br />
Dr. Ramadan Al Blooshi, Advisor to the Director-General of DHA, Director of the Public Health Protection Department, and Chairman of the Summit&rsquo;s Scientific Committee, highlighted the importance of the event as a platform for exchanging insights on the challenges and opportunities in the healthcare sector to improve global public health outcomes.</p>

<p>Dr. Al Blooshi said that DHA&rsquo;s support for this global summit reflects its commitment to fostering innovation, embracing modern technologies, and harnessing AI to enhance the efficiency and sustainability of healthcare services in the emirate, aligning with Dubai&rsquo;s vision in this field.</p>

<p>He also emphasised the importance of strengthening collaboration among regional and international healthcare stakeholders, sharing best practices, and leveraging collective expertise to develop solutions that will better equip health systems to respond to future pandemics.</p>

<p>Sustainable Strategies<br />
His Excellency Dr. Abdulsalam Al Madani, Parliamentary Assembly of the Mediterranean Roving Ambassador for the GCC Region, and CEO of the Healthcare Future Summit, said that Dubai&rsquo;s hosting of the event, along with the participation of a distinguished group of experts and professionals in the healthcare sector, underscores the emirate&#39;s position as a global hub for healthcare innovation.</p>

<p>&ldquo;The Healthcare Future Summit 2024 is a crucial platform for exchanging ideas and highlighting the importance of global collaboration in addressing health challenges and developing sustainable strategies to ensure equitable vaccine distribution while improving the preparedness of global health systems for future pandemics,&rdquo; he said.</p>

<p>The Summit&rsquo;s key themes will explore the intersection of technology and health policies, particularly the role of AI in accelerating vaccine development. It will also showcase cutting-edge advancements in vaccination technologies and more efficient distribution methods.</p>

<p>Panel discussions at the event will address how emerging technologies can improve global health supply chains and foster collaboration between international health institutions to enhance the responsiveness of health systems to global challenges.</p>

<p>Health Economy<br />
The Healthcare Future Summit 2024 will also discuss the health economy and resource management, with presentations on modern economic tools that support decision-making in public health. Discussions will focus on cost-effectiveness and financing models to ensure the sustainability of vaccination programmes while optimising health resource management through partnerships between the public and private sectors.</p>

<p>Additionally, the event will examine vaccine policies in the GCC and explore the development of a unified vision to improve public health in the region. It will address the preparedness of Gulf states for future pandemics by crafting effective strategies to enhance the readiness of health systems. The Summit will also review progress in the prevention of infectious diseases, such as meningitis, in line with global efforts to meet the World Health Organization&#39;s goal of eradicating the disease by 2030.</p>

<p>School Health Conference<br />
Alongside the main event, the School Health Conference will host over 400 participants representing 200 schools across the UAE, focusing on the challenges related to school immunisation programmes and raising health awareness among students, parents, and the wider school community.</p>

<p>The Healthcare Future Summit 2024, organised by INDEX Conferences and Exhibitions Org. LLC, a member of INDEX Holding, is supported by the Dubai Health Authority, the Global Alliance for Vaccines and Immunisation (GAVI), the Emirates Public Health Association, the World Federation of Public Health Associations, the European Society of Clinical Microbiology and Infectious Diseases (ESCMID), the International Federation for Emergency Medicine (IFEM), and the Parliamentary Assembly of the Mediterranean.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 21:07:42 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734666.1729530346!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734666.1729530346!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai to host Healthcare Future Summit 2024 from 29-31 October]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Hamdan Bin Rashid Al Maktoum Foundation organises webinar to raise awareness about breast cancer]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/hamdan-bin-rashid-al-maktoum-foundation-organises-webinar-to-raise-awareness-about-breast-cancer-2024-10-14-1.734449</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/hamdan-bin-rashid-al-maktoum-foundation-organises-webinar-to-raise-awareness-about-breast-cancer-2024-10-14-1.734449</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Hamdan Bin Rashid Al Maktoum Foundation for Medical and Educational Sciences successfully concluded a specialised scientific webinar yesterday, focusing on the latest updates in breast cancer diagnosis and treatment.</p>

<p>The event drew participation from prominent global experts and attracted a wide audience of healthcare professionals, researchers, and individuals engaged in oncology.</p>

<p>The webinar highlighted the most recent medical innovations and scientific breakthroughs in breast cancer care, with participants exploring the ongoing challenges faced by physicians in bridging the gap between research and clinical practice. Among the key challenges discussed was the complexity of breast cancer diagnosis, which is driven by the genetic and biological diversity of the disease.</p>

<p>Achieving an accurate diagnosis requires the use of advanced techniques such as molecular profiling and genetic testing, which allow for the customisation of treatment plans based on each patient&rsquo;s unique characteristics. This complexity places significant demands on physicians to select and apply the most effective treatment paths, as discussed by the experts during the session.</p>

<p>In her remarks, Dr. Salama Al Muhairi, Director of Medical Excellence at Hamdan Bin Rashid Al Maktoum Foundation, underscored the foundation&#39;s commitment to continuous medical education and the importance of raising awareness about cutting-edge advancements in the fight against complex diseases like cancer.</p>

<p>She said, &ldquo;At Hamdan Bin Rashid Al Maktoum Foundation for Medical and Educational Sciences, we are committed to fostering sustainable healthcare solutions by creating opportunities for positive cultural shifts in the medical community&#39;s approach to challenging diseases. We aim to provide an interactive platform for healthcare professionals to exchange expertise and knowledge, helping to elevate the quality of care provided to patients.</p>

<p>Our mission goes beyond the dissemination of new information or research; it&rsquo;s about cultivating a collaborative environment where professionals can stay up-to-date on the latest in breast cancer diagnosis and treatment while sharing their real-world experiences.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Dr. Al Muhairi added, &ldquo;The complexity of breast cancer diagnosis, which can vary significantly depending on the genetic and biological factors of each patient, requires that physicians remain constantly trained and informed about the latest tools and techniques. Advanced imaging, molecular profiling, and targeted therapies are no longer optional but are essential elements of precise and effective care.</p>

<p>Today&rsquo;s healthcare professionals need to master core technologies like MRI and advanced CT scans, along with the ability to interpret intricate genetic analyses, to determine the best treatment options for each patient. This ongoing education and interdisciplinary collaboration are vital to achieving optimal outcomes, and that&rsquo;s why events like this webinar are invaluable. They provide a unique opportunity to learn from global experts and exchange ideas on how to improve patient care and implement the latest research in clinical practice.&rdquo;</p>

<p>During the webinar, the speakers stressed the importance of advanced imaging techniques, such as MRI and CT scans, alongside genetic profiling, in determining the exact stage of the disease and identifying the tumor type.</p>

<p>Despite these advancements, the experts pointed out that these technologies are not yet fully integrated into clinical practice worldwide, contributing to a gap between research and its real-world application.</p>

<p>The webinar featured distinguished contributions from Prof. Melinda Telli, Director of the Breast Cancer Programme at Stanford Cancer Institute, who presented the latest advancements in targeted therapies for triple-negative and hereditary breast cancer. Dr. Abeer Al Sayegh, Head of the Genomics Department at Sultan Qaboos Comprehensive Cancer Center, discussed the role of genomics in improving patient care through personalised treatment solutions.</p>

<p>Prof. Mehran Habibi, Associate Professor of Surgery at Northwell Health, provided valuable insights into surgical innovations, including oncoplastic breast surgery and wire-free tumor excision techniques.</p>

<p>The session was expertly moderated by Dr. Mouza Al Ameri, Assistant Professor of Surgery at UAE University and Tawam Hospital, whose extensive experience in breast cancer care enriched the discussions on best practices in treatment and research.</p>

<p>The webinar concluded with key recommendations aimed at strengthening collaboration among healthcare professionals and implementing the latest research findings in clinical settings. These efforts are expected to contribute to improving patient care in the region and advancing tangible progress in the fight against breast cancer.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 12:54:35 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734450.1728896041!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734450.1728896041!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Hamdan Bin Rashid Al Maktoum Foundation organises webinar to raise awareness about breast cancer]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Mubadalas KELIX bio acquires four GlobalOne Healthcare Holding pharma assets]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/mubadala-s-kelix-bio-acquires-four-globalone-healthcare-holding-pharma-assets-2024-10-14-1.734447</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/mubadala-s-kelix-bio-acquires-four-globalone-healthcare-holding-pharma-assets-2024-10-14-1.734447</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Following the closing of the acquisition of KELIX bio, Mubadala Investment Company PJSC has empowered its new specialty pharmaceutical business to acquire a 100% stake in four of GlobalOne Healthcare Holding&rsquo;s (GHH) pharma assets which include Bioventure, Bioventure Healthcare, Gulf Inject and Wellpharma.</p>

<p>This strategic move consolidates Mubadala&rsquo;s presence in the life sciences ecosystem, advances the UAE&rsquo;s life sciences sector, and positions the nation as a global industry leader while supporting economic diversification.</p>

<p>In March 2024, Mubadala entered into a definitive agreement to acquire KELIX bio, a specialty pharmaceutical business focused on delivering complex generics across emerging markets. The acquisition was successfully closed last September.</p>

<p>GHH&rsquo;s pharma assets include cutting-edge biopharma and IV solutions manufacturing. Integrating these assets into KELIX bio&rsquo;s ecosystem significantly advances their expanded capabilities. Each asset brings unique strengths to the portfolio.</p>

<p>Dr. Bakheet Al Katheeri, Chief Executive Officer of UAE Investments Platform at Mubadala, stated, &ldquo;The rapid completion of the KELIX bio acquisition and this subsequent transaction demonstrate our commitment to building a thriving life sciences sector in the UAE and supporting our nation&rsquo;s ambition for a knowledge-based economy.</p>

<p>We continue to seek partnerships and investments that align with our strategic goals, as we aim to generate value for our stakeholders while strengthening the UAE&#39;s position in this critical global industry. KELIX bio and its assets are well positioned for accelerated growth and will enable us to deliver on our ambition of creating a regional life sciences champion.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Ismail Ali Abdulla, Head of UAE Clusters, at Mubadala&rsquo;s UAE Investments Platform, said, &ldquo;This acquisition reinforces our strategic intent to position the UAE at the forefront of the life sciences ecosystem on a global scale. It contributes to our nation&rsquo;s economic diversification, creates valuable socio-economic returns, and reaffirms Mubadala&rsquo;s ambitions within the sector.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He added, &ldquo;Being a responsible investor we continue to nurture future-centric solutions that boost our nation&rsquo;s GDP, increase job creation, foster innovation, and strengthen medical security, shaping the future of our communities with lasting impact.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Hocine Sidi Said, CEO of KELIX bio, said, &ldquo;The acquisition of GHH assets considerably strengthens our presence in the UAE and provides us access to a greater pipeline of products and technologies. Bringing these businesses and their colleagues into the KELIX bio network is exciting as it accelerates our path to becoming a global life science leader.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Low Ping, Group CEO Yas Holding, commented, &ldquo;Divesting these subsidiaries to KELIX bio marks a strategic pivot for Yas Holding. This decision aligns with our commitment to enhancing healthcare access and innovation across the region. We are confident that under KELIX bio&#39;s stewardship, Wellpharma, Gulf Inject, Bioventure Healthcare, and Bioventure will continue to thrive and contribute significantly to the healthcare landscape. We look forward to witnessing their continued growth and the positive impact they will have on the life science sector at large.&quot;</p>

<p>The acquisition of four GHH assets by KELIX Bio significantly enhances the UAE&#39;s local life sciences capabilities through strategic investments.<br />
This move aligns with government initiatives such as &lsquo;Operation 300bn&rsquo; and &lsquo;Make it in the Emirates&rsquo;, which aim to strengthen the country&#39;s manufacturing sector.</p>

<p>These acquisitions advance Mubadala&#39;s efforts to establish a national pharma champion based in Abu Dhabi. They enhance the UAE&#39;s pharmaceutical infrastructure, address prevalent diseases, secure drug supply, reduce healthcare costs, and progress the nation toward a knowledge-based economy.</p>

<p>GlobalOne Healthcare Holding LLC (GHH) serves as the dedicated Healthcare Division of Yas Holding LLC, focusing on enhancing healthcare outcomes by investing in biopharmaceuticals and healthcare services.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 11:56:15 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734448.1728892543!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734448.1728892543!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Mubadalas KELIX bio acquires four GlobalOne Healthcare Holding pharma assets]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai Health Authority showcases services to empower People of Determination]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/dubai-health-authority-showcases-services-to-empower-people-of-determination-2024-10-07-1.734268</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/dubai-health-authority-showcases-services-to-empower-people-of-determination-2024-10-07-1.734268</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Dubai Health Authority (DHA) will highlight a range of services, initiatives, projects, and achievements aimed at empowering people of determination during its participation in the AccessAbilities Expo for People of Determination.</p>

<p>Dr. Ramadan Al Blooshi, Advisor to the Director-General of DHA and Acting Director of Public Health Protection, stated that during this global event, the authority is showcasing the importance of mental health awareness as part of the &ldquo;Psychological Wellbeing in Dubai&rdquo; initiative.</p>

<p>This initiative aligns with the Dubai Mental Wealth Strategy, which DHA is implementing comprehensively to fulfil its mission: &ldquo;Dubai, a home of health, happiness, and prosperity.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Dr. Al Blooshi explained that this service targets students of determination across the UAE, including those in special needs centres and private schools in Dubai (inclusive education).</p>

<p>He emphasised the importance of this service in enhancing the quality of life in Dubai and promoting mental wellbeing, especially among students. This includes creating supportive environments to improve social and environmental conditions, changing the negative perception surrounding mental health, raising awareness of mental wellbeing among students, their families, and healthcare providers, and identifying the symptoms of mental health disorders and how to address them. Additionally, it aims to empower parents to deal effectively with such issues.</p>

<p>Dr. Al Blooshi highlighted that this specialised service is provided free-of-charge to this group by DHA in collaboration with partners such as Appolonia Dental Centre, Dr. Nicolas &amp; ASP, and Dr. Joy Dental Clinic, adhering to the highest standards and best healthcare protocols. He also noted the community&#39;s positive reception, with DHA delivering 67 lectures and workshops benefiting nearly 5,000 individuals over the past period.</p>

<p>Dr. Al Blooshi also mentioned that during the AccessAbilities Expo for People of Determination, DHA will showcase its Early Eye Health Screening Programme as part of its annual school health services plan, which is implemented across the emirate.</p>

<p>He explained that the service, available to students from centres for people of determination and private schools in Dubai aims to enhance the quality of life by providing additional medical care for students of determination. The programme focuses on preventing eye diseases, early detection of any health issues, and encouraging parents to conduct regular eye check-ups for their children. Parents are also informed about their children&rsquo;s eye health.</p>

<p>Dr. Al Blooshi noted that the service, provided free of charge by a specialised team of medical professionals, adheres to the best protocols, practices, and equipment. The service is offered in collaboration with partners including Al Jaber Optical Centres, Moorfields Eye Hospital Dubai, Burjeel Hospital, and Barraquer Ophthalmology Centre.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 7 Oct 2024 10:23:12 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734269.1728282153!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734269.1728282153!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai Health Authority showcases services to empower People of Determination]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Burjeel Holdings Launches Scan for Life Initiative to Provide Complimentary Breast Cancer Screenings Across the UAE]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/burjeel-holdings-launches-scan-for-life-initiative-to-provide-complimentary-breast-cancer-screenings-across-the-uae-2024-10-03-1.734186</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/burjeel-holdings-launches-scan-for-life-initiative-to-provide-complimentary-breast-cancer-screenings-across-the-uae-2024-10-03-1.734186</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong><em>During World Breast Cancer Awareness Month, the Group&rsquo;s mammogram truck will visit various locations, offering massive screenings for women under the &lsquo;Scan for Life&rsquo; initiative.</em></strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>As part of its commitment to promoting early detection and raising awareness about breast cancer, Burjeel Holdings is launching an initiative under the theme &lsquo;Scan for Life.&rsquo; During October, when World Breast Cancer Awareness Month is observed, the campaign aims to emphasize the critical importance of regular breast cancer screenings. Burjeel&rsquo;s signature Pink Truck will visit multiple locations throughout the month to offer convenient screenings for women.</p>

<p>The &lsquo;Scan for Life&rsquo; campaign emphasizes that a single scan can provide life-saving information, ensuring early detection through Burjeel&rsquo;s advanced breast cancer screenings. It seeks to make breast cancer screenings more accessible, reaching women across various sectors, particularly those over 40 and in the high-risk category. The campaign encourages women to prioritize their health and take advantage of these complimentary mammograms, underscoring the life-saving potential of early detection.</p>

<p>During this month, the Burjeel Pink Truck will visit key locations, including Mohamed Bin Zayed University for Humanities, Abu Dhabi Police GHQ, Ministry of Justice, Zayed International Airport, and the General Pension and Social Security Authority (GPSSA), among others. This outreach will empower women across various sectors to prioritize their health by undergoing mammograms and learning about breast cancer prevention. The mobile unit will also travel to malls, business centers, and educational institutions such as Marina Mall, Rosewood Abu Dhabi, Al Dar Group, Yasmina British Academy Campus, and Dunes International School.</p>

<p>At each location, clinicians will offer complimentary mammograms and educate women about the importance of regular self-examinations and screenings, providing vital information on breast cancer symptoms and risk factors.</p>

<p>Prof. Humaid Al Shamsi, CEO of Burjeel Cancer Institute, emphasized the importance of this campaign, stating, &ldquo;Breast cancer remains one of the most common cancers affecting women worldwide, and early detection is crucial for successful treatment. By bringing screenings directly to workplaces, government entities, and public spaces, we are removing barriers and making it easier for women to prioritize their health. Through &lsquo;Scan for Life,&rsquo; we hope to encourage more women to take the first step towards prevention.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Burjeel Holdings is also working closely with its partners across the UAE to host awareness sessions led by medical experts. These sessions will focus on educating participants about the symptoms of breast cancer, available treatments, and lifestyle changes that can reduce risk.</p>

<p>For more information about the &lsquo;Scan for Life&rsquo; campaign and screening locations, call Burjeel Cancer Institute on 800 23.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 3 Oct 2024 05:55:08 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734188.1727920443!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734188.1727920443!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734188.1727920443!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734187.1727920423!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Burjeel Holdings Launches Scan for Life Initiative to Provide Complimentary Breast Cancer Screenings Across the UAE]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid issues Decree on the Board of Dubai Health]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/health/mohammed-bin-rashid-issues-decree-on-the-board-of-dubai-health-2024-09-25-1.734063</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/health/mohammed-bin-rashid-issues-decree-on-the-board-of-dubai-health-2024-09-25-1.734063</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>In his capacity as the Ruler of Dubai, His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister of the UAE, issued Decree No. (53) of 2024 on the Board of Directors of the Dubai Academic Health Corporation (Dubai Health), chaired by His Highness Sheikh Ahmed bin Saeed Al Maktoum.</p>

<p>As per the Decree, His Highness Sheikh Mansoor bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum will serve as Vice Chairman. Other members of the Board include: Dr. Raja Easa Al Gurg; Abdulla Abdul Rahman Al Shaibani; Professor Ian Andrew Greer; Mohammed Hassan Al Shehhi; Waleed Saeed Al Awadhi, in addition to the CEO of Dubai Health and a representative from the Mohammed Bin Rashid University of Medicine and Health Sciences.</p>

<p>This Decree is effective from the date of its issuance and will be published in the Official Gazette.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 13:38:00 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734064.1728615302!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734064.1728615302!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid issues Decree on the Board of Dubai Health]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Health</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Health</category>
										
					</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
