<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
	<title>Mobile - UAE</title>
	<link>http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-uae-1.708763?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout</link>	
	<atom:link href="http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-uae-1.708763?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" ></atom:link>
	<description>UAE</description>
			        <language>en</language>
    				<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai Municipality awards contracts for second phase of Al Mamzar Beach Development Project]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/dubai-municipality-awards-contracts-for-second-phase-of-al-mamzar-beach-development-project-2025-01-05-1.736059</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/dubai-municipality-awards-contracts-for-second-phase-of-al-mamzar-beach-development-project-2025-01-05-1.736059</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Entailing a cost of AED400 million, the two-phase project, which includes a seasonal events area and world-class wellness facilities, is eyeing completion by the end of 2025</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Among other highlights, the project features a dedicated public beach for women with manifold privacy and safety considerations incorporated into its design</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Jogging, walking, and cycling tracks linking the creek and corniche areas aim to further elevate the visitor experience</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Badr Anwahi: We continue to work towards the vision of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum to make Dubai the world&rsquo;s best city to live, work, and visit</strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>In alignment with the directives of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister of the UAE and Ruler of Dubai, Dubai Municipality has awarded contracts for the second phase of Al Mamzar Beach Development Project. This phase focuses on developing the beachfront in Al Mamzar Corniche, with completion of both phases of the project expected by the end of 2025. The total cost of the project is projected to be around AED400 million across both phases.</p>

<p>The project aims to elevate beach infrastructure through innovative designs that seamlessly connect the creek and the corniche, creating a new beach tourism destination that meets international standards while adhering to sustainability principles and addressing future concerns regarding climate change. It seeks to redefine global beach design concepts by offering integrated beaches equipped with state-of-the-art recreational, sports and commercial facilities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>These enhancements align with the highest specifications and standards, reinforcing Dubai&rsquo;s position as a leading global tourism hub and underscoring its commitment to improving quality of life and well-being for all. Spread over 125,000 square metres and spanning 80 metres across, Al Mamzar Corniche Beach will feature a dedicated public beach for women. Keeping privacy and safety factors paramount, the facility will include a secure gated entrance and fencing. The ladies beach will also enable night swimming and offer tailored amenities such as a sports club, commercial services, and children&rsquo;s play areas.</p>

<p><strong>Novel design</strong></p>

<p>The public beach on Al Mamzar Corniche will also feature 1,000 metres of running, walking, and cycling paths linking Al Mamzar Creek Beach and Al Mamzar Park. This innovative design, the first of its kind in the region, provides a convergence of beach paths with park areas to offer visitors a unique and multifaceted experience. The development will also feature green spaces crafted to the highest standards of aesthetic landscaping. Facilities will include a 5,000-square-metre area for seasonal events and activities, a 2,000-square-metre skateboarding area, children&#39;s play areas, restrooms, and beach lounges.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dubai Municipality will also equip the corniche with public health and wellness facilities, including toilets, changing rooms, showers, and services for people of determination. An administrative building will house a control room and first aid centre. Smart services, including AI-supported surveillance systems, drowning rescue technologies, crowd management tools, and smart luggage lockers, will ensure a seamless visitor experience.</p>

<p>The corniche development also focuses on encouraging business opportunities, introducing waterfront restaurants, food and beverage outlets, beach seating, and spaces for recreational activities, ultimately fostering economic growth while providing visitors an enhanced experience.</p>

<p>Bader Anwahi, CEO of the Public Facilities Agency at Dubai Municipality said, &ldquo;We continue to work towards the vision of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum to make Dubai the world&rsquo;s best city to live, work, and visit. This project reflects our commitment to creating innovative, sustainable infrastructure that aligns with Dubai&#39;s future ambitions, solidifying its leading position across various vital sectors, and supporting the achievement of Dubai Economic Agenda D33 targets.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He added: &ldquo;The development of infrastructure projects for tourist and beachfront facilities is a key strategic objective of Dubai Municipality aimed at building a sustainable and attractive city that offers advanced tourism and recreational facilities. This enhances Dubai&#39;s appeal, elevating quality of life for all, and solidifies the emirate&rsquo;s position as a leading global tourist destination.</p>

<p>&ldquo;We are redefining concepts and standards for the design and development of beaches to align with the future and position them as the most advanced and appealing globally. Our goal is to showcase Dubai&rsquo;s uniqueness in implementing pioneering projects that combine advanced, sustainable infrastructure with modern, aesthetic designs. These projects provide top-notch services and facilities, offering exceptional tourism and recreational experiences that support the emirate&rsquo;s future economic and tourism agendas.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>First phase nears half-way stage</strong></p>

<p>The first phase of the development, work on which commenced in June last year, has achieved 45% completion. Covering an area of 275,000 square metres, the beach ranges in width from 30 to 90 metres at various points. The project includes the construction of a 200-metre-long pedestrian pontoon bridge to connect the two banks of the creek, ensuring ease of access for the public. It also features a 300-metre-long night swimming beach designed to be accessible for people of determination, along with a 5-kilometre walkway and dedicated running and cycling tracks along the beach. These enhancements aim to create an inclusive and vibrant community space for both residents and visitors.</p>

<p>The development also incorporates three children&rsquo;s play areas, two recreational zones, and comprehensive visitor facilities such as barbecue spots and jet ski marinas. In addition, the beach will feature eight toilet blocks, changing rooms, and shower rooms, with eight outdoor shower areas and 1,400 car parking spaces.</p>

<p>Dubai Municipality, which is tasked with the management of waterways and public beaches, aims to enhance recreational facilities across the emirate. By creating world-class tourism infrastructure, the Al Mamzar Beach Development Project will cater to the growing numbers of residents, tourists, and beachgoers, reinforcing Dubai&rsquo;s status as a premier destination for leisure and recreation.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 5 Jan 2025 19:00:36 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736060.1736089258!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736060.1736089258!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai Municipality awards contracts for second phase of Al Mamzar Beach Development Project]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid approves AED5.4 billion housing projects offering beneficiaries 3,004 new homes across Dubai]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-approves-aed5-4-billion-housing-projects-offering-beneficiaries-3-004-new-homes-across-dubai-2025-01-05-1.736056</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-approves-aed5-4-billion-housing-projects-offering-beneficiaries-3-004-new-homes-across-dubai-2025-01-05-1.736056</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong>His Highness emphasises that public wellbeing remains the end goal of all development plans and the primary driver of all government work&nbsp;</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Offering diverse choices for citizens, the projects are aligned with the Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme</strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister of the UAE and Ruler of Dubai, has approved the implementation of a series of housing projects worth AED5.4 billion to benefit citizens across different areas of Dubai.</p>

<p>The projects will see 3,004 new homes being built for Emirati citizens. Of these, 1,181 homes will come up in Latifa City for beneficiaries under the housing loan category. For beneficiaries in the housing grant category, the projects envisage 606 new homes in Al Yalayis 5, 432 homes in Wadi Al Amardi, 398 homes in Al Awir 1, 200 homes in the Makan area of Hatta, 120 homes in Oud Al Muteena, and 67 homes in the countryside and rural areas of Dubai.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The housing projects, offering diverse options for Emirati citizens, align with the Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme launched by Her Highness Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum bin Juma Al Maktoum, wife of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum. The programme aims to support the wellbeing of families in Dubai, strengthen their stability and cohesion, renew community values, enhance the overall quality of family life, offer a stimulating social environment, and help families achieve optimal work-life balance.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed emphasised that citizen wellbeing is the end goal of all development plans and the primary driver of all government work, besides being a key criterion in evaluating the success of development programmes and initiatives in the jobs, manufacturing, infrastructure, and services sectors.</p>

<p>His Highness said: &ldquo;Housing programmes for citizens represent a top priority and we are committed to ensuring that our people have the best living standards and all the support they need to foster stable family environments and community wellbeing. People are the foundation of our renaissance, our successful development experience, and the cornerstone of the global standing we have achieved in all respects.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>Comprehensive plan</strong></p>

<p>His Highness added that major housing initiatives will continue to be part of a comprehensive plan to fulfil the aspirations of citizens for stability and good living standards while helping achieve national strategies to drive ever greater prosperity and shape the future that the people of the UAE truly deserve.</p>

<p>His Excellency Omar Hamad Bu Shehab, CEO of the Mohammed bin Rashid Housing Establishment, said that the new housing projects embody the leadership&rsquo;s vision to offer citizens exceptional quality of life by providing an integrated residential environment that meets all their needs while ensuring the highest levels of comfort and safety.</p>

<p>He added: &ldquo;The housing projects plan is part of a series of projects implemented by the Mohammed bin Rashid Housing Establishment to provide for the future housing needs of Emirati citizens within integrated communities. These plans are implemented drawing upon the best urban planning standards, placing citizens at the forefront of all goals aimed at ensuring public wellbeing over the next 20 years.&rdquo;</p>

<p>According to the Dubai 2040 Urban Master Plan, housing programmes for citizens in Dubai aim to address future housing needs through optimal planning of available spaces in the emirate. This is achieved by ensuring the sustainability of available land in keeping with rigorous standards. A significant effort also goes into ensuring a diverse choice of housing units and communities offering the highest quality of life, with an accent on green spaces, recreational facilities and commercial centres.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 5 Jan 2025 18:53:28 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736058.1736088927!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736058.1736088927!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid approves AED5.4 billion housing projects offering beneficiaries 3,004 new homes across Dubai]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Hind bint Maktoum launches ‘Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme’]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/hind-bint-maktoum-launches-sheikha-hind-bint-maktoum-family-programme-2025-01-04-1.736045</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/hind-bint-maktoum-launches-sheikha-hind-bint-maktoum-family-programme-2025-01-04-1.736045</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>H.H. Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum bin Juma Al Maktoum, wife of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President, Prime Minister and Ruler of Dubai, has launched the &lsquo;Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme&rsquo;.</p>

<p>The programme aims to support the growth, stability and wellbeing of families in Dubai, strengthen community values, enhance quality of life, and promote work-life balance, by offering financial, social, and educational support.</p>

<p>The initiative reflects Her Highness&#39; dedication to empowering Emirati families and fostering their stability and growth.</p>

<p>Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum said the programme reflects H.H. Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum&#39;s vision to strengthen family stability and consolidate the family&rsquo;s status as the nucleus of a cohesive society. It aligns with national priorities to empower Emirati families, uphold their values, and prepare them for future challenges.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Strong families are essential to create a better future. We are committed to fulfilling the aspirations of every Emirati family in Dubai, ensuring their lasting happiness and stability while empowering them to nurture future generations who can shape a brighter tomorrow,&rdquo; Her Highness added.</p>

<p>The &lsquo;Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme&rsquo; introduces a forward-looking vision for the Emirati family with a comprehensive support package that includes wedding support, housing assistance, flexible work policies, and social, financial, and housing awareness and education programmes.</p>

<p>The programme aligns with the objectives of the Dubai Social Agenda 33, which aims to foster happy, connected, and value-driven families and double the number of Emirati families in the emirate by 2033.</p>

<p>The &lsquo;Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme&rsquo; features several key initiatives in its first phase. In collaboration with the Dubai Government Human Resources Department, the programme offers flexible work benefits, including a 10-day paid marriage leave for government sector employees in Dubai and a &lsquo;remote work&rsquo; option on Fridays for mothers during the first year after maternity leave.</p>

<p>The &lsquo;Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme&rsquo; reduces the monthly premium for housing loans to a minimum of AED3,333 for beneficiaries of the Dubai Weddings programme, provided their monthly income does not exceed AED30,000. This initiative aims to ease financial pressures on young people and support their ability to meet other family needs.</p>

<p>In January 2024, under the directives of H.H. Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum bin Juma Al Maktoum, the Community Development Authority in Dubai launched the Dubai Weddings programme, which covers the costs of the main wedding ceremony and provides wedding halls and neighbourhood Majlises free of charge. The Dubai Weddings initiative provides financial support to both husband and wife, easing the financial pressures of marriage. The programme also provides a wide range of discounts to Dubai Weddings beneficiaries including those offered through the Esaad card.</p>

<p>In its first year, the Dubai Weddings programme facilitated 344 weddings, accounting for 28.3% of all Emirati weddings in Dubai by the end of 2024. It also contributed to a 10.1% increase in Emirati weddings last year compared to 2023.</p>

<p>In its first phase, the &lsquo;Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme&rsquo; also offers housing support in collaboration with the Mohammed Bin Rashid Housing Establishment, by prioritising the allocation of ready-made housing for loan beneficiaries under the Dubai Weddings programme.</p>

<p>The &lsquo;Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme&rsquo; includes a range of training initiatives for Dubai Weddings members, such as the &lsquo;Start it Right&rsquo; marital awareness programme. This initiative equips young people with essential skills to wisely plan their lives, fostering the social and emotional tools needed to build happy families and address challenges positively. It offers courses on the social and economic aspects of marriage, emphasising understanding, cooperation, and mutual respect between spouses. To date, 1,013 individuals have benefited from the &lsquo;Start it Right&rsquo; programme, while 208 have benefited from financial support.</p>

<p>The training programmes under the &lsquo;Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme&rsquo; include a financial literacy course for members of the Dubai Weddings initiative. This course provides soon-to-be-married couples with the knowledge needed to plan financially, manage resources effectively, and ensure long-term financial stability. It also emphasises the importance of saving, budgeting, and avoiding debt to safeguard family stability.</p>

<p>The training programmes also include the &lsquo;How to Build Your Home&rsquo; programme for housing loan beneficiaries, in collaboration with the New Economy Academy, aimed at equipping young people with the skills and knowledge necessary to build their homes economically and efficiently.</p>

<p>These benefits apply to new members of the Dubai Weddings programme from 4 January 2025. Those wishing to avail themselves of housing benefits can apply within one year of benefiting from the Dubai Weddings programme.</p>

<p>Future phases of the &lsquo;Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme&rsquo; will expand its scope by introducing new packages and benefits in education, health, and other social services.</p>

<p>All Emirati citizens in Dubai planning to marry can register for the Dubai Weddings programme, provided the prospective bride is an Emirati citizen. Registration is available through the &lsquo;Emirati&rsquo; platform on the Dubai Now app. Alternatively, individuals can register or learn more by visiting the Community Development Authority&#39;s website or contacting the Authority at 800 2121.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sat, 4 Jan 2025 17:50:00 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736046.1736074216!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736046.1736074216!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Hind bint Maktoum launches ‘Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme’]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE Government Issues Federal Decree-Law to Reorganize the Civil Defense Authority]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/uae-government-issues-federal-decree-law-to-reorganize-the-civil-defense-authority-2025-01-03-1.736040</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/uae-government-issues-federal-decree-law-to-reorganize-the-civil-defense-authority-2025-01-03-1.736040</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Establishing a New Civil Defense Authority under the National Emergency, Crisis, and Disasters Management Authority</strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>The UAE Government has issued a federal decree-law to reorganize the Civil Defense Authority, aiming to enhance the country&#39;s readiness to respond to emergencies and disasters while ensuring the highest standards of public safety and protection.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
This decree marks a significant step in modernizing the national civil protection framework. The reorganization focuses on improving coordination between local and federal entities working in civil defense, developing advanced alert and evacuation systems, providing care for affected individuals, and forming specialized teams for relief efforts.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The decree establishes a new entity named the &quot;Civil Defense Authority&quot;, part of the National Emergency, Crisis, and Disasters Management Authority. This new body replaces the Civil Defense Department previously operating under the Ministry of Interior.</p>

<p>The Civil Defense Authority is tasked with strategic responsibilities to enhance civil protection and ensure comprehensive readiness to address risks and disasters. These responsibilities include developing policies, strategies, and regulations related to civil defense in coordination with relevant entities, studying potential risks and incidents, and preparing plans to manage them efficiently.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
The Authority is also responsible for creating hazards prevention programs and establishing safety standards, securing buildings and facilities against fire hazards, and deploying rapid response teams to incident sites to extinguish fires effectively.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Authority&#39;s duties extend to establishing and equipping specialized risk management centers and public alert systems to warn residents of potential hazards. It also prepares evacuation plans for residents when necessary and ensures residential and institutional buildings are adequately equipped. Medical and social care is provided for affected individuals in collaboration with relevant entities.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
To further bolster national preparedness, the Authority is tasked with procuring and maintaining equipment&nbsp; essential for civil defense operations. It also coordinates essential services&mdash;medical, social, engineering, administrative, and educational&mdash;to ensure continuity during times of disasters. Additionally, the Authority organizes efforts and collaborates with entities that have internal security systems, such as oil companies and airports, to provide support as required.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Civil Defense Authority is committed to forming specialized teams to carry out response and relief operations in affected areas. It organizes joint training programs for civil defense personnel and volunteers and implements awareness campaigns to educate residents on the necessary actions during emergencies.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
The Authority&#39;s responsibilities also include monitoring radiological, chemical, and biological hazards and taking the necessary measures to address them in coordination with relevant authorities. Furthermore, it enhances cooperation among UAE emirates to establish support centers that improve civil defense services at national and international levels.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
The Civil Defense Authority prioritizes coordination with entities that maintain internal security and safety systems, such as oil companies and airports, to ensure effective support and assistance when required. This includes organizing methods for providing aid and fostering efficient collaboration during emergencies.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
The Civil Defense Authority is tasked with forming specialized teams for response and relief operations in disaster-affected areas. It organizes training programs and joint simulation exercises for civil defense personnel and volunteers to enhance their readiness for various emergency scenarios. Additionally, the Authority oversees awareness campaigns to educate residents about necessary precautions and procedures during emergencies.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
The Authority requires entities to refrain from issuing any licenses for properties or facilities unless they first obtain a certificate verifying compliance with safety and prevention standards.&nbsp;<br />
The decree establishes a dedicated committee to review compensation claims related to damages caused by civil defense operations, with a grievance mechanism in place. It also enforces strict penalties, including imprisonment of up to (6) six months or fines of up to AED 250,000 for violations of the law or disruptions to civil defense activities.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 3 Jan 2025 19:12:56 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736042.1735917211!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736042.1735917211!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE Government Issues Federal Decree-Law to Reorganize the Civil Defense Authority]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid celebrates his Accession Day by honouring his wife Sheikha Hind]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-celebrates-his-accession-day-by-honouring-his-wife-sheikha-hind-2025-01-03-1.736036</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-celebrates-his-accession-day-by-honouring-his-wife-sheikha-hind-2025-01-03-1.736036</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President, Prime Minister and Ruler of Dubai, graciously dedicated his Accession Day to his esteemed wife, Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum, whom he reverently referred to as the &quot;most beautiful thing&quot; in his life, his &quot;greatest supporter,&quot; and the &ldquo;soul of Dubai&rdquo;</p>

<p>Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid&#39;s Accession Day as Ruler of Dubai falls on 4th January.</p>

<p>In a post on his X account today, His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid said that Sheikha Hind embodies compassion, generosity, and unwavering charity. She is the &#39;&#39;heart of our home, the bedrock of our family, and the guiding star of my professional journey.&#39;&#39;</p>

<p>His Highness described Sheikha Hind as &quot;the Mother of the Sheikhs,&quot; praising her noble qualities and constant generosity.</p>

<p>Sheikh Mohammed wrapped up his note by calling everyone to be loyal to those who deserve loyalty.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 3 Jan 2025 18:20:44 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736037.1735914030!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736037.1735914030!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid celebrates his Accession Day by honouring his wife Sheikha Hind]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[RTA completes traffic improvements at Repton School Dubai in Nad Al Sheba and GEMS Al Khaleej International School in Al Warqa]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/rta-completes-traffic-improvements-at-repton-school-dubai-in-nad-al-sheba-and-gems-al-khaleej-international-school-in-al-warqa-2025-01-02-1.736034</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/rta-completes-traffic-improvements-at-repton-school-dubai-in-nad-al-sheba-and-gems-al-khaleej-international-school-in-al-warqa-2025-01-02-1.736034</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The Roads and Transport Authority (RTA) has completed traffic enhancements at the Repton School Dubai in Nad Al Sheba and GEMS Al Khaleej International School in Al Warqa. These upgrades included the addition of about 150 parking spaces at each school, as well as the provision of safe entrances and exits to the newly expanded parking areas. Designed to improve traffic flow during student drop-off and pick-up times, the enhancements are anticipated to reduce congestion and delays by 35% to 50%.<br />
RTA is dedicated to enhancing the efficiency and flow of Dubai&rsquo;s Road network, with a particular focus on school zones, in line with the urban and developmental growth of the UAE and Dubai. These initiatives serve all road users, including teaching staff, bus drivers, and parents, prioritising the safety of everyone on Dubai&rsquo;s streets.<br />
The traffic enhancements have doubled the parking capacity at Repton School Dubai in Nad Al Sheba to 300 spaces, representing a 100% increase. Similarly, Al Khaleej International School in Al Warqa has seen a 125% expansion in parking capacity, now totalling 270 spaces. These upgrades underscore RTA&rsquo;s ongoing commitment to advancing Dubai&rsquo;s infrastructure, supporting sustainable growth, and enhancing the well-being and happiness of residents in line with the vision of making Dubai the best city in the world to live in.<br />
The improvements encompassed the construction of integrated and safe pedestrian pathways and crossings, along with the installation of directional signage, road markings, and traffic-calming measures in school areas, all designed in compliance with approved technical standards.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 2 Jan 2025 18:22:10 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736035.1735827643!/image/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.JPG" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736035.1735827643!/image/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.JPG" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[RTA completes traffic improvements at Repton School Dubai in Nad Al Sheba and GEMS Al Khaleej International School in Al Warqa]]></media:title>

							<media:description><![CDATA[Works have doubled the parking capacity of the area]]></media:description>
						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Over 2.5 m riders used public transport on New Year’s Eve 2025]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/over-2-5-m-riders-used-public-transport-on-new-year-s-eve-2025-2025-01-01-1.736032</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/over-2-5-m-riders-used-public-transport-on-new-year-s-eve-2025-2025-01-01-1.736032</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The total number of passengers using public transport, shared mobility and taxis in Dubai during the New Year&rsquo;s Eve 2025 celebrations reached 2,502,474, marking a 9.3% increase compared to the 2,288,631 passengers recorded on the same occasion last year.</p>

<p>Across its Red and Green lines, the Dubai Metro accommodated 1,133,251 riders, while the Dubai Tram transported 55,391 riders. Public buses carried a total of 465,779 passengers, and marine transport services ferried 80,066 commuters. Additionally, e-hailing vehicles served 195,651 users, shared transport vehicles catered to 1,238 riders, and taxis transported 571,098 passengers.<br />
The Roads and Transport Authority (RTA) confirmed that passenger movement to and from New Year&rsquo;s Eve celebration venues was seamless and safe, thanks to a comprehensive plan developed in collaboration with relevant entities in Dubai.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 1 Jan 2025 18:23:31 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736033.1735741394!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736033.1735741394!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Over 2.5 m riders used public transport on New Year’s Eve 2025]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[National Center of Meteorology Releases January Climate Summary]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/national-center-of-meteorology-releases-january-climate-summary-2025-01-01-1.736030</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/national-center-of-meteorology-releases-january-climate-summary-2025-01-01-1.736030</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The National Center of Meteorology (NCM) has issued its January climate summary, highlighting key weather patterns and statistics for the month. Known for cooler conditions, January typically experiences a drop in temperatures, with cool days and cold nights. This is attributed to the influence of a high-pressure ridge extending from Siberia, accompanied by a cold air mass affecting the UAE and the Arabian Peninsula.</p>

<h3><strong>Temperature Trends</strong></h3>

<p>Forecasts for January 2025 indicate that the average temperatures will align with or slightly exceed the general average. The national mean temperature for the month is 18.3&deg;C, with notable climatic variations:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Mean air temperature: <strong>16.4&deg;C to 20.0&deg;C</strong></li>
	<li>Mean maximum air temperature: <strong>21.3&deg;C to 25.7&deg;C</strong></li>
	<li>Mean minimum air temperature: <strong>11.6&deg;C to 15.2&deg;C</strong></li>
</ul>

<p>Historical records reveal extreme fluctuations, with the highest maximum temperature of <strong>36.0&deg;C</strong> observed in areas like Asab (1991), Al Hiyer (1983), and Alfoah (1983). The lowest recorded temperature was <strong>-2&deg;C</strong> in Raknah (2021).</p>

<h3><strong>Rainfall and Cloud Development</strong></h3>

<p>The UAE is expected to experience intermittent low-pressure systems moving from west to east. Occasionally, these systems, influenced by upper air troughs and the Red Sea trough, result in cloud formations and rainfall.</p>

<ul>
	<li>Forecasted average rainfall: <strong>11.5 mm</strong></li>
	<li>Highest recorded monthly rainfall: <strong>229.9 mm</strong> at Saqar Port (2020)</li>
</ul>

<h3><strong>Wind and Sea Conditions</strong></h3>

<p>Strong northwesterly winds, locally known as Shamal, are common during January. These winds often stir blowing sand and dust in inland areas, particularly in exposed regions, and contribute to rough sea conditions with increased wave heights.</p>

<ul>
	<li>Mean wind speed: <strong>12 km/h</strong></li>
	<li>Highest wind speed: <strong>99.7 km/h</strong> at Al Gheweifat (2003)</li>
</ul>

<h3><strong>Relative Humidity and Fog Formation</strong></h3>

<p>Humidity levels rise during the early mornings, increasing the likelihood of fog and mist, particularly in inland areas compared to coastal regions.</p>

<ul>
	<li>Mean relative humidity: <strong>63%</strong></li>
	<li>Mean maximum relative humidity: <strong>78% to 91%</strong></li>
	<li>Mean minimum relative humidity: <strong>31% to 47%</strong></li>
</ul>

<p>January 2021 recorded the highest fog and mist occurrences, with <strong>19 foggy days</strong> and <strong>4 misty days</strong>.</p>

<h3><strong>Historical Highlights</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Fog:</strong> The most foggy January occurred in 2021 with significant fog and mist frequencies.</li>
	<li><strong>Rainfall:</strong> The highest recorded monthly rainfall was <strong>229.9 mm</strong> in January 2020.</li>
</ul>

<p>This month&rsquo;s forecasted climatic conditions align with historical averages, underscoring January as a pivotal period for cooler weather, fog development, and occasional rainfall in the UAE.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 1 Jan 2025 18:19:42 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736031.1735741259!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736031.1735741259!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[National Center of Meteorology Releases January Climate Summary]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid bin Mohammed bin Rashid inspects Joint Operations Room of the Events Security Committee]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-bin-mohammed-bin-rashid-inspects-joint-operations-room-of-the-events-security-committee-2024-12-31-1.736024</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-bin-mohammed-bin-rashid-inspects-joint-operations-room-of-the-events-security-committee-2024-12-31-1.736024</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li align="center"><strong>Review meeting involving 55 government, semi-government, and private entities takes stock of elaborate plan to secure New Year festivities</strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum inspected the Joint Operations Room of the Events Security Committee comprising 55 government, semi-government, and private entities. A comprehensive plan to secure the New Year&#39;s Eve 2025 celebrations, covering 36 locations in Dubai, was reviewed. The inspection took place in the presence of His Excellency Lieutenant General Talal Belhoul Al Falasi, Director General of Dubai&#39;s State Security Department; His Excellency Lieutenant General Abdullah Khalifa Al Marri, Commander-in-Chief of Dubai Police, and several directors of government departments, senior officers, and officials.</p>

<p>His Excellency Major General Saif Muhair Al Mazrouei, Acting Assistant Commander-in-Chief for Operations Affairs and Acting Chairman of the Events Security Committee, reviewed the readiness of the participating teams. He briefed His Highness on the capabilities of the Events Security Committee and the strict protocols for securing such major events. A total of 8,530 police officers and 1,145 patrols from Dubai Police have been deployed to secure various celebration sites across the emirate, in addition to 33 marine rescue boats operated by Dubai Police and its partners.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid bin Mohammed bin Rashid was apprised of preparations to secure the New Year&#39;s Eve events during a briefing by His Excellency Expert Major General Ali Hassan Al Mutawa, Assistant Director General for Fire and Rescue Affairs at Dubai Civil Defence. In all, 1,097 firefighters, including officers and non-commissioned officers, will be deployed across various locations to ensure immediate and effective response in emergencies. A total of 257 vital facilities were inspected to ensure their readiness and compliance with safety standards during the celebrations. On the technical front, 123 vehicles with specialised gear are in full readiness to deal with emergencies, backed up by comprehensive logistical support.</p>

<p>His Highness was apprised by Hussein Al Banna, Executive Director of the Traffic and Roads Agency at the Roads and Transport Authority (RTA), on the authority&#39;s preparations to manage traffic flow in accordance with an integrated traffic plan, especially in the Burj Khalifa area. This will be managed through the Traffic Management and Transportation Systems Committee, in direct coordination with the Events Security Committee in Dubai and its strategic partners.</p>

<p><strong>Preparedness for medical emergencies</strong></p>

<p>His Highness also attended a briefing by His Excellency Meshal Abdul Kareem Julfar, Executive Director of the Dubai Corporation for Ambulance Services, on the corporation&#39;s preparations to achieve its strategic objectives of offering rapid response to patients and injured individuals, in addition to providing advanced pre-hospital emergency services. Across the city, 224 ambulance points, including 5 facilities on boats, have been equipped to handle all types of emergencies. Furthermore, 593 paramedics and 29 supervisors have been strategically deployed to ensure utmost responsiveness of ambulance support during the 36 events being held across various areas of the emirate.</p>

<p>The Corporation has allocated 7 ambulances at Dubai Mall, and 19 vehicles with 38 paramedics at Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Boulevard and Burj Khalifa. Apart from this, 4 first responder vehicles, 4 electric bikes, and two bus ambulances are also on call, in addition to the Field Support Unit and the Mobile Medical Store.</p>

<p>In the Boulevard area, 42 volunteers, supervised by paramedics from the Corporation, are on standby. The volunteers have been trained and qualified under the First Responder programme to be effective partners in providing ambulance services by handling simple cases, enhancing the Corporation&#39;s efforts in ensuring rapid response and providing additional support to field teams.</p>

<p>His Highness also attended a briefing by Khalifa Baqer, Chief Operating Officer at Dubai Health, on Dubai Health&rsquo;s plan to ensure prompt medical intervention where required amid the festivities, both at field facilities and at its medical establishments. A fully integrated field hospital has been established in the Burj Khalifa area, and 7 medical points in the celebration site have been reinforced with the services of specialist emergency doctors. Besides this, 6 hospitals and 4 outpatient clinics have been kept on high alert to deal with emergencies. Additionally, 1,800 medical and administrative staff have also been deployed across all DHA facilities to ensure prompt and efficient medical services.</p>

<p><strong>Sub-operations</strong></p>

<p>Brigadier Turki bin Faris, Director of the General Department of Operations at Dubai Police, gave a presentation on the sub-operations at the event sites managed from the Joint Operations Room, along with an overview of the personnel and resources available to manage the event.</p>

<p>His Highness was apprised by Ahmed Al Khaja, CEO of Dubai Festivals and Retail Establishment (DFRE), on the number of events in the emirate during the New Year period and the emirate&#39;s full readiness to host the celebrations, with 175 events and 3,192 activities taking place in the restaurant sector alone. He stressed that the proactive plans developed by the Committee contribute to the success of the various events.</p>

<p>His Highness also inspected supply tents in Downtown Dubai that provide services pertaining to lost and found items, first aid services, logistical support, receiving and caring for lost children, and helping guide visitors, among other services.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 19:42:39 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736025.1735659815!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736025.1735659815!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid bin Mohammed bin Rashid inspects Joint Operations Room of the Events Security Committee]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE President issues Federal Decree appointing Sultan Al Dhaheri as Director of Office of Deputy Chairman of Presidential Court for Special Affairs]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/uae-president-issues-federal-decree-appointing-sultan-al-dhaheri-as-director-of-office-of-deputy-chairman-of-presidential-court-for-special-affairs-2024-12-31-1.736020</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/uae-president-issues-federal-decree-appointing-sultan-al-dhaheri-as-director-of-office-of-deputy-chairman-of-presidential-court-for-special-affairs-2024-12-31-1.736020</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan issued a Federal Decree appointing His Excellency Sultan Hamad Ahmad Hamad Al Mutawa Al Dhaheri as Director of the Office of the Deputy Chairman of the Presidential Court for Special Affairs with the rank of Undersecretary.</p>

<p>The Decree shall be published in the official gazette and shall be effective from the date of issuance.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 18:41:48 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736021.1735656081!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736021.1735656081!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE President issues Federal Decree appointing Sultan Al Dhaheri as Director of Office of Deputy Chairman of Presidential Court for Special Affairs]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed meets with dignitaries and senior officials at Za'abeel Majlis]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/hamdan-bin-mohammed-meets-with-dignitaries-and-senior-officials-at-za-abeel-majlis-2024-12-31-1.736018</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/hamdan-bin-mohammed-meets-with-dignitaries-and-senior-officials-at-za-abeel-majlis-2024-12-31-1.736018</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Vision, innovation and teamwork are key drivers of Dubai&rsquo;s development journey, says His Highness</p>

<p>&ldquo;As we welcome the New Year, our focus remains on advancing our goals with optimism and determination, and transforming challenges into opportunities to create a brighter future&rdquo;</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defence of the UAE, and Chairman of The Executive Council of Dubai, underscored the vital role of strategic vision, teamwork, and innovation, in driving Dubai&#39;s sustainable development journey.</p>

<p>Speaking at a meeting with dignitaries and senior officials at the Za&#39;abeel Majlis, Sheikh Hamdan outlined Dubai&#39;s focus on groundbreaking initiatives that set new benchmarks of excellence across sectors. The event was attended by Her Highness Sheikha Latifa bint Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Chairperson of the Dubai Culture and Arts Authority; His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum; and several ministers and senior officials.</p>

<p>Extending his New Year greetings to all attendees, Sheikh Hamdan urged them to continue their efforts to enhance Dubai&#39;s global reputation. &ldquo;As we welcome the New Year, our focus remains on advancing our goals with optimism and determination, and transforming challenges into opportunities to create a brighter future,&rdquo; he said.</p>

<p>Innovative projects and services that exceed expectations are vital to ensuring Dubai remains one of the world&rsquo;s best cities to live, work and visit, he said. Highlighting Dubai&#39;s global reputation for quality of life and economic opportunity, he said outstanding services, sustainable development initiatives, and programmes to empower national talent, particularly youth, are critical to maintaining this status.<br />
Stressing further on the need to develop young national talent, he said: &ldquo;Empowering our youth to take on leading roles across sectors is essential to achieving our vision for the future.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The meeting also highlighted Dubai&#39;s outstanding achievements in 2024, including exceptional advancements in innovation and technology, robust growth in the digital economy, and strengthened capabilities in financial and logistical services. Dubai&#39;s tourism sector continued to thrive, further consolidating the emirate&#39;s reputation as a global business and leisure destination.<br />
With its forward-thinking policies and dynamic leadership, Dubai is poised to enter the new year with a renewed commitment to progress and innovation, His Highness said.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 18:36:02 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736019.1735655817!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736019.1735655817!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed meets with dignitaries and senior officials at Za'abeel Majlis]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Final Deadline for Visa Violators in the UAE Ends Tomorrow]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/final-deadline-for-visa-violators-in-the-uae-ends-tomorrow-2024-12-30-1.736004</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/final-deadline-for-visa-violators-in-the-uae-ends-tomorrow-2024-12-30-1.736004</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The deadline for regularizing the status of residency law violators in the UAE concludes tomorrow. The Federal Authority for Identity, Citizenship, Customs, and Port Security had extended the grace period by an additional two months, allowing violators to rectify their status without incurring fines or administrative penalties. Initially, the deadline was set to end on October 31, 2024.</p>

<h3><strong>Last Chance to Benefit</strong></h3>

<p>The Authority urged violators of the residency law currently residing in the UAE to take advantage of the final three days of the grace period. They are encouraged to visit service centers across the country to amend their status and benefit from the opportunities provided. Thousands of violators have already utilized this window to either regularize their status or leave the country without facing any financial penalties.</p>

<p>The decision to extend the grace period coincided with the UAE&#39;s celebrations of its 53rd National Day, reflecting the nation&#39;s humanitarian and progressive values. The extension was also in response to appeals from violators seeking to settle their status, either by leaving the country or securing employment contracts to stay legally. The Federal Authority has been actively coordinating through official channels and conducting in-depth studies to evaluate public response and the volume of applications processed at service centers nationwide, particularly in the final days of the initial deadline.</p>

<h3><strong>Fraudulent Practices Uncovered</strong></h3>

<p>Lieutenant General Mohammed Al Marri noted that many violators fell victim to fraudulent practices in their home countries before arriving in the UAE. These individuals were misled into paying fees for visas and promised job opportunities in the UAE, only to discover upon arrival that such opportunities did not exist. He emphasized that these fraudulent schemes are not confined to specific countries but are a widespread issue perpetrated by traffickers globally.</p>

<h3><strong>Successful Employment for Violators</strong></h3>

<p>Al Marri also highlighted the success of Dubai authorities in securing employment for a significant number of violators within the private sector. The Labor Committee in Dubai worked daily with companies seeking workers, facilitating interviews and placements for violators already present in the country. This initiative helped many individuals transition from violating residency regulations to becoming legally employed contributors to the UAE&#39;s economy.</p>

<p>The Authority continues to urge all violators to take immediate action and seize this final opportunity to regularize their status or leave the country without penalties.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:54:07 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736005.1735541875!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736005.1735541875!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Final Deadline for Visa Violators in the UAE Ends Tomorrow]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[1st January announced as official holiday for Dubai government departments]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/1st-january-announced-as-official-holiday-for-dubai-government-departments-2024-12-27-1.735989</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/1st-january-announced-as-official-holiday-for-dubai-government-departments-2024-12-27-1.735989</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The Dubai Government Human Resources (DGHR) Department has announced 1st January 2025, (Wednesday), as an official holiday for Dubai government departments for the occasion of New Year&rsquo;s Day.</p>

<p>Official work will resume as usual on 2nd January 2025 (Thursday).</p>

<p>Entities, departments and institutions operating on shift systems or those involved in public services, or management of public facilities are exempted from this holiday. These entities are authorised to determine the working hours for their staff based on operational requirements to ensure smooth functioning of public services and facilities during the holiday.</p>

<p>The Department extended its heartfelt wishes to the leadership, government, and people of the UAE, as well as its residents, wishing everybody a blessed and prosperous New Year.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:31:19 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735990.1735299067!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735990.1735299067!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[1st January announced as official holiday for Dubai government departments]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid reviews progress of AED3.6 billion Hatta development projects, visits Hatta Winter Festival]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-reviews-progress-of-aed3-6-billion-hatta-development-projects-visits-hatta-winter-festival-2024-12-26-1.735975</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-reviews-progress-of-aed3-6-billion-hatta-development-projects-visits-hatta-winter-festival-2024-12-26-1.735975</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President, Prime Minister and Ruler of Dubai, said today that Dubai remains committed to continuously enhancing its services, facilities, and infrastructure to consolidate its position as one of the world&rsquo;s best cities to live, work, and visit.</p>

<p>Speaking during a visit to Hatta, His Highness also emphasised the vital role of youth in driving sustainable development. &quot;Our projects empower people, create opportunities, and ensure prosperity. Our objective is to make Hatta a global model for harmony between humans and nature, driven by innovation in sustainable development,&quot; he added.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid reviewed the progress of key development projects aligned with Dubai&rsquo;s Vision 2030, the Dubai Economic Agenda D33, and the Dubai Social Agenda 33.</p>

<p>Upon arrival, His Highness was welcomed by Mattar Al Tayer, Director-General and Chairman of the Board of Executive Directors of the Roads and Transport Authority (RTA) and Chairman of the Supreme Committee to Oversee the Development of Hatta; Saeed Mohammed Al Tayer, MD &amp; CEO of the Dubai Electricity and Water Authority (DEWA); and other senior officials.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed was briefed by Mattar Al Tayer on the progress of 65 initiatives in Hatta, featuring a total value of AED3.6 billion, 41 of which have been completed.</p>

<p>The projects are part of the Hatta Master Development Plan, aimed at improving quality of life, enhancing services for residents and visitors, and accelerating the region&rsquo;s social, economic, and educational development.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed and his entourage visited the Hatta Winter Festival, one of the five festivals that form part of Hatta Winter 2024. Launched earlier this month by H.H. Sheikh Ahmed bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Second Deputy Ruler of Dubai and Chairman of the Dubai Media Council, Hatta Winter, running until 22nd January, 2025, spotlights Hatta&rsquo;s growing profile as a must-visit winter destination, combining cultural, entertainment, educational and sports activities catering to people of all ages.</p>

<p>Shaima Al Suwaidi, Director of Brand Dubai, the creative arm of the Government of Dubai Media Office, briefed His Highness about the initiative, which includes four other festivals: Hatta Cultural Nights organised by the Dubai Culture and Arts Authority, Hatta Honey Festival and Hatta Agricultural Festival, both organised by Dubai Municipality, and Hatta x DSF organised by the Dubai Department of Economy and Tourism.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed was briefed on the initiative&rsquo;s focus on promoting local projects, creating opportunities for the private sector and entrepreneurs based in Hatta, and highlighting the offerings of members of Brand Dubai&rsquo;s Proudly From Dubai network. His Highness commended Brand Dubai&#39;s efforts to support tourism and commercial development in the area through the Hatta Winter initiative.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed unveiled the Hatta Sustainable Waterfalls project, implemented by DEWA as part of the Hatta Master Development Plan. The project features a stunning waterfall descending from the Hatta Dam, and the world&rsquo;s largest mosaic panel on the waterfall&rsquo;s slope, recognised by Guinness World Records. Covering 2,200 square metres and crafted from 1.2 million pieces of natural marble, the mosaic pays tribute to the UAE&rsquo;s founding fathers, the late Sheikh Zayed bin Sultan Al Nahyan and Sheikh Rashid bin Saeed Al Maktoum. The Hatta Sustainable Waterfalls project aims to boost tourism and investment in the region, with retail stores and F&amp;B outlets offered free of charge to local Emirati citizens.</p>

<p>His Highness was also briefed on DEWA&rsquo;s projects in Hatta, including the 250 MW pumped-storage hydroelectric power plant, the 30 million imperial gallon water reservoir, the strategic water interconnection projects with other emirates, and the Shams Dubai Initiative, which encourages residents and businesses to install photovoltaic panels on rooftops to generate solar energy and connect to DEWA&rsquo;s electricity grid.</p>

<p>During the tour, His Highness Sheikh Mohammed visited successful projects launched by Khalifa and Ahmed Al Bedwawi, two young engineers from Hatta. Their GoGravity project, launched in 2018, manufactures electric bikes for mountainous areas and rugged terrain. Embodying the &lsquo;Made in the UAE&rsquo; spirit, the project has now expanded to include international exports.</p>

<p>His Highness was briefed on the project and saw a model of their four-wheeled electric bikes.His Highness also visited the Al Bedwawi Honey project, where he learned about its beekeeping and honey production activities from Emirati entrepreneur Mohammed bin Ham Al Bedwawi.</p>

<p>During the visit, His Highness engaged with Hatta&#39;s citizens and discussed ongoing development efforts. Sheikh Mohammed listened to their ideas and suggestions for further developing Hatta&#39;s potential, leveraging its natural and heritage resources.</p>

<p>His Highness was briefed on three ongoing projects in Hatta being implemented in partnership with the private sector. The Hatta Beach project, covering 53,000 square metres, aims to transform the area into a year-round tourist destination. It features a 10,000-square-metre beach, an artificial &lsquo;Crystal Lagoon&rsquo;, service facilities, rest areas, pedestrian pathways, cycling tracks, restaurants, food trucks, and an outdoor cinema, in addition to offering swimming and water sports activities. The other two projects include the development of hotels and resorts and the Hatta Downtown project.</p>

<p>His Highness also reviewed 24 ongoing projects in Hatta, including a world class model school for 700-1,000 students. He also reviewed the Hatta Majlis project, a community gathering space for 100 people. Other projects include a 1,000-guest wedding hall, the Hatta Dam Amphitheatre, the Hatta Service Centre, 200 homes for Emirati citizens, and a model residential neighbourhood.</p>

<p>The project portfolio also includes expansion of cycling and mountain biking trails, the first-of-its-kind hydroelectric power station in the GCC region with a capacity of 250 MW and 1,500 MWh storage, and the Dubai Mountain Peak cable car. The 5.4-kilometre cable car will transport tourists from Hatta Dam to the summit of Um Al Nesoor Peak, the highest natural summit in Dubai, passing over the Hatta Lake, the hydroelectric power station, and the surrounding mountains.</p>

<p>Other projects include the development of the Hatta Hospital, enhancements to the Hatta Sports Club, and the maintenance of dams across the region.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 23:16:00 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735976.1735243416!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735976.1735243416!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid reviews progress of AED3.6 billion Hatta development projects, visits Hatta Winter Festival]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid approves appointment of Director for Federal Youth Authority]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-approves-appointment-of-director-for-federal-youth-authority-2024-12-26-1.735973</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-approves-appointment-of-director-for-federal-youth-authority-2024-12-26-1.735973</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President, Prime Minister and Ruler of Dubai, has approved a decision regarding the appointment of Khaled Mohammed Rashid Al Nuaimi as Director of the Federal Youth Authority, with the rank of Under-Secretary.</p>

<p>Khaled Al Nuaimi is a graduate of the UAE Government Leaders Programme and has held several positions at the Higher Colleges of Technology, including Director of Communications and Senior Manager of Marketing and Partnerships.</p>

<p>He holds a Master&rsquo;s degree in Business Administration from the University of Dubai and a Bachelor&rsquo;s degree in Finance from the Higher Colleges of Technology in 2013.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 23:01:00 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735974.1735243292!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735974.1735243292!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid approves appointment of Director for Federal Youth Authority]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed appoints Ahmed Al Muhairi as Assistant Director General of Dubai’s Protocol and Hospitality Department for the Protocol of Dubai’s Second Deputy Ruler]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/hamdan-bin-mohammed-appoints-ahmed-al-muhairi-as-assistant-director-general-of-dubai-s-protocol-and-hospitality-department-for-the-protocol-of-dubai-s-second-deputy-ruler-2024-12-25-1.735963</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/hamdan-bin-mohammed-appoints-ahmed-al-muhairi-as-assistant-director-general-of-dubai-s-protocol-and-hospitality-department-for-the-protocol-of-dubai-s-second-deputy-ruler-2024-12-25-1.735963</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister, and Minister of Defence, in his capacity as the Chairman of The Executive Council of Dubai, has issued Executive Council Resolution No. (102) of 2024, appointing Ahmed Awad Ahmed Al Haj Al Muhairi as Assistant Director General of Dubai&rsquo;s Protocol and Hospitality Department for the Protocol of the Second Deputy Ruler of Dubai.</p>

<p>The Resolution is effective from the date of its issuance and will be published in the Official Gazette.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:11:01 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735964.1735128726!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735964.1735128726!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed appoints Ahmed Al Muhairi as Assistant Director General of Dubai’s Protocol and Hospitality Department for the Protocol of Dubai’s Second Deputy Ruler]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE President receives Mohammed bin Rashid bin Mohammed bin Rashid]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/uae-president-receives-mohammed-bin-rashid-bin-mohammed-bin-rashid-2024-12-24-1.735959</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/uae-president-receives-mohammed-bin-rashid-bin-mohammed-bin-rashid-2024-12-24-1.735959</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan received H.H. Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum in the presence of H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister, and Minister of Defence.</p>

<p>His Highness the President congratulated him on recently graduating from the Royal Military Academy Sandhurst in the United Kingdom, as well as receiving the Sword of Honour for international students and first place in academic and applied military studies, thereby becoming the first Emirati graduate to be granted both honours.</p>

<p>During the meeting, which took place at Qasr Al Bahr in Abu Dhabi, His Highness the President expressed his pride in H.H. Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum and all Emiratis who represent the country and its youth through their diligence and perseverance, noting that his achievements affirm the ability of Emirati youth to excel academically and professionally. Furthermore, His Highness the President wished him success in serving his country.</p>

<p>In turn, H.H. Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum conveyed his gratitude to His Highness the President, underscoring that His Highness&rsquo; remarks encourage him to strive for continued success.</p>

<p>The meeting was attended by H.H. Sheikh Khaled bin Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi; H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Ruler&rsquo;s Representative in the Al Dhafra Region; H.H. Sheikh Nahyan bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Chairman of the Board of Trustees of Zayed bin Sultan Al Nahyan Charitable and Humanitarian Foundation; H.H. Sheikh Dr. Sultan bin Khalifa Al Nahyan, Advisor to His Highness the UAE President; H.H. Sheikh Theyab bin Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Chairman of the Presidential Court for Development and Fallen Heroes&#39; Affairs; and H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Chairman of Presidential Court for Special Affairs; along with a number of other sheikhs, ministers, senior officials, UAE citizens, and guests.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 21:07:36 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735960.1735060039!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735960.1735060039!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE President receives Mohammed bin Rashid bin Mohammed bin Rashid]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai announces comprehensive security plan for 2025 New Year's Eve celebrations]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/dubai-announces-comprehensive-security-plan-for-2025-new-year-s-eve-celebrations-2024-12-24-1.735953</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/dubai-announces-comprehensive-security-plan-for-2025-new-year-s-eve-celebrations-2024-12-24-1.735953</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>- Plan covers fireworks displays at 36 locations<br />
- 8,530 police officers, and 1,145 patrols deployed to ensure safety and security<br />
- Dubai divided into four operational sectors to streamline safety measures and enhance public services, building on last year&rsquo;s success<br />
- Key road closures announced for New Year&rsquo;s Eve in Dubai<br />
- Dubai Metro (Red and Green lines) will operate continuously for 43 hours from 5:00 AM on 31 December 2024 until midnight on 1 January 2025<br />
- Emergency and non-emergency reports can be made on the toll-free numbers 999 and 901, respectively<br />
- Abdulla Khalifa Al Marri calls for public cooperation, adherence to guidelines, and the immediate reporting of suspicious behaviour to ensure safe and enjoyable New Year&#39;s Eve</p>

<p>The Events Security Committee in Dubai has confirmed its comprehensive preparations to ensure the safety and security of the 2025 New Year&rsquo;s Eve celebrations.</p>

<p>Building on the success of last year&rsquo;s plan, the emirate will once again be divided into four operational sectors&mdash;North, Central, West, and Maritime&mdash;to streamline safety measures and enhance public services in collaboration with strategic partners.</p>

<p>The committee, in coordination with the Permanent Committee for Labour Affairs, has also arranged dedicated viewing areas for workers.</p>

<p>These zones will feature large screens and meal services, allowing workers to enjoy the celebrations, including the fireworks, safely and conveniently while reducing the need for movement to crowded event locations.</p>

<p>Event overview and deployment<br />
The 2025 celebrations will feature fireworks displays at 36 locations across Dubai. Key sites include Burj Khalifa; Global Village; Bab Al Shams Desert Resort; Atlantis The Royal; Al Marmoom Oasis; Expo City; Dubai Frame; and Dubai Design District, among others.</p>

<p>To ensure safety, Dubai Police will deploy 8,530 officers and 1,145 patrols, supported by 33 marine rescue boats, Civil Defence vehicles, and ambulances. Six mobile operations rooms will monitor activities across the emirate.</p>

<p>Dedicated tents will be set up in Downtown Dubai, offering:<br />
&bull; Lost and found services<br />
&bull; First aid<br />
&bull; Logistical support<br />
&bull; Assistance for lost children<br />
&bull; Guidance for visitors</p>

<p>Security plan announcement<br />
During a press conference held at the InterContinental Dubai Festival City, Dubai officials announced the comprehensive security, organisational, and service plans for the New Year&#39;s Eve celebrations.</p>

<p>The press conference was attended by His Excellency Expert Major General Khalil Ibrahim Al Mansouri, Assistant Commander-in-Chief for Criminal Investigation Affairs; His Excellency Major General Saif Muhair Al Mazroui, Acting Assistant Commander-in-Chief for Operations and Chair of the Events Security Committee; His Excellency Mishal Abdul Karim Julfar, CEO of Dubai Corporation for Ambulance Services; His Excellency Expert Major General Ali Hassan Al Mutawa, Assistant Director-General for Fire and Rescue, Dubai Civil Defence; Hussain Al Banna, Executive Director, Roads and Transport Authority (RTA); Adel Al Marzouqi, Executive Director, Dubai Municipality; and representatives from 55 government and private entities.</p>

<p>Major General Khalil Ibrahim Al Mansouri commended the 55 entities&#39; collaborative efforts, highlighting their unified and coordinated approach to delivering the highest levels of safety. He emphasised that preparatory measures included coordination meetings, tabletop exercises, and on-site inspections at the 36 event locations.<br />
He further noted the success of dividing the emirate into operational sectors in 2024 and confirmed this strategy will continue.</p>

<p>&bull; North Sector: includes four event locations<br />
&bull; Central Sector: covers nine locations<br />
&bull; West Sector: comprises 23 locations<br />
&bull; Maritime Sector: ensures safety at all coastal and water-based events</p>

<p>Major General Al Mansouri added that six mobile operation rooms will provide additional support, ensuring seamless communication between entities.</p>

<p>Public Appeal<br />
Major General Al Mansouri urged the public to cooperate with Dubai Police, follow traffic instructions, and avoid congested areas. Emergency and non-emergency reports can be made via the toll-free numbers 999 and 901, respectively.</p>

<p>Public Transport<br />
Hussain Al Banna detailed the RTA&#39;s traffic and transport plan, especially for the Burj Khalifa area:</p>

<p>Traffic Management<br />
Road Closures:<br />
&bull; Al Asayel Street from Oud Metha Road to Burj Khalifa: from 4:00 PM<br />
&bull; Mohammed Bin Rashid Boulevard, Burj Khalifa Street, and Al Mustaqbal Street: from 4:00 PM, depending on parking availability<br />
&bull; Lower Financial Centre Street: from 4:00 PM<br />
&bull; Upper Financial Centre Street and Al Sukook Street: from 8:00 PM<br />
&bull; Public Advisory: Guests with bookings in the area must arrive before 4:00 PM.</p>

<p>Metro and tram services<br />
&bull; Dubai Metro (Red and Green lines) will operate continuously for 43 hours from 5:00 AM on 31 December 2024 until midnight on 1 January 2025.</p>

<p>Shuttle Services and Parking<br />
&bull; 260 buses (20 double-deckers, 240 standard) will transport guests to key locations.<br />
&bull; Additional parking (900 spaces) will be available at Al Wasl Club (500) and Al Jaffiliya (400), with shuttle buses running from 3:00 PM.</p>

<p>Crowd management<br />
Traffic lights near major areas will be monitored in real-time, and pedestrian routes to buses and metro stations will be clearly marked. Smart screens will alert drivers about road closures and alternative routes.</p>

<p>Dubai Municipality measures<br />
Adel Al Marzouqi confirmed Dubai Municipality&#39;s preparedness, with the deployment of 2,776 staff, including 242 supervisors and 2,534 sanitation workers, supported by 246 vehicles. The plan focuses on public health, food safety, and the cleanliness of public spaces.<br />
&bull; Food Safety: Inspections will be conducted at malls, hotels, restaurants, and public event sites.<br />
&bull; Park and Beach Management: Special teams will secure public parks, recreational areas, and beaches, with lifeguards on duty, particularly at night.<br />
&bull; Waste Management: Round-the-clock operations will ensure cleanliness at event sites.</p>

<p>Dubai Civil Defence preparedness<br />
Major General Ali Hassan Al Mutawa announced the deployment of 1,097 firefighters and 123 advanced vehicles across five sectors. Inspections of 257 critical facilities have ensured compliance with safety standards.</p>

<p>Dubai Civil Defence will send 500,000 safety messages to attendees via SMS and has urged the public to comply with safety guidelines.</p>

<p>Ambulance services<br />
Mishal Abdul Karim Julfar detailed Dubai Ambulance&#39;s exceptional readiness, including 224 emergency points and 593 paramedics. Strategic deployment covers key areas like Dubai Mall, Sheikh Mohammed Bin Rashid Boulevard, and Hatta. Resources deployed include:<br />
&bull; Five marine rescue boats<br />
&bull; Seven ambulances at Dubai Mall<br />
&bull; 19 ambulances and 38 paramedics near Burj Khalifa</p>

<p>Volunteer Programme: 42 trained volunteers will support medical teams in handling minor cases.<br />
Public guidance includes carrying necessary medications and contacting 998 or the Dubai Ambulance app in case of emergencies.</p>

<p>His Excellency Lieutenant General Abdulla Khalifa Al Marri, stated: &quot;As Dubai prepares to welcome the new year, Dubai Police and our key partners have stepped up the measures to deliver unmatched security and services during this global event. Over the years, our accumulated expertise has set benchmarks in event management, aligning with Dubai&#39;s position as a leader in hosting world-class celebrations.&quot;</p>

<p>Al Marri called for public cooperation, adherence to guidelines, and the immediate reporting of suspicious behaviour to ensure a safe and enjoyable New Year&#39;s Eve for all.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 18:38:34 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735954.1735051099!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735954.1735051099!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai announces comprehensive security plan for 2025 New Year's Eve celebrations]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[RTA expands nol Card services to enable e-scooter payments]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/rta-expands-nol-card-services-to-enable-e-scooter-payments-2024-12-24-1.735951</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/rta-expands-nol-card-services-to-enable-e-scooter-payments-2024-12-24-1.735951</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Dubai&rsquo;s Roads and Transport Authority (RTA) has expanded its payment solutions for electric scooter users by introducing nol Card as an additional payment option. This service is now available for scooters operated by RTA-accredited providers throughout the emirate.</p>

<p>Salahuddin AlMarzooqi, Director of Automated Collection Systems at RTA&rsquo;s Corporate Technology Support Sector, stated, &ldquo;This initiative aligns with RTA&rsquo;s vision to enhance first and last-mile connectivity by seamlessly integrating public transport with flexible mobility solutions. By introducing the nol Card as a convenient payment method, we aim to provide users with an efficient and user-friendly experience.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He added that nol Card had been incorporated as a new payment method on all authorised electric scooter operator apps. Users can now purchase various packages&mdash;hourly, daily, or monthly&mdash;by linking their nol Card via NFC technology on their smartphones. To access this service, users simply need to download the operator&rsquo;s app.</p>

<p>nol Card is already widely accepted for public transport, including the metro, buses, trams, and marine transport, as well as private transport services like taxis, the Nakheel Monorail, and electric scooters.</p>

<p>RTA has also embarked on upgrading the nol system from traditional Card-Based Ticketing to a modern Account-Based System. This advanced system adheres to global best practices, ensuring the highest standards of electronic and financial security. The upgrade aims to enhance the technologies used in payment systems, improve operational efficiency, and maximise the utilisation of data generated by the system.</p>

<p>Additionally, it seeks to customise services and products to meet customer needs. The new system will offer several innovative features, including trip planning, booking, and pre-payment through smart channels, further advancing Dubai&rsquo;s smart mobility ecosystem.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 18:36:29 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735952.1735050974!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735952.1735050974!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[RTA expands nol Card services to enable e-scooter payments]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid issues Decree establishing Dubai Resilience Centre]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-issues-decree-establishing-dubai-resilience-centre-2024-12-23-1.735949</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-issues-decree-establishing-dubai-resilience-centre-2024-12-23-1.735949</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>In his capacity as the Ruler of Dubai, His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister, has issued Decree No. (48) of 2024 establishing the Dubai Resilience Centre, a new public entity that aims to reinforce Dubai&rsquo;s status as one of the world&rsquo;s most agile cities in addressing risks, emergencies, crises, and disasters.</p>

<p>In a significant initiative to strengthen the emirate&rsquo;s crisis and disaster management capabilities, the Decree grants the new entity, operating under Dubai&rsquo;s Supreme Committee of Crisis and Disaster Management, the legal authority and capacity to implement actions and transactions necessary to fulfil its mandate.</p>

<p>The Decree outlines the Centre&#39;s objectives, foremost of which is making Dubai the world&rsquo;s most agile city in dealing with various risks, emergencies, crises, and disasters, and ensuring it has the ability to take measures to prevent and address such events and ensure rapid recovery if they occur. It will also coordinate and direct joint efforts to deal with any event effectively, and support the Supreme Committee&#39;s efforts in this regard.</p>

<p>The Decree outlines the responsibilities of the Dubai Resilience Centre, most notably, preparing and developing the resilience plan, supporting policies, strategic procedures, and the general framework for crisis resilience in the emirate of Dubai, in coordination with the Executive Committee of the Supreme Committee of Crisis and Disaster Management and relevant authorities in Dubai, and submitting them to the Supreme Committee for approval by The Executive Council of Dubai. Further, the Centre is responsible for measuring performance indicators and the rate of progress in implementing approved plans and programmes and submitting regular reports to the Supreme Committee.</p>

<p>The Centre is responsible for managing a central operations platform for crisis and disaster management and establishing online links with relevant authorities in Dubai to achieve its objectives. It will also establish partnerships and cooperation agreements with specialised entities at local, regional, and international levels to carry out its mission.</p>

<p>Additionally, the Centre will collect and analyse data from relevant authorities to conduct studies and forecasts that support the development of plans and scenarios to address threats, risks, emergencies, crises, and disasters. It aims to implement effective response strategies and propose initiatives and programmes to raise awareness about the importance of crisis preparedness and the best methods for managing such situations.</p>

<p>The Centre will develop simulations and scenario-based exercises for enhancing preparedness to deal with risks, emergencies, crises, and disasters; document outcomes and lessons learned; and submit them to the Supreme Committee for approval.</p>

<p>The Decree outlines the executive structure of the Dubai Resilience Centre, which will be led by an Executive Director appointed by the Chairman of The Executive Council of Dubai. Key responsibilities include proposing policies and strategic plans aligned with Dubai&#39;s goals for approval by the Supreme Committee of Crisis and Disaster Management, overseeing policy implementation, setting performance targets, measuring progress, and coordinating with relevant authorities to develop improvement plans.</p>

<p>Decree No. (48) of 2024 obliges all government and non-government entities in Dubai to fully cooperate with the Centre, provide the necessary support, data, information, documents, statistics, and studies it requests to carry out its tasks.</p>

<p>His Highness the Chairman of the Supreme Committee of Crisis and Disaster Management will issue the decisions necessary to implement the provisions of this Decree. The provisions of any other legislation that conflicts with the Decree will be annulled.</p>

<p>The Decree is effective from the date of its issuance and will be published in the Official Gazette.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 22:27:25 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735950.1734978429!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735950.1734978429!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid issues Decree establishing Dubai Resilience Centre]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
