<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
	<title>Mobile - World</title>
	<link>http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-world-1.708765?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout</link>	
	<atom:link href="http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-world-1.708765?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" ></atom:link>
	<description>World</description>
			        <language>en</language>
    				<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Three UAE aid convoys arrive in Gaza Strip as part of 'Operation Chivalrous Knight 3']]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/three-uae-aid-convoys-arrive-in-gaza-strip-as-part-of-operation-chivalrous-knight-3-2025-01-05-1.736054</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/three-uae-aid-convoys-arrive-in-gaza-strip-as-part-of-operation-chivalrous-knight-3-2025-01-05-1.736054</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Three UAE convoys loaded with various humanitarian aid crossed this week into the Gaza Strip through the Egyptian Rafah Border Crossing.</p>

<p>This is part of the UAE&#39;s efforts to support and provide relief to the Palestinians during the current circumstances in line with &quot;Operation Chivalrous Knight 3&quot;.</p>

<p>The convoys consist of 29 trucks carrying more than 364 tonnes of humanitarian aid. This includes food, winter clothing, shelter tents and other essential needs.</p>

<p>This brings the number of aid convoys that have entered the Gaza Strip through Egyptian border crossings as part of Operation Chivalrous Knight 3, to 150 convoys consisting of 2,319 trucks transporting more than 29,025 tonnes.</p>

<p>Since the start of the crisis, the UAE has provided 46,659 tonnes of urgent relief supplies to the Gaza Strip. This aims to contribute to alleviating the difficult conditions suffered by the people of Gaza.</p>

<p>Operation Chivalrous Knight 3 seeks to assist all affected groups in the Gaza Strip, especially children and women. The UAE is keen to intensify relief efforts and promote humanitarian work for Palestinians.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 5 Jan 2025 18:48:44 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736055.1736088511!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736055.1736088511!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Three UAE aid convoys arrive in Gaza Strip as part of 'Operation Chivalrous Knight 3']]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE President meets with Prime Minister of Pakistan]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-meets-with-prime-minister-of-pakistan-2025-01-05-1.736049</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-meets-with-prime-minister-of-pakistan-2025-01-05-1.736049</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan today met with His Excellency Muhammad Shehbaz Sharif, Prime Minister of the Islamic Republic of Pakistan.</p>

<p>During the meeting, which took place in the city of Rahim Yar Khan in Pakistan, His Highness and the Pakistani Prime Minister discussed cooperation between the UAE and Pakistan and opportunities to enhance ties, especially in the economic, trade, developmental, and other fields that serve their mutual interests and aspirations for sustainable economic development and prosperity for their peoples.</p>

<p>This came as part of the close historical relations that unite the two countries and their shared interest in continuing to develop these ties.</p>

<p>During the meeting, the two sides also exchanged views on a number of regional and international issues of common interest.</p>

<p>For his part, His Excellency Muhammad Shehbaz Sharif underscored his pride in the strong friendship between his country and the UAE, expressing his appreciation to His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan for the continuous support provided by the UAE to Pakistan, especially in developmental fields and through the UAE&#39;s notable initiatives in this regard.</p>

<p>His Excellency stressed the two countries&#39; keenness to strengthen relations and further develop bilateral cooperation in all economic, investment, and developmental fields in a way that benefits their peoples and contributes to achieving joint interests.</p>

<p>The meeting was attended by H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Chairman of the Presidential Court for Special Affairs; Ali bin Hammad Al Shamsi, Secretary-General of the Supreme Council for National Security; and Hamad Obaid Al Zaabi, UAE Ambassador to Pakistan.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 5 Jan 2025 18:41:50 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736050.1736088024!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736050.1736088024!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE President meets with Prime Minister of Pakistan]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE's successful mediation between Russia, Ukraine reflects its role in promoting global peace: President of Arab Parliament]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-s-successful-mediation-between-russia-ukraine-reflects-its-role-in-promoting-global-peace-president-of-arab-parliament-2024-12-31-1.736028</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-s-successful-mediation-between-russia-ukraine-reflects-its-role-in-promoting-global-peace-president-of-arab-parliament-2024-12-31-1.736028</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Mohammed Ahmed Al Yamahi, President of the Arab Parliament, praised the UAE&#39;s successful mediation efforts in facilitating a new exchange of war captives between the Russian Federation and the Republic of Ukraine. This marks the tenth such exchange orchestrated by the UAE between the two countries since the beginning of 2024.</p>

<p>In a statement today, Al Yamahi emphasised that the UAE&#39;s significant efforts reflect its commitment to a global peace approach championed by its wise leadership.</p>

<p>He also commended the UAE&#39;s pioneering role as a reliable global mediator and supporter of diplomatic initiatives and peaceful resolution pathways aimed at achieving peace on all levels.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 19:53:30 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736029.1735660275!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736029.1735660275!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE's successful mediation between Russia, Ukraine reflects its role in promoting global peace: President of Arab Parliament]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Humanitarian situation in Gaza, West Bank worsens due to Israeli aggression: Palestinian entities]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/humanitarian-situation-in-gaza-west-bank-worsens-due-to-israeli-aggression-palestinian-entities-2024-12-31-1.736026</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/humanitarian-situation-in-gaza-west-bank-worsens-due-to-israeli-aggression-palestinian-entities-2024-12-31-1.736026</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Official Palestinian entities have highlighted the worsening humanitarian and educational conditions in the Gaza Strip and the West Bank as a result of continued Israeli aggression since 7th October 2023.</p>

<p>In a statement today, the Palestinian Civil Defence (PCD) in Gaza announced that it has received hundreds of distress calls from displaced individuals whose tents and shelters were flooded by rain, leaving them pleading for help to save their children.</p>

<p>The PCD confirmed that its teams can only evacuate the affected to other locations, which are often unfit for shelter, forcing many to remain exposed to harsh weather conditions, including rain and cold.</p>

<p>The Palestinian Ministry of Education and Higher Education reported the martyrdom of 12,943 students and the injury of 21,681 others since the start of the Israeli aggression. The ministry indicated that over 12,790 students were martyred and 21,026 injured in Gaza, while the West Bank witnessed 120 student fatalities and 655 injuries, along with the detention of 548 students.</p>

<p>The ministry further noted damage to 425 government schools and universities in Gaza, while 109 schools and seven universities in the West Bank were subjected to incursions and vandalism.</p>

<p>It also confirmed that 788,000 students in Gaza remain unable to attend schools and universities since the onset of the aggression, with most students suffering from psychological trauma and facing severe health challenges.</p>

<p>A report by the Palestinian Central Bureau of Statistics on the conditions of Palestinians at the end of 2024 revealed a 6% decline in the population of the Gaza Strip by the year&#39;s end. The report estimated the total Palestinian population at 5.5 million, including 3.4 million in the West Bank. Meanwhile, Gaza&rsquo;s population decreased by approximately 160,000, bringing the estimated population to 2.1 million.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 19:48:42 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736027.1735660104!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736027.1735660104!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Humanitarian situation in Gaza, West Bank worsens due to Israeli aggression: Palestinian entities]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE President receives Prince Khalid bin Salman]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-receives-prince-khalid-bin-salman-2024-12-31-1.736014</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-receives-prince-khalid-bin-salman-2024-12-31-1.736014</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan today received His Royal Highness Prince Khalid bin Salman bin Abdulaziz Al Saud, Minister of Defence of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, in the presence of His Highness Sheikh Mansour bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Vice President, Deputy Prime Minister and Chairman of the Presidential Court.</p>

<p>During the meeting, which took place at Qasr Al Shati in Abu Dhabi, His Royal Highness Prince Khalid bin Salman conveyed the greetings of the Custodian of the Two Holy Mosques, King Salman bin Abdulaziz Al Saud, and His Royal Highness Prince Mohammed bin Salman bin Abdulaziz Al Saud, Crown Prince and Prime Minister of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, to His Highness the UAE President, as well as their wishes for the UAE to experience continued progress and prosperity.</p>

<p>In turn, His Highness the UAE President conveyed his greetings to the Custodian of the Two Holy Mosques and Crown Prince, expressing his wishes for the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia to achieve further progress and prosperity under its leadership.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan and His Royal Highness Prince Khalid bin Salman discussed the deep-rooted relations between the two countries and ways to advance cooperation in all fields to support their common interests and achieve the aspirations of their peoples for development and prosperity.</p>

<p>The meeting also addressed developments in the Middle East, regional and international issues of shared interest, and the importance of enhancing efforts to maintain regional security, peace, and stability.</p>

<p>The meeting was attended by Sheikh Mohamed bin Hamad bin Tahnoun Al Nahyan, Advisor to the UAE President, Ali bin Hammad Al Shamsi, Secretary-General of the Supreme Council for National Security, and Dr. Ahmed Mubarak Al Mazrouei, Chairman of the President&rsquo;s Office for Strategic Affairs and Chairman of the Abu Dhabi Executive Office.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 13:40:38 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736015.1735638020!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736015.1735638020!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE President receives Prince Khalid bin Salman]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed meets with Italy’s Defence Minister in Abu Dhabi]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/hamdan-bin-mohammed-meets-with-italy-s-defence-minister-in-abu-dhabi-2024-12-30-1.736016</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/hamdan-bin-mohammed-meets-with-italy-s-defence-minister-in-abu-dhabi-2024-12-30-1.736016</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai and Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defence of the UAE, met today in Abu Dhabi with His Excellency Guido Crosetto, Italy&rsquo;s Minister of Defence, in the presence of His Excellency Mohamed bin Mubarak Fadhel Al Mazrouei, Minister of State for Defence Affairs, and a number of senior officials from both sides.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Hamdan extended a warm welcome to His Excellency Guido Crosetto, highlighting his visit as a reflection of the deep and time-tested relations between the two friendly countries and peoples, and the spirit of partnership and cooperation that drives new opportunities for bilateral ties at various levels.</p>

<p>During the meeting, the two sides focused on enhancing bilateral relations and ways to further boost cooperation across various fields, with particular emphasis on increasing defence collaboration and partnerships that benefit industries catering to the defence sector. They also highlighted the importance of bilateral visits and the sharing of expertise and best practices in ensuring the development of new defence technologies and improving the military preparedness and efficiency of defence personnel. Such efforts are vital to safeguarding the larger interests of both countries and realising the aspirations of their peoples, the two sides concurred.</p>

<p>The meeting also reviewed the latest regional and international developments, with the situation in the Middle East drawing particular attention. The two sides emphasised the importance of intensifying international cooperation to advance efforts to promote peace and stability across the wider region, thus helping countries in the region achieve their development goals.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Hamdan, accompanied by His Excellency Guido Crosetto, also visited the famed Italian naval training vessel Amerigo Vespucci, which anchored at Zayed Port as part of global tour. The ship is one of the world&rsquo;s few remaining examples of sailing ships that are still in active service and the port call in Abu Dhabi marks its first visit to the UAE in its 93-year history.<br />
At the conclusion of the tour, Sheikh Hamdan, accompanied by the Italian Minister of Defence, recorded a message in the VIP guestbook highlighting the ship&rsquo;s missions of maritime diplomacy and protection of the marine environment, besides its significance as a proud symbol of maritime heritage for the Italian Navy.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 23:45:00 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736017.1735638248!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736017.1735638248!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed meets with Italy’s Defence Minister in Abu Dhabi]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Earthquake of magnitude 5.6 strikes Luzon, Philippines]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/earthquake-of-magnitude-5-6-strikes-luzon-philippines-2024-12-30-1.736010</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/earthquake-of-magnitude-5-6-strikes-luzon-philippines-2024-12-30-1.736010</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>A magnitude 5.6 earthquake struck Luzon in the Philippines on Monday, the German Research Centre for Geosciences (GFZ) said.</p>

<p>The quake was at a depth of 10 kilometres (6.2 miles), GFZ said.</p>

<p>Philippine&#39;s seismology agency Phivolcs said the tremor struck the northern town of Bangui in Ilocos province. The agency was not expecting damage, but said aftershocks are likely from the shallow quake.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 11:08:18 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736011.1735542481!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736011.1735542481!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Earthquake of magnitude 5.6 strikes Luzon, Philippines]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE sends three aid convoys to Gaza as part of Operation Chivalrous Knight 3]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-sends-three-aid-convoys-to-gaza-as-part-of-operation-chivalrous-knight-3-2024-12-30-1.736008</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-sends-three-aid-convoys-to-gaza-as-part-of-operation-chivalrous-knight-3-2024-12-30-1.736008</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Three convoys carrying diverse Emirati humanitarian aid crossed into Gaza this week through the Rafah border crossing, as part of the UAE&rsquo;s efforts to support and assist the Palestinian people during the ongoing crisis under Operation Chivalrous Knight 3.</p>

<p>The convoys comprised 28 trucks loaded with more than 445 tonnes of humanitarian aid, including relief materials such as flour, food parcels, winter clothing, and other essential supplies.</p>

<p>This brings the total number of aid convoys sent to Gaza under Operation Chivalrous Knight 3 to 147, comprising 2,245 trucks.</p>

<p>Through its humanitarian initiative, Operation Chivalrous Knight 3, the UAE continues to reaffirm its role in providing relief since the onset of the crisis in Gaza.</p>

<p>The initiative aims to support the Palestinian people, alleviate their suffering, and meet their urgent needs during these challenging times. This includes implementing relief projects to ease the hardships of displaced Palestinian families, demonstrating a humanitarian commitment to aiding those in need.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 11:06:56 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736009.1735542402!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736009.1735542402!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE sends three aid convoys to Gaza as part of Operation Chivalrous Knight 3]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Former US president Jimmy Carter dies at 100]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/former-us-president-jimmy-carter-dies-at-100-2024-12-30-1.736006</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/former-us-president-jimmy-carter-dies-at-100-2024-12-30-1.736006</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Jimmy Carter, a Nobel Peace Prize laureate, died at his home in Georgia on Sunday, the Carter Centre, a nonprofit organisation, said. He was 100.</p>

<p>The Carter Centre said there will be public observances in Atlanta and Washington. These events will be followed by a private interment in Plains, it said.</p>

<p>Final arrangements for the former president&#39;s state funeral are still pending.</p>

<p>Carter served as the 39th US president from 1977 to 1981. He was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 2002 in recognition of his &quot;untiring effort to find peaceful solutions to international conflicts, to advance democracy and human rights, and to promote economic and social development.&quot;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 11:04:45 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736007.1735542246!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736007.1735542246!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Former US president Jimmy Carter dies at 100]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Abdullah bin Zayed receives Iranian Foreign Minister]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/abdullah-bin-zayed-receives-iranian-foreign-minister-2024-12-29-1.735995</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/abdullah-bin-zayed-receives-iranian-foreign-minister-2024-12-29-1.735995</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;H.H. Sheikh Abdullah bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Foreign Affairs, today received Abbas Araghchi, Minister of Foreign Affairs of the Islamic Republic of Iran.</p>

<p>During the meeting, they discussed bilateral relations between the two countries and ways to enhance them to serve their mutual interests.</p>

<p>The two top diplomats also reviewed the overall situation in the region, discussed current regional developments, and exchanged views on various issues of mutual concern.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 18:54:46 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735996.1735484048!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735996.1735484048!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Abdullah bin Zayed receives Iranian Foreign Minister]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE President and Turkish Foreign Minister discuss bilateral relations and regional developments]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-and-turkish-foreign-minister-discuss-bilateral-relations-and-regional-developments-2024-12-25-1.735969</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-and-turkish-foreign-minister-discuss-bilateral-relations-and-regional-developments-2024-12-25-1.735969</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>UAE President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan and His Excellency Hakan Fidan, Minister of Foreign Affairs of the Republic of T&uuml;rkiye, discussed enhancing cooperation between the UAE and T&uuml;rkiye in various fields in reflection of the strategic relations that unite the two countries.</p>

<p>His Excellency Hakan Fidan conveyed to His Highness the UAE President the greetings of His Excellency Recep Tayyip Erdogan, President of the Republic of T&uuml;rkiye, and his wishes for further progress and prosperity for the UAE.</p>

<p>In turn, His Highness conveyed his greetings to His Excellency President Recep Tayyip Erdogan and his wishes for T&uuml;rkiye to experience continued growth and development.</p>

<p>During the meeting, the two sides reviewed developments in the Middle East, stressing the need to intensify efforts to prevent the expansion of regional conflict, which threatens security and stability, and pursue a clear path to peace that ensures stability and security for all.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan and the Turkish Foreign Minister also discussed the latest developments in Syria, underscoring both countries&#39; firm stance towards Syria&#39;s stability, sovereignty, and territorial integrity, as well as their joint support for the aspirations of the Syrian people for security, stability, and development.</p>

<p>The meeting was attended by H.H. Sheikh Tahnoon bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Ruler of Abu Dhabi and National Security Adviser; H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Chairman of the Presidential Court for Special Affairs; Ali bin Hammad Al Shamsi, Secretary-General of the Supreme Council for National Security, and Khalifa Shaheen Al Marar, Minister of State.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:20:45 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735970.1735129225!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735970.1735129225!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE President and Turkish Foreign Minister discuss bilateral relations and regional developments]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE, Belarus Presidents discuss bilateral relations]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-belarus-presidents-discuss-bilateral-relations-2024-12-22-1.735939</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-belarus-presidents-discuss-bilateral-relations-2024-12-22-1.735939</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan and His Excellency Aleksandr Lukashenko, President of the Republic of Belarus, discussed bilateral relations and ways to enhance cooperation to serve shared interests and advance development and prosperity in both countries.</p>

<p>This came during a meeting between His Highness the President with His Excellency Aleksandr Lukashenko, who is on a working visit to the UAE for several days.</p>

<p>During the meeting, His Highness welcomed His Excellency Lukashenko and expressed appreciation for his keenness to expand UAE-Belarus relations to broader horizons of cooperation and development.</p>

<p>The two sides also exchanged views on a number of regional and international issues of common interest.</p>

<p>His Excellency the President of Belarus conveyed his appreciation to His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan for the warm reception he has received while visiting the UAE, stressing the importance Belarus attaches to strengthening ties and expanding shared interests with the UAE in various fields to foster growth and prosperity for the peoples of both countries.</p>

<p>His Excellency also underscored the continuous development in relations between the UAE and Belarus.</p>

<p>The meeting was attended by H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Chairman of the Presidential Court for Special Affairs; Ali bin Hammad Al Shamsi, Secretary-General of the Supreme Council for National Security; Mohamed Hassan Alsuwaidi, Minister of Investment; Ahmed bin Ali Al Sayegh, Minister of State; and Mohamed Al Abbar, Chairman of Eagle Hills.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 22:35:41 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735940.1734892525!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735940.1734892525!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE, Belarus Presidents discuss bilateral relations]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[World Governments Summit promotes partnerships in Latin America]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/world-governments-summit-promotes-partnerships-in-latin-america-2024-12-17-1.735879</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/world-governments-summit-promotes-partnerships-in-latin-america-2024-12-17-1.735879</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The World Governments Summit (WGS) Organisation signed a Memorandum of Understanding with the Latin American Centre for Public Administration and Development (CLAD) to promote cooperation and participation of Latin America and the Caribbean in the WGS events.</p>

<p>The MoU also focuses on sharing experiences and best practices to support the achievement of the UN Sustainable Development Goals (UNSDGs).</p>

<p>The agreement was concluded during the 29th International State and Public Administration Reform Conference, organised by CLAD in Bras&iacute;lia. This partnership adds to the World Governments Summit&#39;s focus on governments and organisations across Latin America.</p>

<p>The MoU was signed by Esther Dweck, Brazil&#39;s Minister of State for Management and Innovation in Public Services and President of the Board of Directors of CLAD; Mohamed Al Sharhan, Managing Director of the WGS Organisation; and Conrado Ramos, Secretary-General of CLAD.</p>

<p>During the visit, the WGS delegation also met Mauro Vieira, Brazil&#39;s Minister of Foreign Affairs, and Saleh Ahmad Salem Alzaraim Alsuwaidi, UAE Ambassador to Brazil. They further held a series of meetings to highlight the pivotal role of the WGS in shaping the future.</p>

<p>Al Sharhan stated that the World Governments Summit is committed to promoting international partnerships and expanding collaboration with governments and organisations worldwide. He emphasised the importance of knowledge exchange and exploring innovative ideas and practices to advance the SDGs and shape a better future.</p>

<p>&quot;The UAE&#39;s delegation participation in the conference reflects the robust and growing ties with Latin America, spanning a wide range of sectors,&quot; he added.</p>

<p>&quot;The WGS is focused on expanding global partnerships, particularly in Latin America, aligning with our mission to towards shaping the future by bringing together countries, international organisations, experts, and CEOs. These efforts aim at fostering innovation and enable governments to address global challenges together, ultimately driving positive change,&quot; Al Sharhan noted.</p>

<p>During the visit, the World Governments Summit delegation held meetings with government officials and business leaders from Mexico, Colombia, and Brazil, focusing on promoting cooperation with the Global South and Latin American countries. The discussions explored the region&#39;s vast potential in key sectors such as trade, technology, and climate innovation.</p>

<p>The delegation presented an overview of the WGS to members of the Mexican Senate, in the presence of Gerardo Fern&aacute;ndez Noro&ntilde;a, President of the Mexican Senate and Undersecretary of Foreign Affairs of Mexico Mar&iacute;a Teresa Mercado P&eacute;rez.</p>

<p>In Colombia, the delegation met with Efra&iacute;n Cepeda Sarabia, President of the Colombian Senate; Sa&uacute;l Cruz Bonilla, Secretary-General of the Senate; and Juan Manuel Santos, former President of Colombia and Nobel Peace Prize laureate.</p>

<p>The visit encompassed a keynote address on the future of governments and the importance of government development at the CLAD Ministerial Board meeting held in Brasilia, which included Ministers of Public Service and Government Development in Latin America.</p>

<p>In Colombia, Al Sharhan held a working lunch with the RENATA network members hosted by the Executive Director of RENATA, Said Nav&iacute; Lamk Beltr&aacute;n, and concluded the visit with an interview with &quot;El Congreso Magazine,&quot; Colombia&#39;s leading publication on public policy, to highlight the growing role of the WGS in fostering innovation and enhancing international partnerships.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 13:46:32 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735880.1734428779!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735880.1734428779!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[World Governments Summit promotes partnerships in Latin America]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Putin commends UAE President for AI development efforts]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/putin-commends-uae-president-for-ai-development-efforts-2024-12-12-1.735825</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/putin-commends-uae-president-for-ai-development-efforts-2024-12-12-1.735825</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin has praised President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan for his significant focus on advancing artificial intelligence (AI).</p>

<p>In a speech delivered at the AI Journey international conference in Moscow, Putin highlighted the great importance His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed places on AI and its development.</p>

<p>He noted the international ranking level that the UAE achieved last year, adding that it has accomplished remarkable feats in this regard, as it moved up several positions and reached incredible heights.</p>

<p>Putin said that AI technology is called upon to become the critical resource for achieving national development goals to strengthen the country&rsquo;s defence capability, ensure high-quality development of the economy and social sectors, public administration, and growth of innovations.</p>

<p>The Russian President also emphasised that over the past year, AI technologies have significantly transformed entire industries, marking the beginning of a revolution in engineering, as well as the design and construction of fundamentally new components and devices.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 15:53:04 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735826.1734004341!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735826.1734004341!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Putin commends UAE President for AI development efforts]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE President, King of Jordan discuss bilateral relations, regional developments]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-king-of-jordan-discuss-bilateral-relations-regional-developments-2024-12-11-1.735821</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-king-of-jordan-discuss-bilateral-relations-regional-developments-2024-12-11-1.735821</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan held discussions today with His Majesty King Abdullah II bin Al Hussein of the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan, focusing on the close ties between their countries and the latest regional developments.</p>

<p>The meeting in Abu Dhabi was part of a fraternal visit by King Abdullah aimed at continuing mutual consultations on issues of shared interest, particularly in light of recent events in the region.</p>

<p>During the meeting, His Highness and the Jordanian King reviewed developments in the Syrian Arab Republic. They reaffirmed their countries&rsquo; consistent stance in support of Syria&rsquo;s unity, stability, sovereignty, and territorial integrity, while emphasising the importance of safeguarding its national institutions.</p>

<p>They also expressed their commitment to supporting initiatives that align with the aspirations of the Syrian people, underscoring the importance of Syria&rsquo;s stability to the region and the Arab world.</p>

<p>Both leaders also stressed the need to intensify efforts to bolster regional stability and prevent the escalation of conflicts in the region.</p>

<p>The meeting was attended by H.H. Sheikh Khaled bin Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi; H.H. Lt. General Sheikh Saif bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of the Interior; H.H. Sheikh Abdullah bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Foreign Affairs; H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Chairman of the Presidential Court for Special Affairs; Sheikh Mohamed bin Hamad bin Tahnoun Al Nahyan, Adviser to the UAE President; Humaid Obaid Abu Shabas, Chairman of the UAE Accountability Authority; Dr. Sultan bin Ahmed Al Jaber, Minister of Industry and Advanced Technology; and a number of officials.</p>

<p>The meeting was also attended by His Royal Highness Crown Prince Al Hussein bin Abdullah of the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan; Dr. Jafar Hassan, Prime Minister; Ayman Al Safadi, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Foreign Affairs and Expatriates; and a number of senior officials in Jordan.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed had earlier welcomed the arrival of His Majesty King Abdullah II at Abu Dhabi&rsquo;s Al Bateen Airport.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 22:27:22 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735822.1733941600!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735822.1733941600!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE President, King of Jordan discuss bilateral relations, regional developments]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE President receives Vice President of Venezuela]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-receives-vice-president-of-venezuela-2024-12-10-1.735810</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-receives-vice-president-of-venezuela-2024-12-10-1.735810</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>UAE President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan held discussions today with Her Excellency Dr Delcy Rodr&iacute;guez, Vice President of the Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela.</p>

<p>The talks reviewed cooperation between the two nations and explored opportunities to enhance ties aimed at advancing growth and prosperity for their peoples.</p>

<p>During the meeting, held at Qasr Al Shati in Abu Dhabi, Dr Delcy Rodr&iacute;guez conveyed the greetings of His Excellency Nicol&aacute;s Maduro, President of Venezuela, and his wishes for continued progress and prosperity for the UAE. In return, His Highness extended his greetings to the Venezuelan President, along with his wishes for further advancement for the Venezuelan people.</p>

<p>The two sides reviewed a range of issues of mutual interest and exchanged views on key topics. They reaffirmed their commitment to strengthening UAE-Venezuela relations and enhancing collaboration across various sectors to serve their shared interests and achieve sustainable economic growth for their nations.</p>

<p>The meeting was attended by H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Chairman of the Presidential Court for Special Affairs; Sheikh Mohamed bin Hamad bin Tahnoun, Advisor to the UAE President, and Ali bin Hammad Al Shamsi, Secretary-General of the Supreme Council for National Security.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 21:50:49 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735811.1733853024!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735811.1733853024!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE President receives Vice President of Venezuela]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE strongly condemns Israel’s seizure of Golan Heights Buffer Zone]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-strongly-condemns-israel-s-seizure-of-golan-heights-buffer-zone-2024-12-10-1.735808</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-strongly-condemns-israel-s-seizure-of-golan-heights-buffer-zone-2024-12-10-1.735808</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The United Arab Emirates has strongly condemned the Israeli forces&rsquo; seizure of the buffer zone in the Golan Heights, reaffirming the UAE&rsquo;s commitment to the unity, sovereignty, and territorial integrity of the Syrian state.</p>

<p>In a statement, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs (MoFA) stressed that the occupation is in violation and contravention of international law, particularly the &ldquo;Agreement of Disengagement&rdquo; signed between Israel and Syria in 1974.</p>

<p>Furthermore, the UAE underscored its categorial rejection of such practices which threaten further escalation, exacerbate tensions in the region, and hinder efforts to achieve peace and stability.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 21:47:01 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735809.1733852803!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735809.1733852803!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE strongly condemns Israel’s seizure of Golan Heights Buffer Zone]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE President bids farewell to Mauritanian President upon departure]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-bids-farewell-to-mauritanian-president-upon-departure-2024-12-09-1.735793</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-bids-farewell-to-mauritanian-president-upon-departure-2024-12-09-1.735793</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>His Excellency Mohamed Ould Cheikh El Ghazouani, President of the Islamic Republic of Mauritania, departed the UAE today, marking the conclusion of a visit during which he attended the March of the Union of UAE tribes, held in celebration of the UAE&rsquo;s 53rd Eid Al Etihad.</p>

<p>UAE President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan bid farewell to the Mauritanian President as he departed from the Presidential Airport in Abu Dhabi.</p>

<p>Also present to bid farewell to His Excellency were H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Chairman of the Presidential Court for Special Affairs; Sheikh Mohamed bin Hamad bin Tahnoun, Advisor to the UAE President; Ali bin Hammad Al Shamsi, Secretary-General of the Supreme Council for National Security; Abdullah Sultan bin Awwad Al Nuaimi, Minister of Justice; Dr. Ahmed Mubarak Al Mazrouei, Chairman of the President&rsquo;s Office for Strategic Affairs and Chairman of the Abu Dhabi Executive Office; Hamad Ghanem Al Mehairi, UAE Ambassador to Mauritania.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 9 Dec 2024 17:07:26 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735794.1733749628!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735794.1733749628!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE President bids farewell to Mauritanian President upon departure]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE calls for unity of Syria, integrity of national state]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-calls-for-unity-of-syria-integrity-of-national-state-2024-12-09-1.735789</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-calls-for-unity-of-syria-integrity-of-national-state-2024-12-09-1.735789</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The United Arab Emirates is closely monitoring the ongoing developments in the Syrian Arab Republic, and reiterates its commitment to the unity and integrity of the Syrian state, as well as to ensuring security and stability for the brotherly Syrian people.</p>

<p>In a statement, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs (MoFA) called on all Syrian parties to prioritise wisdom during this critical juncture in Syria&#39;s history, in a manner that fulfils the aspirations and ambitions of all segments of the Syrian population.</p>

<p>Furthermore, the Ministry stressed the need to safeguard the Syrian national state and its institutions, and to prevent any descent into chaos and instability.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 9 Dec 2024 17:01:56 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735790.1733749280!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735790.1733749280!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE calls for unity of Syria, integrity of national state]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE President, UK Prime Minister discuss bilateral relations]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-uk-prime-minister-discuss-bilateral-relations-2024-12-09-1.735787</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-uk-prime-minister-discuss-bilateral-relations-2024-12-09-1.735787</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan today welcomed the Rt Hon Sir Keir Starmer, Prime Minister of the United Kingdom, who is on a working visit to the UAE.</p>

<p>During their meeting at Qasr Al Shati in Abu Dhabi, His Highness and the British Prime Minister reviewed areas of bilateral collaboration and explored ways to enhance these ties, with the aim of advancing the development ambitions of both countries and their peoples.</p>

<p>Sir Keir Starmer extended his congratulations to His Highness on the occasion of the UAE&#39;s 53rd Eid Al Etihad, expressing his wishes for continued progress and prosperity for the nation.</p>

<p>Both leaders reaffirmed their shared commitment to further enhancing collaboration and joint efforts in the coming period, building on the historical ties that unite the two countries.</p>

<p>The meeting also covered a range of regional and international issues of mutual interest, with a focus on developments in the Middle East. The two leaders emphasised their countries&#39; commitment to supporting efforts aimed at achieving peace, security, and stability at both the regional and global levels. They underscored the importance of resolving crises through dialogue and diplomatic solutions.</p>

<p>The meeting was attended by H.H. Sheikh Tahnoun bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Ruler of Abu Dhabi and National Security Adviser; H.H. Sheikh Abdullah bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Foreign Affairs; H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Chairman of the Presidential Court for Special Affairs; Sheikh Mohamed bin Hamad bin Tahnoun, Advisor to the UAE President; Reem bint Ebrahim Al Hashimy, Minister of State for International Cooperation; Khaldoun Khalifa Al Mubarak, Chairman of the Executive Affairs Authority; Lieutenant General Issa Saif bin Ablan Al Mazrouei, Chief of Staff of the UAE Armed Forces; and Mansour Abdullah Khalfan Belhoul, UAE Ambassador to the UK.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 9 Dec 2024 16:59:53 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735788.1733749173!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735788.1733749173!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE President, UK Prime Minister discuss bilateral relations]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
