<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
	<title>Mobile - Sports</title>
	<link>http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-sports-1.499780?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout</link>	
	<atom:link href="http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-sports-1.499780?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" ></atom:link>
	<description>Sports</description>
			        <language>en</language>
    				<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Bahrain crowned champions of Arabian Gulf Football Cup 26]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/football/bahrain-crowned-champions-of-arabian-gulf-football-cup-26-2025-01-04-1.736047</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/football/bahrain-crowned-champions-of-arabian-gulf-football-cup-26-2025-01-04-1.736047</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Bahrain have been crowned champions of the Arabian Gulf Football Cup, &lsquo;Khaleeji Zain 26&rsquo;, after defeating Oman 2-1 in the final match held today, Saturday, at the Jaber Al-Ahmad International Stadium in Kuwait.</p>

<p>Bahrain overturned a 1-0 deficit, after Oman scored in the 17th minute through Abdulrahman Al-Mushaifri, to win 2-1. Mohamed Marhoon scored the equaliser for Bahrain in the 78th minute from a penalty, followed by an own goal by Oman&#39;s Mohammed Al-Musalami in the 80th minute.</p>

<p>This is the second time the Bahraini national team has won the Arabian Gulf Cup, following their victory in the 2019 edition.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Sabah Khaled Al-Hamad Al-Sabah, Crown Prince of Kuwait, honoured Gulf football legends during the final match events.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sat, 4 Jan 2025 22:56:00 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736048.1736074565!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736048.1736074565!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Bahrain crowned champions of Arabian Gulf Football Cup 26]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sports</category>
										
																			
											<category>FootBall</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Sports/Football</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Hatta Running Championship to showcase sporting vibe of Hatta Winter initiative]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/hatta-running-championship-to-showcase-sporting-vibe-of-hatta-winter-initiative-2025-01-03-1.736038</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/hatta-running-championship-to-showcase-sporting-vibe-of-hatta-winter-initiative-2025-01-03-1.736038</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The Hatta Running Championship returns on January 4 under the patronage of Sheikh Saeed bin Hamdan bin Rashid Al Maktoum, President of Hatta Club.</p>

<p>Organised by the Hatta Sports, Cultural and Social Club in collaboration with the Dubai Sports Council (DSC) and the Hatta Winter Festival committee, the event has already confirmed over 1,000 participants, including a strong international presence.</p>

<p>The championship is part of the Hatta Winter initiative, with DSC as a key partner.</p>

<p>The event features competition across eight categories, including the Emirati men&rsquo;s category and an open category over a distance of 8 km, the Emirati women&rsquo;s category and an open category over a distance of 5 km, the Emirati youth category and an open category for under-20-year-olds over a distance of 5 km, and the Emirati children&rsquo;s category and an open category for under-16s over a distance of 3 km.</p>

<p>With over 1,000 runners from different nationalities and age groups, the competition offers a prize pool of AED100,000. The routes highlight Hatta&rsquo;s scenic landscapes and tourist spots, with all races concluding at the picturesque Leem Lake.</p>

<p>The Hatta Running Championship is among the highlights of diverse sporting activities organised as part of the Hatta Winter initiative, which is overseen by the Supreme Committee to Supervise the Development of Hatta, and is implemented by Brand Dubai, the creative arm of the Government of Dubai Media Office, in partnership with various government and private entities.</p>

<p>The Hatta Winter initiative serves to provide added impetus to the goals of the Dubai 2040 Urban Master Plan, especially in terms of enhancing tourism competitiveness, driving development activities with the participation of the private sector, supporting efforts to promote tourism and encourage entrepreneurs, as well as organising and hosting activities and sporting events that will help boost the number of visitors to the Hatta region.</p>

<p>The Hatta Running Championship also aligns with concerted efforts being made to enhance the region&rsquo;s profile as a destination for sports tourism and diverse sporting activities, besides its capability to host major sporting events that directly benefit local communities and usher in significant economic benefits.</p>

<p>Among recent sporting events held in Hatta was the Hatta Winter Football Championship, which featured the participation of eight community teams, and the preliminary and exhibition phase of the Dubai International Rally events from 29th November to 1st December. The Emirates Motor Sports Organisation (EMSO) partnered with the Dubai Sports Council to organise the latter event. Another highlight was a walking competition organised by Hatta Adventures, with local farms and the area&rsquo;s unique aflaj irrigation network providing a fascinating backdrop for the event.</p>

<p>The Hatta Winter initiative has also set the stage for mountain biking and kayaking races organised by Hatta Adventures and Hatta Kayak (January 11), and the Stand Up Paddling and Kayaking Challenge (January 25-26), besides sporting challenges with a family flavour on February 1. The Hatta Ramadan Tournament will keep the community engaged in sporting pursuits during the holy month while the Spartan Race is yet another event that promises to be a major draw for international participants as well as local communities.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 3 Jan 2025 18:27:10 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736039.1735914515!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736039.1735914515!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Hatta Running Championship to showcase sporting vibe of Hatta Winter initiative]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sports</category>
										
																			
											<category>Other</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Sports/Other</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[EsportsXO Partners with Abu Dhabi Gaming to Establish Regional Headquarters in the UAE Capital, Driving MENA Expansion]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/esportsxo-partners-with-abu-dhabi-gaming-to-establish-regional-headquarters-in-the-uae-capital-driving-mena-expansion-2024-12-15-1.735859</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/esportsxo-partners-with-abu-dhabi-gaming-to-establish-regional-headquarters-in-the-uae-capital-driving-mena-expansion-2024-12-15-1.735859</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong><em>New strategic partnership to foster growth in the gaming ecosystem and create local opportunities in the Middle East and North Africa (MENA) region</em></strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p><strong><a href="https://esports.battlexo.com/"><span style="color:#0000FF;">EsportsXO</span></a></strong>, a frontrunner in the Indian esports and gaming startup landscape, has announced a strategic partnership with <strong><a href="https://www.adgaming.ae/"><span style="color:#0000CD;">Abu Dhabi Gaming</span></a><span style="color:#0000CD;">,</span></strong> marking a significant expansion into the MENA region. As a part of this agreement, XO will establish its regional headquarter in Abu Dhabi. This collaboration is aimed at fostering the growth of Abu Dhabi&rsquo;s local gaming ecosystem and will enable both companies to seize the emerging opportunities in this growing sector.<br />
With a projected valuation of $397.21 billion by 2029, the global gaming industry is on a sturdy growth track and the MENA region is rapidly emerging as one of its largest markets. By setting up its regional hub in Abu Dhabi, XO is positioning itself at the epicentre of this dynamic landscape, poised to tap into a market ripe for expansion.</p>

<p><em>&ldquo;Working with Abu Dhabi Gaming is a major step for XO as we look to expand our presence in one of the world&rsquo;s most exciting gaming regions,&rdquo;</em> said <strong>Vikas Goel, Founder, XO. </strong>&nbsp;&ldquo;<em>We are eager to contribute to the development of the local gaming ecosystem, nurture homegrown talent, and bring world-class gaming experiences to the MENA region. This reinforces our commitment to expanding our global footprint while fostering meaningful connections with gamers and industry leaders across the region.</em>&rdquo;</p>

<p>Abu Dhabi Gaming, the UAE capital&rsquo;s gaming ecosystem builder, hosts over 100 gaming companies. By joining forces with Abu Dhabi Gaming, XO becomes the first tournament platform to be part of this ecosystem, paving the way for more immersive and large-scale gaming experiences in the MENA region.</p>

<p>Commenting on the same, <strong>Marcos Muller-Habig, Director at Abu Dhabi Gaming</strong> added, <em>&ldquo;We are excited to welcome XO to the Abu Dhabi Gaming ecosystem. Their expertise in esports tournaments and community building will play a crucial role in elevating Abu Dhabi&rsquo;s position as a global gaming hub. Together, we aim to shape the future of gaming in MENA, while providing the platform for local and global talent to achieve the goal of enhancing the growth of Abu Dhabi Gaming&rsquo;s ecosystem&rdquo;</em></p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Focus and Growth</strong><br />
This strategic expansion in Abu Dhabi will be instrumental in shaping the esports and gaming landscape in the MENA region. XO&rsquo;s Abu Dhabi office will focus on key growth areas, including regional esports programs, partnerships with publishers, and innovative advertising solutions. XO&rsquo;s platform, known for its free-to-play, gamified ecosystem, helps gamers discover tournaments and connect with other gamers, creating a more engaging and sticky experience.</p>

<p>This partnership is expected to create a significant amount of jobs over the next five years and support the development of local talent.&nbsp; It also aligns with Abu Dhabi&rsquo;s broader vision to establish itself as a global gaming hub, providing the necessary infrastructure and network to foster innovation.</p>

<p>XO&rsquo;s strategic expansion follows a significant financial and operational growth attained by the company in a short span of three&nbsp; years. XO has raised around $1.4 million USD and achieved revenues of over $4.3 million in the past 3 years, maintaining a EBITDA-positive performance the last three quarters of this year. After a successful fundraising in 2023, XO has demonstrated financial stability and ability to scale sustainably while delivering excellence and value to its growing community of over 1.4 million gamers across the globe.</p>

<p>XO is focused on building a sustainable, inclusive, and borderless gaming ecosystem where gamers, developers and brands co-exist to create mutual value. By offering active, engaged players and delivering a highly targeted engagement, it has emerged as a major player in the regional esports scene. The focus on community engagement, alongside a slow-burn approach to marketing, provides long-term value creation.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 18:41:55 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735860.1734273629!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735860.1734273629!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[EsportsXO Partners with Abu Dhabi Gaming to Establish Regional Headquarters in the UAE Capital, Driving MENA Expansion]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sports</category>
										
																			
											<category>Other</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Sports/Other</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA["Dubai Sports" Delivers Exclusive Coverage of the UIM XCAT World Championship]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/dubai-sports-delivers-exclusive-coverage-of-the-uim-xcat-world-championship-2024-12-13-1.735831</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/dubai-sports-delivers-exclusive-coverage-of-the-uim-xcat-world-championship-2024-12-13-1.735831</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<div>
<blockquote>
<p align="center"><strong><em>Jumeirah Beaches Host Championship Finale as 10 Teams Compete for Titles in Three Races</em></strong></p>
</blockquote>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dubai Sports Channel, part of Dubai Media Incorporated (DMI), has announced its comprehensive coverage of the fifth and final round of the 2024 <strong>UIM XCAT World Championship</strong>. This event marks the conclusion of the global racing season for 2024, hosted in Dubai from December 13 to 15, featuring 10 international powerboats competing for the top spots in two main races as well as the Speed Race title. This initiative reflects DMI&#39;s commitment to positioning Dubai as a global hub for marine sports.</p>

<p>Organized by the Dubai International Marine Club, the grand event will take place on Jumeirah beaches, which previously hosted the global race in 2019 and 2021. Beachgoers at Jumeirah can once again enjoy the championship and experience the action up close.</p>

<p><strong>Abdulrahman Amin, Director of Dubai Sports Channels at DMI</strong>, stated: &quot;The UIM XCAT World Championship is a global sports event that embodies the spirit of challenge and innovation that Dubai is known for. It reaffirms the city&rsquo;s status as a leading destination for hosting prominent international sports events. The championship provides a platform to celebrate teamwork, with teams from around the world delivering exceptional performances combining competition and elegance.&quot;</p>

<p>He also highlighted that &ldquo;Dubai Sports Channel has prepared a comprehensive schedule to bring the event to life, enabling marine sports enthusiasts to follow the competition&rsquo;s details, further enhancing the marine sports industry. This coverage reflects DMI&rsquo;s technical capabilities, logistical expertise, and national talents enriching the local media landscape.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>Mohammed Abdullah Hareb Al Falahi</strong>, Board Member and CEO of Dubai International Marine Club, added: &quot;Hosting this significant event underscores Dubai&rsquo;s leadership as a global center for major sports championships. The club continues its historic contributions, being the first Arab and Asian club to join the International Powerboating Federation (UIM) in the early 1990s and hosting the first world championship finale for powerboats in 1992.&quot;</p>

<p>Al Falahi extended gratitude to the event&#39;s success partners, including DMI, Dubai Police, Dubai Municipality, Roads and Transport Authority (RTA), the National Guard, and Dubai Civil Defense. He also invited the public to attend the championship, enjoy the accompanying activities, and cheer on the competing teams, led by four UAE teams: Fujairah, Victory Team, Sharjah Team, and Faz Marine, alongside international competitors. These competitors include The Kuwaiti team Q8 Oils, The Swedish team Swecat, The Italian team Consulbrokers, Australian Italian team 222 Offshore, The Belgian team Tessilmare alongside the last season&rsquo;s champion, Team GB of Britain.</p>

<p>The return of UIM XCAT World Championship to the club&rsquo;s calendar for the 2024-2025 season, after a two-year hiatus, revives the legacy of Dubai&rsquo;s association with world powerboat championships, cementing its status as the first regional and Middle Eastern destination to host such events since 1992.</p>

<p>This week, Dubai&rsquo;s beaches will be the focal point as the championship title remains undecided among the top-ranked teams. The UIM XCAT World Championship will crown the season&#39;s champion, celebrating the 12th edition of the globally recognized championship that began in Dubai in 2010.</p>

<p>The event schedule starts Thursday with the arrival of participants, completion of registration for participants and contestants, and the official meeting to clarify race instructions and routes. A total of 10 powerboats, with 20 elite racers from across the globe, will compete. The lineup includes the four top-performing UAE teams including <strong>Victory Team</strong>, led by Salem AlAdidi and Eisa Al Ali, currently ranked third with 166 points; <strong>HPI Fujairah</strong>, leading the overall standings with 215 points, led by brothers Rosario and Giuseppe&nbsp;Schiano&nbsp;di Cola. <strong>Sharjah Team</strong>, led by Mikhail Kitashev and Dmitry Vandyshev, ranked eighth with 62 points. <strong>Faz Marine</strong>, led by Arif Al Zaffain and Konstantin Ustinov, with 15 points, currently in tenth place. The Emirati teams will compete against other strong contenders, including:</p>

<ul>
	<li>The Swedish team <strong>Swecat</strong> ranked second with 214 points.</li>
	<li>The Italian team <strong>Consulbrokers </strong>ranked fourth with 163 points.</li>
	<li>Last season&rsquo;s champion, <strong>Team GB</strong>, ranked fifth with 111 points.</li>
	<li>The Kuwaiti team <strong>Q8 Oils</strong>, led by Abdul Latif Al Omani and Khalid Ali, ranked sixth with 112 points.</li>
	<li>The Belgian team <strong>Tessilmare</strong> ranked seventh with 111 points.</li>
	<li>The Australian Italian team <strong>222 Offshore</strong>, currently without any points.</li>
</ul>

<p>The event&#39;s organizing committee has extended an open invitation to the public, marine sports enthusiasts, and powerboat racing fans to attend the major championship at the race site located behind Sunset Mall in Jumeirah 3. A race village has been set up in front of the beach, close to Jumeirah Beachgoers, with the course positioned near the shore to heighten the excitement. Spectators will have the opportunity to watch the event and engage with its thrilling moments over three days.</p>

<p><strong>Event Schedule:</strong><br />
<strong>Friday, December 13, 2024:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Best Time Qualifiers 1 (11:00 AM - 12:15 PM)</li>
	<li>First Race (3:00 PM)</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Saturday, December 14, 2024:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Best Time Qualifiers 2 (12:00 PM - 1:15 PM)</li>
	<li>Speed Race (3:30 PM)</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Sunday, December 15, 2024:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Second Race (2:30 PM)</li>
</ul>
</div>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 13:36:47 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735836.1734082781!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735836.1734082781!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735836.1734082781!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735835.1734082765!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735834.1734082685!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735833.1734082668!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735832.1734082648!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA["Dubai Sports" Delivers Exclusive Coverage of the UIM XCAT World Championship]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sports</category>
										
																			
											<category>Other</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Sports/Other</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Abu Dhabi Sports Council Appoints Burjeel Holdings as Health and Community Wellness Partner]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/abu-dhabi-sports-council-appoints-burjeel-holdings-as-health-and-community-wellness-partner-2024-12-10-1.735801</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/abu-dhabi-sports-council-appoints-burjeel-holdings-as-health-and-community-wellness-partner-2024-12-10-1.735801</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong>The strategic collaboration will promote active lifestyles and holistic well-being for Abu Dhabi&rsquo;s diverse community</strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>The Abu Dhabi Sports Council (ADSC) and Burjeel Holdings, a leading super-specialty healthcare provider in the MENA region, have announced a collaboration to nurture a culture of wellness and active living across Abu Dhabi. The two-fold strategic partnership will see Burjeel Holdings serving as ADSC&rsquo;s official medical partner during its events and leading community health and wellness initiatives.</p>

<p>The collaboration was formalized through a strategic agreement signed by His Excellency Aref Hamad Al Awani, General Secretary of the Abu Dhabi Sports Council, and Dr. Shamsheer Vayalil, Founder and Chairman of Burjeel Holdings. Mr. Omran Al Khoori, Executive Board Member at Burjeel Holdings, Mr. John Sunil, Group CEO of Burjeel Holdings, and Mr. Safeer Ahamed, Group COO of Burjeel Holdings, were also present at the signing ceremony.</p>

<p>As part of their commitment to community wellness, Burjeel Holdings will collaborate with ADSC to launch initiatives, including annual events that provide residents with opportunities to engage in health-focused activities, access wellness resources, and adopt active lifestyles. As the official medical partner, Burjeel Holdings will continue to provide on-site medical teams, emergency response units, and health-focused activations to ensure the well-being of athletes, spectators, and event staff at ADSC&rsquo;s high-profile events. This ongoing support underscores the healthcare provider&rsquo;s expertise in integrating medical excellence with sports to create a safe environment for all participants.</p>

<p>Since 2022, Burjeel Holdings has been the official medical partner of ADSC. Over the past three years, it has supported nearly 500 sports and community events organized by ADSC, including international events like FIFA Club World Cup. Together, the entities have driven impactful initiatives, providing world-class medical services to athletes and spectators at marquee events like the UAE Tour and the ADNOC Marathon. With the renewal of their partnership, the collaboration expands its scope beyond event-specific support to champion a broader mission &ndash; advancing ADSC&rsquo;s vision of cultivating a healthier, more active community through transformative wellness initiatives and meaningful community outreach.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His Excellency Aref Hamad Al Awani expressed his delight in renewing the partnership with Burjeel Holdings. He highlighted that this collaboration reflects ADSC&rsquo;s commitment to providing world-class health and medical services to participants in the international and community events featured in Abu Dhabi&rsquo;s sports calendar. His Excellency Al Awani stated, &ldquo;Through our collaboration with Burjeel, we aim to ensure the highest levels of comfort and well-being for all participants in our events, reflecting the Abu Dhabi government&rsquo;s vision to enhance the quality of life for all community members and participants from diverse nationalities. We extend our best wishes for everyone&rsquo;s continued health and safety.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;We are honored to strengthen our partnership with the Abu Dhabi Sports Council, which aligns with our goal to nurture healthier and more active communities. Together, we aim to set a new standard for integrating healthcare excellence into sports, inspiring people to lead healthier lives and supporting the community in every step of their wellness journey,&rdquo; said Mr. John Sunil.</p>

<p>In addition, the agreement highlights ADSC&rsquo;s support for Burjeel Games, the Group&rsquo;s annual sports tournament, to promote greater employee engagement and well-being.<br />
&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 10:32:29 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735803.1733812286!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735803.1733812286!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735803.1733812286!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735802.1733812261!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Abu Dhabi Sports Council Appoints Burjeel Holdings as Health and Community Wellness Partner]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sports</category>
										
																			
											<category>Other</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Sports/Other</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Russia's Kudermetova, Britain's Burrage advance to Al Habtoor Tennis Challenge's final]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/tennis/russia-s-kudermetova-britain-s-burrage-advance-to-al-habtoor-tennis-challenge-s-final-2024-12-08-1.735776</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/tennis/russia-s-kudermetova-britain-s-burrage-advance-to-al-habtoor-tennis-challenge-s-final-2024-12-08-1.735776</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The 26th edition of the Al Habtoor Tennis Challenge will conclude tomorrow, Sunday, with the finals of both the singles and doubles competitions taking place at the Al Habtoor Grand Resort in Jumeirah, Dubai.</p>

<p>In the singles final, Russia&#39;s Polina Kudermetova, the tournament&#39;s top seed, will face Britain&#39;s Jodie Burrage after both players advanced from Saturday&#39;s semifinals. Sunday will witness the doubles final from 1 pm, followed by the singles final between Kudermetova and Burrage.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 8 Dec 2024 13:44:41 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735777.1733651041!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735777.1733651041!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Russia's Kudermetova, Britain's Burrage advance to Al Habtoor Tennis Challenge's final]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sports</category>
										
																			
											<category>Tennis</category>
										
																								
										
													
				 									<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/General</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[FIFA Club World Cup Trophy tour to visit all 32 participating teams]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/football/fifa-club-world-cup-trophy-tour-to-visit-all-32-participating-teams-2024-12-06-1.735756</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/football/fifa-club-world-cup-trophy-tour-to-visit-all-32-participating-teams-2024-12-06-1.735756</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;FIFA President Gianni Infantino celebrated a &quot;historic day&quot; for club football when he took part in the draw for the inaugural 32-team FIFA Club World Cup&trade;, a tournament which will herald a new era for competitive club football on a global stage when it takes place in the United States from 15th June to 13th July 2025.</p>

<p>Appearing at the start of the star-studded draw show in Miami, Infantino said that a global club competition had been the missing link in the world&#39;s most popular sport. During the event, the FIFA President announced that the FIFA Club World Cup Trophy would be going on a world tour starting in New York on 16th January 2025.</p>

<p>&quot;This is a historic day because today marks the day of the draw of the first-ever FIFA Club World Cup,&quot; the FIFA President said. &quot;Football united the world through the (FIFA) World Cup. The men&#39;s (FIFA) World Cup since 1930, the (FIFA) Women&#39;s World Cup since 1991. But what was missing was something for club football to determine who was the best club in the world. We have it now - the FIFA Club World Cup, which starts a new era in club football.</p>

<p>&quot;It&#39;s about inclusivity, it&#39;s about bringing clubs from all over the world, the 32 best clubs and best players from all over the world, together in the United States&hellip; to determine which one is truly the best in the world.&quot;</p>

<p>Infantino said that the &quot;unique&quot; and &quot;iconic&quot; trophy would go on a global tour, visiting all 32 participating teams so that fans could see it up close. &quot;This trophy will come and see you all, all over the world,&quot; he said. &quot;And the first team that will be able to lift this iconic trophy will be the team that wins the final on 13th July (2025) in the MetLife Stadium in New York New Jersey.&quot;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 6 Dec 2024 18:23:49 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735757.1733495014!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735757.1733495014!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[FIFA Club World Cup Trophy tour to visit all 32 participating teams]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sports</category>
										
																			
											<category>FootBall</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Sports/Football</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[AFC Champions League Elite: Pakhtakor 1-1 Al Ain]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/football/afc-champions-league-elite-pakhtakor-1-1-al-ain-2024-12-03-1.735719</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/football/afc-champions-league-elite-pakhtakor-1-1-al-ain-2024-12-03-1.735719</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Reigning continental champions Al Ain continue to cling on to their hopes of a place in the knockout rounds of the AFC Champions League Elite after Leonardo Jardim&rsquo;s side earned a 1-1 draw with Pakhtakor despite playing the final 35 minutes in Tashkent with 10 men.</p>

<p>Soufiane Rahimi struck in the 49th minute to cancel out Otabek Jurakuziyev&rsquo;s sixth minute opener before Yahia Nader was sent off for a dangerous tackle in the 55th minute to leave the holders short-handed.</p>

<p>The draw moves Al Ain onto two points and leaves the champions three adrift of eighth-placed Esteghlal in the west league standings with two matches remaining while Pakhtakor are one point further ahead of the side from the United Arab Emirates.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 3 Dec 2024 22:51:10 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735720.1733251854!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735720.1733251854!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[AFC Champions League Elite: Pakhtakor 1-1 Al Ain]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sports</category>
										
																			
											<category>FootBall</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Sports/Football</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed leads record-breaking Dubai Run, presented by Mai Dubai]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/hamdan-bin-mohammed-leads-record-breaking-dubai-run-presented-by-mai-dubai-2024-11-24-1.735572</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/hamdan-bin-mohammed-leads-record-breaking-dubai-run-presented-by-mai-dubai-2024-11-24-1.735572</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>- 278,000 people participate in world&rsquo;s largest community fun run<br />
- Sixth edition sets a new record in participants, up 23% on last year&rsquo;s numbers<br />
- Sheikh Zayed Road and Downtown Dubai transformed into giant running tracks in Dubai Fitness Challenge&#39;s stunning finale<br />
- International R&amp;B superstar Jason Derulo makes surprise appearance at the start of the event<br />
- Aerial displays light up the sky before the event; parade of Dubai Police supercars set the stage for Dubai Run</p>

<p>Hamdan bin Mohammed: Dubai Run is a testament to the power of community and the determination of the people of the city to lead healthier and more active lives</p>

<p>Saeed Hareb: Dubai Run unites community members of all ages and abilities under one goal &ndash; the pursuit of a healthier and more active life.</p>

<p>Ahmed Al Khaja: Dubai Run is a powerful testament to the city&rsquo;s commitment to fostering a culture of health and wellbeing</p>

<p>In an inspiring display of community spirit, His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defence of the UAE, and Chairman of The Executive Council of Dubai,&nbsp; led a record-breaking 278,000 runners in Dubai Run, presented by Mai Dubai, a 23% increase from last year&rsquo;s edition.</p>

<p>HH Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum said: &quot;Dubai Run is a testament to the power of community and the determination of the people of the city to lead healthier and more active lives. Today&rsquo;s event reflects the city&rsquo;s energy, its relentless pursuit of excellence, and the community&rsquo;s awareness of the importance of sports and fitness. The remarkable response to this event also highlights Dubai&rsquo;s emergence as one of the world&rsquo;s most active cities and a global leader in fostering a lifestyle centred on wellbeing. We thank everyone who participated in this challenge and contributed to its remarkable success. Together, we are building a healthier, happier, and more connected society while setting an example for future generations. Events like Dubai Run reaffirm our commitment to enhancing the city&rsquo;s quality of life and ensuring Dubai remains the world&rsquo;s best city to visit and live in.&quot;</p>

<p>The energy was palpable as Sheikh Zayed Road and Downtown Dubai were transformed into a sea of green, with runners of all ages, backgrounds, and abilities donning their event t-shirts for the world&rsquo;s largest fun run. Together, they made history with an unforgettable celebration of fitness and community that provided the perfect conclusion to Dubai Fitness Challenge (DFC) 2024. DFC participants have spent the last month leading up to Dubai Run, displaying their passion for health and wellbeing, and their commitment to transforming Dubai into one of the world&rsquo;s most active cities.</p>

<p>UNTOLD DJs at the start and finish lines set an electrifying tone, energising the crowd with vibrant music. Before the event even began, spirits were high as early birds headed to the starting line to be in with a chance of winning exciting prizes. As anticipation built, the sky was lit by three motorised paramotors adorned with colourful LED lights, creating a spectacular aerial display just before sunrise and then later once the event was in full flow. Adding to the spectacle, pyrotechnic skydivers from SkyDive Dubai shot through the sky leaving a wake of the UAE flag&rsquo;s colours behind them, followed by an adrenaline-pumping display from XFlight by XDubai, taking the excitement to even greater heights.</p>

<p>A parade of Dubai Police supercars set the stage for an exhilarating event, led by His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum along the iconic 10 km Sheikh Zayed Route. This thrilling course, culminating at DIFC, wove past several of the city&rsquo;s landmarks. Adding to the excitement, international R&amp;B star Jason Derulo made a surprise appearance at the start of the event, chatting with MC Kris Fade and interacting with the crowd before navigating the course alongside the wider community in a shared love for fitness. There were also appearances by Dubai Sports Council ambassadors, former Paralympian swimmer Jessica Smith, former professional basketball player Fadi El Khatib and Arsenal football legend Bacary Sagna.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the 5 km route offered families, friends, and fitness enthusiasts a relaxed run through Downtown Dubai, past architectural icons like Burj Khalifa and Dubai Opera. Live music, HipHop cardio, performances from African Drummers, the Philippines School Marching Band, Dubai Drums, Stomp Drummers and other street performers, plus appearances from mascots including the beloved Modesh and Dana, Super Mario and Sonic the Hedgehog, who kept the energy high. Both routes offered family-friendly entertainment against the backdrop of Dubai&rsquo;s greatest landmarks, making Dubai Run, presented by Mai Dubai, a memorable celebration of the city and its residents. After the event, numerous F&amp;B venues at DIFC and Dubai Mall opened early to refuel runners after their early morning fitness fun.</p>

<p>His Excellency Saeed Hareb, Secretary General of Dubai Sports Council, commented: &ldquo;Now in its sixth edition, Dubai Run, presented by Mai Dubai, has become one of the most important fitness moments in our city&rsquo;s calendar, uniting community members of all ages, abilities and nationalities to engage in physical activities under one goal &ndash; the pursuit of a healthier and more active life. This year, we were proud to see new participants, families, and seasoned athletes alike, all contributing to Dubai&rsquo;s growing status as one of the world&rsquo;s most active cities.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Ahmed Al Khaja, CEO of Dubai Festivals and Retail Establishment, added: &ldquo;Dubai Run, presented by Mai Dubai, is a powerful testament to the city&rsquo;s commitment to fostering a culture of health and wellbeing. This year&rsquo;s impressive increase in participant numbers highlights the growing success of Dubai Run and serves as a reminder of what we can achieve when we come together as a community with a shared purpose. It&rsquo;s more than just a run; it&rsquo;s an opportunity for everyone - regardless of age or fitness level - to unite in celebration of personal achievement and collective progress.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Abraham Kah, CEO of Mai Dubai, said: &ldquo;Dubai Run is a true celebration of the city&#39;s vibrant spirit and commitment to fostering health, wellness, and community unity. It underscores our shared vision of making the emirate one of the most active cities globally. As Presenting Partners, Mai Dubai is proud to provide water for every participant, supporting their journey as they embrace the challenge. This partnership embodies our dedication to empowering a healthier and more inclusive community, reflecting the very essence of Dubai Fitness Challenge and the city&rsquo;s dynamic culture. We are honoured to be a part of such a transformative initiative that continues to motivate and inspire our city.&rdquo;</p>

<p>A flagship event of Dubai Fitness Challenge, launched in 2017 by His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Dubai Run, presented by Mai Dubai, underscores Dubai&#39;s vision to be the world&rsquo;s most active city and supports its goal to be the best place to visit, live and work in. This year&#39;s edition exemplifies Dubai&#39;s dedication to fostering a vibrant and inclusive community committed to health, wellness, and unity, reflecting the city&#39;s dynamic spirit and collective enthusiasm for wellbeing.</p>

<p>Organised by the Dubai Department of Economy and Tourism (DET) and the Dubai Sports Council, Dubai Run is presented by Mai Dubai, with Association Partners Sun &amp; Sand Sports, dubizzle, Citi Mastercard, La Roche Posay, talabat, WHOOP, and Emaar; Official Partners Dubai Chambers, Emirates, Dubai&rsquo;s Road and Transport Authority (RTA) and Wasl; Media Partner Arabian Radio Network (ARN); and Government Partners Dubai Corporation for Ambulance Services, Dubai Police, and Events Security Committee.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 21:59:09 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735580.1732471910!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735580.1732471910!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed leads record-breaking Dubai Run, presented by Mai Dubai]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sports</category>
										
																			
											<category>Other</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Sports/Other</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Historic Victory: UAE Thrashes Qatar 5-0 in World Cup Qualifiers]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/football/historic-victory-uae-thrashes-qatar-5-0-in-world-cup-qualifiers-2024-11-19-1.735515</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/football/historic-victory-uae-thrashes-qatar-5-0-in-world-cup-qualifiers-2024-11-19-1.735515</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The UAE national football team, &quot;Al Abyad,&quot; achieved a historic 5-0 victory over Qatar, &quot;Al Annabi,&quot; at Al Nahyan Stadium in Abu Dhabi. The win came in the sixth round of Group A matches in the third stage of the Asian qualifiers for the 2026 FIFA World Cup.</p>

<p>This triumph marks the UAE&#39;s largest win over Qatar, surpassing the previous record of a 4-1 victory during the 2015 AFC Asian Cup in Australia. With this result, the UAE has now secured 11 wins against Qatar in their footballing history.</p>

<p>Fabio Lima was the star of the match, netting four goals (a super hat-trick) in the 4th, 45th (penalty), 45+5, and 56th (penalty) minutes. Yahya Al Ghassani added the fifth goal in the 73rd minute, capping off the emphatic win.</p>

<p>The victory bolsters the UAE&rsquo;s chances of directly qualifying for the World Cup, raising their tally to 10 points and securing third place in the group standings. Iran leads the group with 16 points, followed by Uzbekistan with 13 points, while Qatar is fourth with 7 points. Kyrgyzstan holds 3 points, and North Korea is last with 2 points.</p>

<p>The UAE delivered their best performance in years, demonstrating tactical discipline and offensive efficiency. &quot;Al Abyad&quot; dominated the game, consistently pressuring Qatar&rsquo;s defense and showing high morale and determination to keep their World Cup hopes alive.</p>

<p>In the first half, Fabio Lima opened the scoring in the 4th minute, capitalizing on a low cross from Yahya Al Ghassani. Al Ghassani almost doubled the lead in the 32nd minute, but his shot hit the crossbar. Lima extended the lead with a penalty in the 45th minute after Hareb Abdullah was fouled in the box. In stoppage time, Lima unleashed a long-range strike to make it 3-0.</p>

<p>The UAE maintained their dominance in the second half. Lima secured his fourth goal with another penalty, earned by Al Ghassani, before Al Ghassani himself sealed the victory with the fifth goal in the 73rd minute.</p>

<p>In other Group A matches, Iran edged out Kyrgyzstan 3-2 to solidify their top spot, while Uzbekistan defeated North Korea 1-0.</p>

<p>Elsewhere, in Group C, Saudi Arabia suffered a 2-0 defeat to Indonesia in Jakarta, while Japan beat China 3-1 in Xiamen to remain atop the group standings with 16 points. Saudi Arabia, Indonesia, and China each have 6 points.</p>

<p>In Group B, Palestine drew 1-1 with South Korea in Amman, while Iraq defeated Oman 1-0. South Korea leads the group with 14 points, followed by Iraq with 11, Oman with 6, and Palestine with 3.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 23:11:00 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735516.1732068654!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735516.1732068654!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Historic Victory: UAE Thrashes Qatar 5-0 in World Cup Qualifiers]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sports</category>
										
																			
											<category>FootBall</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Sports/Football</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[ADNOC Pro League's market value hit €360 million]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/football/adnoc-pro-league-s-market-value-hit-360-million-2024-11-19-1.735513</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/football/adnoc-pro-league-s-market-value-hit-360-million-2024-11-19-1.735513</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The market value of the ADNOC Pro League reached &euro;360 million, according to the latest statistics of the Transfer Market, the football website with a focus on transfers and market values.</p>

<p>The figures were released ahead of the return of the eighth round next Thursday.</p>

<p>The current value of the competition is the third highest value since the start of the current season at the end of last August, when it reached &euro;352 million at the time, then &euro;373 million in mid-October.<br />
The highest increase in the market value of the competition had jumped to &euro;375 million, with the start of the seventh round before it decreased with the suspension of the competition.</p>

<p>In terms of players, Nabil Fekir, attacking midfielder for UAE Pro League club Al Jazira, maintained his lead as the highest player with a market value of &euro;9 million.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 20:27:09 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735514.1732033595!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735514.1732033595!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[ADNOC Pro League's market value hit €360 million]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sports</category>
										
																			
											<category>FootBall</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Sports/Football</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai Sports Council launches ‘Open Padel Cup for Government Institutions’]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/tennis/dubai-sports-council-launches-open-padel-cup-for-government-institutions-2024-11-19-1.735503</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/tennis/dubai-sports-council-launches-open-padel-cup-for-government-institutions-2024-11-19-1.735503</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The Dubai Sports Council (DSC) has announced the organization of the &lsquo;Open Padel Cup for Government Institutions&rsquo; tournament, which is being held in cooperation with the Just Padel Club, at their courts in Port Rashid area, from December 13-15.</p>

<p>The sport of Padel has witnessed a growing popularity in recent times and the organisers led by the DSC are hoping to tap in local Emirati talent employed in various government departments in the country.</p>

<p>Details of the tournament were announced at a press conference by Fawzia Faridoun, Director of the Community Sports Department at the Dubai Sports Council, Anwar Idrissi, Director of the Just Padel Club, Annie Jiao, CEO of Organizer Royal Griffin, and Harry Chan representative of KuCoin the title sponsor of the event.</p>

<p>Also attending the announcement at the Dubai Sports Council headquarters was former French footballer Ibrahim Bah along with Argentinean padel player Adrian Eduardo Fernandez.</p>

<p>&ldquo;We are delighted to partner with the leading Just Padel Club to organise this tournament. This tournament is a new and distinctive addition to the list of annual sporting events held in Dubai throughout the year. The Dubai Sports Council is pleased to support the tournament as it contributes to enhancing the diversity of sporting events that the Council is keen to achieve while providing opportunities to sports fans of all nationalities who are living in Dubai. This tournament also represents an ideal model of cooperation between the public and private sectors,&rdquo; Fawzia said.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Padel has established its rightful position in Dubai with its wide and rapid spread. By far, it is among the fastest-developing sport in the UAE as it has gained huge popularity, as seen by the growing number of courts dedicated to padel in Dubai itself. Padel is on the rise among players of different ages and gender. Dubai has hosted many major tournaments in recent years, including, but not limited to, the World Team Championship and Masters Championships, the most recent of which was the Premier Dubai Padel 1 Championship that witnessed the participation of an elite group of the best male and female players in the world,&rdquo; she added.</p>

<p>Anwar Idrissi, Director of Just Padel announced the opening of the registration process that actually kicked-off participation in the Open Padel Cup Championship for all government institutions across the UAE. Registration will continue till the tournament entry list reaches a maximum of 32 teams.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Each institution/team will be allowed to field eight (8) male Emirati players, six of whom will be allowed on the field and the remaining two as reserves. Professional players registered in clubs or with the UAE Padel Association will not be allowed to participate, thus ensuring that at least 300 Emirati amateurs will get the benefit of being part of the competition.</p>

<p>The competitions will be held in a single-round, knockout league system, and the first-place winner will walk away with a cash award of AED 30,000, while the runners-up will receive AED 20,000.</p>

<p>Speaking on behalf of sponsors KuCoin,the title sponsor of the tournament, Harry Chan, said: &ldquo;We are pleased to be partner in organizing this pioneering tournament that will contribute in discovering Emirati talent. We, at KuCoin, have chosen to open an office in Dubai because of the renaissance it is witnessing in all sports, tourism and economic fields. We have a desire to dedicate part of our work to the benefit of the community. We have previously sponsored COP28&nbsp; and many such community events. We are happy to be sponsors of this tournament as we realise how important Sports is for the overall development of society.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Padel is not a new sport. In fact, it is among the fastest-growing sports in the UAE and the region. We are here to fuel this growth as we believe Padel has all the ingredients to be an Olympic sport in the future. With the unification of sports and technology, they can have a bright future,&rdquo; Chan added.</p>

<p>Annie Jiao, related: &ldquo;I thank everyone for their interest in the event. We are also grateful to the interest shown by Dubai Sports Council, without whom this event would not have been possible. I thank the sponsors, and we are pleased to cooperate with the tournament sponsor and Just Padel to lay out this inaugural edition of this tournament.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 14:18:07 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735504.1732011497!/image/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.JPG" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735504.1732011497!/image/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.JPG" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai Sports Council launches ‘Open Padel Cup for Government Institutions’]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sports</category>
										
																			
											<category>Tennis</category>
										
																								
										
													
				 									<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/General</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[International Baja set to kick-start with prologue in Hatta on Nov 29]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/international-baja-set-to-kick-start-with-prologue-in-hatta-on-nov-29-2024-11-19-1.735487</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/international-baja-set-to-kick-start-with-prologue-in-hatta-on-nov-29-2024-11-19-1.735487</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Two weeks out from the Baja World Cup title showdown at the Dubai International Baja, competing teams are drawing up elaborate plans and strategies for their visit to one of the UAE&rsquo;s most serene and picturesque locations, with one of the most vibrant urban developments in the region getting set to become the centre of all the action.</p>

<p>Held under the patronage of His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defence of the UAE, and Chairman of The Executive Council of Dubai, the event is organised by the Emirates Motorsports Organization (EMSO) in collaboration with the Dubai Sports Council (DSC). It is backed by Official Automotive Partner Al-Futtaim Toyota, and enjoys the strategic support of the Dubai Government and its entities, including the Dubai Police, RTA, and Dubai Municipality. Additionally, the event proudly partners with charity organisation Al Jalila Foundation.</p>

<p>The Dubai International Baja, an event renowned throughout the off-road motorsports world for its desert challenges, makes a statement this year with a route characterised by unique and awe-inspiring geographical contrasts. For the first time in its current incarnation as an off-road challenge, the event moves away from the traditional sand dunes to venture into the rugged, rural idyll of Hatta for the spectator-friendly prologue at 2.30pm on Friday, 29 November.</p>

<p>Hatta plays host to Dubai International Baja for the first time this year but the spectacular and must-see destination that attracts Emirati and international visitors alike is already a familiar stop in the rallying circuit at the highest level having played host to the event&rsquo;s predecessor, the FIA Dubai International Rally, for several years up to 2015.</p>

<p>The spectacular rocky terrain high in the Hajar Mountains will provide a unique and demanding challenge for drivers and riders before they enter the rolling dunes, which are the familiar stomping ground of the FIA and FIM World Cup competitors coming to Dubai.</p>

<p>Set against the backdrop of the Hajar peaks and within touching distance of the turquoise waters of the Hatta Dam, which offer an equally idyllic getaway for Dubai watersports enthusiasts, the world-famous inland enclave will provide the ideal setting for the vaunted field to set out on this year&rsquo;s Dubai International Baja.</p>

<p>The introduction of the prologue qualifying stage will make this final round of the FIA/FIM World Cup series even more challenging for the crews vying for championship honours in the various competition classes, be it cars, bikes or buggies.</p>

<p>The Qualifying Stage of 4.5 km in Hatta will be a relatively short test on demanding terrain that offers a new challenge to many of the competitors while making its presence felt as a section of key strategic importance.</p>

<p>The prologue establishes the starting position for Special Stage 1 early on Saturday, 30 November and, for the top ten competitors, there is the added opportunity to select their starting position via an ingenious system.</p>

<p>An opportunity no less for fans<br />
Fans travelling to Hatta for the Prologue will witness a stage of key importance in deciding the overall honours. Continuing the organisers&rsquo; policy of bringing the event to the city to make it as accessible as possible to the legions of motorsports fans across the region, Dubai Festival City will once again serve as the event hub throughout the four days of the event, with the official opening ceremony set to wow the crowds on the evening of 29 November.</p>

<p>The Ceremonial Start will be immediately preceded by the Start Selection Ceremony when the top ten competitors from the Prologue will make their choice of starting position for Special Stage 1. The tenth fastest racer from the Prologue is first to make a selection of starting position in the top ten followed by the ninth fastest who can select a position before, after or on the position of previous competitor and can move the previous racer up or down in the order.</p>

<p>Game of strategy<br />
A fascinating game of strategy ensues as the top competitors make their choices. No one wants to be first on the stage, opening the &lsquo;road&rsquo; for the other competitors. Even so, being too far back in the order is also a potential disadvantage, and so the Starting Order Ceremony is always particularly closely watched in the FIA and FIM Bajas World Cup series.</p>

<p>The return to Dubai Festival City for the Opening Ceremony at 7 pm on Friday evening, 29 November, offers fans another opportunity to get close to the competitors and their spectacular machines in the very heart of Dubai. The biggest entertainment, dining and fashion mall in the city sit on the edge of the desert at the doorstep to the city.</p>

<p>The remarkable proximity and inclusion of both the desert setting and the urban landscape are part of the charm of the event, which attracts a world class field across the categories, with many crews citing the unique locations as the one reason they yearn to return year after year.</p>

<p>The inclusion of the protected enclave of Hatta in this year&rsquo;s event is only possible thanks to the vital support from local agencies and stakeholders including the Dubai Sports Council and the police force.</p>

<p>Muhammad Khamis Al Muhairi, Vice President of the Emirates Motorsports Organization and the UAE Sports Executive Committee, stated: &ldquo;We are excited to unveil the introduction of a prologue that will amaze and delight our regular competitors with the fascinating terrain in the always welcoming city of Hatta.</p>

<p>&ldquo;This is an innovation which we are sure will enhance the rally&rsquo;s appeal for competitors, showcasing a landscape of Dubai that is perhaps less known to the international audience, and providing a fantastic spectacle for the local community to enjoy.</p>

<p>&ldquo;The event also returns to Dubai Festival City this year, and with this mix, we anticipate a thrilling event that captivates audiences and competitors alike.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Our collaboration with the Dubai Government, alongside the FIA and FIM, reflects our commitment to delivering a remarkable experience that upholds the highest standards of organisation and safety for all participants and spectators.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The Dubai International Baja is a premier off-road motorsport event held annually in the UAE. The event marks 45 years since its inception as the Dubai International Rally in 1979. Now in its eighth edition under the Baja format, it draws top competitors from around the globe to take on the challenging dunes of Dubai.</p>

<p>Serving as the final round of both the FIA World Baja Cup and the FIM Bajas World Cup, the Dubai International Baja is primed to reassert its place in the region&rsquo;s motorsport heritage.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 08:38:35 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735488.1731991072!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735488.1731991072!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[International Baja set to kick-start with prologue in Hatta on Nov 29]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sports</category>
										
																			
											<category>Other</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Sports/Other</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Mohamed Salah: 90% of my success is rooted in what I’ve learned from books]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/mohamed-salah-90-of-my-success-is-rooted-in-what-i-ve-learned-from-books-2024-11-18-1.735476</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/mohamed-salah-90-of-my-success-is-rooted-in-what-i-ve-learned-from-books-2024-11-18-1.735476</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Global football icon Mohamed Salah captivated audiences on the final day of the 43rd Sharjah International Book Fair (SIBF 2024.) Reflecting on his personal and professional journey, Salah attributed his extraordinary achievements to the transformative power of reading, stating: &quot;90% of my success is rooted in what I&rsquo;ve learned from books. Reading has helped me become a better version of myself.&quot;</p>

<p>Known worldwide for his exceptional speed, precision, and tenacity on the pitch, Salah delved into the profound role books have played in shaping his mindset and career. &quot;I started reading extensively after I left Chelsea,&quot; he shared. &quot;It made me question how people succeed and what it takes to achieve greatness.&quot; He encouraged the audience to embrace a culture of learning and self-discovery, emphasising the value of understanding diverse perspectives. Salah revealed a particular affinity for psychology books, which he credits for helping him better navigate relationships and life&rsquo;s challenges.</p>

<p><strong>A journey from Egypt to the pinnacle of global football</strong></p>

<p>Salah&rsquo;s story began in Egypt, where he honed his skills at Al Mokawloon Al Arab SC before embarking on a remarkable European career. With stints at Basel, Chelsea, Fiorentina, and Roma, he solidified his reputation as a world-class athlete before joining Liverpool FC in 2017.<br />
Throughout the session, Salah provided a glimpse into his disciplined daily routine. &quot;For ten years, I&rsquo;ve trained twice a day, even during holidays&mdash;I always push myself harder,&quot; he said, inspiring the audience with his relentless work ethic.</p>

<p><strong>A commitment to learning and family values</strong></p>

<p>Salah also shared how reading enriches his family life. &quot;I have two daughters, and my wife and I make reading an integral part of their upbringing. Our library contains books in Arabic and English, with a focus on psychology,&quot; he revealed. Despite his busy schedule, Salah ensures that books remain a constant companion: &quot;I always have a book in my bag and try to read before I sleep.&quot;</p>

<p>Looking to the future, Salah announced an exciting plan: &quot;I&#39;m considering writing a biography to serve as a model for younger generations who dream of following the path I took.&quot;</p>

<p>A legacy built on excellence and personal growth</p>

<p>From Premier League and UEFA Champions League titles to Golden Boots and the Puskas Award, Salah&rsquo;s list of accolades is a testament to his talent and determination. Yet, beyond his on-field achievements, his unwavering commitment to personal growth and learning has been a cornerstone of his success.<br />
Salah&rsquo;s talk to his packed SIBF audience served as an inspiring reminder of the transformative power of reading and the boundless potential of self-improvement.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 13:54:06 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735478.1731923543!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735478.1731923543!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735478.1731923543!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735477.1731923532!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Mohamed Salah: 90% of my success is rooted in what I’ve learned from books]]></media:title>

							<media:description><![CDATA[Football legend inspires at the 43rd Sharjah International Book Fair]]></media:description>
						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE to face Qatar tomorrow in AFC Asian Qualifiers]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/football/uae-to-face-qatar-tomorrow-in-afc-asian-qualifiers-2024-11-18-1.735464</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/football/uae-to-face-qatar-tomorrow-in-afc-asian-qualifiers-2024-11-18-1.735464</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The UAE national football team will take on Qatar tomorrow, Tuesday, at Al Nahyan Stadium in Abu Dhabi at 20:00 UAE time, in the sixth round of Group A of the AFC Asian Qualifiers&trade; - Road to 26.</p>

<p>The team is aiming to secure its 10th point and strengthen its chances of qualification.</p>

<p>Both revived their respective campaigns with wins on Thursday and will seek another three points to stay within sight of Iran and Uzbekistan in the race to seal the two automatic qualifying slots.</p>

<p>While the top two finishers in each group qualify automatically, the third and fourth placed teams will advance to a playoff where another two berths will be at stake.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 12:14:04 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735465.1731917607!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735465.1731917607!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE to face Qatar tomorrow in AFC Asian Qualifiers]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sports</category>
										
																			
											<category>FootBall</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Sports/Football</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Make the final week of Dubai Fitness Challenge one to remember]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/make-the-final-week-of-dubai-fitness-challenge-one-to-remember-2024-11-18-1.735462</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/make-the-final-week-of-dubai-fitness-challenge-one-to-remember-2024-11-18-1.735462</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Make the final week of Dubai Fitness Challenge one to remember .. Embrace the thrill of fitness with spectacular line-up of FREE sporting fun for everyone</p>

<p>With three incredible weeks of high-energy fitness activities and boundless enthusiasm behind us, the eighth edition of Dubai Fitness Challenge (DFC) is entering its thrilling home stretch, setting the stage for an unforgettable grand finale.</p>

<p>Since its launch on Sunday 26 October, Dubai has seen a powerful wave of energy, with residents and visitors uniting to crush their 30 x 30 goals and embrace a healthier, more active lifestyle. Now, as the fourth and final week unfolds, an exciting lineup of FREE fitness activities, community events, and wellness initiatives awaits, promising a spectacular close to DFC and a lasting impact on Dubai&rsquo;s fitness scene.</p>

<p>From an unique running experience in the world&rsquo;s largest free fun run at the sixth annual Dubai Run presented by Mai Dubai, to countless fitness classes and events across the city, here&rsquo;s what&rsquo;s in store for an epic final week:</p>

<p>Dubai Run presented by Mai Dubai &ndash; two routes, one iconic experience</p>

<p>Whether your aim is to break a personal record or simply soak in the festive atmosphere, Dubai Run, presented by Mai Dubai, promises an unforgettable final weekend. Taking place on Sunday, 24 November, this celebration of health, fitness, and community spirit is like no other, with two thrilling route options: the 5km Downtown course or the more challenging 10km along Sheikh Zayed Road. Offering a rare chance to run on one of the world&rsquo;s most iconic highways - minus the cars - whilst soaking up the sites of Dubai&rsquo;s stunning skyline, both courses start near the Museum of the Future.</p>

<p>The 5km route, ideal for families, beginners, and casual runners, winds past landmarks such as the Burj Khalifa and Dubai Opera, ending at Souk Al Bahar near Dubai Mall on Sheikh Mohammed Bin Rashid Boulevard. For those looking for more of a challenge, the 10km route stretches along Sheikh Zayed Road, crossing Dubai Canal Bridge, and looping back towards DIFC&rsquo;s Gate Building, offering impressive views of the city&rsquo;s architectural marvels.</p>

<p>Register now for free at www.dubairun.com to secure your spot and experience Dubai like never before. Upon registration, you will receive a QR code, which is required to collect your bib for entry. Bib collection will be available at the Dubai Municipality Zabeel Park 30 x 30 Fitness Village - Gate 2 - until Saturday, 23 November. Collection hours are 4 PM to 11 PM on weekdays, midday to midnight on Fridays, and 8 AM to midnight on weekends. It&rsquo;s also recommended to use public transport as there will be limited public parking available.</p>

<p><br />
<strong>Tomorrow Ride 2024: Join for a healthier community</strong></p>

<p>Looking to warm up ahead of DFC&rsquo;s grand finale event? Join the Tomorrow Ride on 23 November at Hamdan Bin Mohammed Smart University (HBMSU). This cycling event offers two routes: a 4km loop for families and children around the university and a 14km route through Academic City for more experienced cyclists. Organised by the university in collaboration with the Dubai Sports Council, the event kicks off at 6:15 AM and promises a fun-filled day with entertainment, food stalls, and festivities. Whether you&#39;re an avid cyclist or a family looking for a morning adventure, visit the Hopasports website for more information and to register to be part of this exciting fitness celebration!.</p>

<p>Emirates Dubai Sail Grand Prix Presented by P&amp;O Marinas (SailGP)</p>

<p>Make your way to Mina Rashid on Saturday, 23 and Sunday, 24 November for the Emirates Dubai Sail Grand Prix presented by P&amp;O Marinas. Watch 11 national teams, featuring the world&rsquo;s best sailors, battle it out over two thrilling days of high-speed racing as cutting-edge F50s reach over 100 kph. This season, there will also be lots to do and enjoy off the water, including live performances from international superstars Craig David and Tinie Tempah in the Premium Waterfront Lounge in partnership with Nikki Beach Dubai. There will also be a whole host of world-class food options plus family-friendly fun, including interactive fan experiences, F50 simulator sessions, and engaging activities for all ages. Experience the action with a variety of ticketing options that offer unparalleled views and luxury hospitality. Head to www.sailgp.com for more information.</p>

<p>Dubai Padel Cup (DPC) &ndash; An adrenaline-packed competition</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s your last chance to join the Dubai Padel Cup (DPC) as it nears the end of an action-packed month of tournaments. A great way to have fun and find your UAE padel community, you&rsquo;ll learn everything from basic skills to slick, pro-level moves. Plus, with free coaching sessions from some of Dubai&rsquo;s best coaches, you&rsquo;ll have all the tools to take your game to the next level. For more information, visit the Dubai Padel Cup website.</p>

<p>Three free 30x30 30-day Fitness Villages</p>

<p>Get ready for an action-packed final weekend of DFC &ndash; the clock is ticking, and this is your last chance to experience the ultimate fitness adventure across its three free 30x30 Fitness Villages at Kite Beach, Zabeel Park, and Al Warqa&rsquo;a Park. These high-energy hotspots have been buzzing with excitement over the last few weeks, and they&rsquo;re set to go out with a bang! So, whether you&#39;re a fitness fanatic or just starting out, these vibrant locations will help unlock your full potential, push your limits, and make the most of every last moment of DFC.</p>

<p>The DP World Kite Beach 30x30 Fitness Village is a fitness paradise on Dubai&#39;s iconic coastline. With dynamic sessions, family-friendly zones, and ample space to stay active, it&rsquo;s the perfect place to conquer your 30 x 30 goals before the challenge ends. From padel to water sports, beach volleyball to yoga, and so much more, there&rsquo;s no better time to jump in and get active. The difference zones include:</p>

<p>- Decathlon Sports Court</p>

<p>- DP World Cricket Arena</p>

<p>- DP World Sports Hub</p>

<p>- Emarat Padel Courts</p>

<p>- Emirates Rebounder</p>

<p>- Emirates NBD Watersports</p>

<p>- Emirates NBD Yoga</p>

<p>- e&amp; Main Stage</p>

<p>- MIRA Teen Fit &ndash; Boxd &ndash; Martial Arts</p>

<p>- Sun &amp; Sand Sports Beach Volleyball</p>

<p>- talabat Core &ndash; Cardio &ndash; Resistance</p>

<p>- Wasl Gymnastics</p>

<p>- Wasl Parkour</p>

<p>- WHOOP Lift &ndash; Ride &ndash; Row</p>

<p>Classes to look out for this week include Power Row at WHOOP Row &ndash; a full-body workout using rowing machines to build strength and power; and Mindful Movement at Emirates NBD Yoga &ndash; the opportunity to cultivate mindfulness, flexibility, and strength through a blend of poses and breathing techniques. For those looking to improve muscle tone, strength and endurance, there is the Dubai 92 Fitness Rave taking place on Saturday, 23 November at 6 PM &ndash; an energetic dance based class on the e&amp; Main Stage.</p>

<p>Open on weekdays from 3 PM to 11 PM and throughout the final weekend from 7 AM to 11 PM, this fitness village is more than just a place to work out &ndash; it&rsquo;s a lively community space where you can connect, stay active, and smash your 30x30 goals. So, make the most of this open-air gym while you still can!</p>

<p>The perfect spot to get active, the Dubai Municipality Zabeel Park 30x30 Fitness Village offers an exciting variety of activities to boost your health and wellness. Head to the Main Stage for a full-body dance workout to urban moves and beats in a Street Dance Party Class, test your batting and bowling skills at the Cricket Zone or challenge your mates to a game on the Emirates 3 on 3 Basketball Court - there&rsquo;s no shortage of activities to get you moving. Families can also get in on the action at the Dubai Municipality Teens Gym with Junior Jump &ndash; a fun jump-based class where kids can improve distance and power - or Mini HIIT &ndash; a high intensity interval training suitable for the kids!</p>

<p>Serving as the central hub for you to collect your bibs for Dubai Run, presented by Mai Dubai, until Saturday, 23 November, this fitness village is open from 4 PM to 11 PM Monday to Thursday, 12 PM to midnight on Fridays, and 8 AM to midnight for its final weekend.</p>

<p>Get ready for the final week of DFC at the RTA Al Warqa&rsquo;a Park 30x30 Fitness Village, your ultimate outdoor fitness destination. At its heart, you&#39;ll find the Cycling Hub, equipped with 75 bikes and on-site mechanics. Challenge yourself with the Running Club or enjoy some friendly competition on Dubai Municipality&rsquo;s sports pitches and courts. For a more private experience, there&#39;s a ladies-only zone offering specialised classes like FlowShift, a mindful yoga session emphasizing meditation. Kids can dive into their own fun with activities at the children&#39;s area, from the Modesh Inflatable and sports like tennis and basketball, to the Strength Stars class, which builds their strength, endurance, flexibility, and teaches the value of healthy eating.</p>

<p><br />
Open from 4 PM to 11 PM Sunday to Thursday and until 11:30 PM on the final weekend, this fitness village is the perfect place for an active, fun-filled outing with family and friends.</p>

<p><br />
Don&rsquo;t miss out on the action at the 30 x 30 fitness villages &ndash; bring your refillable water bottle and towel, and make sure you are part of the movement by sharing your journey with #ShareYour30 on social media. For full schedules, visit booking.dubaifitnesschallenge.com.</p>

<p><strong>Community Hubs across Dubai</strong></p>

<p>Designed to bring daily free activities and workout sessions to your doorstep, these community fitness hubs make it incredibly convenient for the entire family to achieve a healthier and more active lifestyle. Wherever you are in the city, seize the opportunity to explore these community fitness hubs before the final week concludes:</p>

<p>Bluewaters Fitness Hub | Daily invigorating, open-air Pilates sessions for all fitness levels, set against the breathtaking backdrop of the sea and skyline. Whether you&rsquo;re an experienced Pilates practitioner or just starting out, the skilled instructors will guide you through a series of exercises aimed at enhancing core strength, flexibility and overall well-being.</p>

<p>Dubai Media City Fitness Hub | Multiple zones offering an exciting range of activities including high-intensity workouts and yoga sessions, with daily classes from 8 AM to 9 PM.</p>

<p>Global Village Fitness Hub | Specifically designed for children, the Kids&#39; Theatre will host a series of activities, including dance, creative movement, and interactive fitness sessions. Parents can enjoy the attractions at Global Village while their kids get active. Daily from 5 PM to 9 PM.</p>

<p>The Beach JBR Fitness Hub | Every Friday and Saturday from 4 PM to 8 PM, join the exciting Zumba Festival and swear it out in free Zumba workout sessions led by professional instructors. No registration required, just show up and join the fun.</p>

<p>Tilal Al Ghaf Fitness Hub | Don&rsquo;t miss out on free, community-driven daily activities for all fitness levels. Try four unique zones, from High Intensity and Cardio to Cycling and Wellness (complete with breathwork and ice baths), plus a Kids Zone full of fun. Also, enjoy special partner events like lululemon sessions, movie nights with VOX Cinemas, and nutrition talks by Carrefour. Open weekdays 6:30 AM to 10:30 AM, 6 PM to 9 PM, and weekends 8:30 AM to 9 PM.</p>

<p>Town Square Fitness Hub | Get moving with daily classes from F45, Tula Studios, Easy Fitness, and Spartan. From high-energy HIIT and boxing to core-strengthening Pilates and yoga, there&rsquo;s something for everyone from 7 AM to 7 PM. Make the most of this last week to sweat, smile, and succeed!</p>

<p>Wasl One Fitness Hub | Don&rsquo;t miss your chance to join the Wasl 1 Fitness Hub at Park Gate Residences in Za&#39;abeel 1, running from 18 to 24 November! This week offers a range of workouts for all fitness levels, from high-intensity HIIT and circuit training to relaxing yoga and fun Zumba sessions. Families can also enjoy martial arts classes for kids and adults, plus agility and functional training to boost coordination and balance. Bring your own mat, towel, and water bottle, and be sure to register in advance. Open daily 7am to 7:30am and 6pm to 7:30pm&mdash;embrace a week of health and wellness with the community!</p>

<p>Other community hubs include: Athletic Caravan Initiative Fitness Hub, City Walk Fitness Hub, Danube Sport World Fitness Hub, Dubai Design District Fitness Hub, Dubai Digital Park Fitness Hub, Golf is Good Fitness Hub, Hatta Wadi Hub Fitness Hub, JLT Fitness Hub, Wasl Village Fitness Hub, and Zabeel Ladies Club Fitness Hub.</p>

<p>As the Challenge enters into its final week, now&rsquo;s your chance to push yourself, celebrate your progress, and finish strong. With a variety of exciting events and activities ahead, keep the momentum going and inspire others by sharing your journey with #ShareYour30 on social media.</p>

<p>Head to www.dubaifitnesschallenge.com for more details!</p>

<p>The entities helping DFC strengthen the spirit of the community this year include organisers the Dubai Department of Economy and Tourism (DET) and Dubai Sports Council; Presenting Partners DP World, Dubai Municipality, Mai Dubai, and Dubai&rsquo;s Roads and Transport Authority (RTA); Association Partners Sun and Sand Sports, The Brain and Performance Centre - A DP World Company, Citi Mastercard, Decathlon, dubizzle, Emirates, Emirates NBD, e&amp;, La Roche Posay, MIRA Developments, talabat, Wasl, WHOOP, Shamal &ndash; Kite Beach, Emaar and Hatta Kayak; Official Partners Dubai Chambers, Emarat and Supercare Pharmacy; Media Partner Arabian Radio Network (ARN); and Government Partners Dubai Corporation for Ambulance Services, Dubai Health, Dubai Knowledge and Human Development Authority (KHDA), Dubai Police, Ministry of Education and Event Security Committee.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 11:31:40 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735463.1731915087!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735463.1731915087!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Make the final week of Dubai Fitness Challenge one to remember]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sports</category>
										
																			
											<category>Other</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Sports/Other</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Mansoor bin Mohammed attends Dubai T100 World Tour Final]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/mansoor-bin-mohammed-attends-dubai-t100-world-tour-final-2024-11-18-1.735446</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/mansoor-bin-mohammed-attends-dubai-t100-world-tour-final-2024-11-18-1.735446</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong>- Marten Van Riel from Belgian and Taylor Knibb from the USA claim the inaugural T100 World Championship titles in the elite races</strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mansoor bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Chairman of the Dubai Sports Council (DSC), Yesterday attended the highly anticipated Dubai T100 World Tour Final at the Meydan Racecourse.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mansoor bin Mohammed watched the men&rsquo;s professional race of the T100 World Tour Final witnessing a thrilling showcase of elite endurance sports. He praised the outstanding performance and dedication displayed by all participants competing for the prestigious title.</p>

<p>His Highness highlighted how the Dubai T100 World Tour Final demonstrates Dubai&rsquo;s ability to host world-class international events, reinforcing its status as a global hub for sporting excellence. He also commended the successful organisation of the event, underlining its pivotal role in enhancing Dubai&rsquo;s status as a leading destination for sports.</p>

<p>His Highness added that the success of such events reflects the expertise of the UAE&rsquo;s national workforce, Dubai&rsquo;s state-of-the-art facilities, and the city&rsquo;s commitment to fostering a vibrant and inclusive sporting culture.</p>

<p>The men&rsquo;s pro race was won by Marten Van Riel from Belgian, capping off a spectacular season of wins in San Francisco and Ibiza to win the World Title in Dubai in a time of 3 hours, 9 minutes and 17 seconds. In yesterday&rsquo;s women&rsquo;s pro race, America&rsquo;s Taylor Knibb showcased an exceptional performance, securing both the race victory and the overall series title, further establishing herself as a leading figure in the sport.</p>

<p>Van Riel and Taylor Knibb were presented their World Title trophies by His Excellency Saeed Mohammed Hareb, Secretary General of Dubai Sports Council; Sam Renouf, CEO of the Professional Triathletes Organisations, and Antonio Arimany, President of World Triathlon.</p>

<p>Ahead of the elite men&rsquo;s race, over 3,400 age-group triathletes competed on the same course as their sporting heroes in the 100km Age Group race. Representing 63 nationalities, the athletes were cheered on by thousands of spectators lining the venue and the vibrant Race Village.</p>

<p>In the women&rsquo;s age-group category, Caroline Bridges from the UK claimed the top spot with an impressive finish time of 04:02:27. In the men&rsquo;s age-group category, UAE resident Quentin Amaral took victory, crossing the finish line in 03:25:46.</p>

<p>Besides the racing, people also enjoyed the family-friendly entertainment and activities in the Race Village at the Meydan Racecourse, with brand activations and live music.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 06:50:32 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735447.1731898209!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735447.1731898209!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Mansoor bin Mohammed attends Dubai T100 World Tour Final]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sports</category>
										
																			
											<category>Other</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Sports/Other</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Mansoor bin Mohammed crowns Rory McIlroy as the DP World Tour Championship winner]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/golf/mansoor-bin-mohammed-crowns-rory-mcilroy-as-the-dp-world-tour-championship-winner-2024-11-18-1.735444</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/golf/mansoor-bin-mohammed-crowns-rory-mcilroy-as-the-dp-world-tour-championship-winner-2024-11-18-1.735444</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong>- Northern Ireland&rsquo;s Rory McIlroy clinches his sixth &lsquo;Race to Dubai&rsquo; title and third consecutive victory</strong></li>
	<li><strong>- The 16th edition of the tournament featured a prize fund of $10 million</strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mansoor bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Chairman of the Dubai Sports Council, crowned Northern Ireland&rsquo;s Rory McIlroy as the winner of the 16th edition of the DP World Tour Championship. This marks the season finale of the Race to Dubai and the elite Rolex Series tournaments, held under His Highness&rsquo;s patronage at Jumeirah Golf Estates Club in Dubai.</p>

<p>The tournament concluded today (Sunday), featuring the top 50 golfers in the Race to Dubai rankings, with a total prize fund of $10 million.</p>

<p>His Highness also presented Rory McIlroy with the Harry Vardon Cup, recognising him as the top-ranked player in the Race to Dubai for the sixth time in his career and third in a row. McIlroy&rsquo;s previous triumphs came in 2012, 2014, 2015, 2022, and 2023. He walked away with the tournament champion&rsquo;s prize of $3 million and an additional $2 million for topping the Race to Dubai rankings, totalling $5 million in earnings.</p>

<p>The awards ceremony was attended by His Excellency Sultan Ahmed bin Sulayem, Chairman and CEO of DP World Group, His Excellency Khalfan Belhoul, Vice Chairman of the Dubai Sports Council, and Major General Pilot Abdullah Al Sayed Al Hashemi, Vice Chairman of the Emirates Golf Federation.</p>

<p>McIlroy&rsquo;s victory came after intense competition, finishing at 15-under-par, two shots ahead of runner-up Rasmus Hojgaard of Denmark, who posted a score of 13-under-par.</p>

<p>This championship concluded an exceptional season where the UAE hosted the &quot;final playoffs&quot; under the new format, beginning with the Abu Dhabi HSBC Championship at Yas Links, featuring the top 70 players, followed by the DP World Tour Championship at Jumeirah Golf Estates with the top 50.</p>

<p>The 2024 DP World Tour season included 44 tournaments held across 24 countries, attracting the world&rsquo;s best golfers and competing under the &lsquo;Race to Dubai&rsquo; banner.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 06:43:55 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735445.1731897824!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735445.1731897824!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Mansoor bin Mohammed crowns Rory McIlroy as the DP World Tour Championship winner]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sports</category>
										
																			
											<category>Golf</category>
										
																								
										
													
				 									<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/General</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Discover the community hubs bringing fitness to your doorstep this Dubai Fitness Challenge]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/discover-the-community-hubs-bringing-fitness-to-your-doorstep-this-dubai-fitness-challenge-2024-11-15-1.735421</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/discover-the-community-hubs-bringing-fitness-to-your-doorstep-this-dubai-fitness-challenge-2024-11-15-1.735421</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>As Dubai Fitness Challenge (DFC) continues to ramp up, smashing your 30x30 goals has never been easier and more accessible. With an expansive network of community hubs across the city, you&rsquo;re only moments away from a wide variety of activities tailored to every fitness level and interest &ndash; from adrenaline-pumping, high-energy boot camps to soothing yoga sessions, or even adventurous new sports like dragon boat racing.</p>

<p>Launched by His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defence of the UAE, and Chairman of The Executive Council of Dubai, this year&rsquo;s challenge emphasises community engagement and mutual support in the pursuit of health and wellness. Gather your friends, family, or coworkers and explore the nearest community hub, each offering free daily activities and workout sessions designed to make maintaining a healthier lifestyle effortless and enjoyable.</p>

<p>His Excellency Saeed Hareb, Secretary General of Dubai Sports Council said, &quot;Dubai Fitness Challenge extends beyond a simple fitness initiative; it is a catalyst for lasting change, encouraging everyone to make fitness a daily habit. By bringing fitness directly to local neighbourhoods, we aim to have a sustainable impact on the health and well-being of both residents and visitors, encouraging everyone to embrace wellness and community spirit.&quot;</p>

<p>Ahmed Al Khaja, CEO of Dubai Festivals and Retail Establishment added: &quot;Our mission is to create inviting environments that inspire individuals and families to prioritise their health and begin a transformative fitness journey. With 25 strategically located community hubs around Dubai, each tailored to integrate seamlessly into everyday life, we are making it easier for everyone to achieve their 30 x 30 goals and benefit from an active lifestyle.&quot;</p>

<p>Are you ready to embrace the challenge? No matter where you are in the city, there is a community hub waiting to inspire you on your&nbsp; journey. Here are the hubs that have been motivating fitness enthusiasts this DFC:&nbsp;</p>

<p>-Athletic Caravan Initiative Fitness Hub&nbsp;</p>

<p>-Aqua Fishing Academy Fitness Hub</p>

<p>-Bluewaters Fitness Hub&nbsp;</p>

<p>-City Walk Fitness Hub</p>

<p>-Danube Sport World Fitness Hub&nbsp;</p>

<p>-Dubai Design District Fitness Hub&nbsp;</p>

<p>-Dubai Digital Park Fitness Hub&nbsp;</p>

<p>-Dubai Media City Fitness Hub&nbsp;</p>

<p>-Expo City Dubai Fitness Hub&nbsp;</p>

<p>-Gate Avenue Fitness Hub&nbsp;</p>

<p>-Global Village Fitness Hub&nbsp;</p>

<p>-Golf is Good Fitness Hub&nbsp;</p>

<p>-Hatta Wadi Hub Fitness Hub&nbsp;</p>

<p>-JLT Fitness Hub</p>

<p>-P&amp;O Marinas Fitness Hub&nbsp;</p>

<p>-Ripe Market Fitness Hub&nbsp;</p>

<p>-Sustainable City Fitness Hub&nbsp;</p>

<p>-The Beach, JBR Fitness Hub&nbsp;</p>

<p>-Tilal Al Ghaf Fitness Hub</p>

<p>-Town Square Fitness Hubs</p>

<p>- Wasl Green Park Fitness Hub&nbsp;</p>

<p>- Wasl One Fitness Hub&nbsp;</p>

<p>- Wasl Port Views Fitness Hub&nbsp;</p>

<p>- Wasl Village Fitness Hub&nbsp;</p>

<p>- Zabeel Ladies Club Fitness Hub&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
The availability of activities plus operational dates and hours vary across the different hubs. To learn more and find out what&rsquo;s happening near you, visit www.dubaifitnesschallenge.com. Also, don&rsquo;t forget to #ShareYour30 &ndash; every step, class, or workout can inspire others to join in the challenge.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
The entities helping DFC strengthen the spirit of the community this year include organisers the Dubai Department of Economy and Tourism (DET) and Dubai Sports Council;</p>

<p>Presenting Partners DP World, Dubai Municipality, Mai Dubai, and Dubai&rsquo;s Roads and Transport Authority (RTA); Association Partners Sun &amp; Sand Sports, The Brain and Performance Centre - A DP World Company, Citi Mastercard, Decathlon, Dubizzle, Emirates Airline, Emirates NBD, e&amp;, La Roche Posay, MIRA Developments, talabat, Wasl, Whoop, Shamal &ndash; Kite Beach, Emaar and Hatta Kayak; Official Partners Dubai Chambers, Emarat and Supercare Pharmacy; Media Partner Arabian Radio Network (ARN); and Government Partners Dubai Corporation for Ambulance Services, Dubai Health, Dubai Knowledge and Human Development Authority (KHDA), Dubai Police, Ministry of Education and Event Security Committee.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 13:16:47 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735422.1731662144!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735422.1731662144!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Discover the community hubs bringing fitness to your doorstep this Dubai Fitness Challenge]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sports</category>
										
																			
											<category>Other</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Sports/Other</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai Sports Retreat Receives High Praise for Its Impact on Sports Development and Community Engagement]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/dubai-sports-retreat-receives-high-praise-for-its-impact-on-sports-development-and-community-engagement-2024-11-14-1.735398</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/dubai-sports-retreat-receives-high-praise-for-its-impact-on-sports-development-and-community-engagement-2024-11-14-1.735398</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<div class="flex max-w-full flex-col flex-grow">
<div class="min-h-8 text-message flex w-full flex-col items-end gap-2 whitespace-normal break-words [.text-message+&amp;]:mt-5" data-message-author-role="assistant" data-message-id="eedc08b0-0382-4c6d-9063-0dc3e7d14d07" data-message-model-slug="gpt-4o-mini" dir="auto">
<div class="flex w-full flex-col gap-1 empty:hidden first:pt-[3px]">
<div class="markdown prose w-full break-words dark:prose-invert light">
<p>The recently concluded &#39;Dubai Sports Retreat,&#39; held at the Museum of the Future, has garnered widespread acclaim from participants and international sports figures for its stimulating discussions, innovative topics, and valuable ideas. The event, organized by the Dubai Sports Council under the theme &lsquo;Dubai: The First Sports Destination,&rsquo; brought together 100 decision-makers, specialists, experts, and renowned sports personalities. This collective effort aimed to present actionable suggestions aligned with the government&rsquo;s commitment to further developing Dubai&#39;s sports sector.</p>

<p>The retreat highlighted the unwavering support from Dubai&#39;s wise leadership in promoting sports as a way of life, integral to the health, happiness, and quality of life of its people. Discussions underscored how sports can unify society, enhance wellbeing, and serve as a tool for positive social change. The event also facilitated networking between athletes and experts from various sectors, fostering cooperation to further support the sports industry.</p>

<p>The event&rsquo;s main session, titled &lsquo;The Power of Sport... An Impact Beyond the Field,&rsquo; was led by His Excellency Dr. Ahmed Belhoul Al Falasi, Minister of Sports, alongside notable figures such as His Excellency Hilal Al Marri, Director General of the Department of Economy and Tourism in Dubai, Her Excellency Hessa Buhumaid, Director General of the Community Development Authority in Dubai, and His Excellency Ahmad Bin Byat, Vice Chairman of the Dubai Chamber of Digital Economy.</p>

<p>The second session, &lsquo;Dubai: The Land of Talents... Towards a Promising Future,&rsquo; featured renowned sports stars including MMA world champion Khabib Nurmagomedov, former football captain Patrice Evra, Lebanese basketball legend Fadi Al Khatib, and Indian sports icons Sania Mirza and Harbhajan Singh.</p>

<p>In his opening remarks, His Excellency Khalfan Belhoul, Vice Chairman of the Dubai Sports Council, emphasized the importance of sports in enhancing societal well-being and outlined the vision for expanding Dubai&rsquo;s sports sector.</p>

<p>The retreat also provided a platform for leaders from Dubai&#39;s sports clubs to engage with stakeholders from the government and private sectors. Athletes engaged in informal discussions with professionals from a wide range of industries, including corporate executives, real estate developers, sports investors, and talent development specialists.</p>

<p>Among the notable figures attending were His Excellency Khalifa Saeed Suleiman, Head of Protocol for the Vice President and Prime Minister of the UAE, as well as the chairmen of various Dubai sports clubs, such as Al Nasr Club, Al Wasl Club, Hatta Club, and the Dubai Chess Club, alongside key officials from economic and governmental institutions.</p>

<p><strong>The Economic and Societal Impact of Sports</strong></p>

<p>Participants in the two interactive sessions acknowledged the profound impact of sports on community development, happiness, and the national economy. They stressed that sports play a crucial role in attracting talent, fostering global recognition, and elevating Dubai&rsquo;s standing on the international sports map. Furthermore, government support, coupled with progressive legislation and investment incentives, positions Dubai as a leading sports hub.</p>

<p><strong>Al Falasi Highlights Economic and Social Benefits of Sports</strong></p>

<p>His Excellency Dr. Ahmed Belhoul Al Falasi underlined the global economic power of sports, drawing comparisons with Melbourne, Australia, which generates approximately $4.5 billion annually from sporting events and activities. He stressed the broader economic impact of the sports ecosystem, emphasizing the roles of coaches, nutritionists, and related industries. Additionally, he highlighted the social benefits of sports, such as fostering cohesion and inclusivity. Al Falasi cited the UAE&#39;s experience in hosting the 2019 Special Olympics as a turning point in changing societal perceptions of people with disabilities, referring to them as &#39;People of Determination.&#39;</p>

<p><strong>Buhumaid Emphasizes Social Cohesion through Sports</strong></p>

<p>Her Excellency Hessa Buhumaid praised sports as a tool for community cohesion and integration. In alignment with His Highness Sheikh Mansoor bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum&#39;s vision, Buhumaid highlighted the role of sports in uniting diverse social groups and fostering values of tolerance and understanding. She also noted that volunteerism plays a significant role in sports activities, with the Community Development Authority coordinating thousands of volunteer opportunities in the sector.</p>

<p><strong>Hilal Al Marri: Sports as a Key to Dubai&rsquo;s Growth</strong></p>

<p>His Excellency Hilal Al Marri highlighted the integral role sports play in Dubai&#39;s economic and cultural transformation. He pointed out that Dubai has become a hub for global sports brands, driving investments in fitness, health, and wellness sectors. With ongoing investments in cycling infrastructure and sporting events, Dubai has positioned itself as a destination for health-conscious tourists, fostering both economic and societal growth.</p>

<p><strong>Ahmed Bin Byat Calls for More Integration in Sports Strategy</strong></p>

<p>His Excellency Ahmad Bin Byat stressed the importance of strategic integration of Dubai&rsquo;s residents into sports events, particularly individual sports. He advocated for a more inclusive approach to sporting activities, suggesting a focus on Olympic sports to engage the broader community and ensure long-term sustainability.</p>

<p>The Dubai Sports Retreat has successfully showcased the city&rsquo;s commitment to becoming a global sports leader. It demonstrated the significant role of sports in fostering community cohesion, driving economic growth, and promoting a healthier, more inclusive society. Moving forward, the event&#39;s insights will guide the development of Dubai&rsquo;s sports ecosystem, ensuring its continued success as a premier destination for athletes, investors, and enthusiasts worldwide.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 09:50:33 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735399.1731563396!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735399.1731563396!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735399.1731563396!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735403.1731563568!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735402.1731563555!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735401.1731563542!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735400.1731563528!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai Sports Retreat Receives High Praise for Its Impact on Sports Development and Community Engagement]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sports</category>
										
																			
											<category>Other</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Sports/Other</category>
										
					</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
