<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
	<title>Mobile - Arts and Culture</title>
	<link>http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-arts-and-culture-1.708766?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout</link>	
	<atom:link href="http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-arts-and-culture-1.708766?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" ></atom:link>
	<description>Arts and Culture</description>
			        <language>en</language>
    				<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Latifa bint Mohammed inaugurates fourth edition of ‘Al Marmoom: Film in The Desert’ festival]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/latifa-bint-mohammed-inaugurates-fourth-edition-of-al-marmoom-film-in-the-desert-festival-2025-01-05-1.736061</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/latifa-bint-mohammed-inaugurates-fourth-edition-of-al-marmoom-film-in-the-desert-festival-2025-01-05-1.736061</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Organised by Dubai Culture under the theme &lsquo;Where Stories Come to Life,&rsquo; event running until 12 January aims to support creative talent in the local film industry</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Her Highness: The festival celebrates the authenticity of Dubai&rsquo;s identity, its dynamic spirit, and future aspirations, fostering intellectual dialogue</strong></li>
	<li><strong>&ldquo;Cinema has the profound ability to shape generations rooted in values while addressing the aspirations and challenges of societies and preserving the rich history of nations&rdquo;&nbsp;</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Drawing inspiration from the Ghaf tree, the festival also features an array of musical performances, live shows, and heritage displays</strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p><br />
Her Highness Sheikha Latifa bint Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Chairperson of the Dubai Culture and Arts Authority (Dubai Culture), inaugurated the fourth edition of the &lsquo;Al Marmoom: Film in the Desert&rsquo; festival. Organised by Dubai Culture in the Al Marmoom Desert Reserve, the event seeks to advance the local film industry by providing an innovative platform that supports talented creatives, encouraging them to express their visions and showcase their works and productions to a wider audience.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The festival, an initiative under the Dubai Quality of Life Strategy 2033, features screenings of over 80 feature films. Running until 12 January under the theme &lsquo;Where Stories Come to Life,&rsquo; the event will also host interactive workshops, panel discussions, and talks with a distinguished group of directors, artists, and film industry experts.</p>

<p>Her Highness Sheikha Latifa emphasised that Dubai has excelled in attracting leading directors and talents in the film industry thanks to its extensive capabilities, state-of-the-art infrastructure, and unique creative environment that fosters innovation. She highlighted that, through its ambitious projects and initiatives, the emirate continues to enhance its global leadership, solidify its standing as a cultural and artistic capital, and establish itself as a premier destination for cinematic content creation and production.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Cinema is one of the most powerful expressions of human creativity, distinguished by its unique visual language that seamlessly blends technical mastery with artistic purpose. It has the profound ability to shape generations rooted in values while addressing the aspirations and challenges of societies and preserving the rich history and culture of nations,&rdquo; Her Highness said.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>She added: &ldquo;The Al Marmoom: Film in the Desert festival is a remarkable addition to Dubai&rsquo;s artistic and cinematic landscape through its exceptional cultural experiences and high-quality cinematic works, celebrating the authenticity of Dubai&rsquo;s identity, vibrant energy, and ambitious future aspirations.&nbsp;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Reflecting the beauty of our heritage, the essence of our culture, and the depth of our history, the festival&rsquo;s significance lies in its role as a catalyst for intellectual dialogue, a bridge for cultural exchange, and a source of inspiration for emerging talents. It nurtures creativity; encourages filmmakers to explore the latest industry trends, practices, and opportunities, contributing to fostering a new generation capable of advancing this vital sector, which stands as a cornerstone of Dubai&rsquo;s thriving creative economy.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>Immersive Experience Zone</strong></p>

<p>Sheikha Latifa took an elaborate tour of the festival, exploring, among other highlights, an Immersive Experience Zone. The zone showcased digital artworks created using Artificial Intelligence, in addition to inspiring murals, and installations featuring the work of artists Ghaleb Hawila, Abdullah Lutfi, and Mikhail Antykov.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Her Highness also visited the festival&rsquo;s dedicated pavilions for workshops, seminars, and family-friendly activities and the &lsquo;VIP Barzah&rsquo; area, where she engaged with artists participating in the event, commending their creativity and the diversity of their artistic works. She praised the powerful messages and concepts conveyed through their creations, which reflect a wide array of unique perspectives and artistic visions.</p>

<p>Audiences at the Al Marmoom: Film in the Desert festival will be able to enjoy a curated selection of films chosen from amongst 240 submissions, including notable entries competing for the Al Marmoom Short-Film Competition awards across four categories: documentaries, animation, live-action, and films made using Artificial Intelligence.</p>

<p>The festival&rsquo;s programme includes more than 30 workshops led by renowned creatives and cinema experts, including four workshops organised by the College of Arts and Creative Enterprises at Zayed University. It also offers a diverse array of seminars, panel discussions, and activities tailored to inspire young talents and encourage them to embark on professional careers across the cinema and the arts sectors.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Array of activities</strong></p>

<p>Inspired by the iconic Ghaf tree, the festival serves as a platform to strengthen intercultural engagement and raise environmental awareness by encouraging visitors to explore the Al Marmoom Desert, a treasured nature reserve and one of Dubai&rsquo;s key cultural landmarks. The event features a wide array of activities, including performing arts, musical and heritage shows, and interactive experiences such as &lsquo;Create Your Own AI Movie.&rsquo; Visitors can also visit the planetarium for a stargazing session, or take in the reserve&rsquo;s stunning landscapes on a safari bus tour. A photography competition is also sure to add to the excitement.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dubai Culture dedicates significant space to showcasing traditional crafts and elements of local heritage, reflecting its commitment to promoting cultural authenticity at artistic and cultural events across the emirate. Additionally, attendees can savour traditional cuisine in a heritage-rich and creatively designed setting.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The festival is held in collaboration with an extensive list of partners, including Dubai Mounted Police, Dubai Municipality, Dubai Ambulance, Dubai Police, Dubai Civil Defence, the Roads and Transport Authority, the Islamic Affairs and Charitable Activities Department in Dubai, Mohammed Bin Rashid Space Centre, The Climate Tribe, Lina Kattan, Emirates Airlines, Zayed University, Sandooq Al Watan, Emirates Photography Society, Maraya, Freej, Ferjan Dubai, and Immersee.&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 5 Jan 2025 19:12:41 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736062.1736089926!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736062.1736089926!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Latifa bint Mohammed inaugurates fourth edition of ‘Al Marmoom: Film in The Desert’ festival]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Latifa bint Mohammed unveils groundbreaking report on Dubai’s creative economy]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/latifa-bint-mohammed-unveils-groundbreaking-report-on-dubai-s-creative-economy-2024-12-25-1.735967</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/latifa-bint-mohammed-unveils-groundbreaking-report-on-dubai-s-creative-economy-2024-12-25-1.735967</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>In line with the vision of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister of the UAE, and Ruler of Dubai, to position Dubai as a global centre for culture, an incubator for creativity, and a thriving hub for talent, Her Highness Sheikha Latifa bint Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Chairperson of the Dubai Culture and Arts Authority (Dubai Culture), has unveiled a report titled &lsquo;Creative Dubai: Navigating Tomorrow&rsquo;s Creative Landscape&rsquo;. This initiative is part of Dubai Culture&rsquo;s efforts to advance the objectives of the Dubai Creative Economy Strategy.</p>

<p>The report, developed in collaboration with DinarStandard, a privately-owned growth strategy research and advisory firm empowering organisations for responsible global impact, highlights Dubai&rsquo;s achievements in the cultural and creative industries, the key factors contributing to the city&rsquo;s cultural vision, and significant data tracking the sector&rsquo;s transformation. It also offers a comprehensive analysis of the creative sector&rsquo;s performance and its diverse investment opportunities.</p>

<p>Her Highness emphasised that creativity is a powerful cultural, social, and economic force and a vital pillar in shaping the future of societies and cities. Highlighting its significant impact on advancing Dubai&rsquo;s knowledge and innovation-driven economy, she said: &ldquo;Through its extraordinary growth journey and visionary achievements, Dubai has established itself as a prominent global economic and cultural hub. Under the leadership of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Dubai has become a magnet for talent and investors worldwide. Its dynamic economic system and ambitious initiatives combined with the boundless opportunities it offers creatives and entrepreneurs, Dubai has reinforced its leadership in the creative economy and its role in shaping the future of culture and art.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Her Highness emphasised the strategic significance of the report, highlighting its comprehensive overview of the creative economy in the UAE, the Arab region, and worldwide, as well as its role in shaping the future of the local creative sector. &ldquo;Dubai continues to advance its creative and cultural industries by embracing innovative solutions, developing advanced digital infrastructure, and fostering an environment that empowers and supports the cultural and creative sector.</p>

<p>This involves developing an integrated ecosystem that supports the entire cultural and creative cycle, encompassing creation, production, dissemination, exhibition, reception, transmission, and culminating in consumption or participation. By offering the necessary resources and facilities for creative businesses, we encourage talent to establish their ventures here. This approach has strengthened Dubai&rsquo;s global profile and leadership, transforming it into a thriving cultural hub, strongly aligned with our creative economy strategy.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The report provides a comprehensive overview of the creative sector, which serves as a significant global economic force, representing 6.1% of the world&rsquo;s economy with a total value of $4.3 trillion. The report also shows that the UAE had the largest creative sector in the MENA region in 2021.</p>

<p>According to the Dubai Framework for Cultural Statistics, and data issued by the Dubai Data and Statistics Establishment, Dubai&rsquo;s cultural and creative industries generated AED21.96 billion in added value in 2022, contributing 4.6% to the emirate&rsquo;s GDP. The report reveals that 47,544 companies operate in Dubai&rsquo;s creative sectors, providing jobs for 175,727 employees. In addition, Dubai attracted 898 foreign direct investment (FDI) projects in the cultural and creative industries in 2023, increasing total capital inflows for FDI projects to AED11.8 billion. Additionally, the report reveals that Dubai is home to more than 40% of start-ups in the sector that have secured over $1 million worth of funding in the MENA region, with 306 based in the emirate.</p>

<p>Hala Badri, Director General of Dubai Culture, affirmed that Dubai has strengthened its status as a global hub for the cultural and creative industries thanks to its visionary leadership and attractive legislative and investment environment. She emphasised that the Creative Dubai report reflects the performance and reality of Dubai&rsquo;s cultural sector and its ability to shape a bright future, stating: &ldquo;The report&rsquo;s findings provide strong motivation for members of Dubai&rsquo;s creative community, opening new horizons for them and inspiring innovation, as they continue their professional journeys and implement their unique ideas and projects, contributing to the strength of Dubai&rsquo;s cultural and creative industries, aligned with Dubai Culture&rsquo;s commitment to empowering talent and entrepreneurs.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The report highlights how Dubai&rsquo;s robust infrastructure, business-enabling support and vibrant cultural environment have significantly contributed to its global leadership. This enabled Dubai to win the bid to host the World Cities Culture Summit 2024 for the first time in the MENA region and the International Council of Museums (ICOM) General Conference 2025 for the first time in the Middle East, Africa and South Asia. Furthermore, Dubai ranked first regionally and fourth globally in the Cultural Interaction parameter within the 2023 Global Power City Index for the second consecutive year.</p>

<p>The report also outlines the trends that will shape the sector in Dubai over the coming years. The emirate seeks to enhance its position as a global innovation hub by adopting cutting-edge solutions, supporting artificial intelligence, augmented reality, and blockchain technologies, balancing technological advancement with sustainable innovation while preserving cultural identity, attracting talent and fostering their engagement with the community.</p>

<p>The report provides a comprehensive set of recommendations to foster the growth of Dubai&rsquo;s creative sector. It highlights key opportunity hotspots for investors, showcasing the most dynamic and rapidly expanding cultural and creative domains. The report also identifies relevant innovations, opportunity areas, and investment themes that leverage the UAE&rsquo;s membership in BRICS to broaden the scope of creative collaborations and expand market potential.</p>

<p>A strong emphasis is placed on affordable technological solutions tailored to SMEs, including initiatives such as government-funded projects and public innovation labs. Additionally, the report advocates for the adoption of a hybrid business model that seamlessly integrates physical and digital operations. It underscores the importance of developing integrated curricula that build linkages between the creative industry and educational institutions, ensuring a sustainable talent pipeline and industry growth.</p>

<p>The creative sector&#39;s influence on Dubai is evident in its economy, global distinctiveness, and quality of life. Dubai stands out as a regional leader in the creative sector, fostering cultural enrichment, generating economic opportunities, and championing the conservation and restoration of natural ecosystems. Its innovative urban development and artistic aesthetics further enhance its appeal, solidifying its position as a hub for cultural tourism.</p>

<p>To view the full report, please visit https://dubaiculture.gov.ae/-/media/DC/About-Us/Creative-Dubai-2024-Impact-Report-English.pdf.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:15:55 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735968.1735128923!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735968.1735128923!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Latifa bint Mohammed unveils groundbreaking report on Dubai’s creative economy]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai Culture and Google launch open call for 2nd MENA Creatives Bootcamp – AI & Innovation Edition]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/dubai-culture-and-google-launch-open-call-for-2nd-mena-creatives-bootcamp-ai-innovation-edition-2024-12-24-1.735957</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/technology/dubai-culture-and-google-launch-open-call-for-2nd-mena-creatives-bootcamp-ai-innovation-edition-2024-12-24-1.735957</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p style="box-sizing: border-box; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 1.25em; font-size: 1.375em; color: rgb(113, 120, 125); line-height: 1.375em; font-family: flamabook, Roboto, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, Arial, sans-serif; background-color: rgb(247, 247, 247);">Dubai Culture and Arts Authority (Dubai Culture) has launched the open call for the second &lsquo;MENA Creatives Bootcamp &ndash; AI &amp; Innovation Edition,&rsquo; organised in collaboration with Google. The programme aims to support creative community members, enhance their skills, and empower them to leverage technology and AI solutions to advance their creative projects. It also focuses on boosting digital presence and encouraging experiential learning. This initiative reflects Dubai Culture&rsquo;s commitment to strengthening the cultural and creative industries, positioning Dubai as a global centre for culture, an incubator for creativity, and a thriving hub for talent.<br style="box-sizing: border-box;" />
<br style="box-sizing: border-box;" />
The Authority has invited all creatives in UAE and MENA region to register for the bootcamp, with applications open until to 10 January, 2025. Spaces are limited to gain access to the four-day event, which offers participants opportunities to network, collaborate with outstanding talent and gain tailored one-on-one mentorship from Google&rsquo;s AI experts. Google&rsquo;s office in Dubai will host the bootcamp activities, while Al Quoz Creative Zone will host the last day with a specialised programme covering innovation, digital art and artificial intelligence.<br style="box-sizing: border-box;" />
<br style="box-sizing: border-box;" />
Shaima Rashed Al Suwaidi, Director of the Marketing &amp; Corporate Communication Department at Dubai Culture, affirmed the significance of the &lsquo;MENA Creatives Bootcamp &ndash; AI &amp; Innovation Edition&rsquo; and its role in fostering innovation and encouraging the harnessing of digital tools, in line with the UAE National Innovation Strategy, saying: &ldquo;Through this bootcamp, Dubai Culture seeks to open new horizons for creatives and provide them with access to experts, tools and knowledge to explore technology and advanced AI applications that can be applied to their creative practices and projects. These applications possess unique capabilities in content creation and generating original ideas for their projects, contributing to Dubai&rsquo;s global leadership as one of the most future-ready cities in the world.&rdquo;<br style="box-sizing: border-box;" />
<br style="box-sizing: border-box;" />
The first edition of the &lsquo;MENA Creatives Bootcamp &ndash; Sustainability Edition&rsquo; aligned with the UAE Year of Sustainability as well as the hosting of COP 28 and succeeded in attracting over 88 applications from creatives locally and regionally. Of these, 21 creatives from 10 countries were selected to join the bootcamp, guided by 41 mentors and specialists across various fields. The programme also featured one-on-one mentoring sessions led by 19 Google experts, as well as a wide range of workshops and sessions on achieving sustainability and discovering eco-friendly design practices.</p>

<p style="box-sizing: border-box; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 1.25em; font-size: 1.375em; color: rgb(113, 120, 125); line-height: 1.375em; font-family: flamabook, Roboto, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, Arial, sans-serif; background-color: rgb(247, 247, 247);">To register in the bootcamp, visit&nbsp;<a href="https://dubaiculture.gov.ae/en/about-us/special-projects/our-projects-events/Dubai-Culture-and-Google-launch-open-call-for-2nd-MENA-Creatives-Bootcamp" style="box-sizing: border-box; color: rgb(0, 174, 242); text-decoration-line: none; word-break: break-all; background-color: transparent;">this link</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 18:45:28 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735958.1735051516!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735958.1735051516!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai Culture and Google launch open call for 2nd MENA Creatives Bootcamp – AI & Innovation Edition]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Technology</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Technology</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid congratulates winner of Great Arab Minds Award in Literature & Arts]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/mohammed-bin-rashid-congratulates-winner-of-great-arab-minds-award-in-literature-arts-2024-12-19-1.735909</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/mohammed-bin-rashid-congratulates-winner-of-great-arab-minds-award-in-literature-arts-2024-12-19-1.735909</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President, Prime Minister and Ruler of Dubai, has congratulated artist Dia Al-Azzawi on winning the Great Arab Minds Award in the Literature and Arts category.</p>

<p>In a post on &quot;X&quot;, His Highness Sheikh Mohammed said, &quot;We congratulate the winner of the Great Arab Minds Award in the Literature and Arts category, artist Dia Al-Azzawi from Iraq. He has drawn inspiration from the rich heritage of Mesopotamia to create numerous works displayed in the world&#39;s most prestigious museums and galleries. His art addresses important Arab humanitarian issues and combines calligraphy, poetry, and tradition in a contemporary artistic form.&quot;</p>

<p>In a video call with Al-Azzawi, Mohammad bin Abdullah Al Gergawi, Minister of Cabinet Affairs and Chairman of the Great Arab Minds Higher Committee, informed him of his win in the Literature and Arts category of the Great Arab Minds Award and praised his global contributions, which have elevated the profile of contemporary Arab art internationally.</p>

<p>Al Gergawi emphasised that the Great Arab Minds Award is a strategic initiative that reflects Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid&#39;s vision, providing a platform for the most creative Arab minds and celebrating their impactful contributions. It also aims to inspire emerging talents and motivate young Arabs to contribute positively to the advancement of humanity.</p>

<p>For over fifty years, Dia Al-Azzawi, a visual artist specialising in contemporary Arab art, has been a leading figure in the field. He has showcased Arab culture and heritage to the world through his innovative and diverse works.</p>

<p>He has produced hundreds of artworks and organised and participated in numerous art exhibitions worldwide, significantly bridging contemporary art with Arab culture, history, and its most pressing issues. His works embody Arab identity and heritage through a creative style that seamlessly blends modernity with tradition.</p>

<p>Al-Azzawi is distinguished for his use of visual art, Arabic calligraphy, and sculpture to highlight events and challenges relevant to the Arab world in a contemporary style that resonates with global audiences. His innovative approach integrates Arabic letters and poetry into modern artistic expressions, skillfully blending text and imagery in a unique and creative manner.</p>

<p>The Great Arab Minds Award is the largest of its kind in the Arab world, recognising pioneering contributions across six key areas: Natural Sciences (Physics, Mathematics, Chemistry), Economics, Medicine, Literature and Arts, Engineering and Technology, and Architecture and Design.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 14:27:33 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735915.1734604692!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735915.1734604692!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735915.1734604692!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735910.1734604033!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid congratulates winner of Great Arab Minds Award in Literature & Arts]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[The 11th Camel Trek Nears Completion: A Celebration of UAE Heritage]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/the-11th-camel-trek-nears-completion-a-celebration-of-uae-heritage-2024-12-18-1.735899</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/the-11th-camel-trek-nears-completion-a-celebration-of-uae-heritage-2024-12-18-1.735899</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<ul>
	<li>
	<blockquote>
	<h3><strong>Abdullah Hamdan Bin Dalmouk: The Journey Embodies Our Historical and Cultural Values</strong></h3>
	</blockquote>
	</li>
</ul>

<p><br />
The 11th edition of the Camel Trek, organized by the Hamdan Bin Mohammed Heritage Center (HHC), is nearing its final destination in Dubai after covering over half of its 680 km journey across the UAE desert. Featuring 33 participants from 17 nationalities, the trek will culminate at the Heritage Village in Global Village on December 21, after 13 days of travel.</p>

<p>The expedition began on December 9 in the Rub&#39; al Khali desert and has passed key checkpoints, including Tel Marib, South Shah, the Arabian Oryx Sanctuary &ldquo;Bab Bin Mudhahiya,&rdquo; Al-Du&rsquo;aisiya, and North Al-Qaw&rsquo;a, among others. The caravan is now advancing towards Khaznah, Ajban, and Saih Al-Silm before reaching its final destination.</p>

<h3><strong>A Journey with a Message</strong></h3>

<p>Abdullah Hamdan Bin Dalmouk, CEO of the Hamdan Bin Mohammed Heritage Center, commended the participants&#39; dedication and resilience in facing natural challenges like cold weather and tough terrain. He highlighted the role of HHC trainers in preparing the participants for such hardships, stating:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;This journey was a real test of teamwork. With the increase in participants, we extended travel hours, often arriving after nightfall. This year&rsquo;s trek simulated historical journeys, with participants preparing their meals and adapting to conditions similar to those faced by our ancestors.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Bin Dalmouk emphasized that the trek carries a significant cultural message, aiming to raise awareness about the UAE&#39;s rich heritage:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Through this journey, we aim to reconnect with our history, preserving our national identity and introducing future generations to the essence of desert life&mdash;a key part of our ancestors&rsquo; lives.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>

<h3><strong>Traditions and Personal Stories</strong></h3>

<p>For some participants, the trek was a journey of self-discovery and cultural immersion. Emirati citizen Khaled Yahya Al-Balushi, inspired by Al-Oula Radio, shared:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;This experience allows me to honor my forefathers&#39; journeys and represent the UAE&rsquo;s traditions in the best light. Through cooperation and commitment, we showcase the beauty of Emirati customs alongside participants from diverse backgrounds.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Dutch horse trainer Harmke Westervelt also expressed her joy at participating:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;This journey was challenging yet deeply rewarding. As a horse trainer, I found bonding with my camel a unique and transformative experience, highlighting the incredible traits of these remarkable creatures.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>

<h3><strong>About the Hamdan Bin Mohammed Heritage Center</strong></h3>

<p>The Hamdan Bin Mohammed Heritage Center (HHC) is a leading organization dedicated to the preservation and promotion of Emirati culture and heritage. It serves as a hub for cultural and heritage initiatives, competitions, and research, fostering a deep sense of national identity among Emirati youth while promoting UAE traditions on a global stage.</p>

<p>For more information, visit <a href="http://www.hhc.gov.ae" rel="noopener" target="_new">www.hhc.gov.ae</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 12:56:18 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735903.1734512100!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735903.1734512100!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735903.1734512100!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735902.1734512029!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735901.1734511954!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735900.1734511936!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[The 11th Camel Trek Nears Completion: A Celebration of UAE Heritage]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[How Netflix Dominated the Streaming Wars]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/how-netflix-dominated-the-streaming-wars-2024-12-17-1.735878</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/how-netflix-dominated-the-streaming-wars-2024-12-17-1.735878</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Netflix&rsquo;s rise to dominance in the streaming wars is a testament to its innovative approach, relentless focus on customer satisfaction, and ability to adapt to changing market dynamics. What started in 1997 as a DVD rental-by-mail service evolved into the world&rsquo;s leading streaming platform, disrupting the entertainment industry and defining the modern era of content consumption.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Central to Netflix&#39;s success was its early pivot to streaming in 2007, a move that capitalized on advancements in internet speed and the growing demand for on-demand entertainment. Unlike traditional TV networks, Netflix empowered viewers with the freedom to watch what they wanted, when they wanted, laying the groundwork for the &ldquo;binge-watching&rdquo; culture that revolutionized viewing habits&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Netflix&rsquo;s investment in original programming further cemented its position as a leader. Hits like House of Cards and Stranger Things not only garnered critical acclaim but also built brand loyalty, drawing millions of subscribers. By 2024, the platform boasted a vast library of diverse, high-quality content, including films, documentaries, and foreign-language series like &quot;Squid Game&quot; appealing to a global audience.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Data-driven decision-making also gave Netflix an edge. Leveraging viewer data, the company refined its content recommendations and greenlit projects with high chances of success. This approach maximized engagement, ensuring subscribers felt the platform catered to their preferences.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Netflix&rsquo;s ability to navigate competition and challenges solidified its dominance. While rivals like Disney+ and Amazon Prime Video entered the fray with compelling offerings, Netflix continued to innovate with interactive content, partnerships, and expansion into gaming.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ultimately, Netflix&rsquo;s success lies in its adaptability and foresight. By constantly evolving and anticipating consumer needs, the company not only survived the streaming wars but also set the standard for what a modern entertainment platform can achieve.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 13:43:54 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735885.1734429087!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735885.1734429087!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>&#8203;Abdulla Al-Qemzi </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[How Netflix Dominated the Streaming Wars]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Camel Trek Embarks on Epic Journey Across the Western Desert]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/camel-trek-embarks-on-epic-journey-across-the-western-desert-2024-12-15-1.735851</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/camel-trek-embarks-on-epic-journey-across-the-western-desert-2024-12-15-1.735851</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li>Abdullah Hamdan bin Dalmouk Extends Heartfelt Gratitude to Our Partners for Their Role in Safeguarding UAE&#39;s Heritage</li>
	<li>&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>In a bold celebration of the UAE&rsquo;s timeless heritage, the 11th edition of the Camel Trek is well into its 13-day desert odyssey, with 33 participants from 17 countries, each embodying the spirit of the Emirates. The participants, hailing from both the UAE and beyond, set off from the heart of the Empty Quarter desert and are currently crossing the vast, shifting sands of the Western Desert. Their journey will culminate at the Heritage Village in Global Village on December 21.</p>

<p>The caravan&rsquo;s journey began on December 9 from the Arada area, deep within the Empty Quarter. Along the way, participants have passed through notable stations, including Tel Marib, South Shah, Al Maha Sanctuary &quot;Bab bin Madhiah,&quot; Al Maha Sanctuary &quot;Al Khor,&quot; Al Dwayseah, South Al Quo&#39;a, and North Al Quo&#39;a. The trek continues towards Al Thuqaybah, Bouts, Al Khazna, Al Ajban, and Saih Al Salam. The grand finale awaits at the Heritage Village, marking the trek&rsquo;s conclusion on December 21.</p>

<p><strong>Gratitude and Appreciation</strong></p>

<p>At the helm of this extraordinary journey is His Excellency Abdullah Hamdan bin Dalmouk, CEO of the Hamdan bin Mohammed Heritage Center. His leadership has been instrumental in the trek&rsquo;s success. In a message of deep appreciation, bin Dalmouk acknowledged the vital role played by national partners, including Dubai Ambulance, the Environment Agency &ndash; Abu Dhabi, Dubai Police, and Abu Dhabi Police.</p>

<p>&quot;We are incredibly grateful to all our national partners,&quot; bin Dalmouk said. &quot;This Camel Trek is a product of shared vision and collective effort, a partnership that reflects the UAE&rsquo;s dedication to preserving its heritage while fostering a deeper connection between its people, history, and land.&quot;</p>

<p>He continued, &ldquo;The success of this journey is a direct result of the expertise and resources contributed by these institutions. Together, we are creating a legacy&mdash;a bridge between past and future that ensures our traditions are passed down to the next generation with pride.&quot;</p>

<p>Bin Dalmouk concluded with a poignant reminder of the trek&#39;s greater purpose: &quot;Preserving our heritage is not just an act of duty but a mission that unites us all. Through our work and this journey, we aim to inspire future generations to carry forward the rich cultural legacy that makes the UAE so unique.&quot;</p>

<p><strong>Trek Progress</strong></p>

<p>The trek is progressing smoothly, with the caravan covering an impressive 45 to 50 kilometers each day, thanks to the team&rsquo;s intimate knowledge of the desert&#39;s geography. Despite early challenges such as sandstorms and unforgiving terrain, participants, led by a seasoned team of guides and experts, have navigated these obstacles with grace and perseverance.</p>

<p>&quot;We&rsquo;ve faced our share of hurdles, but the team&rsquo;s resilience has been remarkable,&quot; bin Dalmouk said. &quot;Our deep connection to these lands, built over years of experience, has made all the difference. The spirit of the journey is about overcoming the desert&rsquo;s challenges while embracing the silence and beauty it offers.&quot;</p>

<p><strong>An Adventure of a Lifetime</strong></p>

<p>For participants, the Camel Trek is far more than an endurance test&mdash;it is an immersion into the authentic, rugged beauty of the UAE&rsquo;s desert and an exploration of its cultural roots.</p>

<p>Amina Abdullah Al Naqbi, Training Coordinator at the Sharjah Museums Authority, shared her enthusiasm for the journey. &ldquo;I&rsquo;ve been dreaming of this moment for years,&quot; she said. &quot;Preparing mentally and physically for the desert trek was no small feat, but the training from the Hamdan bin Mohammed Heritage Center and the constant guidance from Abdullah bin Dalmouk made all the difference. Every step in this desert feels like we&rsquo;re walking through history.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Ivan Kovalenko, a Russian participant who placed second in the Camel Trek Marathon at the Sheikh Zayed Festival, echoed her sentiments. &ldquo;At first, I thought it would be a simple camel ride,&quot; he admitted. &quot;But this journey has been so much more&mdash;it&rsquo;s a true test of patience, strength, and endurance. Along the way, I&rsquo;ve learned not just about the desert but about the traditions of the Emirati people, their hospitality, and the deep respect they have for this land.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:58:40 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735855.1734256634!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735855.1734256634!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735855.1734256634!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735854.1734256614!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735853.1734256601!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735852.1734256581!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Camel Trek Embarks on Epic Journey Across the Western Desert]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Explore Oriental Charm and Embark on a Creative Feast: The 'CCPIT' (UAE) Cultural and Creative Exhibition Awaits You!]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/explore-oriental-charm-and-embark-on-a-creative-feast-the-ccpit-uae-cultural-and-creative-exhibition-awaits-you-2024-12-11-1.735814</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/explore-oriental-charm-and-embark-on-a-creative-feast-the-ccpit-uae-cultural-and-creative-exhibition-awaits-you-2024-12-11-1.735814</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>In the dazzling Dubai Expo City, a cultural feast blending tradition and modernity awaits your arrival! From December 12 to 14, 2024, the &quot;CCPIT&quot; (UAE) Cultural and Creative Exhibition invites you to embark on a cross-temporal cultural journey.</p>

<p><strong>Traverse the Millennia-Old Cultural Corridor, Touch the Boundless Possibilities of Creativity.</strong></p>

<p><strong>Exhibition Highlights:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>CULTURAL AND CREATIVE PRODUCTS</strong><br />
	Discover innovative products embodying the essence of Chinese culture. From classical aesthetics to modern design, each exhibit pays homage to traditional culture while celebrating the collision of tradition and innovation.</li>
	<li><strong>TRADE OPPORTUNITIES</strong><br />
	During the exhibition, seize the chance to meet and network with merchants from around the world. Explore collaboration opportunities and expand the international market for Chinese cultural and creative products.</li>
	<li><strong>FREE ENTRY</strong><br />
	We warmly invite all who are passionate about Chinese culture to join this cultural and creative feast, free of charge. No tickets are required&mdash;just bring your curiosity and spirit of exploration to step into this cross-temporal cultural journey.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Exhibition Venue:</strong></p>

<p>China-UAE Economy And Trade Exchange Center</p>

<p>(China Pavilion EXPO 2020), Dubai Expo City<br />
<strong>Exhibition Dates:</strong> December 12&ndash;14, 2024</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 11:44:18 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735815.1733902874!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735815.1733902874!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Explore Oriental Charm and Embark on a Creative Feast: The 'CCPIT' (UAE) Cultural and Creative Exhibition Awaits You!]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai Culture Launches ‘Art + Tech Collaborative Training Programme’ in Partnership with REALIITY]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/dubai-culture-launches-art-tech-collaborative-training-programme-in-partnership-with-realiity-2024-12-10-1.735812</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/dubai-culture-launches-art-tech-collaborative-training-programme-in-partnership-with-realiity-2024-12-10-1.735812</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Dubai Culture and Arts Authority (Dubai Culture) has announced the launch of the &lsquo;Art + Tech Collaborative Training Programme,&rsquo; developed in partnership with REALIITY. This transformative four-month initiative is designed to bridge the gap between artistic creativity and technological proficiency, equipping artists with the skills to integrate advanced technology into their creative processes. Through this initiative, Dubai Culture continues to support the emirate&rsquo;s cultural and creative industries, aligning with its vision to establish Dubai as a global centre for culture, an incubator for creativity, and a thriving hub for talent.</p>

<p><br />
Running until 10 February 2025, the programme invited six talented artists to embark on an intensive journey to explore the intersection of art and technology, delving into the history of technology in art, learning coding (Python), and gaining hands-on experience with basic electronics, sensors, microcontroller programming, 3D modelling, and 3D printing. This comprehensive training will culminate in the creation of individual art-tech installations, which will be showcased in a public exhibition.</p>

<p><br />
The weekly workshops are guided by industry expert Dr Ahmed Al Attar and are held at Bait 341 in Al Shindagha Historical District. The programme cultivates technical skill development and encourages innovative thinking and collaborative learning among participants. Artists will benefit from personalised mentorship, opportunities for experimentation, and exposure to pioneering art-tech practices.</p>

<p>Dr Saeed Mubarak bin Kharbash, CEO of the Arts, Design and Literature Sector at Dubai Culture, said: &ldquo;Dubai&rsquo;s commitment to innovation and digital transformation has positioned the emirate as a global laboratory for pioneering ideas; the &lsquo;Art + Tech Collaborative Training Programme&rsquo; reflects Dubai Culture&rsquo;s mission to empower artists and inspire them to enrich the creative landscape. By providing artists with a platform to merge art and technology, we are fostering a culture of innovation by enabling them to create unique works that reflect contemporary advancements and engage diverse audiences. This initiative underscores Dubai&rsquo;s leadership in promoting a knowledge- and innovation-driven economy.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The programme is delivered under the umbrella of the Dubai Cultural Grant programme, reinforcing the Authority&rsquo;s commitment to nurturing talent and supporting innovative artistic practices. As the participants progress, they will gain practical experience in creating interactive art installations, integrating sensors and 3D printing technologies, and collaborating with peers in a dynamic and supportive environment. The programme will conclude with a public exhibition where participants will present their work, offering them recognition and engagement opportunities.</p>

<p><br />
Through this initiative, Dubai Culture continues to champion the convergence of art and technology, supporting the growth of the creative economy and enhancing Dubai&rsquo;s global cultural influence.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 21:56:38 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735813.1733853332!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735813.1733853332!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai Culture Launches ‘Art + Tech Collaborative Training Programme’ in Partnership with REALIITY]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai Culture Offers Children Enriching Winter Camp Experiences]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/dubai-culture-offers-children-enriching-winter-camp-experiences-2024-12-09-1.735799</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/dubai-culture-offers-children-enriching-winter-camp-experiences-2024-12-09-1.735799</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Dubai Culture and Arts Authority (Dubai Culture) has announced the launch of its winter camps, set to take place across its cultural and heritage sites in December. Organised in two sessions, the first will run from 16 to 20 December and the second from 23 to 27 December. The camps aim to provide children aged 4 to 14 with interactive cultural and artistic experiences, nurturing their talents and skills, in line with Dubai Culture&rsquo;s mission to create an inspiring environment that fosters creativity, innovation, and self-expression, broadening their horizons.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Al Shindagha Museum Winter Camp invites children to embark on an archaeological adventure, exploring Dubai&rsquo;s historical treasures through rich, educational, and interactive workshops. Participants will engage with archaeology experts to learn excavation techniques, artefact restoration and preservation, site analysis, and report writing. Activities include creating seal designs inspired by archaeological findings and a field trip to the Jumeirah Archaeological Site.</p>

<p>At the Etihad Museum Winter Camp, themed &lsquo;Young Leaders: Shaping Tomorrow,&rsquo; participants will explore the vision, values, and achievements of the UAE&rsquo;s Founding Fathers through interactive challenges and group activities. Participants will develop leadership, communication, teamwork, and community engagement skills. The camp will also introduce them to Dubai&rsquo;s traditional architecture, the UAE&rsquo;s green initiatives, and its strides in technology, space exploration, and creative industries.</p>

<p>The Al Fahidi Historical Neighbourhood Winter Camp, under the theme &lsquo;Journey of the Pioneers in Al Fahidi,&rsquo; provides a mix of cultural, recreational, and creative activities. Highlights include star mapping, crafting sundials inspired by Dubai&rsquo;s landmarks, and building traditional wooden boats. A workshop on &lsquo;Future City Planning&rsquo; will allow children to design futuristic cities inspired by the historical neighbourhood.</p>

<p>The Al Jalila Cultural Centre for Children Winter Camp, themed &lsquo;Al Jalila&rsquo;s Winter Wonders,&rsquo; offers various workshops to enhance children&rsquo;s creativity and talents. Activities include pottery-making, working with clay, exploring theatre and performing arts, and honing artistic skills in painting, and design, enriching children&rsquo;s imaginations and fostering their creative growth.</p>

<p>The Dubai Public Library Winter Camp, under the theme &lsquo;Little Explorers&rsquo;, presents a blend of art and science through workshops at Al Safa Art and Design, Al Rashidiya, Al Twar, Umm Suqeim, Al Mankhool, and Hatta libraries. Supervised by experts, children will create marine-inspired sculptures, design and decorate pottery and learn about the UAE&rsquo;s national tree, the Ghaf. Other activities include mirror painting, designing space-themed artworks, and using paints and stencils.</p>

<p>Throughout the camp, children will embark on virtual reality adventures to explore space and astronomy, measure weather elements, design sustainable cities, and uncover the science of fluid mechanics through hydraulic systems. They&rsquo;ll also delve into eco-friendly material creation, optics experiments to understand light transmission and image formation, and the mysteries of chemical and biological reactions in problem-solving. Interactive games and challenges will add excitement, with special prizes awarded to winners to enhance their experience and encourage learning and creativity.</p>

<p>Coinciding with the camp, the Second-Hand Book Fair will be held at Al Mankhool Public Library from December 16 to 27, offering visitors the opportunity to purchase a curated selection of books at nominal prices of AED 2, 5 and 10. The book fair will be open from 8:00 AM to 8:00 PM, Sunday to Thursday, and from 8:00 AM to 12:00 PM on Friday and aims to promote the concept of book sustainability and spread culture and knowledge across different age groups.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 9 Dec 2024 18:10:03 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735800.1733753344!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735800.1733753344!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai Culture Offers Children Enriching Winter Camp Experiences]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Latifa bint Mohammed launches the Dubai Photography Museum project]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/latifa-bint-mohammed-launches-the-dubai-photography-museum-project-2024-11-27-1.735653</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/latifa-bint-mohammed-launches-the-dubai-photography-museum-project-2024-11-27-1.735653</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p><strong>- Under the directives of Hamdan bin Mohammed, Latifa bint Mohammed launches the Dubai Photography Museum project</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Under the directives of His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defence of the UAE, and Chairman of The Executive Council of Dubai, Her Highness Sheikha Latifa bint Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Chairperson of Dubai Culture and Arts Authority (Dubai Culture), launched the Dubai Photography Museum project.</p>

<p>The new attraction seeks to enhance Dubai&rsquo;s museums sector by documenting the history of photography regionally and globally, showcasing a wide array of exhibits and collections. The museum offers interactive and educational spaces designed to engage and inspire even as it celebrates local and international photography talent, highlighting their diverse journeys, and reinforces Dubai&rsquo;s position as a global centre for culture, an incubator for creativity, and a thriving hub for talent.</p>

<p>Her Highness affirmed Dubai&rsquo;s commitment to global leadership through innovative initiatives and projects: &ldquo;The Dubai Photography Museum is a remarkable milestone that reinforces the emirate&rsquo;s position as a global hub for talent and a premier destination for photographers worldwide. It serves as a platform for exchanging knowledge and expertise with leading cultural institutions, embodying our commitment to innovation and fostering meaningful dialogue through arts and culture while also reflecting Dubai&rsquo;s rich cultural diversity, offering visitors unique educational experiences and preserving the collective memory of photography as part of our shared human heritage.</p>

<p>&ldquo;It highlights the UAE&rsquo;s dedication to safeguarding cultural heritage, securing the legacy for future generations, and contributing to the global narrative of arts and creativity, playing a vital role in promoting cultural tourism, strengthening Dubai&rsquo;s creative industries, and driving growth within the UAE&rsquo;s thriving creative economy.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>Collaborative initiative</strong></p>

<p>A collaborative initiative between Dubai Culture and the private sector, the Dubai Photography Museum is dedicated to strengthening the emirate&rsquo;s position as a global hub for visual arts. The museum will foster a vibrant creative environment, attracting both local and international talent by providing the necessary support to transform artistic visions into impactful projects with economic value; these creations will be showcased through the museum&rsquo;s permanent and temporary exhibitions, offering a platform for dialogue and cultural exchange.</p>

<p>This initiative aligns with the Dubai Urban Master Plan 2040, the cultural and heritage priorities of Dubai Plan 2030, and Dubai Culture&rsquo;s mission to safeguard both tangible and intangible cultural heritage. It also seeks to promote the visual documentation of the city&rsquo;s narrative on a local and global scale, reinforcing Dubai&rsquo;s standing as a dynamic cultural capital.</p>

<p>This project comes at a time when the global photography market is expected to reach $62.4 billion by 2027, and when museums stimulate job creation in related industries worldwide, with over 1.5 million people employed. This highlights the importance of this art form in supporting and strengthening cultural and creative industries.</p>

<p>The museum, a new addition to Dubai&rsquo;s creative landscape, will preserve the region&rsquo;s collective visual memory. It will serve as a leading international hub for photography, bringing together photographers from around the world to exchange expertise, share and deepen knowledge, and offer educational resources and workshops for youth and photography enthusiasts.</p>

<p>Furthermore, the project will attract leading cultural institutions in the field of photography, encouraging them to establish a presence within the museum&rsquo;s facilities. It will facilitate creative exchanges and strengthen collaboration with local cultural institutions, enhancing Dubai&rsquo;s cultural tourism sector, which hosts numerous festivals and cultural events annually, enriching the local cultural scene.</p>

<p><strong>Global competition</strong></p>

<p>Among other plans, Dubai Culture will launch a global architectural competition next year aimed at enabling architects and designers to present their visions for the design of the new museum. The competition will offer a prize of AED1 million. The museum&rsquo;s new design will factor in dedicated spaces for permanent and temporary exhibitions highlighting the history of photography, its styles and techniques, various photographic genres, a dedicated interactive children&rsquo;s space, historical retrospectives, and multimedia projects. The museum&#39;s operational spaces will feature lecture halls, event and workshop areas, photography and restoration labs, a library and archive, as well as retail and food and beverage facilities.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 16:19:40 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735654.1732709941!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735654.1732709941!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Latifa bint Mohammed launches the Dubai Photography Museum project]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[ICOM, the ICOM Dubai 2025 Organising Committee, ICOM-UAE, and DWTC Sign Landmark Agreement]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/icom-the-icom-dubai-2025-organising-committee-icom-uae-and-dwtc-sign-landmark-agreement-2024-11-25-1.735591</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/icom-the-icom-dubai-2025-organising-committee-icom-uae-and-dwtc-sign-landmark-agreement-2024-11-25-1.735591</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>- ICOM, the ICOM Dubai 2025 Organising Committee, ICOM-UAE, and DWTC Sign Landmark Agreement to forge the path for the 27th ICOM General Conference in Dubai</p>

<p>ICOM Dubai 2025 Organising Committee has signed a landmark agreement with the International Council of Museums (ICOM), the National Committee of ICOM in the United Arab Emirates (ICOM-UAE), and Dubai World Trade Centre (DWTC). This strategic partnership strengthens cooperation among all parties in preparation for the 27th ICOM General Conference (ICOM Dubai 2025). Set to be hosted in Dubai for the first time in the Middle East, North Africa, and South Asia (MEASA) region, the conference will focus on the theme &lsquo;The Future of Museums in Rapidly Changing Communities.&rsquo;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>The agreement was formalised at the Etihad Museum in the presence of Her Excellency Hala Badri, Director General of Dubai Culture and Chairperson of ICOM Dubai 2025 Organising Committee; Dr. Emma Nardi, President of the International Council of Museums; Medea S. Ekner, Director General of the International Council of Museums; Nasir Al Darmaki, Chair of ICOM UAE; and Khalid Al Hammadi, Senior Vice President of DXB LIVE, the integrated event management arm of the Dubai World Trade Centre.</p>

<p>Building on the momentum of the successful &lsquo;ICOM 2024 International Symposium&rsquo; hosted at the Etihad Museum, the agreement emphasises the roles of the four parties in bringing together a world-class General Conference, scheduled from 11-17 November 2025 at the Dubai World Trade Centre. It sets out a collaborative, participatory and inclusive approach, ensuring a clear framework while upholding the highest standards of quality. The conference aspires to foster active learning, meaningful dialogues, diverse perspectives, knowledge sharing, and cultural exploration, distinguishing it as a transformative gathering in the museum and cultural sectors.</p>

<p>ICOM Dubai 2025 is expected to welcome over 4,500 museum professionals and cultural experts from around the world. The conference will serve as a platform for diverse voices, innovative ideas and fresh perspectives, reimagining the role of museums in an era of global transformation. Delegates will be invited to push boundaries and explore new museological paradigms, and ultimately develop actionable strategies for creating a sustainable future for museums and the communities they serve, while identifying opportunities for regional and international collaborations.</p>

<p>Another highlight of the conference will be the &lsquo;Museum Fair,&rsquo; showcasing cutting-edge innovations and advancements in the museum sector through dedicated pavilions. This showcase will spotlight pioneering solutions and partnership opportunities, underscoring Dubai&rsquo;s position as a global hub for culture and innovation.</p>

<p><br />
In this context, Her Excellency Hala Badri emphasised that Dubai&rsquo;s hosting of this prestigious conference underscores its leadership and significant role in enriching the global cultural movement: &ldquo;Dubai, with its ambitions and forward-looking vision, continues to build bridges between cultures, transform museums into centres of knowledge, and amplify their role in preserving intangible heritage and supporting the global cultural landscape.&rdquo; She further underscored the importance of ICOM Dubai 2025 in shaping the future of museums, advancing their initiatives and activities, and empowering them to better serve their communities.</p>

<p>Nasir Al Darmaki, Chair of ICOM UAE, said: &quot;The signing of this agreement for the ICOM General Conference in Dubai 2025 is a monumental achievement, bringing together museum professionals to elevate the UAE&#39;s cultural standing and redefine the future of museums. By hosting this prestigious event, we aim to inspire innovation, foster international collaboration, and shape the cultural landscape for generations to come.&quot;</p>

<p>The International Council of Museums, founded in 1946 under the auspices of the United Nations, is a leading global organisation dedicated to preserving, promoting, and advancing museums and the museum profession. As a cornerstone institution in the cultural sector, ICOM represents over 50,000 members across 120 countries and nearly 20,000 museums worldwide. In 2021, ICOM-UAE, in collaboration with Dubai Culture, Dubai Municipality, and Dubai&rsquo;s Department of Economy and Tourism, submitted a successful bid to host the ICOM General Conference 2025 in Dubai.</p>

<p>The UAE was selected as the host city, standing out among competing international cities due to its prominent global reach, significant role in culture and heritage preservation, and steadfast commitment to fostering a thriving creative economy.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 12:51:25 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735592.1732524663!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735592.1732524663!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[ICOM, the ICOM Dubai 2025 Organising Committee, ICOM-UAE, and DWTC Sign Landmark Agreement]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Global Women’s Forum Dubai 2024 to host cultural dinner in honour of distinguished guests]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/global-women-s-forum-dubai-2024-to-host-cultural-dinner-in-honour-of-distinguished-guests-2024-11-24-1.735578</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/global-women-s-forum-dubai-2024-to-host-cultural-dinner-in-honour-of-distinguished-guests-2024-11-24-1.735578</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>- Global Women&rsquo;s Forum Dubai 2024 to host cultural dinner in honour of distinguished guests at Al Shindagha Historic Neighbourhood</p>

<p>As part of the Global Women&rsquo;s Forum Dubai 2024, taking place on 26&ndash;27 November under the patronage of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister of the UAE and Ruler of Dubai, the Dubai Women Establishment will host a cultural dinner in collaboration with the Dubai Culture and Arts Authority, the Forum&rsquo;s cultural partner, on 26 November.</p>

<p>The dinner, set to take place at the Al Shindagha Historic Neighbourhood, will honour the forum&rsquo;s distinguished guests, including First Ladies, prominent leaders, keynote speakers, decision-makers, and international partners. The exclusive event reflects the commitment of the Dubai Women Establishment and the Dubai Culture and Arts Authority to foster global collaboration and partnerships and showcase Dubai&rsquo;s vibrant cultural heritage and artistic legacy.</p>

<p>The cultural dinner will offer a rich experience, blending history, humanity, and inspiring stories, showcasing Dubai&rsquo;s vibrant cultural heritage. Recognising culture as a vital bridge for fostering constructive dialogue between nations, the event will also feature an art exhibition highlighting the creative works of Emirati female artists. Guests will be immersed in a unique blend of visual arts and Emirati heritage, with paintings that vividly illustrate the city&rsquo;s history and cultural character.</p>

<p>Offering guests a guided tour of Al Shindagha, focused on exploring the city&rsquo;s cultural and historical journey and timeless traditions, the invitation-only dinner will spotlight Dubai&rsquo;s rich heritage.</p>

<p>Fatima Behzad, a member of the forum&rsquo;s organising committee, highlighted the cultural and historical significance of Al Shindagha, describing it as a symbol of Dubai&rsquo;s origins and its aspirational spirit. She noted that the dinner, held in collaboration with the Dubai Culture and Arts Authority, will offer guests a glimpse into the city&rsquo;s rich history, blending inspiring stories and cultural experiences. Behzad emphasised Dubai&rsquo;s commitment to honouring its traditions while using culture as a bridge to foster dialogue and shape a bright future, a theme central to the forum&rsquo;s discussions.</p>

<p>The Global Women&rsquo;s Forum Dubai (GWFD) serves as a platform for fostering meaningful dialogue and actionable strategies to advance women&rsquo;s empowerment and gender balance worldwide. GWFD underscores the UAE&rsquo;s leadership in promoting gender equality and its commitment to the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals, particularly Goal 5: Gender Equality.</p>

<p>The 2024 edition, themed &#39;The Power of Influence&#39;, will be held on November 26-27 at Madinat Jumeirah, Dubai. With over 130 high-powered sessions, the forum will bring together over 250 high-profile global speakers from 65 countries. It will also host over 25 ministers and welcome over 4,000 influential figures, including female leaders across various fields. Discussions at the event centre on three transformative pillars: Future Economies and Societies, Collective Engagements and Actions, and Impactful Technologies and Innovations.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 22:09:54 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735579.1732471720!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735579.1732471720!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Global Women’s Forum Dubai 2024 to host cultural dinner in honour of distinguished guests]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed unveils first-of-its-kind immersive ‘Earth Dreams’ exhibition at the Museum of the Future]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/hamdan-bin-mohammed-unveils-first-of-its-kind-immersive-earth-dreams-exhibition-at-the-museum-of-the-future-2024-11-22-1.735556</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/hamdan-bin-mohammed-unveils-first-of-its-kind-immersive-earth-dreams-exhibition-at-the-museum-of-the-future-2024-11-22-1.735556</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>His Highness takes a special tour of the exhibition, which explores the intersection of art, technology, and nature&nbsp;</p>

<p>The project reimagines the complex relationship between technological and artistic innovation in the age of Artificial Intelligence</p>

<p>Created by Refik Anadol Studio in collaboration with the museum, the display draws upon millions of photos of the natural world, satellite imagery, and meteorological data<br />
Government of Dubai Media Office &ndash; 22 November 2024: His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defence of the UAE, Chairman of The Executive Council of Dubai, and Chairman of the Board of Trustees of the Dubai Future Foundation (DFF), unveiled a groundbreaking new exhibition at the Museum of the Future.&nbsp;<br />
The museum&rsquo;s new immersive experience, entitled &lsquo;Earth Dreams&rsquo;, debuted on the &lsquo;Tomorrow, Today&rsquo; floor during the week of the Dubai Future Forum. His highness took a special tour of the exhibition that showcases a unique journey through the intersection of art, technology, and nature.<br />
Earth Dreams is a series of immersive data paintings that imagine a new reality and envision a world where human memory, machine intelligence and the rhythms of nature merge into one. Created by Refik Anadol Studio in collaboration with the Museum of the Future, this first-of-its-kind exhibition draws upon millions of photos of the natural world, in addition to satellite imagery and meteorological data. Using over 30 projectors and by applying generative AI models, Anadol animates these elements, crafting a visual symphony that highlights the beauty and complexity of our planet.<br />
Aligned with the Museum of the Future&rsquo;s mission to create a home for both imagination, and possibility, Earth Dreams is a project that reimagines the complex relationship between technological and artistic innovation in the age of Artificial Intelligence. This synergy leverages the museum&rsquo;s distinctive architecture and state-of-the-art projection technology to create an AI-powered, interactive and immersive exhibition that seamlessly integrates with the museum&rsquo;s iconic design. The resulting artwork unfolds in three chapters, generating a novel form of synesthetic storytelling that invites visitors to experience a dream-like fragmentation and an expanding, dynamic network of interconnections.<br />
The Three Captivating Chapters&nbsp;<br />
Chapter 1: AIR&nbsp;<br />
The first chapter presents a series of AI data paintings based on cloud and atmospheric imagery, offering a breathtaking view of the skies.&nbsp;<br />
Chapter 2: LAND&nbsp;<br />
The second chapter intertwines extensive datasets of Earth imagery and meteorological data, generating a multisensory exploration of the beauty of our planet.<br />
Chapter 3: WATER<br />
In the final interactive chapter, the boundaries between past and future, Artificial Intelligence and living beings, thought and physical action, all merge into one seamless experience.&nbsp;<br />
&lsquo;Earth Dreams&rsquo; invites you to explore a new perspective of our shared planet through the lens of cutting-edge technology and artistic expression. This unique fusion of science and art offers an immersive experience of the natural world, encouraging visitors to reflect on the profound relationships that bind ecosystems, species, and landscapes together.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 16:39:37 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735557.1732279210!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735557.1732279210!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed unveils first-of-its-kind immersive ‘Earth Dreams’ exhibition at the Museum of the Future]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Latifa bint Mohammed inaugurates 3rd UNESCO World OER Congress in Dubai]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/latifa-bint-mohammed-inaugurates-3rd-unesco-world-oer-congress-in-dubai-2024-11-19-1.735511</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/latifa-bint-mohammed-inaugurates-3rd-unesco-world-oer-congress-in-dubai-2024-11-19-1.735511</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>H.H. Sheikha Latifa bint Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Chairperson of Dubai Culture and Arts Authority, today inaugurated the 3rd UNESCO World Open Educational Resources (OER) Congress, hosted for the first time in the Arab World at the Dubai World Trade Centre.</p>

<p>Organised by the United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organisation (UNESCO), in collaboration with the Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum Knowledge Foundation (MBRF), the event convenes global leaders, policymakers, and innovators to explore open solutions and artificial intelligence (AI) for inclusive access to knowledge.</p>

<p>Under the theme &lsquo;Digital Public Goods: Open Solutions and AI for Inclusive Access to Knowledge,&rsquo; the Congress features high-level panels, breakout sessions, and expert discussions to advance equitable, sustainable education through OER and emerging technologies. Over 500 global participants are attending the two-day event, including ministers, academics, and representatives from the private sector.</p>

<p>Sheikha Latifa delivered the opening speech at the Congress, during which she emphasised the key role of the event in unlocking the potential of open educational resources to enhance access to knowledge, promoting collaboration in digital education and aligning global efforts to advance shared learning.</p>

<p>She highlighted the importance of leveraging technology to tackle global challenges, expand educational opportunities, and ensure the accuracy and transparency of knowledge in an era of rapid technological progress.</p>

<p>She also stressed the need to develop licensed programmes that provide reliable information, laying a solid foundation for the future of education worldwide.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Dr Tawfik Jelassi, UNESCO&rsquo;s Assistant Director-General for Communication and Information, delivered an address titled &lsquo;Embracing Open Solutions for a Knowledge-Inclusive Future&rsquo;, highlighting the transformative potential of OER in addressing global educational challenges.</p>

<p>The event included several thought-provoking sessions, such as the &lsquo;Ministerial Panel: Shaping the Future of Education,&rsquo; chaired by Louise Haxthausen, Director of UNESCO Nairobi.</p>

<p>Another session titled &lsquo;Policies for Openly Licensed Learning Content&rsquo; featured the participation of distinguished speakers, such as Dr Yaw Osei Adutwum, Minister for Education of Ghana; Dr Dingara Jacques Sosth&egrave;ne, Minister of National Education, Ministry of National Education, Burkina Faso; Dr Huai Jinpeng, Minister of Education of China (via video); Dr Abdul Latheef Mohamed, Minister of State for Education, Maldives; Dr Bo Chankoulika, Under Secretary of State in charge of Policy and Cross-Sector Coordination of Cambodia; and Shannielle Hoosein-Outar, Permanent Secretary for Education from Guyana.</p>

<p>The speakers shared their experiences and strategies for fostering innovation and inclusion through OER.</p>

<p>During a panel discussion titled &lsquo;Harnessing OER and Generative AI for Digital Inclusion,&rsquo; experts delved into the potential of AI and OER to address global challenges, with topics ranging from promoting gender parity in education to leveraging AI for inclusivity.</p>

<p>The session was chaired by Dr Colin de la Higuera, Unesco Chair in Open Educational Resources, Universit&eacute; of Nantes, France. Panellists included Dr Phumzile Mlambo-Ngcuka, Former United Nations Under-Secretary-General and Executive Director of UN Women and Founder of the Umlambo Foundation, South Africa, who highlighted open solutions for achieving gender parity; Seizo Onoe, Director of the Telecommunication Standardization Bureau at the International Telecommunications Union (ITU), who discussed AI&rsquo;s role in standardisation for digital inclusion; and Kevin Chan, Director for Global Policy Campaign Strategies at Meta Platforms, Canada, who emphasised the key role of open AI in supporting language inclusion efforts.</p>

<p>Another panel discussion titled &lsquo;The Value Proposition for Openly Licensed Learning Content,&rsquo; chaired by Dr Jane Frances Agbu, Advisor Higher Education, Commonwealth of Learning, highlighted the innovative applications of OER and shared global best practices.</p>

<p>During the session, Dr Tawfik Jelassi shed light on the 2019 recommendation for OER&rsquo;s vision for the future, while Anna Tumad&oacute;ttir, CEO of Creative Commons, Iceland, highlighted the role of open licensing in the future of education. Mucktarr M.Y. Darboe, Permanent Secretary from The Gambia, presented innovative applications of OER in his country.</p>

<p>Building on this, Tuula Yrj&ouml;l&auml;, Finland&rsquo;s Ambassador to the Kingdom of Bahrain and the UAE, shared insights into the Finnish OER Library and its pivotal role in advancing openly licensed learning content. Concluding the discussion, Dr Johanna B&ouml;rsch-Supan, Director General for General Education, Vocational Training, and Lifelong Learning at Germany&rsquo;s Federal Ministry of Education and Research, highlighted Germany&rsquo;s national OER strategy through video conferencing.</p>

<p>In addition, the event featured two breakout sessions focused on implementing the 2019 Recommendation on OER. The first centred on Action Areas 1 and 2, designed to enhance capacity building and policy development aligned with UNESCO&rsquo;s vision for Open Educational Resources.</p>

<p>The sessions provided a platform for in-depth discussions on key issues identified during the 2023 First Consultation of this normative instrument. Emphasising inclusivity, participants addressed the unique needs of Africa, least developed countries (LDC), Small Island Developing States (SIDS), youth, indigenous people, and other vulnerable groups.</p>

<p>Action Area 1 focused on capacity building to strengthen the foundations of OER initiatives. Room A&rsquo;s discussions centred on establishing and optimising OER repositories and providing targeted training. Room B explored strategies for OER&rsquo;s digital skills development. Meanwhile, Room C emphasised the significance of mapping open solutions ecosystems in the OER landscape.</p>

<p>Action Area 2 addressed creating and refining policies to support OER adoption and sustainability. Room D delved into critical topics such as data protection, privacy, and the ethical use of openly licensed content. In Room E, participants examined the role of governmental and institutional incentives in crafting robust policy frameworks that foster the growth and integration of OER.</p>

<p>The second breakout session covered Action Areas 3 and 4, which focused on enhancing quality, accessibility, and sustainability in OER. These sessions aimed to address critical challenges and explore innovative solutions in alignment with the priorities identified during the 2023 First Consultation.</p>

<p>The discussions highlighted the importance of promoting gender equality and addressing the needs of Africa, LDCs, Small Island Developing States (SIDS), and vulnerable groups, such as youth and indigenous communities.</p>

<p>Sessions under Action Area 3 emphasised inclusive access to high-quality OER. In Room A, participants discussed strategies to enhance accessibility for people of determination in low-bandwidth environments. Room B focused on establishing quality assurance mechanisms to ensure inclusive access to quality OER. Meanwhile, Room C explored approaches to contextualisation and cultural diversity.</p>

<p>Action Area 4 sessions delved into the sustainability of OER initiatives. Room D addressed the development of sustainable business models for OER. Room E explored the creation of sustainable organisational ecosystems.</p>

<p>The day concluded with a Congress Reception, during which His Excellency Jamal Bin Huwaireb, CEO of the Mohammed Bin Rashid Al Maktoum Knowledge Foundation, delivered a welcome address, highlighting Dubai&rsquo;s vital role in advancing global knowledge-sharing and innovation.</p>

<p>The Congress will further establish guidelines to promote openly licensed content and tackle challenges arising from AI and other emerging technologies. Discussions will conclude with the Dubai Declaration for Action on OER, outlining concrete steps to advance inclusive and equitable quality education.</p>

<p>Many countries have made exceptional progress in implementing UNESCO&rsquo;s OER recommendations, with their initiatives set to be highlighted at the Congress. For instance, Virtual Health University transformed healthcare education in Cuba by providing flexible, accessible, OER-based learning for professionals, even in remote areas.</p>

<p>Furthermore, Madagascar responded exceptionally to COVID-19 challenges by launching an e-learning platform, distributing tablets, and utilising radio broadcasts to bridge digital divides in primary education. In addition, Malaysia&rsquo;s inclusive OER Policy ensures accessible resources to all, supported by the government for educator training and technology investment.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Morocco&rsquo;s 2024 national OER and Open Science strategy aims to modernise education and expand research accessibility, driven by strong engagement from educators. These initiatives showcase diverse approaches to advancing equitable access to knowledge through OER across different contexts.</p>

<p>The Congress aligns with the objectives of Knowledge Summit, which has positioned itself as a leading global event for exchanging knowledge, expertise, and success stories. The impact extends beyond discussions, providing a vital platform for introducing groundbreaking insights and innovative ideas. By showcasing best practices, the summit provides actionable solutions for pressing global challenges, making it an invaluable event for stakeholders worldwide.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 20:24:09 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735512.1732033383!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735512.1732033383!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Latifa bint Mohammed inaugurates 3rd UNESCO World OER Congress in Dubai]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Latifa bint Mohammed opens ‘Dubai Future Solutions – Prototypes for Humanity’ initiative]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/latifa-bint-mohammed-opens-dubai-future-solutions-prototypes-for-humanity-initiative-2024-11-18-1.735485</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/latifa-bint-mohammed-opens-dubai-future-solutions-prototypes-for-humanity-initiative-2024-11-18-1.735485</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Her Highness Sheikha Latifa bint Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Chairperson of Dubai Culture and Arts Authority (Dubai Culture), officially opened the &lsquo;Dubai Future Solutions &ndash; Prototypes for Humanity&rsquo; initiative. This transformative programme, approved by His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defence of the UAE, and Chairman of the Board of Trustees of the Dubai Future Foundation, reflects the emirate&rsquo;s commitment to excellence, creativity, and innovation in the service of humanity.<br />
The initiative, held in partnership with the Dubai Future Foundation, seeks to drive positive societal change by leveraging innovative projects initiated by enterprising university students and distinguished academics to address complex global challenges. Bringing together one of the most diverse assemblies of academic talent and innovation, the initiative will witness participation from elite professors and university students from leading institutions worldwide, who presented the top 100 projects offering practical solutions to critical challenges facing our planet and societies. The event is taking place on the sidelines of the 2024 Dubai Future Forum at the Museum of the Future on 19 and 20 November, bringing together over 2,500 experts and 100 international institutions specialising in future foresight and design.</p>

<p>Her Highness Sheikha Latifa expressed her pride in the groundbreaking achievements and creative solutions for global challenges that came about courtesy of the &lsquo;Prototypes for Humanity&rsquo; initiative over the past decade. She highlighted that expanding the initiative, an Art Dubai Group enterprise, through &lsquo;Dubai Future Solutions &ndash; Prototypes for Humanity,&rsquo; further strengthens its contribution to nurturing innovation and serving societies.</p>

<ul>
	<li>Empowering forum</li>
</ul>

<p>Her Highness said: &ldquo;Today, we celebrate a decade of innovation &ndash; a journey defined by continuing efforts to advance scientific research, mobilise visionary ideas, and transform them into impactful, pioneering solutions to address some of the world&rsquo;s most pressing challenges. This initiative reflects our dedication to shaping the future, providing a global platform for creators and innovators to drive meaningful change. It also inspires the development and acceleration of transformative technologies, supports entrepreneurship, empowers individuals, and harnesses talent to serve humanity, all while contributing to the overarching goals of comprehensive and sustainable development.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Her Highness added: &ldquo;I am proud to witness generations of young innovators from international universities and institutions across academic, cultural, technological, and creative fields who have harnessed knowledge to develop innovative solutions aimed at serving humanity, and we hope to support their growth from Dubai.&rdquo;<br />
The initiative attracted 2,700 applications from over 800 universities worldwide. During the event, the top five exceptional innovators will be announced and honoured with awards totalling AED 360,000, enabling them to further advance their research in vital fields.</p>

<p><strong>Exhibition celebrates pioneers</strong></p>

<p>Sheikha Latifa inaugurated the &lsquo;Dubai Future Solutions &ndash; Prototypes for Humanity&rsquo; 2024 exhibition, which showcases cutting-edge innovations and breakthrough projects in key domains such as healthcare, energy, society, nature, and data science. These creative projects lay the foundation for a robust infrastructure that supports Dubai&rsquo;s status as a global hub for innovation and future opportunities.</p>

<p>Her Highness also hosted a meeting, bringing together government officials, decision-makers and experts, including His Excellency Saeed Al Tayer &ndash; Managing Director and CEO of Dubai Electricity and Water Authority; His Excellency Dawood Al Hajri &ndash; Director General of Dubai Municipality; His Excellency Awad Saqr Al Ketbi &ndash; Director General of the Dubai Health Authority; His Excellency Dr. Amer Sharif &ndash; CEO of Dubai Health and President of Mohammed bin Rashid University of Medicine and Health Sciences; Her Excellency Hala Badri &ndash; Director General of Dubai Culture and Arts Authority; His Excellency Khalfan Belhoul &ndash; CEO of Dubai Future Foundation; as well as investors, entrepreneurs, and pioneers who advanced groundbreaking concepts. The discussions focused on adopting and transforming these creative solutions into successful, impactful projects.</p>

<ul>
	<li>Key partners</li>
</ul>

<p>Key partners in the &lsquo;Dubai Future Solutions &ndash; Prototypes for Humanity&rsquo; initiative include Dubai Culture and Arts Authority, the Dubai Future Foundation, the Dubai International Financial Centre, and the Hussain Sajwani &ndash; DAMAC Foundation, which has committed<br />
AED100 million to advance innovation and technology in Dubai, further driving progress and impact.</p>

<p>His Excellency Khalfan Belhoul, CEO of Dubai Future Foundation, said: &ldquo;The Dubai Future Solutions &ndash; Prototypes for Humanity programme offers an unparalleled platform for young innovators to showcase their transformative ideas alongside the annual Dubai Future Forum, reinforcing Dubai&rsquo;s commitment to fostering global solutions. With the invaluable leadership of Her Highness Sheikha Latifa and the support of a diverse network of partners, we&rsquo;re driving impactful change through collaboration, empowering the next generation to address critical challenges with creativity and vision.&rdquo;<br />
Arif Amiri, Chief Executive Officer of the DIFC Authority and Chairman of the Board of Art Dubai said: &ldquo;This year&rsquo;s Prototypes for Humanity programme is truly inspirational and demonstrates how young innovators are creating a better world by developing creative solutions to global challenges. As a founding partner, DIFC&rsquo;s longstanding support for Prototypes for Humanity underscores our commitment to solidifying Dubai&rsquo;s reputation as a global hub for innovation, where the brightest minds can come together to build a more responsible and sustainable future.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Hussain Sajwani, Founder and Chairman of DAMAC, said: &ldquo;Our partnership with the Dubai Future Foundation aligns with the vision of the emirate&rsquo;s leadership to establish the city as a global hub for creativity and technology. The &lsquo;Dubai Future Solutions &ndash; Prototypes for Humanity&rsquo; initiative is a significant milestone in realising these aspirations, and at DAMAC, we are honoured to collaborate with the Foundation on programmes that attract top talent and expertise towards unlocking their potential to serve humanity, reflecting our commitment to enhancing quality of life and addressing the needs of future generations. We firmly believe that innovation and technology are the keys to advancing nations and shaping a sustainable, prosperous future.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Taddeu Baldani Caravieri, Director of the &lsquo;Prototypes for Humanity&rsquo; initiative, said: &lsquo;Whilst the Prototypes for Humanity programme has grown significantly over the past ten years, its guiding principle has always been to shine a light and empower the best ideas that help make for a better tomorrow. We are delighted to have so many innovators present here today and with the support of our invaluable network of partners we look forward to seeing them thrive in Dubai and beyond.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The &lsquo;Dubai Future Solutions &ndash; Prototypes for Humanity&rsquo; initiative aims to identify and enable projects that can comprehensively address critical issues and seeks to collaborate with distinguished graduates and professors from more than 800 global universities. Students and academics across diverse disciplines showcased innovations in agriculture, healthcare, energy, civil society, mobility, water and the environment.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 19:30:00 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735486.1731990611!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735486.1731990611!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Latifa bint Mohammed opens ‘Dubai Future Solutions – Prototypes for Humanity’ initiative]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Mohamed Salah: 90% of my success is rooted in what I’ve learned from books]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/mohamed-salah-90-of-my-success-is-rooted-in-what-i-ve-learned-from-books-2024-11-18-1.735476</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/mohamed-salah-90-of-my-success-is-rooted-in-what-i-ve-learned-from-books-2024-11-18-1.735476</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Global football icon Mohamed Salah captivated audiences on the final day of the 43rd Sharjah International Book Fair (SIBF 2024.) Reflecting on his personal and professional journey, Salah attributed his extraordinary achievements to the transformative power of reading, stating: &quot;90% of my success is rooted in what I&rsquo;ve learned from books. Reading has helped me become a better version of myself.&quot;</p>

<p>Known worldwide for his exceptional speed, precision, and tenacity on the pitch, Salah delved into the profound role books have played in shaping his mindset and career. &quot;I started reading extensively after I left Chelsea,&quot; he shared. &quot;It made me question how people succeed and what it takes to achieve greatness.&quot; He encouraged the audience to embrace a culture of learning and self-discovery, emphasising the value of understanding diverse perspectives. Salah revealed a particular affinity for psychology books, which he credits for helping him better navigate relationships and life&rsquo;s challenges.</p>

<p><strong>A journey from Egypt to the pinnacle of global football</strong></p>

<p>Salah&rsquo;s story began in Egypt, where he honed his skills at Al Mokawloon Al Arab SC before embarking on a remarkable European career. With stints at Basel, Chelsea, Fiorentina, and Roma, he solidified his reputation as a world-class athlete before joining Liverpool FC in 2017.<br />
Throughout the session, Salah provided a glimpse into his disciplined daily routine. &quot;For ten years, I&rsquo;ve trained twice a day, even during holidays&mdash;I always push myself harder,&quot; he said, inspiring the audience with his relentless work ethic.</p>

<p><strong>A commitment to learning and family values</strong></p>

<p>Salah also shared how reading enriches his family life. &quot;I have two daughters, and my wife and I make reading an integral part of their upbringing. Our library contains books in Arabic and English, with a focus on psychology,&quot; he revealed. Despite his busy schedule, Salah ensures that books remain a constant companion: &quot;I always have a book in my bag and try to read before I sleep.&quot;</p>

<p>Looking to the future, Salah announced an exciting plan: &quot;I&#39;m considering writing a biography to serve as a model for younger generations who dream of following the path I took.&quot;</p>

<p>A legacy built on excellence and personal growth</p>

<p>From Premier League and UEFA Champions League titles to Golden Boots and the Puskas Award, Salah&rsquo;s list of accolades is a testament to his talent and determination. Yet, beyond his on-field achievements, his unwavering commitment to personal growth and learning has been a cornerstone of his success.<br />
Salah&rsquo;s talk to his packed SIBF audience served as an inspiring reminder of the transformative power of reading and the boundless potential of self-improvement.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 13:54:06 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735478.1731923543!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735478.1731923543!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735478.1731923543!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735477.1731923532!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Mohamed Salah: 90% of my success is rooted in what I’ve learned from books]]></media:title>

							<media:description><![CDATA[Football legend inspires at the 43rd Sharjah International Book Fair]]></media:description>
						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Latifa bint Mohammed announces AED180 million 'Dubai Cultural Grant' programme]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/latifa-bint-mohammed-announces-aed180-million-dubai-cultural-grant-programme-2024-11-18-1.735436</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/latifa-bint-mohammed-announces-aed180-million-dubai-cultural-grant-programme-2024-11-18-1.735436</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong>- Innovative programme aims to strengthen Dubai&rsquo;s cultural and arts sectors and empower creative communities</strong></li>
	<li><strong>- Series of grants valued at AED180 million to be allocated over the next decade</strong></li>
	<li><strong>- First year of the programme features 18 grants valued at AED12 million that will support local talent across various creative disciplines</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Her Highness: Dubai continues to lead in supporting and empowering the cultural and creative sectors, strengthening its global standing by attracting talent and investors from around the world while nurturing entrepreneurship across various creative fields</strong></li>
	<li><strong>- &ldquo;The &lsquo;Dubai Cultural Grant&rsquo; is an investment in future generations that is designed to ignite a cultural movement in Dubai&rdquo;</strong></li>
	<li><strong>- &ldquo;The initiative represents a pivotal step in supporting the creative economy by providing transformative opportunities for artists, writers, intellectuals,</strong> and entrepreneurs&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>- Launch of the programme further establishes Dubai&rsquo;s position as a global centre for culture, an incubator for creativity, and a thriving hub for talent</p>

<p>Her Highness Sheikha Latifa bint Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Chairperson of Dubai Culture and Arts Authority (Dubai Culture), has announced the launch of the &lsquo;Dubai Cultural Grant&rsquo; programme &mdash; an initiative aimed at developing Dubai&rsquo;s cultural and arts sectors while providing robust support for its creative communities. The innovative programme aims to offer a series of grants valued at AED180 million, to be allocated over the next decade. These grants are dedicated to supporting and empowering local talent across a wide range of cultural and creative industries, including visual and fine arts, design, performing arts, culinary arts, public art, digital arts, literature, heritage, gaming, museology, and professional development.</p>

<p>Starting from this year, the newly-launched programme will feature 18 grants, each comprising a package of grants, valued in total of AED12 million, further establishing Dubai&rsquo;s position as a global centre for culture, an incubator for creativity, and a thriving hub for talent.</p>

<p>The announcement was made during an event organised by Dubai Culture at Etihad Museum, in the presence of a number of officials, partners, and creative talents, including Her Excellency Aisha Abdullah Miran, Director General of the Knowledge and Human Development Authority in Dubai; representatives of Alserkal Group, Art Jameel, Art Dubai Group, the Emirates Literature Foundation, Shatha Essa Kids, HOUSE OF PIANOS, REALIITY, the International Centre for Culinary Arts Dubai, Dubai National Theater, and Sandooq Al Watan; a cohort from the Mohammed bin Rashid Centre for Leadership Development&rsquo;s (MBRCLD) Impactful Leaders Programme; and experts from &lsquo;Tamakan Studio&rsquo;.</p>

<p>Her Highness Sheikha Latifa bint Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum stressed Dubai&#39;s commitment to being a global hub for cultural expression, exchange and innovation, a vision deeply rooted in the leadership of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister of the UAE and Ruler of Dubai. She underscored that the launch of the &lsquo;Dubai Cultural Grant&rsquo; reflects Dubai&#39;s progressive outlook and steadfast support for the creative community, with a focus on bolstering the cultural and creative industries that are pivotal to the city&#39;s vibrant creative economy.</p>

<p>Her Highness said: &ldquo;Dubai continues to lead in supporting and empowering the cultural and arts sectors, strengthening its global standing by attracting talent and investors from around the world while nurturing entrepreneurship across various creative fields. The &lsquo;Dubai Cultural Grant&rsquo; embodies this vision&mdash;an investment in future generations designed to ignite a cultural movement in Dubai. Knowledge, skill, and creativity lie at the heart of our progress, and our diverse cultural landscape enriches and inspires our shared journey.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Expressing her confidence in the impact of the &lsquo;Dubai Cultural Grant,&rsquo; Her Highness added that it represents a pivotal step in supporting the creative economy by providing transformative opportunities for artists, writers, intellectuals, and entrepreneurs. The programme fosters innovation and cultivates strategic partnerships, enabling creatives to bring their unique visions to life while contributing to the local economy through projects that deliver lasting and tangible value.</p>

<p>The Dubai Cultural Grant&rsquo; programme&rsquo;s strategic framework was crafted by a cohort from the Mohammed bin Rashid Centre for Leadership Development&rsquo;s (MBRCLD) Impactful Leaders Programme&mdash;comprising Hamad Al Shirawi, Maitha Al Nuaimi, Ahmad Al Murr, Shaikha Al Shaikh, and Hind Al Mutawa.</p>

<p>The programme&rsquo;s visual identity was crafted by Tamakan Studio, showcasing a wide array of grants designed to empower Emirati talent. One such initiative, the Emirati Creatives in Venice Programme, enables ten Emirati artists to embark on a cultural exchange in Venice, exploring the Venice Biennale and engaging with global artisans and artists through diverse workshops and discussions.</p>

<p>Additionally, the Etihad Museum Research Grant offers researchers an annual award of AED50,000, encouraging in-depth exploration of the Emirati identity through Etihad Museum&rsquo;s extensive archives, offering a unique opportunity to engage with Dubai&rsquo;s historical and cultural heritage. The Emirati Chefs Grant, in partnership with ICCA Dubai, supports aspiring Emirati chefs, focusing on diplomas that meet Dubai&rsquo;s market demands, where participants will develop skills in traditional cuisines and innovative practices, preparing them for success in the culinary industry.</p>

<p>In collaboration with L&#39;&Eacute;cole, School of Jewelry Arts, the Talent Atelier programme provides twelve Emirati designers with an immersive experience in jewellery and gemstone craftsmanship, while the Art Jameel Research and Practice Platform targets UAE-based artists, providing 10 grants for projects addressing environmental themes through artistic practice and exploring sustainable approaches in art. The Shatha Essa Kids Pop-Up at Harrods celebrated a milestone as the first Emirati childrenswear brand featured at Harrods, London. This global showcase highlights Emirati talent and culture on a renowned international platform.</p>

<p>Other initiatives include the Quoz Arts Fest, which offers the creative community a unique platform to engage and connect with the public by showcasing their diverse works and creations at Alserkal Avenue. The Dubai Design Week Grants support Emirati artisans and designers, allowing them to showcase their unique products and ideas at the Dubai Design Week Marketplace. This initiative has led to the creation of the UAE Designer Exhibition, public art installations, and university exhibitions, highlighting the talent and creativity within the UAE.<br />
Furthermore, the Art Dubai Grants enhance the participation of established and emerging Emirati artists in Art Dubai, the Middle East&rsquo;s leading international art fair that showcases art from around the world, with a focus on the MENASA region. Campus Art Dubai, in collaboration with Art Dubai, offers UAE-based creatives workshops and mentorship, enriching their professional growth. This programme welcomes aspiring artists, curators, and cultural producers to develop skills and advance in the creative sector.</p>

<p>The Maison &amp; Objet UAE Designers Showcase Grant will enable 15 UAE-based designers to showcase their work at Maison &amp; Objet in Paris, a leading home decor and lifestyle trade fair. This showcase highlights Emirati talent on an international stage, providing valuable exposure. The International Art Fairs Grant supports Dubai-based galleries in participating in international art fairs, providing a platform to showcase UAE and Emirati artists on the global stage. This initiative expands the international presence of local galleries while promoting cross-cultural artistic exchange.</p>

<p>Through the Exporting Local Literary Talent programme, Dubai Culture, in collaboration with the Emirates Literature Foundation, aims to connect Emirati literary talent with international literary festivals, offering authors and poets a platform to gain global visibility and expand Emirati literature&rsquo;s reach. Through the Emirates Airline Festival of Literature, the Arab world&rsquo;s largest literary festival, Dubai Culture enables 46 established and emerging authors to participate in the festival that celebrates diverse voices and fosters a love for reading.</p>

<p>HOUSE OF PIANOS UAE and STEINWAY &amp; SONS Dubai, in strategic partnership with Dubai Culture, also offer the Piano Camp, a six-month intensive programme that features expert-led workshops in piano performance for young talent aged 6 to 17, helping them enhance their musical abilities. The Theatre Accelerator, in partnership with Sandooq Al Watan and Dubai National Theater, is an immersive month-long programme offering specialised training in scenography, sound, and theatrical arts, where participants gain hands-on experience, enhancing their skills for future theatre projects, while the Family Eid Play programme, in partnership with Dubai National Theater, brings families together through performance art by presenting theatrical performances for children that celebrate local storytelling, encouraging young people to unleash their talents in the performing arts.</p>

<p>The Art + Tech Training Programme, a four-month initiative under the Sikka platform and in partnership with &lsquo;REALIITY&rsquo;, equips artists with the skills to integrate technology into their creative practice, enabling them to design tech-art installations for public exhibitions and contribute to the growth of Dubai&rsquo;s digital art scene.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 06:34:55 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735437.1731897233!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735437.1731897233!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Latifa bint Mohammed announces AED180 million 'Dubai Cultural Grant' programme]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid Arabic language Award opens nominations for 9th edition]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/mohammed-bin-rashid-arabic-language-award-opens-nominations-for-9th-edition-2024-11-17-1.735450</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/mohammed-bin-rashid-arabic-language-award-opens-nominations-for-9th-edition-2024-11-17-1.735450</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;The Mohammed Bin Rashid Arabic Language Award, part of the Mohammed Bin Rashid Al Maktoum Global Initiatives and organised by the Mohammed Bin Rashid Library (MBRL), has announced the opening of nominations for its 9th edition. The initiative continues the UAE leadership&#39;s unwavering commitment to supporting the Arabic language and enhancing its global presence. It also reaffirms Dubai and the UAE&#39;s dedication to preserving and developing Arab cultural heritage through various innovative means.</p>

<p>Launched under the patronage of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister of the UAE and Ruler of Dubai, the Mohammed Bin Rashid Arabic Language Award reflects a forward-thinking vision to position Arabic as a modern, globally influential language. Since its inception, it has become a premier platform recognising individuals and institutions who have made significant contributions to the Arabic language through innovation and creativity in education, research, and publishing.</p>

<p>Bilal Al Budoor, Secretary General of the Mohammed Bin Rashid Arabic Language Award, emphasised its strategic importance, stating: &quot;The Mohammed Bin Rashid Arabic Language Award embodies Dubai and the UAE&#39;s commitment to supporting the Arabic language in line with our wise leadership&#39;s vision, making it a cornerstone of cultural and intellectual development in the Arab world. The remarkable achievements of previous editions, especially the last edition, have elevated the Award&#39;s global stature. We are eager to launch the 9th edition, aspiring to even greater accomplishments and innovations.&quot;</p>

<p>Al Budoor added: &quot;The 8th edition marked significant achievements in empowering the Arabic language and promoting it creatively on a global scale, contributing notably to the advancement of digital and educational tools. We are confident that the upcoming edition will witness further innovations and initiatives that propel the Arabic language to new heights.&quot;</p>

<p>The Mohammed Bin Rashid Arabic Language Award has attracted entries from around the world in its previous editions, driving innovation and creativity in service of the Arabic language. Over the years, the Award has honoured pioneers and institutions from various continents, reflecting the international recognition it has garnered as a global platform for excellence.</p>

<p>The Award continually seeks to develop new approaches that elevate the Arabic language, adapting to rapid technological changes. With the support of Dubai and its visionary leadership, the Award plays a pivotal role in showcasing Arabic as a language of science and knowledge, contributing to various modern fields.</p>

<p>The Mohammed Bin Rashid Arabic Language Award&rsquo;s Board of Trustees invites individuals and institutions passionate about and dedicated to the Arabic language to submit their nominations. The Award welcomes entries from innovators who aim to present projects that address contemporary needs and contribute to the advancement of the Arabic language. It particularly encourages submissions related to the use of Arabic in education and technology, as well as groundbreaking research that advances publishing and promotion methods.</p>

<p>This call presents an excellent opportunity for creative minds, researchers, and institutions looking to offer practical, innovative solutions to enhance the presence of Arabic in digital and technological platforms. The Award is committed to providing a platform for exceptional ideas to shine and contribute to the future of the Arabic language.</p>

<p>Submissions must be completed by the given deadline, with only one entry permitted per cycle. Registration forms should be filled out online, and submissions must be made through the official award website. The organizing committee reserves the right to withdraw or disqualify any entry that does not meet the requirements. Additionally, the Award Board of Trustees retains the authority to revoke an award if it is determined that there has been a violation of the terms, intellectual property rights, or any other serious infringement. Members of the judging panels and the Award Board of Trustees are strictly prohibited from participating in the award in any manner, either directly or indirectly. The deadline for submissions is 14 March 2025.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 20:55:00 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735451.1731898533!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735451.1731898533!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid Arabic language Award opens nominations for 9th edition]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai Culture Celebrates Emerging Talent at Third Dubai Festival for Youth Music]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/dubai-culture-celebrates-emerging-talent-at-third-dubai-festival-for-youth-music-2024-11-14-1.735415</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/dubai-culture-celebrates-emerging-talent-at-third-dubai-festival-for-youth-music-2024-11-14-1.735415</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The Dubai Culture and Arts Authority (Dubai Culture) has announced the upcoming third edition of the Dubai Festival for Youth Music, an initiative aimed at identifying, nurturing, and empowering emerging talent across all musical arts. The festival strives to inspire young creatives to pursue their artistic passions, support musical arts centres, and enrich the local music scene by infusing it with fresh blood.</p>

<p>The Etihad Museum will host this year&rsquo;s festival on 20 November, showcasing over 85 skilled participants from across the UAE. These young artists will compete for the festival&rsquo;s prestigious awards across five main categories: Best Vocal Performance, Best Arabic Instrumental Performance (Oud), Best Classical Instrumental Performance (Violin), Best Piano Performance, and Best Ensemble Performance, among others.</p>

<p>Dubai Culture has awarded Dr Aref Alshaikh the &lsquo;Musical Personality of the Year&rsquo; title in recognition of his longstanding literary contributions and influential role in enriching the local cultural landscape, and he will be honoured during the festival. Dr. Sheikh is one of the UAE&rsquo;s esteemed poets, and has penned the UAE national anthem and authored over 60 poetry and literature publications, including titles such as &lsquo;Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum: An Extraordinary Phenomenon,&rsquo; &lsquo;What the Thirsty Seek,&rsquo; and &lsquo;Names from the Gulf&rsquo;. The festival&rsquo;s judging panel will comprise renowned figures like Composer Mohammad Malulla, maestro Fadel Hamidi, and artist Jasem Mohamed, who will evaluate the finalists&#39; performances. Noteworthy individuals Abdulla Ali Makki and Ameera Al-Ali, participants of the Steinway Piano Camp organised by House of Pianos and Steinway &amp; Sons &ndash; Dubai in partnership with Dubai Culture, will also grace the festival with their performances.</p>

<p>Fatma Al Jallaf, Acting Director of the Performing Arts Department at Dubai Culture, emphasised the Authority&rsquo;s commitment to elevating the local music sector, a pillar of the creative economy, saying, &ldquo;Through the Dubai Festival for Youth Music, Dubai Culture aims to create a sustainable creative environment that supports and empowers talent, offering them platforms to flourish. We hope to inspire them to continue their artistic journeys and to contribute, through their musical abilities, to the strength of the cultural and creative industries.&rdquo; She also highlighted the importance of honouring leading figures in the arts and literature as part of Dubai Culture&rsquo;s dedication to recognising local creative icons and raising public awareness of their achievements.</p>

<p>The Dubai Festival for Youth Music invites the entry of young Emirati and UAE-based musicians, solo vocalists, bands, and instrumentalists - both traditional and contemporary - aged 15 to 35. Festival participants must submit original, documented musical works, that are in line with UAE laws, and have not been previously showcased at local or international festivals. The submissions should reflect the values and traditions of the community and be produced locally, either by individual artists or music groups.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 13:01:17 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735418.1731598042!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735418.1731598042!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai Culture Celebrates Emerging Talent at Third Dubai Festival for Youth Music]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
