<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
	<title>Mobile - Climate</title>
	<link>http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-climate-1.708778?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout</link>	
	<atom:link href="http://www.emirates247.com/cmlink/mobile-climate-1.708778?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" ></atom:link>
	<description>Climate</description>
			        <language>en</language>
    				<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Saif bin Zayed leads global ministerial forum on law enforcement’s role in climate action on sidelines of COP29]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/saif-bin-zayed-leads-global-ministerial-forum-on-law-enforcement-s-role-in-climate-action-on-sidelines-of-cop29-2024-11-16-1.735432</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/saif-bin-zayed-leads-global-ministerial-forum-on-law-enforcement-s-role-in-climate-action-on-sidelines-of-cop29-2024-11-16-1.735432</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;H.H. Lt. General Sheikh Saif bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of the Interior, presided over a high-level ministerial forum in the Blue Zone at COP29, gathering prominent global leaders in law enforcement and environmental protection.</p>

<p>The forum, held in cooperation with the Office of the Prosecutor General of Azerbaijan and the United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime (UNODC), underscored the critical role of law enforcement in addressing climate and cross-border challenges on the sidelines of COP29 in Baku, Azerbaijan.</p>

<p>As an extension of last year&rsquo;s ministerial meeting at COP28 in Dubai, this year&rsquo;s forum welcomed high-ranking participants, including Dr. Kamran Aliyev, Prosecutor-General of Azerbaijan and Vice-President of the International Association of Prosecutors; Dr. Ghada Waly, Executive Director of UNODC; Mukhtar Babayev, COP29 President-designate; and Alexander Zouev, Assistant Secretary-General for Rule of Law and Security Institutions at the UN.</p>

<p>In his keynote address, Sheikh Saif congratulated Azerbaijan for hosting COP29 and thanked Dr. Aliyev and Dr. Waly for their collaboration in organising the groundbreaking event, &ldquo;Mobilizing Law Enforcement to Promote Climate Action.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Sheikh Saif shared an impactful message, likening the Earth to a mother whose health is essential for the survival and well-being of humanity. &ldquo;If the health of our land is sound, then humanity thrives, the world flourishes, and future generations are secure, citing the UAE&rsquo;s core philosophy that sustainable environmental practices are foundational to societal well-being,&quot; he said.</p>

<p>Sheikh Saif further introduced I2LEC, an initiative aimed at environmental protection, noting that the criminal is not only the thief or the terrorist; there is a terrorism that targets our environment.</p>

<p>H.H. Lt. General Sheikh Saif bin Zayed emphasised that transparency and collaboration are key to combating what he described as &ldquo;environmental terrorism&rdquo;, adding that &ldquo;we must be clear with ourselves and with each other, and we must shed light on those committing crimes against humanity and our planet, and call for real change in global policies that protect the environment.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Acknowledging the positive contributions of some nations, he also highlighted the destructive role played by others, urging collective accountability.</p>

<p>Sheikh Saif expressed gratitude to international partners who have supported the I2LEC initiative since COP28, reporting promising initial results. Notably, the Green Justice and Jungle Shield operations &ndash; spanning the Amazon and Congo Basins with the participation of 11 countries, UNODC, ISRI, and the Lusaka Convention Working Group &ndash; yielded significant impacts. These operations sized more than 32 kilogrammes of illegally mined gold while preventing over 213,000 tonnes of carbon dioxide emissions.</p>

<p>H.H. Lt. General Sheikh Saif bin Zayed stressed that these operations underscored the intricate links between environmental crimes, money laundering, corruption, human trafficking, and the financing of terrorism.</p>

<p>Sheikh Saif highlighted the alarming statistics on forest fires, stating that natural fires alone release approximately 8 billion tonnes of carbon dioxide annually, accounting for 20 percent of global fossil fuel emissions. Of greater concern, he noted, is that human activity causes 90 percent of these fires, with 80 percent of Amazon fires aimed at clearing land for agriculture.</p>

<p>The Minister underscored that global cooperation is crucial in combating environmental crimes, emphasising the need for unified and integrated efforts. International and regional legal frameworks, coupled with adequate financing for climate projects, form the cornerstone of this collaboration. Such measures enable the development of effective policies, empower law enforcement to act decisively, and ensure rapid intervention to protect the environment.</p>

<p>He further affirmed that this solidarity is essential to preserve Earth&#39;s resources and safeguard a sustainable future for coming generations.</p>

<p>Sheikh Saif also called for a re-evaluation of climate financing frameworks to better support law enforcement agencies in their environmental protection efforts. He reiterated the UAE&rsquo;s steadfast commitment, guided by the vision of President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, to strengthening law enforcement&rsquo;s role in global climate action.</p>

<p>He stressed that by fostering international cooperation, we can combat environmental crimes, restore ecosystems, and build a better world for future generations, extending his wishes for the success of all efforts toward this noble goal.</p>

<p>Speakers at the forum expanded on these themes, exploring strategies to enhance law enforcement&rsquo;s capacity to tackle environmental crimes like illegal logging, wildlife trafficking, marine pollution, and illegal mining.</p>

<p>Discussions included frameworks for strengthening inter-agency cooperation and adopting innovative approaches, such as utilising renewable energy, implementing energy-efficient practices, and leveraging digital technologies to reduce the carbon footprint of law enforcement agencies.</p>

<p>The event also showcased the innovative &ldquo;Heat Map&rdquo; tool, developed in collaboration with ESRI. This tool enables law enforcement to identify crime hotspots, track sources of environmental harm, and align strategies with global climate goals. The platform was hailed as a significant advancement in enhancing the role of law enforcement in protecting ecosystems and promoting sustainability worldwide.</p>

<p>The forum concluded with the unveiling of the &ldquo;Baku Call to Action&rdquo;, a declaration that reinforces global commitment to empowering law enforcement in addressing environmental challenges. This landmark initiative calls on participating nations and organisations to enhance international collaboration, bolster the capabilities of law enforcement personnel, and prioritise climate-focused strategies to combat environmental crimes and their associated threats.</p>

<p>This pivotal event builds on the momentum of the ministerial forums initiated at COP28 in Dubai, where the UAE launched the International Law Enforcement for Climate (I2LEC) initiative in partnership with the United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime (UNODC). At COP28, the &ldquo;Abu Dhabi Call to Action&rdquo; was introduced, marking a historic milestone in uniting global law enforcement to safeguard biodiversity, restore ecosystems, and fortify resilience against climate disasters. The initiative underscored the importance of equipping law enforcement agencies with the skills and resources necessary to combat environmental crimes effectively.</p>

<p>The &ldquo;Baku Call to Action&rdquo; not only reaffirms these commitments but also amplifies the urgency of collective action in the face of escalating climate challenges. By strengthening the global law enforcement community&rsquo;s ability to respond to environmental crimes, this initiative supports peacebuilding, ensures climate restoration, and fosters a sustainable future for all.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 13:31:53 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735433.1731749443!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735433.1731749443!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Saif bin Zayed leads global ministerial forum on law enforcement’s role in climate action on sidelines of COP29]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Winners announced for HIPA’s sustainability-themed 13th season]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/winners-announced-for-hipa-s-sustainability-themed-13th-season-2024-11-13-1.735352</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/winners-announced-for-hipa-s-sustainability-themed-13th-season-2024-11-13-1.735352</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Under the patronage of His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defence of the UAE, and Chairman of The Executive Council of Dubai, the Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum International Photography Award (HIPA) held its 13th annual awards ceremony for the competition, themed &lsquo;Sustainability&rsquo;, at the Museum of the Future. Dignitaries and prominent members of the global photography community attended the event.</p>

<p>Poignant contrast<br />
Her Highness Sheikha Latifa bint Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Chairperson of the Dubai Culture and Arts Authority (Dubai Culture), presented the $200,000 Grand Prize to Chinese photographer Liping Cao. His black-and-white image captures a poignant scene of nature and technology in harmony: towering wind turbines rise prominently on the horizon, their blades slowly rotating in the breeze, embodying the quiet power of renewable energy. Behind them, the sky is speckled with drifting clouds, creating a dynamic backdrop. The dry riverbed beneath the turbines adds depth to the image, reminding us of the importance of sustainable practices in a world facing environmental challenges.</p>

<p>Special Awards<br />
Sheikha Latifa affirmed that Dubai, with its visionary approach, is a nurturing space for innovative initiatives and awards, establishing itself as a global source of inspiration and a gathering place for creative minds and exceptional talents from diverse fields. She noted that the Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum International Photography Award reflects the emirate&rsquo;s inspiring ethos, cultural richness, and the strength of its visual and creative arts landscape.</p>

<p>&ldquo;This award, with its diverse categories, embodies Dubai&rsquo;s ambitious vision and leadership, enhancing its position on the global stage as a magnet for photographers and creatives in general. It showcases Dubai&rsquo;s ability to build bridges of communication among people and communities by honouring talented individuals who, through their creative work, tell the stories of cultures, document traditions, and convey powerful messages that reflect society and heritage. This, in turn, uplifts photographers in the UAE and the Arab region, strengthening their presence on the international art scene,&rdquo; Her Highness said.</p>

<p>Sustainability theme<br />
Sheikha Latifa also highlighted that the award aligns with the UAE&rsquo;s commitment to the Sustainable Development Goals, focusing in its current cycle on &lsquo;Sustainability,&rsquo; a theme that reflects the forward-thinking mindset of the award&rsquo;s organisers and their conviction in the critical role of culture and the arts in advancing sustainability, thereby contributing to the well-being of societies.</p>

<p>His Excellency Ali Khalifa bin Thalith, HIPA&rsquo;s Secretary General, thanked Sheikh Hamdan for his continued support of HIPA and the art of photography. &ldquo;In our thirteenth year, we have extended our reach to 205 countries. What truly matters to us is the advancement of the photographer and the photography industry. His Highness&rsquo; vision for nurturing human creativity is apparent from his decision to raise the total prize purse under the award to $1 million.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Praising the emergence of Emirati and Arab photographers on the global stage, His Excellency Bin Thalith said: &ldquo;Over the past 13 years, HIPA has enhanced Dubai&rsquo;s artistic and cultural presence globally and has made a tangible difference to photographer communities regionally and internationally. We have established a solid creative base in Dubai and have successfully honed Emirati talent, elevating them to international levels of competitiveness. The presence of winners from the UAE, Palestine, Saudi Arabia and Syria is evidence that Arab photographers have earned their place on the world stage.&rdquo;</p>

<p>More than a quarter of the winners in this season&rsquo;s awards reside in the UAE, benefiting from a creative environment that stimulates innovation and competitiveness, Bin Thalith highlighted. &ldquo;This reinforces the UAE&rsquo;s leadership in attracting global talent and innovators,&rdquo; he said.</p>

<p>James &lsquo;Jimmy&rsquo; Philip Nelson, a Dutch photographer known for his work with indigenous communities, received the Photography Appreciation Award for his significant contributions to photography and projects that foster greater understanding between different cultures.</p>

<p>Emirati winner<br />
The Photography Content Creator Award went to Emirati photographer Salma Ali Humaid Alsuwaidi for her pioneering work documenting the wildlife and bird species of the UAE. Her book, &lsquo;Common Birds and Their Nests in the United Arab Emirates,&rsquo; significantly contributes to the scientific and artistic communities.</p>

<p>New award<br />
The inaugural HIPA Photographer of the Year Award was presented to Samy Al Olabi, a Syrian astrophotographer renowned for his breathtaking images of celestial objects and nature photography, particularly in the dark skies of the Arabian Peninsula. He is famous for his projects photographing stars from the dark corners of the Arabian Peninsula. His work has been featured in more than 80 local and international publications.</p>

<p>Sustainability Awards<br />
Her Highness Sheikha Latifa bint Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, honoured the winners in the &lsquo;Sustainability&rsquo; category. Ruijuan Huang from China took the first prize, with French photographer Virginie Ellis and Ranganathan Mukkai from India finishing second and third respectively.</p>

<p>His Excellency Bin Thalith presented the awards to winners in the &lsquo;General - Colour&rsquo; category. Rahul Vishwanath Sachdev from India took first place, followed by Youmn Mohammed Almanla from Saudi Arabia, and Ahmed Abdallah Al Housni from Oman.</p>

<p>In the &lsquo;General - Black and White&rsquo; category, American photographer Renee Capozzola took the first prize, followed by Hikkaduwa Liyanage Prasantha Vinod from Sri Lanka, and Ateeb Hussain from India.</p>

<p>Portfolio Awards<br />
His Excellency Abdulrahman bin Mohamed Al Owais, Minister of Health and Prevention and Chairman of the Board of Trustees of HIPA, honoured the winners of the &lsquo;Portfolio (Story-Telling)&rsquo; category, in which Palestinian photographer Fatma Alzahra Shbair won first place, with Sarah Wouters from the Netherlands taking second spot and Wen Bing from China finishing third.</p>

<p>Sports Photography<br />
Her Excellency Hala Badri, Director General of Dubai Culture, presented the Sports Photography awards. Tobias Friedrich from Germany took the first prize, followed by Karim Iliya from the USA, and Hendra Agus Setyawan from Indonesia respectively.</p>

<p>Short Videos<br />
His Excellency Abdulrahman bin Mohamed Al Owais honoured the winners in the &lsquo;Short Video (For Social Media)&rsquo; category. Aleksandr Tsuprun from the Russian Federation won first prize, followed by Norbert von Niman from Sweden, and Abhin Kizhakke Veettil from India, who finished third.</p>

<p>The HIPA 13th Season Awards once again highlighted the incredible talent of the global photographer community, with a strong emphasis on sustainability and creativity. With continued support from His Highness Sheikh Hamdan, HIPA remains a leading platform for advancing the art of photography and celebrating the photographers who inspire the world through their work.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 10:13:51 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735353.1731478385!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735353.1731478385!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Winners announced for HIPA’s sustainability-themed 13th season]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																								
											<category>Arts_culture</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Art_Culture</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE President meets with heads of state, delegation leaders at COP29 in Azerbaijan]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-meets-with-heads-of-state-delegation-leaders-at-cop29-in-azerbaijan-2024-11-12-1.735344</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-meets-with-heads-of-state-delegation-leaders-at-cop29-in-azerbaijan-2024-11-12-1.735344</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan met today with a number of heads of state and delegation leaders on the sidelines of the COP29 climate conference in Baku, Azerbaijan.</p>

<p>His Highness held separate meetings with His Excellency Mohamed Ould Ghazouani, President of the Islamic Republic of Mauritania, His Excellency Recep Tayyip Erdogan, President of the Republic of T&uuml;rkiye, His Excellency Viktor Orb&aacute;n, Prime Minister of Hungary, and Her Excellency Željka Cvijanović, member of the Presidency of Bosnia and Herzegovina.</p>

<p>During the meetings, His Highness discussed with the leaders cooperation between the UAE and their respective countries in various fields, including clean energy, sustainability, and climate action, and ways to further develop these ties.</p>

<p>The meetings also discussed the aims of the COP29 conference, with all sides stressing the importance of ongoing partnerships and global cooperation.</p>

<p>His Highness reiterated the UAE&rsquo;s steadfast commitment to supporting all efforts aimed at accelerating climate action and fostering international collaboration to co-create a climate-resilient future for all.</p>

<p>Discussions also covered a number of regional and international issues of mutual concern, with those present emphasising the importance of working together to promote peace and stability at both the regional and global levels.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 20:08:06 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735345.1731427638!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735345.1731427638!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE President meets with heads of state, delegation leaders at COP29 in Azerbaijan]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE President arrives in Azerbaijan to participate in COP29 climate conference]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-arrives-in-azerbaijan-to-participate-in-cop29-climate-conference-2024-11-11-1.735318</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-arrives-in-azerbaijan-to-participate-in-cop29-climate-conference-2024-11-11-1.735318</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>UAE President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan arrived today at Heydar Aliyev International Airport in Baku on a working visit to the Republic of Azerbaijan, during which he will participate in the COP29 climate conference.</p>

<p>The conference is being hosted in the Azerbaijan capital from 11 to 22 November under the slogan &lsquo;In Solidarity for a Green World.&rsquo;</p>

<p>His Highness is accompanied by an official delegation that includes H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Chairman of the Presidential Court for Special Affairs; Sheikh Mohammed bin Hamad bin Tahnoun Al Nahyan, Advisor for Special Affairs at the Presidential Court; Dr. Sultan bin Ahmed Al Jaber, Minister of Industry and Advanced Technology; Mohamed Hassan Alsuwaidi, Minister of Investment; Dr. Amna bint Abdullah Al Dahak Al Shamsi, Minister of Climate Change and the Environment; Ahmed Ali Al Sayegh, Minister of State; Dr Ahmed Mubarak Al Mazrouei, Chairman of the President&#39;s Office for Strategic Affairs at the Presidential Court; Faisal Abdulaziz Mohammed Al Bannai, Adviser to the UAE President for Strategic Research and Advanced Technology, and Mohammed Murad Al Balushi, UAE Ambassador to Azerbaijan.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 19:35:24 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735319.1731340841!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735319.1731340841!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE President arrives in Azerbaijan to participate in COP29 climate conference]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>World</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/World</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai Reef Reaches Major Milestone with Fabrication of the First 1,000 Purpose-Built Reef Modules]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sustainability/dubai-reef-reaches-major-milestone-with-fabrication-of-the-first-1-000-purpose-built-reef-modules-2024-10-30-1.734947</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sustainability/dubai-reef-reaches-major-milestone-with-fabrication-of-the-first-1-000-purpose-built-reef-modules-2024-10-30-1.734947</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Dubai Reef, a sustainable initiative by Dubai Can, and the world&#39;s largest purpose-built reef development, has successfully reached another major milestone with the fabrication of the initial 1,000 purpose-built reef modules. This marks a significant step in its journey towards enhancing marine biodiversity and promoting ecological sustainability in Dubai&#39;s waters.</p>

<p>Launched by His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defence of the UAE, and Chairman of The Executive Council of Dubai, the Dubai Reef project involves the deployment of 20,000 purpose-built reef modules of various sizes over a three-year period. The pilot stage was inaugurated by His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum in April 2024, and the deployment of the first 1,000 reef modules is set to start in the last week of November 2024.</p>

<p>The Dubai Reef project will see numerous different purpose-built reef module types deployed at various depths across four clusters. The modules vary in dimensions to create various habitats for different fish species, with the height ranging from 1.60 metres to 6.5 metres, and deployed in depths from 15 metres to 25 metres. The reef modules aim to establish a vibrant marine habitat for reef fish and aquatic fauna such as hard and soft corals, sea anemones, sponges and mollusks.</p>

<p>The construction of the Dubai Reef modules began in August 2024, with the pouring of the Arab Marine Pyramid module type. Fabricated by HaejooX on a site powered by biofuels, the materials used ensure durability, and promote and support marine life &ndash; a process that adheres to sustainability and environmentally-friendly practices.</p>

<p>His Excellency Ahmed Mohammed bin Thani, Director General of DECCA, said: &ldquo;The successful fabrication of the first 1,000 reef modules is a significant achievement, and we are excited to see the project take shape. Dubai Reef is a shining example of what can be achieved through collaboration and innovation. We are proud to continue serving as one of the key strategic partners of this project, which aligns with our mission to ensure environmental protection, preserve the quality and natural balance of the environment, and maintain Dubai&rsquo;s natural resources.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Sheikh Dr. Saeed bin Ahmed bin Khalifa Al Maktoum, Executive Director of the Dubai Maritime Authority (DMA) at the Ports, Customs, and Free Zone Corporation (PCFC), expressed pride in the efforts made by DMA and PCFC to support leading environmental initiatives, such as Dubai Reef, which reflects Dubai&rsquo;s future-looking vision while supporting marine biodiversity. He said: &ldquo;The progress we have seen so far is the result of the unwavering commitment and tireless efforts of our strategic partners, aligning with DMA&rsquo;s mission to create an integrated marine ecosystem supporting Dubai&rsquo;s blue economy, while establishing the emirate&rsquo;s position as a leading global destination for innovation and marine sustainability. We are progressing according to the schedule, with the ultimate goal of fostering a balanced and sustainable marine ecosystem, elevating Dubai as a leader in the marine sector.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Yousuf Lootah, CEO of Corporate Strategy and Performance, who heads the Dubai Can sustainable initiatives and Dubai Reef project in the Dubai Department of Economy and Tourism (DET), added: &ldquo;The delivery of the first 1,000 reef modules marks an important milestone that demonstrates Dubai&rsquo;s commitment to developing a vibrant and resilient habitat for our marine ecosystem. The capability to fabricate and deliver consistent numbers of modules will ensure reliable production throughout the project&rsquo;s lifecycle, enabling us to meet our overarching goals. Dubai Reef&rsquo;s strategic partners have played a crucial role in getting the project to this stage, and we hope that this milestone will inspire and encourage more organisations and individuals to participate in this landmark sustainability initiative.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Ryan Paik, CEO of HaejooX, said: &ldquo;As the official construction and fabrication contractor for Dubai Reef, we are thrilled to reach this important milestone. The completion of the first 1,000 reef modules is as per the project timeline, and we look forward to delivering on our promise to positively impact Dubai&rsquo;s marine environment.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Spanning 600 square kilometres of Dubai&rsquo;s waters, Dubai Reef is the second major project under the pioneering Dubai Can sustainability initiative launched by His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, and is aligned with the ambitious goals of the Dubai Economic Agenda, D33, to further consolidate Dubai&rsquo;s position as a leading global city for business and leisure.<br />
A citywide collaboration from across the public and private sectors, Dubai Reef&rsquo;s strategic partners include Dubai Department of Economy and Tourism (DET), Dubai Environment and Climate Change Authority (DECCA), DP World, Dubai Chambers, Nakheel, Ports, Customs and Free Zone Corporation (PCFC), and Emirates.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 16:21:21 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734954.1730290841!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734954.1730290841!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai Reef Reaches Major Milestone with Fabrication of the First 1,000 Purpose-Built Reef Modules]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sustainability</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Climate</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[DXB achieves top sustainability milestone with global accreditation]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sustainability/dxb-achieves-top-sustainability-milestone-with-global-accreditation-2024-10-28-1.734851</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sustainability/dxb-achieves-top-sustainability-milestone-with-global-accreditation-2024-10-28-1.734851</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Dubai International&rsquo;s (DXB) work to cut carbon emissions has been recognised with a Level 4 &ldquo;Transformation&rdquo; accreditation from Airports Council International (ACI) Airport Carbon Accreditation (ACA) programme, placing it, as of September 2024, among the top 5% of participating airports worldwide to achieve this status.</p>

<p>The &ldquo;Transformation&rdquo; certification is awarded to airports that realise absolute emissions reductions and drive systemic change with its stakeholders. In strategic alignment with the UAE, Dubai Airports is playing a vital role in supporting the country&rsquo;s Net Zero 2050 strategy&mdash; through its commitment to minimising its environmental impact and enhancing operational efficiency, with a comprehensive focus on decarbonisation, resource conservation, and the adoption of cutting-edge technologies.</p>

<p>Paul Griffiths, CEO of Dubai Airports commented: &ldquo;Achieving Level 4 &lsquo;Transformation&rsquo; accreditation underscores our firm commitment to embedding sustainability at the core of everything we do at Dubai Airports. This recognition not only highlights our progress in reducing our own carbon footprint but also reflects the strength of our partnerships in driving broader, systemic change across the aviation ecosystem.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;For us, sustainability is not a checkbox &ndash; it&rsquo;s a long-term strategy that involves collaboration, innovation, and constant improvement.&nbsp; The responsibility we own goes beyond our operation; it&rsquo;s about leading by example and embracing a culture where every stakeholder plays a part in creating a more sustainable future. Together, we are setting a new standard for what is possible in airport operations, as we continue to support Dubai&rsquo;s and the UAE&rsquo;s leadership in the global effort towards Net Zero by 2050,&rdquo; he added.</p>

<p>Stefano Baronci, Director General, ACI Asia-Pacific &amp; Middle East, said: &ldquo;We congratulate Dubai Airports for its significant strides in reducing carbon emissions, setting a benchmark for airports across the region. By positioning itself as one of the leaders in efficient carbon management, Dubai Airports demonstrates a strong commitment to building a more sustainable future. Dubai Airports&rsquo; approach aligns with our industry&#39;s collective vision of achieving net zero emissions by 2050.&rdquo;</p>

<p>DXB has made significant progress through key initiatives and partnerships aimed at advancing sustainable aviation. A recent example is the collaboration with dnata and Emirates National Oil Company (ENOC), transitioning dnata&rsquo;s non-electric airside fleet to a biodiesel blend, reducing carbon emissions by over 3,500 tonnes annually.</p>

<p>Other initiatives include a partnership with Etihad Energy Services to enhance energy efficiency through building and lighting retrofit and solar integration, and a collaboration with BEEAH Group, reducing landfill waste by 60% through an innovative food waste treatment plan. DXB&rsquo;s adoption of the &lsquo;Follow the Greens&rsquo; system has also optimised aircraft taxiing, cutting fuel consumption and emissions. Other successful initiatives include active engagement with &lsquo;Airports of Tomorrow&rsquo;, a collaborative venture by the World Economic Forum (WEF) and ACI, to steer the aviation industry toward net-zero carbon emissions by 2050.</p>

<p>The recently launched oneDXB Sustainability Alliance, a network of airport partners, is further driving sustainability by exploring over 180 additional potential decarbonisation projects.</p>

<p>The Level 4 ACI Accreditation affirms Dubai Airports&rsquo; leadership in sustainability and positions DXB as a benchmark in the global airport community.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 11:27:18 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734852.1730100424!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734852.1730100424!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[DXB achieves top sustainability milestone with global accreditation]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sustainability</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Climate</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[28th IRENA Council convenes in Abu Dhabi ahead of COP29]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sustainability/28th-irena-council-convenes-in-abu-dhabi-ahead-of-cop29-2024-10-24-1.734778</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sustainability/28th-irena-council-convenes-in-abu-dhabi-ahead-of-cop29-2024-10-24-1.734778</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The International Renewable Energy Agency (IRENA) convenes its 28th Council meeting in Abu Dhabi today, the last before the 29th Conference of the Parties (COP29).</p>

<p>Over the next two days, IRENA Members are expected to discuss critical topics related to the energy transition, including progress towards tripling renewable energy capacity and doubling energy efficiency by 2030, as outlined in the Outcome of the First Global Stocktake.</p>

<p>A recently published IRENA report, Delivering on the UAE Consensus: Tracking Progress Toward Tripling Renewable Energy Capacity and Doubling Energy Efficiency by 2030, in collaboration with COP28 and COP29 Presidencies, the Government of Brazil (host of COP30), the Ministry of Energy of Azerbaijan and the Global Renewables Alliance (GRA), confirms that current national plans are projected to deliver only half of the required growth in renewable power by 2030 to limit rising global temperatures to 1.5&deg;C.</p>

<p>&ldquo;The 1.5&deg;C target is still within reach, but the risk of missing it is becoming increasingly near,&rdquo; said IRENA Director-General Francesco La Camera. &ldquo;The third round of Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs) must close the gap towards 2030. With COP29 less than a month away, the gathering of the IRENA Council presents another opportunity to re-emphasise the urgent need to approach Baku with significantly heightened ambition.&rdquo;</p>

<p>In her capacity as IRENA Council Chair, Dr. Gloria Magombo Secretary for Energy and Power Development, Zimbabwe stated: &ldquo;The alarming gap between the current global trajectory of the renewables-based energy transition and our collective climate targets underscore the urgency of IRENA&rsquo;s mission. As Chair, I am committed to ensure that the 28th IRENA Council meets with collaborative resolve in support of the Agency&rsquo;s work to accelerate progress across its Membership.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The 28th IRENA Council will also engage in discussions on national experiences in energy transition, challenges and opportunities to enhance the mobilisation of finance towards renewables, and innovative technologies and partnerships essential for the energy transformation of small island economies.</p>

<p>The two-day meetings will also collaboratively consider the implementation of the Agency&rsquo;s work programme and budget.</p>

<p>IRENA recently launched &lsquo;#3xRenewables for the planet and its people&rsquo;, a global campaign designed to drive action and collaboration towards tripling renewable energy capacity by 2030.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 12:05:20 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734779.1729757081!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734779.1729757081!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[28th IRENA Council convenes in Abu Dhabi ahead of COP29]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sustainability</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Climate</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[DIFC Leads Global Push with 2nd Future Sustainability Forum in Dubai]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sustainability/difc-leads-global-push-with-2nd-future-sustainability-forum-in-dubai-2024-10-22-1.734689</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sustainability/difc-leads-global-push-with-2nd-future-sustainability-forum-in-dubai-2024-10-22-1.734689</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<div>
<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong><em>DIFC&rsquo;s forum aligns with vision of UAE&rsquo;s leadership to fast-track the transition to greener economies through sustainable technology, banking and finance, renewable energy, and waste management. </em></strong></li>
	<li><strong><em>Second edition of the Future Sustainability Forum takes place in Dubai on 4 and 5 December.</em></strong></li>
	<li><strong><em>Coinciding with first anniversary of COP28 being held in the UAE, the Forum is a step towards accelerating efforts to meet the Paris Agreement goals and the UN SDGs 2030.</em></strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>Dubai International Financial Centre (DIFC), the leading global financial hub in the Middle East, Africa and South Asia (MEASA) region, announces the 2<sup>nd</sup> edition of the Future Sustainability Forum. Scheduled for 4 and 5 December 2024 at the Madinat Jumeirah, Dubai, the Forum will focus on mobilising sustainable practices, engaging in influential discussions on sustainable development, working towards environmental conservation, social equity and innovation.</p>

<p>The announcement of the 2nd edition of the Forum underscores DIFC&rsquo;s commitment to advancing UAE sustainability priorities alongside initiatives such as the DIFC Sustainable Finance Catalyst which aims to grow sustainable finance flows from Dubai to USD 100+ billion by 2030.</p>

<p>The Forum coincides with the first anniversary of COP28 being hosted in the UAE and is set to attract over 3,000 participants. The event will mobilise industry leaders, investors, tech disruptors, and policymakers into achieving the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) and contributing to the delivery of the Paris Agreement, whilst aiming to channel investment flows between the global north and south to accelerate climate action.</p>

<p><strong>Alya Al Zarouni, Chief Operating Officer of DIFC Authority and Co-Chair of the Dubai Sustainable Finance Working Group</strong>, said, &ldquo;The DIFC organised Future Sustainability Forum is a vital platform for collaborative action towards a more sustainable future. As the global economic landscape evolves, so must our commitment to responsible and inclusive growth. At DIFC, we are proud to be convening this gathering of industry leaders, innovators, and policymakers to address the most pressing environmental and social challenges of our time. Together, we can forge new pathways to a more resilient and sustainable future for financial services and other important industries.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>Dr Bernd van Linder, Chief Executive Officer of the Commercial Bank of Dubai</strong>, the presenting sponsor of the Forum, stated, &quot;Commercial Bank of Dubai is proud to support the UAE&#39;s sustainability ambitions through our participation in the Future Sustainability Forum 2024 as Presenting Sponsor. Our proactive approach in addressing environmental challenges, exemplified by the successful issuance of CBD&#39;s inaugural green bond, demonstrates our alignment with global environmental goals.&quot;</p>

<p>The Forum will address critical sustainability issues across eight core pillars spanning different industries including banking and finance, construction, renewable and future energy, transportation and mobility, manufacturing and production, recycling and waste management, sustainable technology, and agriculture and food production.</p>

<p>In addition to the packed conference agenda that will feature over 100 sustainability and climate action expert speakers, the Forum will bring together the most innovative solutions and service providers from across the global sustainability landscape through the Climate Action &amp; Renewable Energy Expo (CARE).</p>
</div>

<p>Government entities in the UAE have spearheaded a range of comprehensive sustainability programmes in the pursuit of a net-zero future. Initiatives such as the Dubai Clean Energy Strategy 2050, the UAE Net Zero 2050 strategic initiative, and the UAE Vision 2070, emphasise on a commitment to renewable energy adoption, water conservation, waste management, and sustainable urban development.</p>

<p>For more information and to register, please visit the <a href="https://futuresustainabilityforum.com/">Future Sustainability Forum</a> website.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 14:39:56 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734690.1729595202!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734690.1729595202!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[DIFC Leads Global Push with 2nd Future Sustainability Forum in Dubai]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sustainability</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Climate</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Al Ain Zoo’s Safe Haven Attracts Eurasian Golden Oriole Bird]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sustainability/al-ain-zoo-s-safe-haven-attracts-eurasian-golden-oriole-bird-2024-10-22-1.734673</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sustainability/al-ain-zoo-s-safe-haven-attracts-eurasian-golden-oriole-bird-2024-10-22-1.734673</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Al Ain Zoo is pleased to announce the sighting of the migratory Eurasian Golden Oriole. This discovery was made during the Zoo&rsquo;s monthly bird survey, which focuses on monitoring bird species, populations, and the quality of the Zoo&rsquo;s habitats as a refuge for wildlife.</p>

<p>The Zoo conducts comprehensive monthly studies to track the movement of wild birds, recording species, numbers, and their duration of stay. These observations are then compared with findings from other research on bird migration. Notably, the Zoo has seen an increase in bird numbers during the winter season, which spans from October to March.</p>

<p>The presence of migratory birds at Al Ain Zoo is a testament to its ideal environment, offering a safe haven with secure reserves, shaded areas, and well-maintained greenery. The Zoo&rsquo;s ponds and water basins also contribute to attracting various bird species. To ensure a natural and healthy habitat for wildlife, no pesticides are used on the Zoo&rsquo;s trees and plants.</p>

<p>In line with its mission to promote conservation and education, Al Ain Zoo regularly organizes bird-watching tours to raise awareness about the importance of birds and their role in maintaining ecological balance. These initiatives encourage public participation in cleaning campaigns to preserve habitats, promote sustainable agriculture practices, advocate against pesticide use, and support government and environmental organizations&rsquo; efforts across the UAE.</p>

<p>A shy bird, it hears more than it sees except during migration. It is characterized by its yellow color and black wings. Orioles are monogamous, meaning they mate with one partner for life. Their nests are hanging and woven in the shape of a cup. The female lays between 2-3 eggs, and rarely up to 6 eggs. The female&#39;s feathers are pale, while the male&#39;s feathers are bright. They inhabit parks with tall trees and farms, feeding on insects and fruits like berries and figs.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 08:38:22 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734674.1729571858!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734674.1729571858!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Al Ain Zoo’s Safe Haven Attracts Eurasian Golden Oriole Bird]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sustainability</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Climate</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Dubai joins the SDG Cities Global Initiative]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sustainability/dubai-joins-the-sdg-cities-global-initiative-2024-10-21-1.734642</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sustainability/dubai-joins-the-sdg-cities-global-initiative-2024-10-21-1.734642</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p dir="RTL" style="text-align: left;"><strong><span dir="LTR">Hamad Al Mansoori:</span></strong></p>

<p><strong>These efforts underline Digital Dubai&#39;s dedication to advancing sustainability across all sectors, highlighting its strategic role in promoting the digital lifestyle, leveraging the latest technologies to benefit the community, and delivering an urban experience that serves as an inspiration to cities worldwide. </strong></p>

<p dir="RTL" style="text-align: left;"><strong><span dir="LTR">Younus Al Nasser:</span></strong></p>

<p><strong>Global experiences, with Digital Dubai&rsquo;s journey at the forefront, have shown that integrating artificial intelligence and data driven technologies play significant role in advancing sustainability. These technologies offer innovative solutions and services that reduce emissions and improve the quality of life.</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<p dir="RTL">&nbsp;</p>

<p>In alignment with its global mission to foster a sustainable future, Digital Dubai signed the contribution agreement for Dubai&rsquo;s joining The SDG Cities Global Initiative, under the umbrella of The United Nations Human Settlements Program. Digital Dubai oversees Dubai&#39;s integration into this initiative and reinforcing the emirate&rsquo;s position in advancing the global efforts and shaping a comprehensive international approach that benefits societies worldwide.</p>

<p>Dubai&#39;s access to the SDG Cities Global Initiative was achieved with the active involvement of <span dir="RTL">13 </span>local government entities, demonstrating their commitment to the United Nations&rsquo; 2030 Sustainable Development Goals. The entities emphasized their dedication to adopting the best global practices and developing innovative policies that contribute to improving the quality of life while preserving natural and environmental resources.</p>

<p>H.E Hamad Obaid Al Mansoori, Director General of Digital Dubai, emphasized Digital Dubai&rsquo;s dedication to advancing sustainability across all sectors, highlighting its strategic role in promoting the digital lifestyle, leveraging the latest technologies to benefit the community, and delivering an urban experience that serves as an inspiration to cities worldwide.</p>

<p>H.E said: &ldquo;Sustainability has always been an integral component of our strategies and programs reflecting the vision and directives of our wise leadership to shape a brighter future. We are proud that Dubai is one of the first cities in the region to join The SDG Cities Global Initiative, in collaboration with the United Nations Human Settlements Program. This milestone underscores Dubai&#39;s ongoing commitment to foster a sustainable and prosperous future for all its residents&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Digitization and modern technologies play vital roles in promoting the culture of sustainability and ensuring adherence to global standards. This initiative is not just a step towards achieving sustainable goals, it is a key component of a broader vision aiming at enhancing Dubai&rsquo;s position as one of the most sustainable and innovative cities in the world&rdquo;. H.E added</p>

<p>On his behalf, Younus Al Nasser, Chief Executive, Dubai Data &amp; Statistics Establishment &ndash; Digital Dubai,&nbsp;said: &ldquo;Sustainability is a fundamental pillar in Digital Dubai&rsquo;s mission and its forward-looking strategy which is reflected in the use of digital technologies and data to advance sustainable development goals establishing Dubai as a global model for future cities. Global experiences, with Digital Dubai&rsquo;s journey at the forefront, have shown that integrating artificial intelligence and data-driven technologies plays a significant role in advancing sustainability. These technologies offer innovative solutions and services that reduce emissions and improve the quality of life&rdquo;.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Through this productive collaboration that comes in the Year of Sustainability, we aim to make significant strides in urban, economic, environmental, social, and cultural sustainability. The urban monitoring framework we have developed will allow us to accurately assess the emirate&rsquo;s performance, ensuring that Dubai continues to lead globally in driving positive change.&rdquo;</p>

<p dir="RTL" style="text-align: left;"><strong><span dir="LTR">Dubai: </span></strong><strong><span dir="LTR">Leading the Way in Sustainability for a Better Future</span></strong></p>

<p>This accession reflects Dubai&rsquo;s keenness to fostering a culture of sustainability across all sectors. It reflects alignment with the future vision of sustainability and strong commitment to the initiative&rsquo;s goals, which include seven key areas: that enhancing the quality of life through existing innovative projects and improving infrastructure, and providing better services to the community</p>

<p>The second clause focuses on enhancing environmental sustainability through effective plans aimed at preserving natural resources and reducing carbon emissions, thereby advancing Dubai&rsquo;s position as an environmentally friendly city. The third clause emphasizes stimulating the green economy by supporting sustainable economic initiatives, fostering entrepreneurship and promoting innovation in green sectors. This approach contributes to creating new job opportunities and strengthening the local economy. The fourth clause focuses on enhancing collaboration and partnerships among government, private and civil society organization to achieve sustainable development goals. The fifth clause involves developing an integrated urban monitoring framework assess urban performance. This framework will enable the monitoring and measurement of the emirate&rsquo;s progress in urban sustainability through the collection and analysis of data using specific performance indicators. The sixth clause pertains to sustainable development goals certificates for cities, as Dubai aims to achieve high levels of compliance with global sustainability standards, by perusing these certificates. These certificates will reflect Dubai&#39;s commitment to excellence in the areas of environmental, economic, social, cultural and governance sustainability, further enhancing its position as an inclusive, safe, resilient and sustainable city. The seventh and final clause involves producing the Voluntary Local Reviews (VLR) report, reinforcing Dubai&rsquo;s commitment to transparency and accountability in achieving the sustainable development goals. This report will allow Dubai to showcase its progress, share achievements and challenges with the international community, and foster greater cooperation and knowledge exchange.</p>

<p><strong>Existing strategic plans in Dubai:</strong></p>

<p>To achieve the objectives of this accession, Dubai is implementing a set of plans and strategies, including the Dubai Urban Plan 2040, which outlines a comprehensive approach to sustainable urban development, emphasizing a human-centered focus aimed at improving the quality of life and boosting the emirate&rsquo;s global competitiveness. Moreover, The Dubai Economic and Social Agenda 33 aims to drive comprehensive economic and social development by improving the quality of life in Dubai and promoting sustainability. This agenda aligns with the global sustainable development goals.</p>

<p>Joining this initiative is part of a broad future vision encompassing multiple facets. In the same context, Digital Dubai, in collaboration with the International Telecommunication Union and the United Nations International Computing Center, launched the &ldquo;Discovering the CityVerse&rdquo; initiative, which is a joint global initiative that aims to leverage the role of innovation and virtual technologies in realizing the United Nations&rsquo; sustainable development goals.</p>

<p>The main pillars of this initiative include networking virtual cities, with several related initiatives such as the Virtual Cities Challenge. This challenge fosters innovation by addressing the obstacles associated with virtual city applications, all with the aim of advancing sustainable development goals.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 12:49:49 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734644.1729500576!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734644.1729500576!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734644.1729500576!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734643.1729500560!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Dubai joins the SDG Cities Global Initiative]]></media:title>

							<media:description><![CDATA[Launched Under the Umbrella of The United Nations Human Settlements Program]]></media:description>
						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sustainability</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Climate</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[16-Year-Old Leads Recycling Initiative for Environmental Sustainability]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sustainability/16-year-old-leads-recycling-initiative-for-environmental-sustainability-2024-10-21-1.734626</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sustainability/16-year-old-leads-recycling-initiative-for-environmental-sustainability-2024-10-21-1.734626</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Tahani Siraj, a 16-year-old Grade 11 student, is making a significant impact through her passion for recycling and environmental activism. What started as a personal recycling program at home, focusing on plastic bottles and cans, has expanded to include collecting recyclables from her neighborhood and local parks.</p>

<p>Tahani credits her school for the success of her initiative, expressing heartfelt gratitude to her principal and supervisor at Gems Millennium School Sharjah for their unwavering support. &quot;Their encouragement, along with the school circular they issued, has motivated me to continue making a positive environmental impact,&quot; she remarked. &quot;I feel fortunate to be part of a school that values social activities as much as academics,&quot; she added.</p>

<p>Her commitment to recycling highlights the broader environmental crisis facing the world today. Plastic waste accelerates climate change, threatens ecosystems, and endangers both wildlife and human health. Tahani emphasizes the need for immediate action, advocating for recycling and reducing plastic use to secure a sustainable future.</p>

<p>Inspired by the UAE&#39;s environmental efforts, she praised the country&#39;s eco-friendly initiatives, including waste collection apps and sustainable practices showcased during Expo 2020. Reflecting on her inspiration, Sheikh Zayed, Tahani stated, &quot;We cherish our environment because it is an integral part of our country, our history, and our heritage.&quot;</p>

<p>Tahani delivered the plastic bottles she collected to Ecyclex International Recycling, a company founded in 2012 with the mission of maximizing reuse and recycling. Looking ahead, she is determined to build on her efforts. &quot;I am committed to continuing this project every year, ensuring that my efforts to promote recycling and sustainability grow stronger with time,&quot; she said, adding that small acts, when multiplied by millions, can change the world.</p>

<p>Tahani&rsquo;s initiative serves as an inspiring example of how individual actions can contribute to environmental preservation and make a lasting impact.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 06:33:49 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734629.1729477991!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734629.1729477991!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
							<media:group>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734629.1729477991!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734628.1729477976!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
																	<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734627.1729477949!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
													</media:content>
									</media:group>
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[16-Year-Old Leads Recycling Initiative for Environmental Sustainability]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sustainability</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Climate</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Mariam Almheiri leads UAE delegation at Hamburg Sustainability Conference]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sustainability/mariam-almheiri-leads-uae-delegation-at-hamburg-sustainability-conference-2024-10-14-1.734451</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sustainability/mariam-almheiri-leads-uae-delegation-at-hamburg-sustainability-conference-2024-10-14-1.734451</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>On behalf of President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Mariam Almheiri, Head of the International Affairs Office at the Presidential Court, led the United Arab Emirates&rsquo; delegation to the Hamburg Sustainability Conference (HSC). The HSC was inaugurated by Germany&rsquo;s Federal Chancellor, Olaf Scholz.</p>

<p>Almheiri&#39;s participation, with representatives from the Ministry of Climate Change and Environment (MoCCAE) and the Ministry of Foreign Affairs (MoFA), underscores the UAE&#39;s commitment to global collaboration on pressing sustainability, energy and humanitarian challenges.</p>

<p>Almheiri said, &ldquo;From policymakers to CEOs, scientists to civil society leaders, the Hamburg Sustainability Conference brings together the diverse voices and perspectives needed to drive systemic change and achieve the SDGs.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The ethos behind HSC reflects the outlook of the UAE itself ‒ it isn&#39;t just about identifying problems; it&#39;s about showcasing solutions. It&#39;s about sharing innovative ideas, scaling up successful initiatives and inspiring bold action, all of which were key features behind the UAE&rsquo;s approach at COP28 last year, and the milestone breakthroughs made, not least the UAE Consensus itself.&rdquo;</p>

<p>She continued, &ldquo;Meaningful dialogue is at the heart of progress, and the UAE delegation is focused on how we can foster the open and constructive conversations that are essential for forging a path towards a more sustainable and equitable future.&rdquo;</p>

<p>In addition to her attendance at the High-Level Panel Discussion, Mariam Almheiri held a series of strategic side meetings with key German officials in her capacity as Envoy of the Minister of Foreign Affairs to Germany, including Dr. Peter Tschentscher, President of the Senate and First Mayor of the Free and Hanseatic City of Hamburg; Svenja Schulze, Federal Minister for Economic Co-operation and Development; and Niels Annen, Parliamentary State Secretary to the Federal Ministry for Economic Co-operation and Development (BMZ) and Member of the Bundestag (SPD).</p>

<p>During her meetings, Almheiri emphasised the strength of the UAE&rsquo;s relations with Germany, stating, &ldquo;The UAE deeply values its partnership with Germany. Our collaboration, built on mutual respect and shared objectives, is a driving force for positive change &ndash; from advancing sustainable development and addressing climate change to fostering peace and stability in the region and beyond.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The discussions with key German officials centred around COP28 legacy, the UAE Consensus and building upon the successes of COP28 and advancing the implementation of the UAE Consensus;<br />
Talks also focused on International Co-operation and Mangrove Conservation: Assessing the success and progress of the UAE and Germany&rsquo;s Green Coast Initiative, aimed at protecting and restoring mangrove trees in Africa; and<br />
They also examined Hamburg&#39;s progress in developing a robust hydrogen market and identifying potential areas for knowledge exchange and collaboration.</p>

<p>Almheiri&#39;s participation at the HSC highlights the UAE&#39;s proactive role in fostering international dialogue and co-operation on critical global issues.</p>

<p>On Day 2 of the Conference, she joined influential German business leaders, including representatives from Bayer, Airbus and Nordic Investment Bank, for a Business Luncheon, exploring greater economic, investment and business integration between the UAE and the German private sector.</p>

<p>The two-day conference was opened by Germany&rsquo;s Federal Chancellor, Olaf Scholz, and Hamburg&#39;s First Mayor, Dr. Peter Tschentscher, as well as the Administrator of the United Nations Development Programme (UNDP), Achim Steiner.</p>

<p>Speaking to delegates, Germany&rsquo;s Development Minister, Svenja Schulze, said, &ldquo;The principle of international co-operation is under enormous pressure worldwide.&rdquo;</p>

<p>She stressed the need for greater collaboration, stating, &ldquo;The major challenges of our time cannot be solved in a national shell but only through international co-operation. Togetherness is better for all than division.&rdquo;</p>

<p>This sentiment was echoed by First Mayor of Hamburg, Peter Tschentscher, who emphasised the geographic importance of Hamburg in driving greater co-operation, stating that &ldquo;with Germany&#39;s largest seaport and around 100 consulates, we have excellent connections to all continents&rdquo;.</p>

<p>The 2024 Hamburg Sustainability Conference is the inaugural conference hosted in the German city of Hamburg. The Conference brought together around 1600 participants from 102 countries, including high-ranking state and government representatives, to discuss how to accelerate action and remove barriers to achieving the UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).</p>

<p>With a focus on transforming challenges into opportunities, the event consisted of three Forums ‒ Reshaping International Financial Architecture, Unleashing Investments for SDGs and Leveraging Transformation &ndash; as well as five Hubs with SDG-based topics that change annually.</p>

<p>The HSC 2024 Hubs were: Resilient Food Systems, Responsible AI &amp; Digitalisation, Green Energy &amp; Net Zero, Empowering Societies and Future Cities.</p>

<p>The annual conference is a joint initiative of the German Federal Ministry for Economic Co-operation and Development (BMZ), the United Nations Development Programme (UNDP), the Michael Otto Foundation and the Free and Hanseatic City of Hamburg.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 12:55:38 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734452.1728896106!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734452.1728896106!/image/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Mariam Almheiri leads UAE delegation at Hamburg Sustainability Conference]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sustainability</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Climate</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Zayed Sustainability Prize announces 2025 finalists pioneering global solutions]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sustainability/zayed-sustainability-prize-announces-2025-finalists-pioneering-global-solutions-2024-10-09-1.734356</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sustainability/zayed-sustainability-prize-announces-2025-finalists-pioneering-global-solutions-2024-10-09-1.734356</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The Zayed Sustainability Prize, the UAE&#39;s pioneering award for innovative solutions to global challenges, has announced this year&#39;s finalists following deliberation by its esteemed Jury.</p>

<p>The winners will be announced at the Zayed Sustainability Prize Awards Ceremony on 14th January 2025 as part of Abu Dhabi Sustainability Week.</p>

<p>The Zayed Sustainability Prize&#39;s Jury elected the 33 finalists from 5,980 entries received across six categories: Health, Food, Energy, Water, Climate Action and Global High Schools &ndash; a 15% increase in submissions over last year.</p>

<p>Dr. Sultan Ahmed Al Jaber, Minister of Industry and Advanced Technology, COP28 President and Director-General of the Zayed Sustainability Prize, highlighted that the finalists demonstrate exceptional innovation and impact.</p>

<p>&quot;The Zayed Sustainability Prize continues to honour the enduring legacy of Sheikh Zayed, whose visionary leadership in sustainability and humanitarianism guides the UAE&#39;s mission to uplift livelihoods worldwide by fostering development in some of the most vulnerable regions.</p>

<p>This cycle, we received an unprecedented number of submissions, with notable participation from the Global South and youth. In fact, this year&#39;s submissions reflect the three megatrends shaping our future, namely the rise of the Global South, the pace of the energy transition and the growth of AI.</p>

<p>These changemakers are tackling urgent environmental challenges head-on, while simultaneously advancing economic progress through innovative solutions. By leveraging emerging technologies, such as AI, carbon capture and removal, tidal energy, precision agriculture, biomimicry, and climate analytics, they are addressing the needs of the moment while inspiring the next generation to innovate and drive sustainability in impactful ways.&quot;</p>

<p>Through the Prize&#39;s 117 winners to date, 11.35 million people have gained access to safe drinking water, 54 million homes have gained access to reliable energy, 3.6 million people have gained access to more nutritious food, and over 744,600 people have gained access to affordable healthcare.</p>

<p>&Oacute;lafur Ragnar Gr&iacute;msson, Chair of the Prize Jury, said, &quot;This year&#39;s Prize finalists showcase the remarkable steps being taken around the world to address urgent needs with creativity and determination &ndash; offering a vision of a more sustainable future. From enhancing biodiversity and food security through innovative technology to providing critical energy and healthcare solutions for underserved populations, these pioneers are reshaping our world.&quot;</p>

<p>This year&#39;s Health finalists focused on delivering quality healthcare services to underserved and remote communities.</p>

<p>The Health finalists are:</p>

<p>&bull; Periwinkle Technologies, an SME from India that deploys a portable, AI enabled cervical cancer screening device that provides results in 30 seconds.</p>

<p>&bull; Rology, an SME from Egypt that has created a 24/7 AI-assisted teleradiology platform that integrates with hospital systems to ensure prompt and accurate diagnoses.</p>

<p>&bull; Telemedan, an SME from Chad that deploys solar powered, internet-connected medical kiosks that provide affordable healthcare to people in remote communities.</p>

<p>Food finalists focused on empowering small-scale producers, promoting sustainable food preservation, and transforming arid land into productive farms.</p>

<p>The Food finalists are:</p>

<p>&bull; ABALOBI, an NPO from South Africa that created a mobile app and marketplace that empowers small-scale fishers to log catches and sell directly to consumers.</p>

<p>&bull; Nafarm Foods, an SME from Nigeria that develops scalable hybrid solar food dryers that preserve food and reduce CO2 emissions.</p>

<p>&bull; Xinjiang Shawan Oasis Sustainable Development Institute, an NPO from China that specialises in solar powered smart greenhouses that transform desert land into farms.</p>

<p>Energy finalists are delivering solutions that improve energy efficiency and enhance access to clean energy and transportation.</p>

<p>The Energy finalists are:</p>

<p>&bull; D-Olivette Global Enterprise, an SME from Nigeria that develops an IoT and AI assisted smart waste management solution that improves collection efficiency by 40%.</p>

<p>&bull; Palki Motors Limited, an SME from Bangladesh that manufactures local, low-cost electric cars with solar powered battery swap stations.</p>

<p>&bull; Turbulent, an SME from Belgium that develops cost-effective, eco-friendly vortex hydropower turbines with 60% efficiency.</p>

<p>Water finalists are implementing solutions that optimise water use and improve access to clean drinking water.</p>

<p>The Water finalists are:</p>

<p>&bull; Elman Teknoloji Ltd, an SME from T&uuml;rkiye that employs sensors to optimise water use in irrigation and agriculture, cutting labour costs by 80%.</p>

<p>&bull; High Atlas Foundation, an NPO from Morocco that provides a solar powered water pumping system to optimise groundwater extraction.</p>

<p>&bull; SkyJuice Foundation Inc., an NPO from Australia that develops low-cost, easy to deploy water filters that provide clean drinking water without the need for chemicals, pumps, or external energy sources.</p>

<p>Climate Action finalists focused on advancing carbon capture, ecosystem restoration, and building climate resilience.</p>

<p>The Climate Action finalists are:</p>

<p>&bull; Distant Imagery, an SME from the UAE that specialises in the development of AI-powered drones for environmental monitoring, seed planting and habitat restoration.</p>

<p>&bull; Hyera Inc., an SME from the USA that has developed a carbon capture process for removing pollutants from water by converting agricultural and forest waste into activated carbon.</p>

<p>&bull; OpenMap Development Tanzania, an NPO from Tanzania that deploys a flood management solution that combines indigenous knowledge with geospatial data.</p>

<p>The Global High Schools&#39; finalists presented project-based, student-led sustainability solutions, with finalists divided into six regions. The regional finalists include:</p>

<p>The Americas: Centro de Estudios Tecnol&oacute;gicos del Mar 07, Mexico; Instituci&oacute;n Educativa San Nicol&aacute;s de Tolentino, Colombia; and Mulgrave School, Canada.</p>

<p>Sub-Saharan Africa: Mpesa Foundation Academy, Kenya; Sakafia Islamic Senior High School, Ghana; and St Kizito High School Namugongo, Uganda.</p>

<p>Middle East &amp; North Africa: Benlahrech Said High School, Algeria; Merryland International School Abu Dhabi, UAE; and Obour STEM School, Egypt.</p>

<p>Europe &amp; Central Asia: Baku Modern Educational Complex, Azerbaijan; Gebze Bah&ccedil;eehr Science &amp; Technology High School, T&uuml;rkiye; and Presidential School in Tashkent, Uzbekistan.</p>

<p>South Asia: Faafu Atoll Education Centre, Maldives; Girls Higher Secondary School Khaplu, Pakistan; and Janamaitri Multiple Campus, Nepal.</p>

<p>East Asia &amp; the Pacific: Beijing World Youth Academy, China; Te Pā o Rākaihautū, New Zealand; and Votualevu College, Fiji.</p>

<p>In the Health, Food, Energy, Water and Climate Action categories, each winner receives US$1 million. Each of the six winning Global High Schools receives up to US$150,000.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Wed, 9 Oct 2024 11:58:12 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734357.1728460634!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.734357.1728460634!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Zayed Sustainability Prize announces 2025 finalists pioneering global solutions]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sustainability</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Climate</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[DP WORLD SETS NEW AMBITIOUS CARBON REDUCTION TARGET AS IT SECURES SBTI VALIDATION]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/business/corporate/dp-world-sets-new-ambitious-carbon-reduction-target-as-it-secures-sbti-validation-2024-08-27-1.733807</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/business/corporate/dp-world-sets-new-ambitious-carbon-reduction-target-as-it-secures-sbti-validation-2024-08-27-1.733807</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong><em>Validation marks vote of confidence in DP World&rsquo;s plans to transform supply chains with a new and ambitious target to deliver 42% Scope 1 and 2 GHG emissions reduction by 2030 </em></strong></li>
	<li><strong><em>DP World is the first logistics company in the Middle East to achieve validation&nbsp; </em></strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>DP World has secured validation from the <a name="_Hlk167803445">Science Based Targets initiative (SBTi)</a> for its ambitious commitment to reduce its carbon footprint.</p>

<p>The global trade and logistics firm commits to reduce scope 1 greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions 42% by 2030 from a 2022 base year*. DP World also commits to reduce scope 2 GHG emissions 62.2%, and reduce absolute scope 3 GHG emissions 28% within the same timeframe.</p>

<p>The SBTi is a world leading authority in advancing private sector progress to reduce GHG emissions, helping prevent the impacts of climate change. Its validation underscores the strength of DP World&rsquo;s &#39;Our World, Our Future&#39; sustainability strategy, recognising its progress-to-date and ambitious plans, which focus on slashing its own emissions and empowering its customers to meet their own Scope 3 reduction targets.</p>

<p><strong>Sultan Ahmed bin Sulayem, Group Chairman and CEO, DP World</strong> said: &quot;DP World is committed to leading the supply chain industry towards a more sustainable and efficient future, and ultimately achieving net zero emissions by 2050. The SBTi&rsquo;s validation confirms the strength and ambition of our plans as we remain committed to playing a pivotal role in uniting our industry for a better tomorrow.&quot;</p>

<p>DP World has made notable progress on its sustainability strategy in recent years, announcing a 13% reduction in emissions since the 2022 base year. Its new 42% reduction target and increased commitments on Scope 3 reductions build on the success to date.</p>

<p><strong>Piotr Konopka, Group Vice President at DP World, Global Decarbonisation &amp; Energy</strong>, said: &ldquo;We are delighted to have achieved SBTi validation and we will continue to drive progress in a range of areas, including equipment electrification, renewable energy, efficiency, and low carbon fuels. Furthermore, we look forward to driving increased collaboration through industry-wide initiatives such as green trade corridors and portside electrification as seen with our Zero Emissions Port Alliance.&rdquo; &nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>DP World&rsquo;s ambitious decarbonisation plans and achievements include, but are not limited to, the following:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li><a href="https://www.dpworld.com/news/releases/apm-terminals-and-dp-world-launch-zero-emission-port-alliance-at-cop28/">The Zero Emission Port Alliance (ZEPA),</a> an industry-wide strategic coalition led by DP World in partnership with APM Terminals to accelerate progress towards zero emissions for container handling equipment (CHE) in ports.</li>
	<li>Entered a <a href="https://www.dpworld.com/news/releases/dp-world-joins-forces-with-maersk-mc-kinney-moller-center-for-zero-carbon-shipping--to-help-decarbonize-the-maritime-industry/">strategic partnership with M&aelig;rsk Mc-Kinney M&oslash;ller Center for Zero Carbon Shipping</a> (the Center) in 2022, whereby DP World committed to long-term strategic collaboration and contribution to the development of zero carbon technologies and solutions for the maritime industry.</li>
	<li><a href="https://www.dpworld.com/news/releases/dp-world-joins-first-movers-coalition-to-decarbonise-shipping/">DP World&rsquo;s membership of the World Economic Forum and the US Government-led First Movers Coalition</a>, which aims to address the decarbonisation challenges of seven hard-to-abate sectors, including shipping.</li>
	<li>DP World&rsquo;s work to advance fuel efficiency and alternative fuel adoption, as well as the introduction of new, more efficient vessels across its network, including an agreement for methanol-capable container feeder vessels in Europe by 2026, and the introduction of hybrid-electric Ro-Pax ferries in the UK.</li>
	<li>DP World has won a series of sustainability awards for its work, including the EKOenergy ecological label for the installation of the first photovoltaic plant in the deep-water port of Posorja, and two <a href="https://www.dpworld.com/news/releases/dp-world-wins-two-new-sustainability-awards/">2024 SEAL Awards</a> for the use of waste for energy and its BOXBAY offer.</li>
	<li>As of 2023, 60% of DP World&rsquo;s electricity consumption comes from renewable sources, with an aim to increase this to 70% by 2030 and 100% by 2040.</li>
</ul>

<p>To find out more about DP World&rsquo;s &#39;Our World, Our Future&#39; sustainability strategy please visit <a href="http://www.dpworld.com/sustainability">www.dpworld.com/sustainability</a></p>

<p>* The target boundary includes land-related emissions and removals from bioenergy feedstocks.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 10:28:27 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733808.1724739996!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733808.1724739996!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[DP WORLD SETS NEW AMBITIOUS CARBON REDUCTION TARGET AS IT SECURES SBTI VALIDATION]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Business</category>
										
																			
											<category>Corporate</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Business/Corporate</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE Meteorology Centre Reports on July Climate Summary]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/uae-meteorology-centre-reports-on-july-climate-summary-2024-07-02-1.733356</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/uae-meteorology-centre-reports-on-july-climate-summary-2024-07-02-1.733356</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<h3>&nbsp;</h3>

<p>The UAE Meteorology Centre has released its comprehensive summary of the July climate, highlighting significant weather patterns and climatic statistics across the country. July, known for its summer heat, experiences increased temperatures influenced by the extension of thermal lows, notably the Indian monsoon low pressure system.</p>

<p><strong>Weather Patterns:</strong></p>

<p>Throughout July, the eastern mountains and southern regions of the UAE were characterized by cloud cover, attributed to mountainous terrain and high temperatures. Afternoon rains were observed in interior areas, driven by these developing clouds. Additionally, the Intertropical Convergence Zone (ITCZ) impacted parts of the country, particularly in the latter half of the month, leading to convective rainy clouds at times.</p>

<p><strong>Wind Circulations:</strong></p>

<p>The month saw significant variability in wind patterns. Southeasterly winds predominated during the night and morning periods, shifting to northerly winds during the day. Fresh southerly winds occasionally caused blowing dust in the mornings, while fresh northwesterly winds contributed to sporadic blowing and suspended dust.</p>

<p><strong>Humidity and Fog:</strong></p>

<p>Relative humidity levels varied, with increases during early morning hours over certain areas, occasionally resulting in mist or fog formation. July 2023 witnessed the highest frequency of fog occurrences, with 11 instances of fog and 5 misty days reported.</p>

<p><strong>Climatic Statistics:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>
	<p><strong>Air Temperature:</strong></p>

	<ul>
		<li>Mean air temperature ranged between 34.6&deg;C and 37.2&deg;C.</li>
		<li>Mean maximum air temperature ranged from 39.7&deg;C to 43.8&deg;C.</li>
		<li>Mean minimum air temperature varied between 29.1&deg;C and 31.4&deg;C.</li>
		<li>The highest maximum temperature recorded was 51.8&deg;C at Mezaira in 2017, while the lowest minimum temperature dropped to 16.9&deg;C at Jais Mountain in 2022.</li>
	</ul>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><strong>Wind:</strong></p>

	<ul>
		<li>Mean wind speed averaged 13 km/h.</li>
		<li>The highest sustained winds reached 105 km/h at Khatam Al Shaklah in 2016.</li>
		<li>The highest wind gust recorded was 130 km/h at Al Ain Airport in 2022.</li>
	</ul>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><strong>Relative Humidity:</strong></p>

	<ul>
		<li>Mean relative humidity stood at 46%.</li>
		<li>Mean maximum relative humidity fluctuated between 64% and 81%.</li>
		<li>Mean minimum relative humidity ranged from 19% to 36%.</li>
	</ul>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><strong>Rainfall:</strong></p>

	<ul>
		<li>The highest recorded rainfall for July was 234.9 mm at the port of Fujairah in 2022.</li>
	</ul>
	</li>
</ul>

<p>The UAE Meteorology Centre continues to monitor and report on weather patterns and climate trends, providing crucial information for residents and stakeholders across the country.</p>

<p>For more details and updates, please visit <a href="#" rel="noreferrer">UAE Meteorology Centre&#39;s website</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Tue, 2 Jul 2024 15:32:40 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733357.1719920064!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733357.1719920064!/image/image.png_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.png" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE Meteorology Centre Reports on July Climate Summary]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UAE takes second place globally in new FDI projects at 1,323 in 2023]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/uae-takes-second-place-globally-in-new-fdi-projects-at-1-323-in-2023-2024-06-20-1.733284</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/uae-takes-second-place-globally-in-new-fdi-projects-at-1-323-in-2023-2024-06-20-1.733284</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>The UAE took the second place after the United States in greenfield FDI project announcements in 2023 at 1,323, an increase of 33 percent compared with 2022, according to the World Investment Report 2024, published today by the UN Trade and Development (UNCTAD).</p>

<p><br />
In terms of FDI inflows in 2023, the UAE attracted US$ 30.688 billion compared to US$ 22.737 billion in 2022, a y-o-y growth of 35 percent.</p>

<p>The UNCTAD report showed that FDI outflows stood at US$ 22.328 billion compared to US$ 24.833 billion in 2022.</p>

<p><br />
FDI outflow stock grew to US$ 262.208 billion in 2023 from US$ 239.880 billion in 2022.</p>

<p><br />
The United Arab Emirates gained two places in the ranking of top destinations for greenfield projects, after entering the top five in 2022.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 14:28:00 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733285.1719052066!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733285.1719052066!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[UAE takes second place globally in new FDI projects at 1,323 in 2023]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Eid Al Adha Weather Forecast in the UAE (June 15 - June 18, 2024)]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/eid-al-adha-weather-forecast-in-the-uae-june-15-june-18-2024-2024-06-14-1.733251</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/eid-al-adha-weather-forecast-in-the-uae-june-15-june-18-2024-2024-06-14-1.733251</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>As Eid Al Adha approaches, the UAE National Metrology Centre has released the weather forecast for the holiday period, spanning from Saturday, June 15 to Tuesday, June 18, 2024.</p>

<p><strong>General Weather Conditions:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Daytime:</strong> The weather is expected to be hot in general, with dusty and partly cloudy conditions in some areas.</li>
	<li><strong>Night and Early Morning:</strong> Temperatures will range from hot to moderate.</li>
	<li><strong>Eastern Coast:</strong> Low clouds are predicted, with a chance of convective clouds forming by the afternoon. These clouds may bring rainfall, particularly in the Eastern and Southern areas, especially on Sunday and Monday.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Humidity:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Relative Humidity:</strong> An increase in relative humidity is anticipated during the late night and early morning hours over some coastal areas.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Winds:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Direction and Speed:</strong> Winds will be light to moderate, shifting from Southeasterly to Northeasterly, and becoming Northwesterly in general. They will freshen at times during the daytime and with clouds, potentially causing blowing dust.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Sea Conditions:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Arabian Gulf and Oman Sea:</strong> The sea is expected to be light to moderate.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Temperature Ranges:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Maximum Temperatures:</strong>

	<ul>
		<li>Coasts and islands: 39&deg;C - 46&deg;C</li>
		<li>Internal areas: 44&deg;C - 49&deg;C</li>
		<li>Mountainous areas: 28&deg;C - 35&deg;C</li>
	</ul>
	</li>
	<li><strong>Minimum Temperatures:</strong>
	<ul>
		<li>Coasts and islands: 30&deg;C - 34&deg;C</li>
		<li>Internal areas: 27&deg;C - 33&deg;C</li>
		<li>Mountainous areas: 25&deg;C - 31&deg;C</li>
	</ul>
	</li>
</ul>

<p>Residents and visitors are advised to stay hydrated and take necessary precautions to stay cool during the hot daytime conditions. Enjoy a safe and pleasant Eid Al Adha!</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 13:07:57 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733252.1718356003!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733252.1718356003!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Eid Al Adha Weather Forecast in the UAE (June 15 - June 18, 2024)]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Emirates powers flights with sustainable aviation fuel from Singapore]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/business/travel/emirates-powers-flights-with-sustainable-aviation-fuel-from-singapore-2024-06-13-1.733218</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/business/travel/emirates-powers-flights-with-sustainable-aviation-fuel-from-singapore-2024-06-13-1.733218</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>Emirates has begun using Sustainable Aviation Fuel (SAF) as part of its fuel agreement with Neste on flights departing from Singapore Changi Airport, marking its inaugural SAF investment in Asia.</p>

<p>According to Emirates&#39; statement, approximately 3.3 million litres of blended SAF have been integrated into the fuelling system of Changi airport over the last few weeks.</p>

<p>Emirates is tracking the delivery of SAF into the fuelling systems, accounting for and assigning its environmental benefits through widely used and accepted industry methodologies.</p>

<p>Earlier this year, the airline closely collaborated with Neste to supply 2.6 million litres of neat SAF to Amsterdam Schiphol airport&#39;s fuelling systems.</p>

<p>The SAF being provided by Neste is produced from sustainably sourced and 100% renewable waste as well as residue raw materials, including used cooking oil and animal fat waste.</p>

<p>SAF used as part of this agreement can be safely used in existing Emirates aircraft and airport fuelling infrastructure, and in neat form reduces lifecycle carbon emissions (CO2) by up to 80% compared to using conventional jet fuel.</p>

<p>Adel Al Redha, Deputy President and Chief Operations Officer of Emirates, said, &quot;Emirates&#39; investment into Neste-produced SAF in Singapore marks a first step forward in our SAF adoption in Asia, a region that is primed to become a leading supplier of SAF, which continues to be in short supply.</p>

<p>While the activation of this agreement marks a milestone in our SAF journey in a new region, there&#39;s still a lot of work to do. And as we procure SAF for the short term, we&#39;ve got our sights set on longer-term agreements to help scale up a steady supply of SAF for our operations.&quot;</p>

<p>Alexander Kueper, Vice President of Renewable Aviation Business at Neste, said, &quot;This makes Emirates the first international visiting carrier using SAF at the airport produced at our Singapore refinery and supplied into the airport via our integrated supply chain.&quot;</p>

<p>In 2023, Emirates was also the first airline in the world to operate two landmark demonstration flights from Dubai on the Boeing 777 and A380 with 100% SAF in one engine in partnership with Neste and other committed partners, supporting future certification where 100% drop in SAF is approved for commercial airline operations.</p>

<p>Currently, SAF is approved for use in all aircraft, but only in blends of up to 50% with conventional jet fuel.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 15:16:08 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733219.1718277326!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733219.1718277326!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>E247 </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Emirates powers flights with sustainable aviation fuel from Singapore]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Business</category>
										
																			
											<category>Travel</category>
										
																								
										
													
				 									<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/General</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Khaled bin Mohamed bin Zayed approves launch of AgriFood Growth and Water Abundance Cluster]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/khaled-bin-mohamed-bin-zayed-approves-launch-of-agrifood-growth-and-water-abundance-cluster-2024-06-09-1.733106</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/uae/khaled-bin-mohamed-bin-zayed-approves-launch-of-agrifood-growth-and-water-abundance-cluster-2024-06-09-1.733106</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>H.H. Sheikh Khaled bin Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi and Chairman of the Abu Dhabi Executive Council, has approved the launch of the AgriFood Growth and Water Abundance (AGWA) Cluster.</p>

<p>Located in Abu Dhabi, AGWA is an integrated economic cluster poised to play a leading role in global efforts to tackle food shortages and water scarcity.</p>

<p>Led by the Abu Dhabi Department of Economic Development (ADDED) and Abu Dhabi Investment Office (ADIO), AGWA is set to become a global hub for novel food and ingredients, as well as technologies to increase access to and the utilisation of water resources. This innovative cluster is designed to support local suppliers and exporters alike, serving as a platform to maximise commercial opportunities. The cluster aims to help meet increasing global demand, alleviate pressures on agricultural systems, address shifting dietary patterns, capitalise on technological advancements, and support global food security to ensure a reliable and resilient supply chain.</p>

<p>H.H. Sheikh Khaled bin Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan emphasised the pivotal role of the AgriFood Growth and Water Abundance (AGWA) cluster in strengthening the national food and water security ecosystem, adding that by embracing cutting-edge technologies and innovative solutions, the cluster will cultivate sustainable local production and effectively address the increasing international and regional demand for food and water.</p>

<p>His Highness also highlighted that food and water security is a top national priority for the leadership to ensure a resilient agricultural and water production ecosystem, using smart solutions and driving research and innovation projects in modern agricultural technologies to not only diversify the local economy but also propel sustainable development in line with the goals of the National Food Security Strategy 2051 and the UAE Water Security Strategy 2036.</p>

<p>AGWA will support pioneers in the food and water industry to leverage innovations in alternative proteins, algae and reverse osmosis technologies, and also to enhance traditional food and water production and supply.</p>

<p>AGWA taps into a AED77.4 trillion industry with significant potential for economic growth and job creation. By 2045, AGWA is expected to contribute AED90 billion in incremental GDP to Abu Dhabi&rsquo;s economy, create more than 60,000 new jobs, and attract AED128 billion in investments.</p>

<p>Ahmed Jasim Al Zaabi, Chairman of the Abu Dhabi Department of Economic Development (ADDED), said: The launch of AgriFood Growth &amp; Water Abundance cluster (AGWA) is a game changer in our efforts to further diversify the economy, enhance innovation, and achieve objectives of the UAE food security strategy 2051. It enables us to accelerate innovations in advanced technologies to address the pressing needs for sustainable water and food sources both locally and globally&rdquo;.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Abu Dhabi has been exploring sustainable solution to food production challenges since late 1960s. In 1969, the late Sheikh Zayed, the visionary founder of the UAE, established the first network of greenhouses on Saadiyat Island, employing advanced technologies of that era to ensure sustainable food production. Our recent initiatives continue this legacy of long-term vision and commitment to innovation, sustainability, and inclusive socio-economic development&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Al Zaabi adds: &ldquo;Our thriving &ldquo;Falcon Economy&quot; offers vast opportunities for investors to grow and expand, supported by a business-friendly ecosystem, agile policies, robust infrastructure, a strong supply chain, government support and incentives, access to funding, advanced trade facilitation solutions, international markets connectivity, and incentives to boost non-oil economy.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Badr Al-Olama, Director General at the Abu Dhabi Investment Office (ADIO), said: &ldquo;Abu Dhabi&rsquo;s new food and water economic cluster addresses sustainability, critical global challenges, and new investment opportunities. This is the next step in achieving Abu Dhabi&rsquo;s economic diversification strategy by accelerating non-oil sectors.&rdquo;</p>

<p>In most regions worldwide, over 70 per cent of freshwater is utilised for agriculture. By 2050, feeding a global population exceeding nine billion will necessitate a projected 50 per cent increase in agricultural production and a 15 per cent rise in water withdrawals, according to the World Bank.</p>

<p>Abu Dhabi has long recognised the profound challenges posed by global food and water insecurity. AGWA represents the next phase of the emirate&rsquo;s strategy, channelling investment and resources into future-focused economic clusters while simultaneously addressing critical global challenges.</p>

<p>AGWA is the second in a series of economic clusters launched by Abu Dhabi that aim to propel economic growth, diversification and job creation, alongside promoting investment opportunities in future-focused industries. In October 2023, Abu Dhabi launched the Smart and Autonomous Vehicle Industries (SAVI) cluster to position the emirate at the forefront of future mobility solutions across air, land and sea applications.</p>

<p>The launch of AGWA is set to strengthen Abu Dhabi&rsquo;s efforts to enhance the emirate&rsquo;s pioneering role in harnessing advanced innovations and solutions in food and water production and developing traditional agricultural methods. Abu Dhabi is home to 24,000 farms, 50 per cent of which are located in Al Ain City. Abu Dhabi Investment Office signed partnerships with various innovative food and water production companies, specifically focusing on solutions applicable to the desert environment.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 9 Jun 2024 21:42:12 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733107.1717954890!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733107.1717954890!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Khaled bin Mohamed bin Zayed approves launch of AgriFood Growth and Water Abundance Cluster]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>UAE</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/UAE</category>
										
					</item>
			<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Azerbaijan confirmed as host of COP29]]></title>
						
			<link>https://www.emirates247.com/sustainability/azerbaijan-confirmed-as-host-of-cop29-2024-06-09-1.733089</link>
			<guid>https://www.emirates247.com/sustainability/azerbaijan-confirmed-as-host-of-cop29-2024-06-09-1.733089</guid>

			
						    				  	<description><![CDATA[<p>COP29 President-Designate Mukhtar Babayev and UNFCCC Executive Secretary Simon Stiell attended a signing ceremony and exchanged letters, reaffirming Azerbaijan&rsquo;s status as the host country for this year&rsquo;s COP29 UN climate conference.</p>

<p>The exchange of letters followed the COP29 Operating Company&rsquo;s announcement of progress in its preparations to welcome international delegates to the conference in Baku and the Presidency&rsquo;s engagements with parties to ensure that their concerns and priorities are addressed.</p>

<p>During the Bonn Climate Change Conference, the COP29 Presidency held a wide-ranging briefing and feedback session on details and plans for transportation, accommodation, and hospitality for the thousands of visitors expected to participate in this year&rsquo;s COP29 conference, along with logistical aspects related to the venue itself. The COP29 Presidency continued its consultations with observer organisations and country delegates on the logistics for COP29 to ensure that the upcoming climate conference is accessible for all.</p>

<p>Guided by the principles of the conference, sustainability is a priority, together with a focus on encouraging international cooperation and hosting an accessible and inclusive event that will leave a lasting legacy in Azerbaijan and beyond.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;The COP29 Presidency has made significant progress and will be ready to deliver a world-class event. We have applied our experiences hosting many other global events, as well as learnings from past COPs, to our preparations,&rdquo; said COP29 President-Designate Mukhtar Babayev. &ldquo;Hosting COP29 is an opportunity and a responsibility &ndash; and one we do not take lightly. As hosts, we will be transparent, action-oriented, welcoming and inclusive.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Covering comprehensive event planning and operational readiness, Narmin Jarchalova, COO of the COP29 Operating Company said, &ldquo;Our country has a lot to offer as a COP29 host destination thanks to the unique components of natural diversity, a multicultural society, historic heritage and a forward-looking vision. Our experienced and dedicated team organising the conference logistics and services is excited to host COP29 and welcome the world to Azerbaijan this November.&rdquo;</p>

<p>During the presentation, the COP29 Presidency shared information regarding the conference venue and green zone arrangements, working facilities dedicated to supporting a successful conference and other necessary elements for high standard door-to-door guest experience, including but not limited to transportation, accommodation, visas, and catering.</p>

<p>Referencing the principles that underpin the organisation of the conference, the COP29 Presidency highlighted its sustainability considerations. To deliver a commitment to carbon neutrality and the sustainability of the conference, COP29 will regularly monitor and report on emissions directly and indirectly generated by operations throughout the event.</p>

<p>Inclusivity is a top priority across all elements of event preparations. The organisers are focused on promoting a culture of respect and inclusivity. A strong emphasis will be placed on diverse representation in speakers, panels, and workshop facilitators as well as ensuring participation from underrepresented groups. A range of measures address accessibility to the conference venue and facilities.</p>

<p>A specially designed legacy programme has been devised with elements related to building human capital, enhancing infrastructure, and fostering sustainable development. It focuses on capacity building, raising local awareness and reusing logistics and infrastructure items.</p>]]></description>
										<pubDate>Sun, 9 Jun 2024 17:09:20 +0400</pubDate>			
								
								<enclosure url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733090.1717938498!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" length="5000" type="image/jpeg" />
								<media:content url="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.733090.1717938498!/image/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/rectangular_320/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
									</media:content>
						
			
							<dc:creator>WAM </dc:creator>
			
			<media:title><![CDATA[Azerbaijan confirmed as host of COP29]]></media:title>

						
																	
										
																			
											<category>Sustainability</category>
										
																								
										
													
													<category>/7229,22312099265/E247/Climate</category>
										
					</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
