<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/newstand-feed-1.679820?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout]]></id>
	<updated><![CDATA[2025-01-05T19:14:48+04:00]]></updated>
	<title><![CDATA[Latest]]></title>
	<subtitle><![CDATA[]]></subtitle>
	<link rel="self" href="https://www.emirates247.com/newstand-feed-1.679820?ot=ot.AjaxPageLayout" />
			<author>
			<name><![CDATA[]]></name>
		</author>
			<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>

		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/latifa-bint-mohammed-inaugurates-fourth-edition-of-al-marmoom-film-in-the-desert-festival-2025-01-05-1.736061]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Latifa bint Mohammed inaugurates fourth edition of ‘Al Marmoom: Film in The Desert’ festival]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2025-01-05T19:12:41+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2025-01-05T19:14:48+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Organised by Dubai Culture under the theme &lsquo;Where Stories Come to Life,&rsquo; event running until 12 January aims to support creative talent in the local film industry</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Her Highness: The festival celebrates the authenticity of Dubai&rsquo;s identity, its dynamic spirit, and future aspirations, fostering intellectual dialogue</strong></li>
	<li><strong>&ldquo;Cinema has the profound ability to shape generations rooted in values while addressing the aspirations and challenges of societies and preserving the rich history of nations&rdquo;&nbsp;</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Drawing inspiration from the Ghaf tree, the festival also features an array of musical performances, live shows, and heritage displays</strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p><br />
Her Highness Sheikha Latifa bint Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Chairperson of the Dubai Culture and Arts Authority (Dubai Culture), inaugurated the fourth edition of the &lsquo;Al Marmoom: Film in the Desert&rsquo; festival. Organised by Dubai Culture in the Al Marmoom Desert Reserve, the event seeks to advance the local film industry by providing an innovative platform that supports talented creatives, encouraging them to express their visions and showcase their works and productions to a wider audience.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The festival, an initiative under the Dubai Quality of Life Strategy 2033, features screenings of over 80 feature films. Running until 12 January under the theme &lsquo;Where Stories Come to Life,&rsquo; the event will also host interactive workshops, panel discussions, and talks with a distinguished group of directors, artists, and film industry experts.</p>

<p>Her Highness Sheikha Latifa emphasised that Dubai has excelled in attracting leading directors and talents in the film industry thanks to its extensive capabilities, state-of-the-art infrastructure, and unique creative environment that fosters innovation. She highlighted that, through its ambitious projects and initiatives, the emirate continues to enhance its global leadership, solidify its standing as a cultural and artistic capital, and establish itself as a premier destination for cinematic content creation and production.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Cinema is one of the most powerful expressions of human creativity, distinguished by its unique visual language that seamlessly blends technical mastery with artistic purpose. It has the profound ability to shape generations rooted in values while addressing the aspirations and challenges of societies and preserving the rich history and culture of nations,&rdquo; Her Highness said.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>She added: &ldquo;The Al Marmoom: Film in the Desert festival is a remarkable addition to Dubai&rsquo;s artistic and cinematic landscape through its exceptional cultural experiences and high-quality cinematic works, celebrating the authenticity of Dubai&rsquo;s identity, vibrant energy, and ambitious future aspirations.&nbsp;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Reflecting the beauty of our heritage, the essence of our culture, and the depth of our history, the festival&rsquo;s significance lies in its role as a catalyst for intellectual dialogue, a bridge for cultural exchange, and a source of inspiration for emerging talents. It nurtures creativity; encourages filmmakers to explore the latest industry trends, practices, and opportunities, contributing to fostering a new generation capable of advancing this vital sector, which stands as a cornerstone of Dubai&rsquo;s thriving creative economy.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>Immersive Experience Zone</strong></p>

<p>Sheikha Latifa took an elaborate tour of the festival, exploring, among other highlights, an Immersive Experience Zone. The zone showcased digital artworks created using Artificial Intelligence, in addition to inspiring murals, and installations featuring the work of artists Ghaleb Hawila, Abdullah Lutfi, and Mikhail Antykov.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Her Highness also visited the festival&rsquo;s dedicated pavilions for workshops, seminars, and family-friendly activities and the &lsquo;VIP Barzah&rsquo; area, where she engaged with artists participating in the event, commending their creativity and the diversity of their artistic works. She praised the powerful messages and concepts conveyed through their creations, which reflect a wide array of unique perspectives and artistic visions.</p>

<p>Audiences at the Al Marmoom: Film in the Desert festival will be able to enjoy a curated selection of films chosen from amongst 240 submissions, including notable entries competing for the Al Marmoom Short-Film Competition awards across four categories: documentaries, animation, live-action, and films made using Artificial Intelligence.</p>

<p>The festival&rsquo;s programme includes more than 30 workshops led by renowned creatives and cinema experts, including four workshops organised by the College of Arts and Creative Enterprises at Zayed University. It also offers a diverse array of seminars, panel discussions, and activities tailored to inspire young talents and encourage them to embark on professional careers across the cinema and the arts sectors.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Array of activities</strong></p>

<p>Inspired by the iconic Ghaf tree, the festival serves as a platform to strengthen intercultural engagement and raise environmental awareness by encouraging visitors to explore the Al Marmoom Desert, a treasured nature reserve and one of Dubai&rsquo;s key cultural landmarks. The event features a wide array of activities, including performing arts, musical and heritage shows, and interactive experiences such as &lsquo;Create Your Own AI Movie.&rsquo; Visitors can also visit the planetarium for a stargazing session, or take in the reserve&rsquo;s stunning landscapes on a safari bus tour. A photography competition is also sure to add to the excitement.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dubai Culture dedicates significant space to showcasing traditional crafts and elements of local heritage, reflecting its commitment to promoting cultural authenticity at artistic and cultural events across the emirate. Additionally, attendees can savour traditional cuisine in a heritage-rich and creatively designed setting.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The festival is held in collaboration with an extensive list of partners, including Dubai Mounted Police, Dubai Municipality, Dubai Ambulance, Dubai Police, Dubai Civil Defence, the Roads and Transport Authority, the Islamic Affairs and Charitable Activities Department in Dubai, Mohammed Bin Rashid Space Centre, The Climate Tribe, Lina Kattan, Emirates Airlines, Zayed University, Sandooq Al Watan, Emirates Photography Society, Maraya, Freej, Ferjan Dubai, and Immersee.&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/arts-culture/latifa-bint-mohammed-inaugurates-fourth-edition-of-al-marmoom-film-in-the-desert-festival-2025-01-05-1.736061"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736062.1736089926!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
															
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="Arts_culture"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[Organised by Dubai Culture under the theme ‘Where Stories Come to Life,’ event running until 12 January aims to support]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[E247]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/uae/dubai-municipality-awards-contracts-for-second-phase-of-al-mamzar-beach-development-project-2025-01-05-1.736059]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Dubai Municipality awards contracts for second phase of Al Mamzar Beach Development Project]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2025-01-05T19:00:36+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2025-01-05T19:06:43+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Entailing a cost of AED400 million, the two-phase project, which includes a seasonal events area and world-class wellness facilities, is eyeing completion by the end of 2025</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Among other highlights, the project features a dedicated public beach for women with manifold privacy and safety considerations incorporated into its design</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Jogging, walking, and cycling tracks linking the creek and corniche areas aim to further elevate the visitor experience</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Badr Anwahi: We continue to work towards the vision of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum to make Dubai the world&rsquo;s best city to live, work, and visit</strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>In alignment with the directives of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister of the UAE and Ruler of Dubai, Dubai Municipality has awarded contracts for the second phase of Al Mamzar Beach Development Project. This phase focuses on developing the beachfront in Al Mamzar Corniche, with completion of both phases of the project expected by the end of 2025. The total cost of the project is projected to be around AED400 million across both phases.</p>

<p>The project aims to elevate beach infrastructure through innovative designs that seamlessly connect the creek and the corniche, creating a new beach tourism destination that meets international standards while adhering to sustainability principles and addressing future concerns regarding climate change. It seeks to redefine global beach design concepts by offering integrated beaches equipped with state-of-the-art recreational, sports and commercial facilities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>These enhancements align with the highest specifications and standards, reinforcing Dubai&rsquo;s position as a leading global tourism hub and underscoring its commitment to improving quality of life and well-being for all. Spread over 125,000 square metres and spanning 80 metres across, Al Mamzar Corniche Beach will feature a dedicated public beach for women. Keeping privacy and safety factors paramount, the facility will include a secure gated entrance and fencing. The ladies beach will also enable night swimming and offer tailored amenities such as a sports club, commercial services, and children&rsquo;s play areas.</p>

<p><strong>Novel design</strong></p>

<p>The public beach on Al Mamzar Corniche will also feature 1,000 metres of running, walking, and cycling paths linking Al Mamzar Creek Beach and Al Mamzar Park. This innovative design, the first of its kind in the region, provides a convergence of beach paths with park areas to offer visitors a unique and multifaceted experience. The development will also feature green spaces crafted to the highest standards of aesthetic landscaping. Facilities will include a 5,000-square-metre area for seasonal events and activities, a 2,000-square-metre skateboarding area, children&#39;s play areas, restrooms, and beach lounges.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dubai Municipality will also equip the corniche with public health and wellness facilities, including toilets, changing rooms, showers, and services for people of determination. An administrative building will house a control room and first aid centre. Smart services, including AI-supported surveillance systems, drowning rescue technologies, crowd management tools, and smart luggage lockers, will ensure a seamless visitor experience.</p>

<p>The corniche development also focuses on encouraging business opportunities, introducing waterfront restaurants, food and beverage outlets, beach seating, and spaces for recreational activities, ultimately fostering economic growth while providing visitors an enhanced experience.</p>

<p>Bader Anwahi, CEO of the Public Facilities Agency at Dubai Municipality said, &ldquo;We continue to work towards the vision of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum to make Dubai the world&rsquo;s best city to live, work, and visit. This project reflects our commitment to creating innovative, sustainable infrastructure that aligns with Dubai&#39;s future ambitions, solidifying its leading position across various vital sectors, and supporting the achievement of Dubai Economic Agenda D33 targets.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He added: &ldquo;The development of infrastructure projects for tourist and beachfront facilities is a key strategic objective of Dubai Municipality aimed at building a sustainable and attractive city that offers advanced tourism and recreational facilities. This enhances Dubai&#39;s appeal, elevating quality of life for all, and solidifies the emirate&rsquo;s position as a leading global tourist destination.</p>

<p>&ldquo;We are redefining concepts and standards for the design and development of beaches to align with the future and position them as the most advanced and appealing globally. Our goal is to showcase Dubai&rsquo;s uniqueness in implementing pioneering projects that combine advanced, sustainable infrastructure with modern, aesthetic designs. These projects provide top-notch services and facilities, offering exceptional tourism and recreational experiences that support the emirate&rsquo;s future economic and tourism agendas.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>First phase nears half-way stage</strong></p>

<p>The first phase of the development, work on which commenced in June last year, has achieved 45% completion. Covering an area of 275,000 square metres, the beach ranges in width from 30 to 90 metres at various points. The project includes the construction of a 200-metre-long pedestrian pontoon bridge to connect the two banks of the creek, ensuring ease of access for the public. It also features a 300-metre-long night swimming beach designed to be accessible for people of determination, along with a 5-kilometre walkway and dedicated running and cycling tracks along the beach. These enhancements aim to create an inclusive and vibrant community space for both residents and visitors.</p>

<p>The development also incorporates three children&rsquo;s play areas, two recreational zones, and comprehensive visitor facilities such as barbecue spots and jet ski marinas. In addition, the beach will feature eight toilet blocks, changing rooms, and shower rooms, with eight outdoor shower areas and 1,400 car parking spaces.</p>

<p>Dubai Municipality, which is tasked with the management of waterways and public beaches, aims to enhance recreational facilities across the emirate. By creating world-class tourism infrastructure, the Al Mamzar Beach Development Project will cater to the growing numbers of residents, tourists, and beachgoers, reinforcing Dubai&rsquo;s status as a premier destination for leisure and recreation.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/uae/dubai-municipality-awards-contracts-for-second-phase-of-al-mamzar-beach-development-project-2025-01-05-1.736059"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736060.1736089258!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="UAE"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[Entailing a cost of AED400 million, the two-phase project, which includes a seasonal events area and world-class ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[E247]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-approves-aed5-4-billion-housing-projects-offering-beneficiaries-3-004-new-homes-across-dubai-2025-01-05-1.736056]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid approves AED5.4 billion housing projects offering beneficiaries 3,004 new homes across Dubai]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2025-01-05T18:53:28+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2025-01-05T18:56:30+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong>His Highness emphasises that public wellbeing remains the end goal of all development plans and the primary driver of all government work&nbsp;</strong></li>
	<li><strong>Offering diverse choices for citizens, the projects are aligned with the Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme</strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister of the UAE and Ruler of Dubai, has approved the implementation of a series of housing projects worth AED5.4 billion to benefit citizens across different areas of Dubai.</p>

<p>The projects will see 3,004 new homes being built for Emirati citizens. Of these, 1,181 homes will come up in Latifa City for beneficiaries under the housing loan category. For beneficiaries in the housing grant category, the projects envisage 606 new homes in Al Yalayis 5, 432 homes in Wadi Al Amardi, 398 homes in Al Awir 1, 200 homes in the Makan area of Hatta, 120 homes in Oud Al Muteena, and 67 homes in the countryside and rural areas of Dubai.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The housing projects, offering diverse options for Emirati citizens, align with the Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme launched by Her Highness Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum bin Juma Al Maktoum, wife of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum. The programme aims to support the wellbeing of families in Dubai, strengthen their stability and cohesion, renew community values, enhance the overall quality of family life, offer a stimulating social environment, and help families achieve optimal work-life balance.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed emphasised that citizen wellbeing is the end goal of all development plans and the primary driver of all government work, besides being a key criterion in evaluating the success of development programmes and initiatives in the jobs, manufacturing, infrastructure, and services sectors.</p>

<p>His Highness said: &ldquo;Housing programmes for citizens represent a top priority and we are committed to ensuring that our people have the best living standards and all the support they need to foster stable family environments and community wellbeing. People are the foundation of our renaissance, our successful development experience, and the cornerstone of the global standing we have achieved in all respects.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>Comprehensive plan</strong></p>

<p>His Highness added that major housing initiatives will continue to be part of a comprehensive plan to fulfil the aspirations of citizens for stability and good living standards while helping achieve national strategies to drive ever greater prosperity and shape the future that the people of the UAE truly deserve.</p>

<p>His Excellency Omar Hamad Bu Shehab, CEO of the Mohammed bin Rashid Housing Establishment, said that the new housing projects embody the leadership&rsquo;s vision to offer citizens exceptional quality of life by providing an integrated residential environment that meets all their needs while ensuring the highest levels of comfort and safety.</p>

<p>He added: &ldquo;The housing projects plan is part of a series of projects implemented by the Mohammed bin Rashid Housing Establishment to provide for the future housing needs of Emirati citizens within integrated communities. These plans are implemented drawing upon the best urban planning standards, placing citizens at the forefront of all goals aimed at ensuring public wellbeing over the next 20 years.&rdquo;</p>

<p>According to the Dubai 2040 Urban Master Plan, housing programmes for citizens in Dubai aim to address future housing needs through optimal planning of available spaces in the emirate. This is achieved by ensuring the sustainability of available land in keeping with rigorous standards. A significant effort also goes into ensuring a diverse choice of housing units and communities offering the highest quality of life, with an accent on green spaces, recreational facilities and commercial centres.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-approves-aed5-4-billion-housing-projects-offering-beneficiaries-3-004-new-homes-across-dubai-2025-01-05-1.736056"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736057.1736088778!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="UAE"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[His Highness emphasises that public wellbeing remains the end goal of all development plans and the primary driver of ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[E247]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/world/three-uae-aid-convoys-arrive-in-gaza-strip-as-part-of-operation-chivalrous-knight-3-2025-01-05-1.736054]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Three UAE aid convoys arrive in Gaza Strip as part of 'Operation Chivalrous Knight 3']]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2025-01-05T18:48:44+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2025-01-05T18:49:20+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Three UAE convoys loaded with various humanitarian aid crossed this week into the Gaza Strip through the Egyptian Rafah Border Crossing.</p>

<p>This is part of the UAE&#39;s efforts to support and provide relief to the Palestinians during the current circumstances in line with &quot;Operation Chivalrous Knight 3&quot;.</p>

<p>The convoys consist of 29 trucks carrying more than 364 tonnes of humanitarian aid. This includes food, winter clothing, shelter tents and other essential needs.</p>

<p>This brings the number of aid convoys that have entered the Gaza Strip through Egyptian border crossings as part of Operation Chivalrous Knight 3, to 150 convoys consisting of 2,319 trucks transporting more than 29,025 tonnes.</p>

<p>Since the start of the crisis, the UAE has provided 46,659 tonnes of urgent relief supplies to the Gaza Strip. This aims to contribute to alleviating the difficult conditions suffered by the people of Gaza.</p>

<p>Operation Chivalrous Knight 3 seeks to assist all affected groups in the Gaza Strip, especially children and women. The UAE is keen to intensify relief efforts and promote humanitarian work for Palestinians.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/world/three-uae-aid-convoys-arrive-in-gaza-strip-as-part-of-operation-chivalrous-knight-3-2025-01-05-1.736054"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736055.1736088511!/image/image.jpeg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="World"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[Three UAE convoys loaded with various humanitarian aid crossed this week into the Gaza Strip through the Egyptian Rafah]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[WAM]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/business/economy-finance/dubai-ranks-among-world-s-top-10-cities-in-global-power-city-index-for-second-consecutive-year-2025-01-05-1.736051]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Dubai ranks among world’s top 10 cities in Global Power City Index for second consecutive year]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2025-01-05T18:45:28+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2025-01-05T18:47:20+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dubai has been ranked eighth worldwide and first in the Middle East in the Global Power City Index 2024 (GPCI) for the second year in a row.</p>

<p>In an annual study released by Japan&rsquo;s Mori Memorial Foundation, the index highlights Dubai&rsquo;s role as a leader in innovation, economic dynamism, and global connectivity.</p>

<p>This achievement makes Dubai the only city in the Middle East to feature in the top 10, reaffirming its position as a major global hub for business, talent, and investment.</p>

<p>H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister, Minister of Defence, and Chairman of The Executive Council of Dubai, attributed this achievement to the visionary leadership of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President, Prime Minister and Ruler of Dubai.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Dubai continues to redefine what is possible, combining innovation, sustainability, and a focus on nurturing talent,&rdquo; said Sheikh Hamdan. &ldquo;The city has created one of the world&rsquo;s best environments for businesses to thrive, creative ideas to take shape, and individuals to realise their aspirations while enjoying an exceptional quality of life. This achievement reflects not only visionary leadership but also the collective contributions of countless individuals who share a commitment to excellence.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The Crown Prince highlighted the key drivers behind Dubai&#39;s success, including its world-class infrastructure, which continues to attract global investment and top talent. He highlighted the city&rsquo;s flexible and progressive legislative framework, designed to foster innovation and adapt to evolving global trends.</p>

<p>He also underscored the importance of Dubai&rsquo;s strong public-private sector partnerships, which have created a dynamic ecosystem for collaboration and growth.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Dubai&rsquo;s high ranking on global indices shows that we are not just keeping pace with the world, we are setting new benchmarks for excellence,&rdquo; he added.</p>

<p>Reaffirming Dubai&#39;s commitment to sustainable growth, Sheikh Hamdan said, &ldquo;We remain steadfast in our efforts to consolidate Dubai&rsquo;s global status as a city of the future. By embracing strategic innovation and maintaining a strong commitment to excellence, we are creating new opportunities across industries.&rdquo;</p>

<p>With a strong focus on improving quality of life and fostering economic opportunities, Dubai continues to attract the world&rsquo;s leading minds, businesses, and investors. One of the fastest-growing cities in the index, Dubai is also constantly establishing new benchmarks for urban innovation, connectivity, and resilience.</p>

<p>The Global Power City Index (GPCI) evaluates and ranks the major cities of the world according to their &ldquo;magnetism,&rdquo; or their comprehensive power to attract people, capital, and enterprises from around the world. It does so by measuring six functions&mdash;Economy, Research and Development, Cultural Interaction, Livability, Environment, and Accessibility&mdash;providing a multidimensional ranking.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/business/economy-finance/dubai-ranks-among-world-s-top-10-cities-in-global-power-city-index-for-second-consecutive-year-2025-01-05-1.736051"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736052.1736088302!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="Business/Economy and Finance"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[Dubai has been ranked eighth worldwide and first in the Middle East in the Global Power City Index 2024 (GPCI) for the ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[E247]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-meets-with-prime-minister-of-pakistan-2025-01-05-1.736049]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[UAE President meets with Prime Minister of Pakistan]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2025-01-05T18:41:50+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2025-01-05T18:42:01+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan today met with His Excellency Muhammad Shehbaz Sharif, Prime Minister of the Islamic Republic of Pakistan.</p>

<p>During the meeting, which took place in the city of Rahim Yar Khan in Pakistan, His Highness and the Pakistani Prime Minister discussed cooperation between the UAE and Pakistan and opportunities to enhance ties, especially in the economic, trade, developmental, and other fields that serve their mutual interests and aspirations for sustainable economic development and prosperity for their peoples.</p>

<p>This came as part of the close historical relations that unite the two countries and their shared interest in continuing to develop these ties.</p>

<p>During the meeting, the two sides also exchanged views on a number of regional and international issues of common interest.</p>

<p>For his part, His Excellency Muhammad Shehbaz Sharif underscored his pride in the strong friendship between his country and the UAE, expressing his appreciation to His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan for the continuous support provided by the UAE to Pakistan, especially in developmental fields and through the UAE&#39;s notable initiatives in this regard.</p>

<p>His Excellency stressed the two countries&#39; keenness to strengthen relations and further develop bilateral cooperation in all economic, investment, and developmental fields in a way that benefits their peoples and contributes to achieving joint interests.</p>

<p>The meeting was attended by H.H. Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Chairman of the Presidential Court for Special Affairs; Ali bin Hammad Al Shamsi, Secretary-General of the Supreme Council for National Security; and Hamad Obaid Al Zaabi, UAE Ambassador to Pakistan.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-meets-with-prime-minister-of-pakistan-2025-01-05-1.736049"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736050.1736088024!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="World"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan today met with His Excellency Muhammad Shehbaz Sharif, Prime ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[WAM]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/sports/football/bahrain-crowned-champions-of-arabian-gulf-football-cup-26-2025-01-04-1.736047]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Bahrain crowned champions of Arabian Gulf Football Cup 26]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2025-01-04T22:56:00+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2025-01-05T14:57:40+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Bahrain have been crowned champions of the Arabian Gulf Football Cup, &lsquo;Khaleeji Zain 26&rsquo;, after defeating Oman 2-1 in the final match held today, Saturday, at the Jaber Al-Ahmad International Stadium in Kuwait.</p>

<p>Bahrain overturned a 1-0 deficit, after Oman scored in the 17th minute through Abdulrahman Al-Mushaifri, to win 2-1. Mohamed Marhoon scored the equaliser for Bahrain in the 78th minute from a penalty, followed by an own goal by Oman&#39;s Mohammed Al-Musalami in the 80th minute.</p>

<p>This is the second time the Bahraini national team has won the Arabian Gulf Cup, following their victory in the 2019 edition.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Sabah Khaled Al-Hamad Al-Sabah, Crown Prince of Kuwait, honoured Gulf football legends during the final match events.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/sports/football/bahrain-crowned-champions-of-arabian-gulf-football-cup-26-2025-01-04-1.736047"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736048.1736074565!/image/image.jpeg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="Sports/FootBall"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[Bahrain have been crowned champions of the Arabian Gulf Football Cup, ‘Khaleeji Zain 26’, after defeating Oman 2-1 in ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[WAM]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/uae/hind-bint-maktoum-launches-sheikha-hind-bint-maktoum-family-programme-2025-01-04-1.736045]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Hind bint Maktoum launches ‘Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme’]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2025-01-04T17:50:00+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2025-01-05T14:52:18+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>H.H. Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum bin Juma Al Maktoum, wife of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President, Prime Minister and Ruler of Dubai, has launched the &lsquo;Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme&rsquo;.</p>

<p>The programme aims to support the growth, stability and wellbeing of families in Dubai, strengthen community values, enhance quality of life, and promote work-life balance, by offering financial, social, and educational support.</p>

<p>The initiative reflects Her Highness&#39; dedication to empowering Emirati families and fostering their stability and growth.</p>

<p>Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum said the programme reflects H.H. Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum&#39;s vision to strengthen family stability and consolidate the family&rsquo;s status as the nucleus of a cohesive society. It aligns with national priorities to empower Emirati families, uphold their values, and prepare them for future challenges.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Strong families are essential to create a better future. We are committed to fulfilling the aspirations of every Emirati family in Dubai, ensuring their lasting happiness and stability while empowering them to nurture future generations who can shape a brighter tomorrow,&rdquo; Her Highness added.</p>

<p>The &lsquo;Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme&rsquo; introduces a forward-looking vision for the Emirati family with a comprehensive support package that includes wedding support, housing assistance, flexible work policies, and social, financial, and housing awareness and education programmes.</p>

<p>The programme aligns with the objectives of the Dubai Social Agenda 33, which aims to foster happy, connected, and value-driven families and double the number of Emirati families in the emirate by 2033.</p>

<p>The &lsquo;Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme&rsquo; features several key initiatives in its first phase. In collaboration with the Dubai Government Human Resources Department, the programme offers flexible work benefits, including a 10-day paid marriage leave for government sector employees in Dubai and a &lsquo;remote work&rsquo; option on Fridays for mothers during the first year after maternity leave.</p>

<p>The &lsquo;Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme&rsquo; reduces the monthly premium for housing loans to a minimum of AED3,333 for beneficiaries of the Dubai Weddings programme, provided their monthly income does not exceed AED30,000. This initiative aims to ease financial pressures on young people and support their ability to meet other family needs.</p>

<p>In January 2024, under the directives of H.H. Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum bin Juma Al Maktoum, the Community Development Authority in Dubai launched the Dubai Weddings programme, which covers the costs of the main wedding ceremony and provides wedding halls and neighbourhood Majlises free of charge. The Dubai Weddings initiative provides financial support to both husband and wife, easing the financial pressures of marriage. The programme also provides a wide range of discounts to Dubai Weddings beneficiaries including those offered through the Esaad card.</p>

<p>In its first year, the Dubai Weddings programme facilitated 344 weddings, accounting for 28.3% of all Emirati weddings in Dubai by the end of 2024. It also contributed to a 10.1% increase in Emirati weddings last year compared to 2023.</p>

<p>In its first phase, the &lsquo;Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme&rsquo; also offers housing support in collaboration with the Mohammed Bin Rashid Housing Establishment, by prioritising the allocation of ready-made housing for loan beneficiaries under the Dubai Weddings programme.</p>

<p>The &lsquo;Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme&rsquo; includes a range of training initiatives for Dubai Weddings members, such as the &lsquo;Start it Right&rsquo; marital awareness programme. This initiative equips young people with essential skills to wisely plan their lives, fostering the social and emotional tools needed to build happy families and address challenges positively. It offers courses on the social and economic aspects of marriage, emphasising understanding, cooperation, and mutual respect between spouses. To date, 1,013 individuals have benefited from the &lsquo;Start it Right&rsquo; programme, while 208 have benefited from financial support.</p>

<p>The training programmes under the &lsquo;Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme&rsquo; include a financial literacy course for members of the Dubai Weddings initiative. This course provides soon-to-be-married couples with the knowledge needed to plan financially, manage resources effectively, and ensure long-term financial stability. It also emphasises the importance of saving, budgeting, and avoiding debt to safeguard family stability.</p>

<p>The training programmes also include the &lsquo;How to Build Your Home&rsquo; programme for housing loan beneficiaries, in collaboration with the New Economy Academy, aimed at equipping young people with the skills and knowledge necessary to build their homes economically and efficiently.</p>

<p>These benefits apply to new members of the Dubai Weddings programme from 4 January 2025. Those wishing to avail themselves of housing benefits can apply within one year of benefiting from the Dubai Weddings programme.</p>

<p>Future phases of the &lsquo;Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum Family Programme&rsquo; will expand its scope by introducing new packages and benefits in education, health, and other social services.</p>

<p>All Emirati citizens in Dubai planning to marry can register for the Dubai Weddings programme, provided the prospective bride is an Emirati citizen. Registration is available through the &lsquo;Emirati&rsquo; platform on the Dubai Now app. Alternatively, individuals can register or learn more by visiting the Community Development Authority&#39;s website or contacting the Authority at 800 2121.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/uae/hind-bint-maktoum-launches-sheikha-hind-bint-maktoum-family-programme-2025-01-04-1.736045"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736046.1736074216!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="UAE"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[  H.H. Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum bin Juma Al Maktoum, wife of His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[WAM]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/technology/yapiee-app-sets-new-standards-in-influencer-brand-partnerships-for-uae-businesses-2025-01-04-1.736043]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Yapiee App Sets New Standards in Influencer-Brand Partnerships for UAE Businesses]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2025-01-04T13:35:46+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2025-01-04T13:35:56+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
	<li><strong><em>Yapiee transforms influencer marketing in the UAE, fostering impactful collaborations between brands and influencers. </em></strong></li>
</ul>

<p>Yapiee App, an influencer marketing platform, has been innovative, mainly in the space of the influencer marketing apps. It changes how brands would get in touch with influencers across the UAE. Being different from others, this platform provides a path for companies of all sorts to team up with an influencer to reduce the influence marketing process while at the same time making it easier to promote businesses, allowing companies to gain visibility along with interacting with customers via meaningful engagement.</p>

<p>At the core is the AI-powered matching system which links a brand with its influencer based on their audience&#39;s demographics and interest. It means marketing campaigns would not only be effective but customized: because the needs of each business will be different. Businesses can create a unique offer to a niche audience, and that results in increased customer loyalty and sales. Importantly, Yapiee also provides an opportunity to offer the brand&#39;s goods or services in exchange for influencer collaborations instead of money, and this seems to be very cost-efficient and beneficial to both parties.</p>

<p>One of the most significant value propositions that has been there for Yapiee is its real-time collaboration functions. These help influencers as well as brands coordinate with each other in a seamless manner without causing any issues, so that the campaigns reach the right time frame and maximize the effectiveness of every marketing campaign. Thus, it&#39;s a tool crucial for any business looking to drive success in the competitive digital market.</p>

<p>Achievement in cost-effective marketing can be realized through the acquisition of this app by businesses anywhere in the UAE. This initiative not only contributes to the development of the local economy but also enhances brand engagement through influencer marketing. The app offers multilingual support in six languages: Arabic, English, German, Spanish, French, and Italian. This feature ensures that people from diverse backgrounds can connect easily, facilitating effective communication between brands and consumers, regardless of cultural and linguistic differences.</p>

<p>With flexible social media integration, Yapiee is able to connect businesses to their target audience across all the major platforms like Instagram, X, YouTube, TikTok, and Facebook. And that goes with the scope of engagement and visibility, the requirements to thrive in this competitive market today.</p>

<p>Very recently, Yapiee exhibited at GITEX/North Star 2024 held in Dubai. It marked a difference among the many 6,500 participants with regard to showcasing its unique value proposition in front of international spectators. This platform helped grab the attention of visitors and clients, as well as influencers, toward the new product.</p>

<p>It&#39;s free to download and use, and thus the application is even more attractive for brands and their influencers. Yapiee is also planning to expand its operations internationally by early 2025.</p>

<p>Summed up in a nutshell, it can be said that Yapiee is not merely a marketing tool but is something that can change the face of business entities within the UAE. It helps in bringing people closer to forming a community and increasing visibility; they are engaging the audience to a great extent by bringing forward these innovative features and continuous collaborations.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zz1OE8hfYLg"><span style="color:#0000FF;">Click here to know how Yapiee works for Businesses</span></a><span style="color:#0000FF;"> or </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T6JQ6xqe-pU"><span style="color:#0000FF;">get an overview of the Yapiee App here</span></a><span style="color:#0000FF;">.</span></strong></p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/technology/yapiee-app-sets-new-standards-in-influencer-brand-partnerships-for-uae-businesses-2025-01-04-1.736043"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736044.1735983268!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="Technology"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[Yapiee transforms influencer marketing in the UAE, fostering impactful collaborations between brands and influencers. ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[E247]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/uae/uae-government-issues-federal-decree-law-to-reorganize-the-civil-defense-authority-2025-01-03-1.736040]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[UAE Government Issues Federal Decree-Law to Reorganize the Civil Defense Authority]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2025-01-03T19:12:56+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2025-01-03T19:14:02+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Establishing a New Civil Defense Authority under the National Emergency, Crisis, and Disasters Management Authority</strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>The UAE Government has issued a federal decree-law to reorganize the Civil Defense Authority, aiming to enhance the country&#39;s readiness to respond to emergencies and disasters while ensuring the highest standards of public safety and protection.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
This decree marks a significant step in modernizing the national civil protection framework. The reorganization focuses on improving coordination between local and federal entities working in civil defense, developing advanced alert and evacuation systems, providing care for affected individuals, and forming specialized teams for relief efforts.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The decree establishes a new entity named the &quot;Civil Defense Authority&quot;, part of the National Emergency, Crisis, and Disasters Management Authority. This new body replaces the Civil Defense Department previously operating under the Ministry of Interior.</p>

<p>The Civil Defense Authority is tasked with strategic responsibilities to enhance civil protection and ensure comprehensive readiness to address risks and disasters. These responsibilities include developing policies, strategies, and regulations related to civil defense in coordination with relevant entities, studying potential risks and incidents, and preparing plans to manage them efficiently.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
The Authority is also responsible for creating hazards prevention programs and establishing safety standards, securing buildings and facilities against fire hazards, and deploying rapid response teams to incident sites to extinguish fires effectively.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Authority&#39;s duties extend to establishing and equipping specialized risk management centers and public alert systems to warn residents of potential hazards. It also prepares evacuation plans for residents when necessary and ensures residential and institutional buildings are adequately equipped. Medical and social care is provided for affected individuals in collaboration with relevant entities.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
To further bolster national preparedness, the Authority is tasked with procuring and maintaining equipment&nbsp; essential for civil defense operations. It also coordinates essential services&mdash;medical, social, engineering, administrative, and educational&mdash;to ensure continuity during times of disasters. Additionally, the Authority organizes efforts and collaborates with entities that have internal security systems, such as oil companies and airports, to provide support as required.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Civil Defense Authority is committed to forming specialized teams to carry out response and relief operations in affected areas. It organizes joint training programs for civil defense personnel and volunteers and implements awareness campaigns to educate residents on the necessary actions during emergencies.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
The Authority&#39;s responsibilities also include monitoring radiological, chemical, and biological hazards and taking the necessary measures to address them in coordination with relevant authorities. Furthermore, it enhances cooperation among UAE emirates to establish support centers that improve civil defense services at national and international levels.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
The Civil Defense Authority prioritizes coordination with entities that maintain internal security and safety systems, such as oil companies and airports, to ensure effective support and assistance when required. This includes organizing methods for providing aid and fostering efficient collaboration during emergencies.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
The Civil Defense Authority is tasked with forming specialized teams for response and relief operations in disaster-affected areas. It organizes training programs and joint simulation exercises for civil defense personnel and volunteers to enhance their readiness for various emergency scenarios. Additionally, the Authority oversees awareness campaigns to educate residents about necessary precautions and procedures during emergencies.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
The Authority requires entities to refrain from issuing any licenses for properties or facilities unless they first obtain a certificate verifying compliance with safety and prevention standards.&nbsp;<br />
The decree establishes a dedicated committee to review compensation claims related to damages caused by civil defense operations, with a grievance mechanism in place. It also enforces strict penalties, including imprisonment of up to (6) six months or fines of up to AED 250,000 for violations of the law or disruptions to civil defense activities.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/uae/uae-government-issues-federal-decree-law-to-reorganize-the-civil-defense-authority-2025-01-03-1.736040"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736041.1735917127!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="UAE"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[Establishing a New Civil Defense Authority under the National Emergency, Crisis, and Disasters Management Authority The]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[E247]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/hatta-running-championship-to-showcase-sporting-vibe-of-hatta-winter-initiative-2025-01-03-1.736038]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Hatta Running Championship to showcase sporting vibe of Hatta Winter initiative]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2025-01-03T18:27:10+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2025-01-03T18:29:10+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Hatta Running Championship returns on January 4 under the patronage of Sheikh Saeed bin Hamdan bin Rashid Al Maktoum, President of Hatta Club.</p>

<p>Organised by the Hatta Sports, Cultural and Social Club in collaboration with the Dubai Sports Council (DSC) and the Hatta Winter Festival committee, the event has already confirmed over 1,000 participants, including a strong international presence.</p>

<p>The championship is part of the Hatta Winter initiative, with DSC as a key partner.</p>

<p>The event features competition across eight categories, including the Emirati men&rsquo;s category and an open category over a distance of 8 km, the Emirati women&rsquo;s category and an open category over a distance of 5 km, the Emirati youth category and an open category for under-20-year-olds over a distance of 5 km, and the Emirati children&rsquo;s category and an open category for under-16s over a distance of 3 km.</p>

<p>With over 1,000 runners from different nationalities and age groups, the competition offers a prize pool of AED100,000. The routes highlight Hatta&rsquo;s scenic landscapes and tourist spots, with all races concluding at the picturesque Leem Lake.</p>

<p>The Hatta Running Championship is among the highlights of diverse sporting activities organised as part of the Hatta Winter initiative, which is overseen by the Supreme Committee to Supervise the Development of Hatta, and is implemented by Brand Dubai, the creative arm of the Government of Dubai Media Office, in partnership with various government and private entities.</p>

<p>The Hatta Winter initiative serves to provide added impetus to the goals of the Dubai 2040 Urban Master Plan, especially in terms of enhancing tourism competitiveness, driving development activities with the participation of the private sector, supporting efforts to promote tourism and encourage entrepreneurs, as well as organising and hosting activities and sporting events that will help boost the number of visitors to the Hatta region.</p>

<p>The Hatta Running Championship also aligns with concerted efforts being made to enhance the region&rsquo;s profile as a destination for sports tourism and diverse sporting activities, besides its capability to host major sporting events that directly benefit local communities and usher in significant economic benefits.</p>

<p>Among recent sporting events held in Hatta was the Hatta Winter Football Championship, which featured the participation of eight community teams, and the preliminary and exhibition phase of the Dubai International Rally events from 29th November to 1st December. The Emirates Motor Sports Organisation (EMSO) partnered with the Dubai Sports Council to organise the latter event. Another highlight was a walking competition organised by Hatta Adventures, with local farms and the area&rsquo;s unique aflaj irrigation network providing a fascinating backdrop for the event.</p>

<p>The Hatta Winter initiative has also set the stage for mountain biking and kayaking races organised by Hatta Adventures and Hatta Kayak (January 11), and the Stand Up Paddling and Kayaking Challenge (January 25-26), besides sporting challenges with a family flavour on February 1. The Hatta Ramadan Tournament will keep the community engaged in sporting pursuits during the holy month while the Spartan Race is yet another event that promises to be a major draw for international participants as well as local communities.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/sports/other/hatta-running-championship-to-showcase-sporting-vibe-of-hatta-winter-initiative-2025-01-03-1.736038"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736039.1735914515!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="Sports/Other"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[The Hatta Running Championship returns on January 4 under the patronage of Sheikh Saeed bin Hamdan bin Rashid Al ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[E247]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-celebrates-his-accession-day-by-honouring-his-wife-sheikha-hind-2025-01-03-1.736036]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid celebrates his Accession Day by honouring his wife Sheikha Hind]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2025-01-03T18:20:44+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2025-01-03T18:21:14+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President, Prime Minister and Ruler of Dubai, graciously dedicated his Accession Day to his esteemed wife, Sheikha Hind bint Maktoum, whom he reverently referred to as the &quot;most beautiful thing&quot; in his life, his &quot;greatest supporter,&quot; and the &ldquo;soul of Dubai&rdquo;</p>

<p>Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid&#39;s Accession Day as Ruler of Dubai falls on 4th January.</p>

<p>In a post on his X account today, His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid said that Sheikha Hind embodies compassion, generosity, and unwavering charity. She is the &#39;&#39;heart of our home, the bedrock of our family, and the guiding star of my professional journey.&#39;&#39;</p>

<p>His Highness described Sheikha Hind as &quot;the Mother of the Sheikhs,&quot; praising her noble qualities and constant generosity.</p>

<p>Sheikh Mohammed wrapped up his note by calling everyone to be loyal to those who deserve loyalty.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-celebrates-his-accession-day-by-honouring-his-wife-sheikha-hind-2025-01-03-1.736036"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736037.1735914030!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="UAE"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President, Prime Minister and Ruler of Dubai, graciously ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[WAM]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/uae/rta-completes-traffic-improvements-at-repton-school-dubai-in-nad-al-sheba-and-gems-al-khaleej-international-school-in-al-warqa-2025-01-02-1.736034]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[RTA completes traffic improvements at Repton School Dubai in Nad Al Sheba and GEMS Al Khaleej International School in Al Warqa]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2025-01-02T18:22:10+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2025-01-02T18:22:39+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Roads and Transport Authority (RTA) has completed traffic enhancements at the Repton School Dubai in Nad Al Sheba and GEMS Al Khaleej International School in Al Warqa. These upgrades included the addition of about 150 parking spaces at each school, as well as the provision of safe entrances and exits to the newly expanded parking areas. Designed to improve traffic flow during student drop-off and pick-up times, the enhancements are anticipated to reduce congestion and delays by 35% to 50%.<br />
RTA is dedicated to enhancing the efficiency and flow of Dubai&rsquo;s Road network, with a particular focus on school zones, in line with the urban and developmental growth of the UAE and Dubai. These initiatives serve all road users, including teaching staff, bus drivers, and parents, prioritising the safety of everyone on Dubai&rsquo;s streets.<br />
The traffic enhancements have doubled the parking capacity at Repton School Dubai in Nad Al Sheba to 300 spaces, representing a 100% increase. Similarly, Al Khaleej International School in Al Warqa has seen a 125% expansion in parking capacity, now totalling 270 spaces. These upgrades underscore RTA&rsquo;s ongoing commitment to advancing Dubai&rsquo;s infrastructure, supporting sustainable growth, and enhancing the well-being and happiness of residents in line with the vision of making Dubai the best city in the world to live in.<br />
The improvements encompassed the construction of integrated and safe pedestrian pathways and crossings, along with the installation of directional signage, road markings, and traffic-calming measures in school areas, all designed in compliance with approved technical standards.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/uae/rta-completes-traffic-improvements-at-repton-school-dubai-in-nad-al-sheba-and-gems-al-khaleej-international-school-in-al-warqa-2025-01-02-1.736034"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736035.1735827643!/image/image.JPG" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="UAE"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[The Roads and Transport Authority (RTA) has completed traffic enhancements at the Repton School Dubai in Nad Al Sheba ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[E247]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/uae/over-2-5-m-riders-used-public-transport-on-new-year-s-eve-2025-2025-01-01-1.736032]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Over 2.5 m riders used public transport on New Year’s Eve 2025]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2025-01-01T18:23:31+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2025-01-01T18:24:02+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The total number of passengers using public transport, shared mobility and taxis in Dubai during the New Year&rsquo;s Eve 2025 celebrations reached 2,502,474, marking a 9.3% increase compared to the 2,288,631 passengers recorded on the same occasion last year.</p>

<p>Across its Red and Green lines, the Dubai Metro accommodated 1,133,251 riders, while the Dubai Tram transported 55,391 riders. Public buses carried a total of 465,779 passengers, and marine transport services ferried 80,066 commuters. Additionally, e-hailing vehicles served 195,651 users, shared transport vehicles catered to 1,238 riders, and taxis transported 571,098 passengers.<br />
The Roads and Transport Authority (RTA) confirmed that passenger movement to and from New Year&rsquo;s Eve celebration venues was seamless and safe, thanks to a comprehensive plan developed in collaboration with relevant entities in Dubai.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/uae/over-2-5-m-riders-used-public-transport-on-new-year-s-eve-2025-2025-01-01-1.736032"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736033.1735741394!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="UAE"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[The total number of passengers using public transport, shared mobility and taxis in Dubai during the New Year’s Eve ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[E247]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/uae/national-center-of-meteorology-releases-january-climate-summary-2025-01-01-1.736030]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[National Center of Meteorology Releases January Climate Summary]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2025-01-01T18:19:42+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2025-01-01T18:21:14+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The National Center of Meteorology (NCM) has issued its January climate summary, highlighting key weather patterns and statistics for the month. Known for cooler conditions, January typically experiences a drop in temperatures, with cool days and cold nights. This is attributed to the influence of a high-pressure ridge extending from Siberia, accompanied by a cold air mass affecting the UAE and the Arabian Peninsula.</p>

<h3><strong>Temperature Trends</strong></h3>

<p>Forecasts for January 2025 indicate that the average temperatures will align with or slightly exceed the general average. The national mean temperature for the month is 18.3&deg;C, with notable climatic variations:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Mean air temperature: <strong>16.4&deg;C to 20.0&deg;C</strong></li>
	<li>Mean maximum air temperature: <strong>21.3&deg;C to 25.7&deg;C</strong></li>
	<li>Mean minimum air temperature: <strong>11.6&deg;C to 15.2&deg;C</strong></li>
</ul>

<p>Historical records reveal extreme fluctuations, with the highest maximum temperature of <strong>36.0&deg;C</strong> observed in areas like Asab (1991), Al Hiyer (1983), and Alfoah (1983). The lowest recorded temperature was <strong>-2&deg;C</strong> in Raknah (2021).</p>

<h3><strong>Rainfall and Cloud Development</strong></h3>

<p>The UAE is expected to experience intermittent low-pressure systems moving from west to east. Occasionally, these systems, influenced by upper air troughs and the Red Sea trough, result in cloud formations and rainfall.</p>

<ul>
	<li>Forecasted average rainfall: <strong>11.5 mm</strong></li>
	<li>Highest recorded monthly rainfall: <strong>229.9 mm</strong> at Saqar Port (2020)</li>
</ul>

<h3><strong>Wind and Sea Conditions</strong></h3>

<p>Strong northwesterly winds, locally known as Shamal, are common during January. These winds often stir blowing sand and dust in inland areas, particularly in exposed regions, and contribute to rough sea conditions with increased wave heights.</p>

<ul>
	<li>Mean wind speed: <strong>12 km/h</strong></li>
	<li>Highest wind speed: <strong>99.7 km/h</strong> at Al Gheweifat (2003)</li>
</ul>

<h3><strong>Relative Humidity and Fog Formation</strong></h3>

<p>Humidity levels rise during the early mornings, increasing the likelihood of fog and mist, particularly in inland areas compared to coastal regions.</p>

<ul>
	<li>Mean relative humidity: <strong>63%</strong></li>
	<li>Mean maximum relative humidity: <strong>78% to 91%</strong></li>
	<li>Mean minimum relative humidity: <strong>31% to 47%</strong></li>
</ul>

<p>January 2021 recorded the highest fog and mist occurrences, with <strong>19 foggy days</strong> and <strong>4 misty days</strong>.</p>

<h3><strong>Historical Highlights</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Fog:</strong> The most foggy January occurred in 2021 with significant fog and mist frequencies.</li>
	<li><strong>Rainfall:</strong> The highest recorded monthly rainfall was <strong>229.9 mm</strong> in January 2020.</li>
</ul>

<p>This month&rsquo;s forecasted climatic conditions align with historical averages, underscoring January as a pivotal period for cooler weather, fog development, and occasional rainfall in the UAE.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/uae/national-center-of-meteorology-releases-january-climate-summary-2025-01-01-1.736030"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736031.1735741259!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="UAE"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[The National Center of Meteorology (NCM) has issued its January climate summary, highlighting key weather patterns and ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[E247]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-s-successful-mediation-between-russia-ukraine-reflects-its-role-in-promoting-global-peace-president-of-arab-parliament-2024-12-31-1.736028]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[UAE's successful mediation between Russia, Ukraine reflects its role in promoting global peace: President of Arab Parliament]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2024-12-31T19:53:30+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2024-12-31T19:54:21+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mohammed Ahmed Al Yamahi, President of the Arab Parliament, praised the UAE&#39;s successful mediation efforts in facilitating a new exchange of war captives between the Russian Federation and the Republic of Ukraine. This marks the tenth such exchange orchestrated by the UAE between the two countries since the beginning of 2024.</p>

<p>In a statement today, Al Yamahi emphasised that the UAE&#39;s significant efforts reflect its commitment to a global peace approach championed by its wise leadership.</p>

<p>He also commended the UAE&#39;s pioneering role as a reliable global mediator and supporter of diplomatic initiatives and peaceful resolution pathways aimed at achieving peace on all levels.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-s-successful-mediation-between-russia-ukraine-reflects-its-role-in-promoting-global-peace-president-of-arab-parliament-2024-12-31-1.736028"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736029.1735660275!/image/image.jpeg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="World"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[Mohammed Ahmed Al Yamahi, President of the Arab Parliament, praised the UAE's successful mediation efforts in ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[WAM]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/world/humanitarian-situation-in-gaza-west-bank-worsens-due-to-israeli-aggression-palestinian-entities-2024-12-31-1.736026]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Humanitarian situation in Gaza, West Bank worsens due to Israeli aggression: Palestinian entities]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2024-12-31T19:48:42+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2024-12-31T19:49:14+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Official Palestinian entities have highlighted the worsening humanitarian and educational conditions in the Gaza Strip and the West Bank as a result of continued Israeli aggression since 7th October 2023.</p>

<p>In a statement today, the Palestinian Civil Defence (PCD) in Gaza announced that it has received hundreds of distress calls from displaced individuals whose tents and shelters were flooded by rain, leaving them pleading for help to save their children.</p>

<p>The PCD confirmed that its teams can only evacuate the affected to other locations, which are often unfit for shelter, forcing many to remain exposed to harsh weather conditions, including rain and cold.</p>

<p>The Palestinian Ministry of Education and Higher Education reported the martyrdom of 12,943 students and the injury of 21,681 others since the start of the Israeli aggression. The ministry indicated that over 12,790 students were martyred and 21,026 injured in Gaza, while the West Bank witnessed 120 student fatalities and 655 injuries, along with the detention of 548 students.</p>

<p>The ministry further noted damage to 425 government schools and universities in Gaza, while 109 schools and seven universities in the West Bank were subjected to incursions and vandalism.</p>

<p>It also confirmed that 788,000 students in Gaza remain unable to attend schools and universities since the onset of the aggression, with most students suffering from psychological trauma and facing severe health challenges.</p>

<p>A report by the Palestinian Central Bureau of Statistics on the conditions of Palestinians at the end of 2024 revealed a 6% decline in the population of the Gaza Strip by the year&#39;s end. The report estimated the total Palestinian population at 5.5 million, including 3.4 million in the West Bank. Meanwhile, Gaza&rsquo;s population decreased by approximately 160,000, bringing the estimated population to 2.1 million.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/world/humanitarian-situation-in-gaza-west-bank-worsens-due-to-israeli-aggression-palestinian-entities-2024-12-31-1.736026"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736027.1735660104!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="World"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[Official Palestinian entities have highlighted the worsening humanitarian and educational conditions in the Gaza Strip ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[WAM]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-bin-mohammed-bin-rashid-inspects-joint-operations-room-of-the-events-security-committee-2024-12-31-1.736024]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Mohammed bin Rashid bin Mohammed bin Rashid inspects Joint Operations Room of the Events Security Committee]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2024-12-31T19:42:39+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2024-12-31T19:44:00+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<ul>
	<li align="center"><strong>Review meeting involving 55 government, semi-government, and private entities takes stock of elaborate plan to secure New Year festivities</strong></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum inspected the Joint Operations Room of the Events Security Committee comprising 55 government, semi-government, and private entities. A comprehensive plan to secure the New Year&#39;s Eve 2025 celebrations, covering 36 locations in Dubai, was reviewed. The inspection took place in the presence of His Excellency Lieutenant General Talal Belhoul Al Falasi, Director General of Dubai&#39;s State Security Department; His Excellency Lieutenant General Abdullah Khalifa Al Marri, Commander-in-Chief of Dubai Police, and several directors of government departments, senior officers, and officials.</p>

<p>His Excellency Major General Saif Muhair Al Mazrouei, Acting Assistant Commander-in-Chief for Operations Affairs and Acting Chairman of the Events Security Committee, reviewed the readiness of the participating teams. He briefed His Highness on the capabilities of the Events Security Committee and the strict protocols for securing such major events. A total of 8,530 police officers and 1,145 patrols from Dubai Police have been deployed to secure various celebration sites across the emirate, in addition to 33 marine rescue boats operated by Dubai Police and its partners.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid bin Mohammed bin Rashid was apprised of preparations to secure the New Year&#39;s Eve events during a briefing by His Excellency Expert Major General Ali Hassan Al Mutawa, Assistant Director General for Fire and Rescue Affairs at Dubai Civil Defence. In all, 1,097 firefighters, including officers and non-commissioned officers, will be deployed across various locations to ensure immediate and effective response in emergencies. A total of 257 vital facilities were inspected to ensure their readiness and compliance with safety standards during the celebrations. On the technical front, 123 vehicles with specialised gear are in full readiness to deal with emergencies, backed up by comprehensive logistical support.</p>

<p>His Highness was apprised by Hussein Al Banna, Executive Director of the Traffic and Roads Agency at the Roads and Transport Authority (RTA), on the authority&#39;s preparations to manage traffic flow in accordance with an integrated traffic plan, especially in the Burj Khalifa area. This will be managed through the Traffic Management and Transportation Systems Committee, in direct coordination with the Events Security Committee in Dubai and its strategic partners.</p>

<p><strong>Preparedness for medical emergencies</strong></p>

<p>His Highness also attended a briefing by His Excellency Meshal Abdul Kareem Julfar, Executive Director of the Dubai Corporation for Ambulance Services, on the corporation&#39;s preparations to achieve its strategic objectives of offering rapid response to patients and injured individuals, in addition to providing advanced pre-hospital emergency services. Across the city, 224 ambulance points, including 5 facilities on boats, have been equipped to handle all types of emergencies. Furthermore, 593 paramedics and 29 supervisors have been strategically deployed to ensure utmost responsiveness of ambulance support during the 36 events being held across various areas of the emirate.</p>

<p>The Corporation has allocated 7 ambulances at Dubai Mall, and 19 vehicles with 38 paramedics at Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Boulevard and Burj Khalifa. Apart from this, 4 first responder vehicles, 4 electric bikes, and two bus ambulances are also on call, in addition to the Field Support Unit and the Mobile Medical Store.</p>

<p>In the Boulevard area, 42 volunteers, supervised by paramedics from the Corporation, are on standby. The volunteers have been trained and qualified under the First Responder programme to be effective partners in providing ambulance services by handling simple cases, enhancing the Corporation&#39;s efforts in ensuring rapid response and providing additional support to field teams.</p>

<p>His Highness also attended a briefing by Khalifa Baqer, Chief Operating Officer at Dubai Health, on Dubai Health&rsquo;s plan to ensure prompt medical intervention where required amid the festivities, both at field facilities and at its medical establishments. A fully integrated field hospital has been established in the Burj Khalifa area, and 7 medical points in the celebration site have been reinforced with the services of specialist emergency doctors. Besides this, 6 hospitals and 4 outpatient clinics have been kept on high alert to deal with emergencies. Additionally, 1,800 medical and administrative staff have also been deployed across all DHA facilities to ensure prompt and efficient medical services.</p>

<p><strong>Sub-operations</strong></p>

<p>Brigadier Turki bin Faris, Director of the General Department of Operations at Dubai Police, gave a presentation on the sub-operations at the event sites managed from the Joint Operations Room, along with an overview of the personnel and resources available to manage the event.</p>

<p>His Highness was apprised by Ahmed Al Khaja, CEO of Dubai Festivals and Retail Establishment (DFRE), on the number of events in the emirate during the New Year period and the emirate&#39;s full readiness to host the celebrations, with 175 events and 3,192 activities taking place in the restaurant sector alone. He stressed that the proactive plans developed by the Committee contribute to the success of the various events.</p>

<p>His Highness also inspected supply tents in Downtown Dubai that provide services pertaining to lost and found items, first aid services, logistical support, receiving and caring for lost children, and helping guide visitors, among other services.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/uae/mohammed-bin-rashid-bin-mohammed-bin-rashid-inspects-joint-operations-room-of-the-events-security-committee-2024-12-31-1.736024"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736025.1735659815!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="UAE"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[Review meeting involving 55 government, semi-government, and private entities takes stock of elaborate plan to secure ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[E247]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/global-village-announces-seven-drone-shows-coinciding-with-seven-new-year-s-eve-firework-countdowns-2024-12-31-1.736022]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Global Village announces seven drone shows coinciding with seven New Year’s Eve firework countdowns]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2024-12-31T18:44:28+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2024-12-31T18:45:38+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p><strong>-&nbsp; A new surprise unveiled, adding to the packed calendar of festivities taking place at the destination tonight 31 December 2024.</strong></p>

<p><strong>-&nbsp; Countdowns to light up the sky at 8:00PM, 9:00PM, 10:00PM, 10:30PM, 11:00PM: 12:00AM and 1:00AM.</strong></p>

<p><strong>- All celebrations and activations are included in the entry ticket for every guest to enjoy.</strong></p>

<p><strong>-&nbsp; Park is open on NYE from 4:00PM to 2:00AM welcoming families, couples and ladies.</strong></p>

<p><strong>- Watch the festivities video here</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>Global Village, the region&rsquo;s premier multicultural family destination for entertainment, dining, shopping, and attractions, has announced the demonstration of seven drone shows, each perfectly timed to coincide with one of the seven New Year&rsquo;s Eve firework countdowns. The unveiled surprise is the latest addition to the signature celebrations the park is set to host tonight 31 December 2024 at 8:00PM, 9:00PM, 10:00PM, 10:30PM, 11:00PM: 12:00AM and 1:00AM.</p>

<p>As part of its dedication to delivering new guest experiences every season, Global Village has featured the drone show display to its New Year&rsquo;s Eve activations for the first time. The show will illuminate the sky above the destination jointly with the renowned firework displays amidst the on-ground festivities. Highlights include Main Stage live performances, extravagant DJ show and several roaming entertainment acts across the park. All celebrations are part of the Global Village&rsquo;s entry ticket, ensuring every guest can fully enjoy the flagship experience.</p>

<p>With Global Village named the leading destination for exploring cultural diversity and proudly hosting guests from across the world, each drone show will present the &lsquo;Happy New Year&rsquo; message alongside the firework display, marking the arrival of the New Year in a different time zone.</p>

<p>End-of-year shopping experiences across 30 cultural pavilions and 3,500 shopping outlets as well as 250+ dining options and over 200 rides and entertainment attractions are all available throughout the night for adults, teens and children visiting.</p>

<p>The destination&rsquo;s three renowned gates will open on the New Year&rsquo;s Eve exclusively from 4:00PM to 2:00AM, welcoming guests from families, couples and ladies.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/global-village-announces-seven-drone-shows-coinciding-with-seven-new-year-s-eve-firework-countdowns-2024-12-31-1.736022"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736023.1735656204!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="Lifestyle"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[-  A new surprise unveiled, adding to the packed calendar of festivities taking place at the destination tonight 31 ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[E247]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/uae/uae-president-issues-federal-decree-appointing-sultan-al-dhaheri-as-director-of-office-of-deputy-chairman-of-presidential-court-for-special-affairs-2024-12-31-1.736020]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[UAE President issues Federal Decree appointing Sultan Al Dhaheri as Director of Office of Deputy Chairman of Presidential Court for Special Affairs]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2024-12-31T18:41:48+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2024-12-31T18:42:16+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan issued a Federal Decree appointing His Excellency Sultan Hamad Ahmad Hamad Al Mutawa Al Dhaheri as Director of the Office of the Deputy Chairman of the Presidential Court for Special Affairs with the rank of Undersecretary.</p>

<p>The Decree shall be published in the official gazette and shall be effective from the date of issuance.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/uae/uae-president-issues-federal-decree-appointing-sultan-al-dhaheri-as-director-of-office-of-deputy-chairman-of-presidential-court-for-special-affairs-2024-12-31-1.736020"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736021.1735656081!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="UAE"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan issued a Federal Decree appointing His Excellency Sultan ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[WAM]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/uae/hamdan-bin-mohammed-meets-with-dignitaries-and-senior-officials-at-za-abeel-majlis-2024-12-31-1.736018]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed meets with dignitaries and senior officials at Za'abeel Majlis]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2024-12-31T18:36:02+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2024-12-31T18:37:22+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Vision, innovation and teamwork are key drivers of Dubai&rsquo;s development journey, says His Highness</p>

<p>&ldquo;As we welcome the New Year, our focus remains on advancing our goals with optimism and determination, and transforming challenges into opportunities to create a brighter future&rdquo;</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defence of the UAE, and Chairman of The Executive Council of Dubai, underscored the vital role of strategic vision, teamwork, and innovation, in driving Dubai&#39;s sustainable development journey.</p>

<p>Speaking at a meeting with dignitaries and senior officials at the Za&#39;abeel Majlis, Sheikh Hamdan outlined Dubai&#39;s focus on groundbreaking initiatives that set new benchmarks of excellence across sectors. The event was attended by Her Highness Sheikha Latifa bint Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Chairperson of the Dubai Culture and Arts Authority; His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum; and several ministers and senior officials.</p>

<p>Extending his New Year greetings to all attendees, Sheikh Hamdan urged them to continue their efforts to enhance Dubai&#39;s global reputation. &ldquo;As we welcome the New Year, our focus remains on advancing our goals with optimism and determination, and transforming challenges into opportunities to create a brighter future,&rdquo; he said.</p>

<p>Innovative projects and services that exceed expectations are vital to ensuring Dubai remains one of the world&rsquo;s best cities to live, work and visit, he said. Highlighting Dubai&#39;s global reputation for quality of life and economic opportunity, he said outstanding services, sustainable development initiatives, and programmes to empower national talent, particularly youth, are critical to maintaining this status.<br />
Stressing further on the need to develop young national talent, he said: &ldquo;Empowering our youth to take on leading roles across sectors is essential to achieving our vision for the future.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The meeting also highlighted Dubai&#39;s outstanding achievements in 2024, including exceptional advancements in innovation and technology, robust growth in the digital economy, and strengthened capabilities in financial and logistical services. Dubai&#39;s tourism sector continued to thrive, further consolidating the emirate&#39;s reputation as a global business and leisure destination.<br />
With its forward-thinking policies and dynamic leadership, Dubai is poised to enter the new year with a renewed commitment to progress and innovation, His Highness said.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/uae/hamdan-bin-mohammed-meets-with-dignitaries-and-senior-officials-at-za-abeel-majlis-2024-12-31-1.736018"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736019.1735655817!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="UAE"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[Vision, innovation and teamwork are key drivers of Dubai’s development journey, says His Highness “As we welcome the ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[E247]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-receives-prince-khalid-bin-salman-2024-12-31-1.736014]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[UAE President receives Prince Khalid bin Salman]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2024-12-31T13:40:38+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2024-12-31T13:48:33+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan today received His Royal Highness Prince Khalid bin Salman bin Abdulaziz Al Saud, Minister of Defence of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, in the presence of His Highness Sheikh Mansour bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Vice President, Deputy Prime Minister and Chairman of the Presidential Court.</p>

<p>During the meeting, which took place at Qasr Al Shati in Abu Dhabi, His Royal Highness Prince Khalid bin Salman conveyed the greetings of the Custodian of the Two Holy Mosques, King Salman bin Abdulaziz Al Saud, and His Royal Highness Prince Mohammed bin Salman bin Abdulaziz Al Saud, Crown Prince and Prime Minister of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, to His Highness the UAE President, as well as their wishes for the UAE to experience continued progress and prosperity.</p>

<p>In turn, His Highness the UAE President conveyed his greetings to the Custodian of the Two Holy Mosques and Crown Prince, expressing his wishes for the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia to achieve further progress and prosperity under its leadership.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan and His Royal Highness Prince Khalid bin Salman discussed the deep-rooted relations between the two countries and ways to advance cooperation in all fields to support their common interests and achieve the aspirations of their peoples for development and prosperity.</p>

<p>The meeting also addressed developments in the Middle East, regional and international issues of shared interest, and the importance of enhancing efforts to maintain regional security, peace, and stability.</p>

<p>The meeting was attended by Sheikh Mohamed bin Hamad bin Tahnoun Al Nahyan, Advisor to the UAE President, Ali bin Hammad Al Shamsi, Secretary-General of the Supreme Council for National Security, and Dr. Ahmed Mubarak Al Mazrouei, Chairman of the President&rsquo;s Office for Strategic Affairs and Chairman of the Abu Dhabi Executive Office.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-president-receives-prince-khalid-bin-salman-2024-12-31-1.736014"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736015.1735638020!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="World"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[President His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan today received His Royal Highness Prince Khalid bin Salman ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[WAM]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/business/energy/fuel-prices-remain-stable-in-the-uae-for-january-2025-2024-12-31-1.736012]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Fuel Prices Remain Stable in the UAE for January 2025]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2024-12-31T10:59:10+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2024-12-31T10:59:35+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The UAE&#39;s Fuel Price Committee has announced the gasoline and diesel prices for January 2025, which remain stable compared to previous rates. The prices are as follows:</p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Diesel:</strong> AED 2.68 per liter</li>
	<li><strong>Super 98 Gasoline:</strong> AED 2.61 per liter</li>
	<li><strong>Special 95 Gasoline:</strong> AED 2.50 per liter</li>
	<li><strong>E-Plus 91 Gasoline:</strong> AED 2.43 per liter</li>
</ul>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/business/energy/fuel-prices-remain-stable-in-the-uae-for-january-2025-2024-12-31-1.736012"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736013.1735628316!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="Business/Energy"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[The UAE's Fuel Price Committee has announced the gasoline and diesel prices for January 2025, which remain stable ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[E247]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/world/hamdan-bin-mohammed-meets-with-italy-s-defence-minister-in-abu-dhabi-2024-12-30-1.736016]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Hamdan bin Mohammed meets with Italy’s Defence Minister in Abu Dhabi]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2024-12-30T23:45:00+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2024-12-31T13:47:10+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai and Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defence of the UAE, met today in Abu Dhabi with His Excellency Guido Crosetto, Italy&rsquo;s Minister of Defence, in the presence of His Excellency Mohamed bin Mubarak Fadhel Al Mazrouei, Minister of State for Defence Affairs, and a number of senior officials from both sides.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Hamdan extended a warm welcome to His Excellency Guido Crosetto, highlighting his visit as a reflection of the deep and time-tested relations between the two friendly countries and peoples, and the spirit of partnership and cooperation that drives new opportunities for bilateral ties at various levels.</p>

<p>During the meeting, the two sides focused on enhancing bilateral relations and ways to further boost cooperation across various fields, with particular emphasis on increasing defence collaboration and partnerships that benefit industries catering to the defence sector. They also highlighted the importance of bilateral visits and the sharing of expertise and best practices in ensuring the development of new defence technologies and improving the military preparedness and efficiency of defence personnel. Such efforts are vital to safeguarding the larger interests of both countries and realising the aspirations of their peoples, the two sides concurred.</p>

<p>The meeting also reviewed the latest regional and international developments, with the situation in the Middle East drawing particular attention. The two sides emphasised the importance of intensifying international cooperation to advance efforts to promote peace and stability across the wider region, thus helping countries in the region achieve their development goals.</p>

<p>His Highness Sheikh Hamdan, accompanied by His Excellency Guido Crosetto, also visited the famed Italian naval training vessel Amerigo Vespucci, which anchored at Zayed Port as part of global tour. The ship is one of the world&rsquo;s few remaining examples of sailing ships that are still in active service and the port call in Abu Dhabi marks its first visit to the UAE in its 93-year history.<br />
At the conclusion of the tour, Sheikh Hamdan, accompanied by the Italian Minister of Defence, recorded a message in the VIP guestbook highlighting the ship&rsquo;s missions of maritime diplomacy and protection of the marine environment, besides its significance as a proud symbol of maritime heritage for the Italian Navy.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/world/hamdan-bin-mohammed-meets-with-italy-s-defence-minister-in-abu-dhabi-2024-12-30-1.736016"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736017.1735638248!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="World"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[His Highness Sheikh Hamdan bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Crown Prince of Dubai and Deputy Prime Minister and ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[E247]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/world/earthquake-of-magnitude-5-6-strikes-luzon-philippines-2024-12-30-1.736010]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Earthquake of magnitude 5.6 strikes Luzon, Philippines]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2024-12-30T11:08:18+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2024-12-30T11:08:44+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A magnitude 5.6 earthquake struck Luzon in the Philippines on Monday, the German Research Centre for Geosciences (GFZ) said.</p>

<p>The quake was at a depth of 10 kilometres (6.2 miles), GFZ said.</p>

<p>Philippine&#39;s seismology agency Phivolcs said the tremor struck the northern town of Bangui in Ilocos province. The agency was not expecting damage, but said aftershocks are likely from the shallow quake.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/world/earthquake-of-magnitude-5-6-strikes-luzon-philippines-2024-12-30-1.736010"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736011.1735542481!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="World"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[A magnitude 5.6 earthquake struck Luzon in the Philippines on Monday, the German Research Centre for Geosciences (GFZ) ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[WAM]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-sends-three-aid-convoys-to-gaza-as-part-of-operation-chivalrous-knight-3-2024-12-30-1.736008]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[UAE sends three aid convoys to Gaza as part of Operation Chivalrous Knight 3]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2024-12-30T11:06:56+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2024-12-30T11:07:24+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Three convoys carrying diverse Emirati humanitarian aid crossed into Gaza this week through the Rafah border crossing, as part of the UAE&rsquo;s efforts to support and assist the Palestinian people during the ongoing crisis under Operation Chivalrous Knight 3.</p>

<p>The convoys comprised 28 trucks loaded with more than 445 tonnes of humanitarian aid, including relief materials such as flour, food parcels, winter clothing, and other essential supplies.</p>

<p>This brings the total number of aid convoys sent to Gaza under Operation Chivalrous Knight 3 to 147, comprising 2,245 trucks.</p>

<p>Through its humanitarian initiative, Operation Chivalrous Knight 3, the UAE continues to reaffirm its role in providing relief since the onset of the crisis in Gaza.</p>

<p>The initiative aims to support the Palestinian people, alleviate their suffering, and meet their urgent needs during these challenging times. This includes implementing relief projects to ease the hardships of displaced Palestinian families, demonstrating a humanitarian commitment to aiding those in need.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/world/uae-sends-three-aid-convoys-to-gaza-as-part-of-operation-chivalrous-knight-3-2024-12-30-1.736008"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736009.1735542402!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="World"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[Three convoys carrying diverse Emirati humanitarian aid crossed into Gaza this week through the Rafah border crossing, ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[WAM]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/world/former-us-president-jimmy-carter-dies-at-100-2024-12-30-1.736006]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Former US president Jimmy Carter dies at 100]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2024-12-30T11:04:45+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2024-12-30T11:04:55+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Jimmy Carter, a Nobel Peace Prize laureate, died at his home in Georgia on Sunday, the Carter Centre, a nonprofit organisation, said. He was 100.</p>

<p>The Carter Centre said there will be public observances in Atlanta and Washington. These events will be followed by a private interment in Plains, it said.</p>

<p>Final arrangements for the former president&#39;s state funeral are still pending.</p>

<p>Carter served as the 39th US president from 1977 to 1981. He was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 2002 in recognition of his &quot;untiring effort to find peaceful solutions to international conflicts, to advance democracy and human rights, and to promote economic and social development.&quot;</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/world/former-us-president-jimmy-carter-dies-at-100-2024-12-30-1.736006"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736007.1735542246!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="World"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[Former US President Jimmy Carter, a Nobel Peace Prize laureate, died at his home in Georgia on Sunday, the Carter ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[E247]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/uae/final-deadline-for-visa-violators-in-the-uae-ends-tomorrow-2024-12-30-1.736004]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Final Deadline for Visa Violators in the UAE Ends Tomorrow]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2024-12-30T10:54:07+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2024-12-30T10:54:33+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The deadline for regularizing the status of residency law violators in the UAE concludes tomorrow. The Federal Authority for Identity, Citizenship, Customs, and Port Security had extended the grace period by an additional two months, allowing violators to rectify their status without incurring fines or administrative penalties. Initially, the deadline was set to end on October 31, 2024.</p>

<h3><strong>Last Chance to Benefit</strong></h3>

<p>The Authority urged violators of the residency law currently residing in the UAE to take advantage of the final three days of the grace period. They are encouraged to visit service centers across the country to amend their status and benefit from the opportunities provided. Thousands of violators have already utilized this window to either regularize their status or leave the country without facing any financial penalties.</p>

<p>The decision to extend the grace period coincided with the UAE&#39;s celebrations of its 53rd National Day, reflecting the nation&#39;s humanitarian and progressive values. The extension was also in response to appeals from violators seeking to settle their status, either by leaving the country or securing employment contracts to stay legally. The Federal Authority has been actively coordinating through official channels and conducting in-depth studies to evaluate public response and the volume of applications processed at service centers nationwide, particularly in the final days of the initial deadline.</p>

<h3><strong>Fraudulent Practices Uncovered</strong></h3>

<p>Lieutenant General Mohammed Al Marri noted that many violators fell victim to fraudulent practices in their home countries before arriving in the UAE. These individuals were misled into paying fees for visas and promised job opportunities in the UAE, only to discover upon arrival that such opportunities did not exist. He emphasized that these fraudulent schemes are not confined to specific countries but are a widespread issue perpetrated by traffickers globally.</p>

<h3><strong>Successful Employment for Violators</strong></h3>

<p>Al Marri also highlighted the success of Dubai authorities in securing employment for a significant number of violators within the private sector. The Labor Committee in Dubai worked daily with companies seeking workers, facilitating interviews and placements for violators already present in the country. This initiative helped many individuals transition from violating residency regulations to becoming legally employed contributors to the UAE&#39;s economy.</p>

<p>The Authority continues to urge all violators to take immediate action and seize this final opportunity to regularize their status or leave the country without penalties.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/uae/final-deadline-for-visa-violators-in-the-uae-ends-tomorrow-2024-12-30-1.736004"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736005.1735541875!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="UAE"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[The deadline for regularizing the status of residency law violators in the UAE concludes tomorrow. The Federal ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[E247]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/dubai-set-to-amaze-the-world-with-spectacular-new-year-celebrations-2024-12-30-1.735999]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Dubai Set to Amaze the World with Spectacular New Year Celebrations]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2024-12-30T08:04:00+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2024-12-30T06:23:36+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
	<li><strong>Broadcast live, on Dubai Media Incorporated&rsquo;s flagship channels, including Dubai One TV, these festivities highlight the spirit of the city&rsquo;s glamour as 2024 ends and 2025 is welcomed in style.&nbsp;</strong></li>
</ul>

<p>As the countdown begins, all eyes will be on Dubai&rsquo;s iconic landmarks. From the world&rsquo;s tallest building, Burj Khalifa, to The Palm&rsquo;s The Pointe and the historic Al Seef district, the emirate will come alive with breathtaking fireworks displays and choreographed drone shows. The dazzling light and pyrotechnic spectacle at Burj Khalifa, lasting from 11:50 PM to 12:10 AM, promises to be the centrepiece, captivating global audiences and thousands of visitors in attendance.</p>

<p>Dubai Media Inc. (DMI) has announced its comprehensive plans to cover Dubai&rsquo;s highly anticipated New Year&rsquo;s Eve celebrations, showcasing the emirate&rsquo;s unmatched festive spirit and world-renowned attractions. Starting from Tuesday evening, December 31, 2024, until the early hours of January 1, 2025. Bringing the celebrations to life with exclusive broadcasts and special programming across its platforms and will broadcast the festivities across its channels, including Dubai TV and Sama Dubai, with unified programming starting at 11:00 PM.&nbsp;</p>

<p>From Dubai One TV, Amy Kitchingman will be delivering live updates and capturing the energy of the city&#39;s most iconic New Year&rsquo;s Eve destination. The program will provide an insider&rsquo;s look at Dubai&rsquo;s dazzling celebrations, featuring live reports, interactive segments, and exclusive stories highlighting the city&rsquo;s vibrancy as it welcomes 2025.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Emirati superstar Ahlam will perform as part of the &quot;In Love with Dubai&quot; program, a live New Year&rsquo;s Eve special hosted by Ahmed Abdullah and Roaa Al Sabban at 9pm on Dubai TV.</p>

<p>Alongside the show, Jad Shihab and Sally Saeed from Dubai TV will report from various other locations throughout the city, showcasing the vibrant celebrations and fireworks displays capturing the energy and excitement of the emirate as it ushers in the New Year.</p>

<p>Sarah Al Jarman, Senior Vice President of TV and Radio Channels at DMI, emphasized the global significance of Dubai&rsquo;s celebrations, stating: &ldquo;New Year&rsquo;s Eve in Dubai is a global event that highlights the emirate&rsquo;s ability to deliver extraordinary experiences. Our goal is to bring the spirit of Dubai to viewers worldwide, ensuring they witness the magic and grandeur of this remarkable city.&rdquo;</p>

<p>DMI&rsquo;s broadcast will also spotlight the meticulous planning and innovative logistics behind Dubai&rsquo;s New Year&rsquo;s celebrations, from seamless transportation provided by the Roads and Transport Authority to the safety measures led by Dubai Police. These celebrations include several iconic locations, like Dubai Frame, Festival City, Dubai Creek Harbour, and Expo City Dubai, will host immersive celebrations, featuring live entertainment, cultural displays, and family-friendly activities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As the world turns its gaze to Dubai this New Year&rsquo;s Eve, DMI&rsquo;s coverage promises to showcase the city as a beacon of innovation, culture, and celebration, making it the ultimate global destination to welcome 2025.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/dubai-set-to-amaze-the-world-with-spectacular-new-year-celebrations-2024-12-30-1.735999"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736003.1735525398!/image/image.jpg" />
																<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736001.1735491745!/image/image.jpg" />
																<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.736000.1735492188!/image/image.png" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="Lifestyle"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[Broadcast live, on Dubai Media Incorporated’s flagship channels, including Dubai One TV, these festivities highlight ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[E247]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/health/uae-government-issues-federal-decree-law-on-medical-products-pharmacy-profession-pharmaceutical-establishments-2024-12-29-1.735997]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[UAE Government issues Federal Decree-Law on medical products, pharmacy profession, pharmaceutical establishments]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2024-12-29T18:56:01+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2024-12-29T18:56:37+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The UAE Government has issued a Federal Decree-Law to regulate medical products, the pharmacy profession, and pharmaceutical establishments.</p>

<p>The objectives include solidifying the UAE&rsquo;s position as a globally trusted hub for pharmaceutical and medical industries, enhancing pharmaceutical security, and streamlining the development, approval, manufacturing, marketing, and distribution of medical products, all in adherence to international standards and competitive costs and timelines.</p>

<p>The provisions of the Decree-Law apply to all medical products, including drug products, medical devices, pharmaceutical products, healthcare products, biological products, dietary supplements, cosmetics, and genetically modified organism products intended for medical use. It also covers chemical precursors, controlled substances, semi-controlled substances, and hazardous or toxic materials for human and veterinary use.</p>

<p>The Decree-Law governs all pharmaceutical establishments and biobanks within the UAE, including those located in free zones. It applies to pharmacies, pharmacy chains, compounding pharmacies, medical warehouses, medical storage facilities, manufacturing facilities, contract-based manufacturing companies, marketing firms, pharmaceutical consulting firms, pharmaceutical laboratories, pre-clinical and clinical research entities, bioequivalence centres, biobanks, contract-based research and development companies, and other pharmaceutical establishments specified by the UAE Cabinet.</p>

<p>Additionally, the law encompasses practitioners of the pharmacy profession operating across the UAE, including within free zones.</p>

<p>The Decree-Law regulates all aspects of licencing, monitoring, and supervising pharmaceutical establishments and biobanks. It includes provisions for ownership transfers, temporary suspensions, precautionary closures, and licence revocations. The legislation outlines the roles and responsibilities of the Emirates Drug Establishment, the Ministry of Health and Prevention, and local health authorities.</p>

<p>Under the law, manufacturing facilities, contract-based manufacturing companies, medical warehouses, medical storage facilities, marketing firms, pharmaceutical consulting firms, and pharmaceutical laboratories are subject to licencing and monitoring by the Emirates Drug Establishment.</p>

<p>Biobanks, pre-clinical and clinical research entities, contract-based research and development companies, and bioequivalence centres fall under the jurisdiction of either the Emirates Drug Establishment or the relevant local health authorities, each within its jurisdiction.</p>

<p>Pharmacies, pharmacy chains, compounding pharmacies, blood storage units in hospitals, and medical stores in government health facilities with activities limited to storage are regulated by the ministry or the relevant local health authorities, each within its jurisdiction.</p>

<p>The Decree-Law prioritises fostering investment in the pharmaceutical sector by introducing an incentive framework to attract investments and encourage innovation and development within the medical industries. The Cabinet will issue a decision to establish this framework based on a proposal by the Chairman of the Emirates Drug Establishment in consultation with relevant health authorities and other stakeholders.</p>

<p>The Decree-Law also includes provisions to protect innovation by implementing a regulated protection mechanism for documents and data related to innovative medical products or those containing at least one new active ingredient, whether developed domestically or imported.</p>

<p>For the first time, the Emirates Drug Establishment is authorised to develop, publish, and update the UAE Pharmacopeia, approve reference pharmacopeias, and issue guidelines and standards for good practices aligned with internationally recognised principles.</p>

<p>The Decree-Law establishes clear conditions for granting marketing authorisations for medical products, including exclusive marketing authorisations, conditional marketing authorisations, and emergency use authorisations.</p>

<p>It introduces a fast-track approval pathway for innovative medical products of therapeutic importance and other qualifying medical products, ensuring compliance with international standards of quality, safety, and efficacy.</p>

<p>The legislation regulates all aspects of managing medical products, encompassing development, manufacturing, registration, pricing, import, export, circulation, distribution, possession, marketing, sale, use and safe disposal.</p>

<p>It includes general provisions for developing and manufacturing medical products in compliance with good practice guidelines issued by the Emirates Drug Establishment and aligned with international standards. For the first time, the law permits the transfer of excipients and solvents between licenced manufacturing facilities within the UAE, subject to approval by the Emirates Drug Establishment.</p>

<p>The Decree-Law also regulates the advertising, promotion, import, export, and re-export of medical products under the supervision of the Emirates Drug Establishment.</p>

<p>Moreover, the Decree-Law defines the provisions regulating the pricing of medical products and establishes the &ldquo;Pharmaceutical Policies Committee&rdquo;, working under the Chairperson of the Board of Directors of the Emirates Drug Establishment. The new law also requires pharmacy practitioners in the UAE to obtain a licence from the Ministry of Health and Prevention or the competent local health authority and specifies the duties of pharmacists and the activities that a clinical pharmacist is authorised to practice.</p>

<p>The Decree-Law regulates the provisions tied to the pharmacovigilance system in the UAE, ensuring the safe use of medical products and reducing side effects and adverse reactions. Additionally, it regulates, for the first time, the provisions for establishing and managing national databases for medical products, pharmaceutical facilities, and biobanks in the UAE.</p>

<p>The Decree-Law prescribes disciplinary measures for violations, including written warnings and financial fines ranging from AED1,000 to AED1 million for pharmaceutical establishments and biobanks and up to AED500,000 for practitioners of the pharmacy profession.</p>

<p>Penalties may also include temporary suspension of licences for up to six months or license revocation for severe breaches.</p>

<p>Entities and individuals covered under the law are granted a one-year grace period to comply with its provisions, with the possibility of an extension through a Cabinet decision.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/health/uae-government-issues-federal-decree-law-on-medical-products-pharmacy-profession-pharmaceutical-establishments-2024-12-29-1.735997"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735998.1735484149!/image/image.jpeg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="Health"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[The UAE Government has issued a Federal Decree-Law to regulate medical products, the pharmacy profession, and ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[E247]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/world/abdullah-bin-zayed-receives-iranian-foreign-minister-2024-12-29-1.735995]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[Abdullah bin Zayed receives Iranian Foreign Minister]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2024-12-29T18:54:46+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2024-12-29T18:54:55+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;H.H. Sheikh Abdullah bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Foreign Affairs, today received Abbas Araghchi, Minister of Foreign Affairs of the Islamic Republic of Iran.</p>

<p>During the meeting, they discussed bilateral relations between the two countries and ways to enhance them to serve their mutual interests.</p>

<p>The two top diplomats also reviewed the overall situation in the region, discussed current regional developments, and exchanged views on various issues of mutual concern.</p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/world/abdullah-bin-zayed-receives-iranian-foreign-minister-2024-12-29-1.735995"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735996.1735484048!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="World"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[ H.H. Sheikh Abdullah bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Foreign Affairs, today received Abbas ]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[WAM]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
		<entry>
					<id><![CDATA[https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/2025-new-year-s-celebrations-in-dubai-faqs-2024-12-29-1.735993]]></id>
				<title type="text"><![CDATA[2025 New Year's Celebrations in Dubai – FAQs]]></title>
		<published><![CDATA[2024-12-29T18:42:25+04:00]]></published>
		<updated><![CDATA[2024-12-29T18:49:30+04:00]]></updated>
		<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Where are the fireworks and drone show locations for the 2025 New Year&#39;s celebrations</p>

<p><a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dubai-events-calendar/nye-downtown-dubai"><strong>Burj Park</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li>Time: 11:59 PM</li>
	<li>Location: Burj Park &ndash; Opposite Burj Khalifa</li>
</ul>

<h1><strong>Burj Al Arab</strong></h1>

<ul>
	<li>Time: 11:59 PM</li>
	<li>Location: Burj Al Arab &ndash; Jumeirah</li>
</ul>

<h1><strong><a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dubai-events-calendar/dsf-drones-light-show">Dubai Shopping Festival (DSF) Drones Show</a></strong></h1>

<ul>
	<li>Time: 8:00 PM and 10:00 PM</li>
	<li>Location: Bluewaters and The Beach opposite Jumeirah Beach Residence</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://www.visitdubai.com/en/whats-on/dubai-events-calendar/dsf-fireworks-nights"><strong>Dubai Shopping Festival (DSF) Fireworks</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li>Time: 11:59 PM</li>
	<li>Location: Dubai Festival City Mall, Al Seef, Bluewaters, The Beach opposite Jumeirah Beach Residence, and Hatta<strong><span dir="RTL">.</span></strong></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://marine.rta.ae/rta_b2c/opentickets.html"><strong>Marine Transportation</strong></a></p>

<ul>
	<li>Departure locations for cruises: Marina Mall, Al Ghubaiba, Bluewaters, Al Fahidi, and Al Jaddaf.</li>
	<li>Advance booking is recommended through <a href="mailto:marinebooking@rta.ae" target="_blank">marinebooking@rta.ae</a> to secure a starting point nearest to your location.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>How can I reach the celebration sites?</strong></p>

<p>You can proceed to the celebration sites either by private vehicles or by using public transportation. The Dubai Metro is a convenient option considering there might be street closures in the areas surrounding the designated celebration sites. It is advisable to head to the venues early before road closures take effect to avoid traffic congestion and ensure a comfortable, safe, and secure experience<span dir="RTL">.</span></p>

<p><strong>Which roads will be closed in Dubai in preparation for the celebrations? And what are the closure timings</strong><strong><span dir="RTL">?</span></strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Al Asayel Street will be closed to traffic at exactly 4:00 pm, notably the stretch from Oud Metha Street towards the Burj Khalifa area.</li>
	<li>Mohammed Bin Rashid Boulevard, Burj Khalifa Street, and Future Street will be closed starting from 4:00 pm as the parking spaces in these areas reach full capacity. Members of the public who have reserved places at establishments in the Boulevard area or Dubai Mall are advised to arrive before 4:00 pm on Tuesday.</li>
	<li>Lower Financial Center Street will be closed around 4:00 pm. On Upper Financial Center Street and Sukuk Street, traffic restrictions will be enforced from 8:00 pm.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>What are the alternative routes that can be used to access other areas near the celebration sites during the closure of the roads leading to those sites?</strong></p>

<p>Sheikh Zayed Road will remain fully open until a partial closure takes effect at 11:00 pm. Alternatively, the public can use Jumeirah Street, Al Wasl Street, Sheikh Mohammed Bin Zayed Road, and Al Khail Road.</p>

<p><strong>Where can I park my private vehicle on arriving at a celebration site?</strong></p>

<p>Park your vehicle in one of the designated parking areas so that you can enjoy the events and festivities undisturbed. Be mindful of others&rsquo; safety and comfort while parking your vehicle. Avoid parking in the middle of the road, which causes traffic obstruction and inconvenience to others.</p>

<p><strong>Can I bring my children to the celebration sites?</strong></p>

<p>Celebrating with family and friends makes the festivities even more enjoyable, but please be mindful of children&#39;s safety, especially in crowded areas. Always keep a close eye on the children in your group and ensure they stay by your side right through. It is preferable for children to wear safety wristbands.</p>

<p><strong>What should I do if myself, a family member, or someone present at the location, experiences an injury or a medical emergency?</strong></p>

<p>You should call the emergency number 998 to report any medical emergencies, or promptly contact a Dubai Police officer or security personnel present at the location. They will take the necessary steps to summon one of the ambulance teams present at the location to provide the necessary medical assistance.</p>

<p><strong>Are ambulance services available across all New Year&#39;s celebration sites?</strong></p>

<p>Dubai always ensures the comfort, safety, and security of everyone during all major events and occasions by providing all services that guarantee the swiftest response during emergencies of any kind. Specialised teams are available at all New Year&#39;s celebration sites to provide first aid services, in addition to which ambulance teams are always at hand to deal with cases that require urgent medical intervention.</p>

<p><strong>Are all celebration sites secured in the event of a fire?</strong></p>

<p>Preparedness for all kinds of emergencies, including fire, is a top priority for Dubai&#39;s Events Security Committee (ESC). Civil Defense teams are stationed at various celebration sites, as is the case with all major events hosted by Dubai throughout the year. Ensuring everyone&rsquo;s safety and security is a responsibility Dubai takes very seriously and always places topmost amongst its priorities.</p>

<p><strong>What should I do if I find a lost bag or personal belongings at celebrations sites?</strong></p>

<p>Please inform the police or security personnel present at the location. Your cooperation is key in ensuring that lost items are returned to their owners.</p>

<p><strong>What should I do if I lose my bag or some of my belongings during the festivities?</strong></p>

<p>You should inform Dubai Police or any security personnel present at the location, leave your contact information, and provide a detailed description of the lost items. You will be contacted to come and collect them as soon as they are found.</p>

<p><strong>Can I bring family picnic items to the celebration site?</strong></p>

<p>Avoid carrying large bags or items to the celebration sites to ensure smooth entry and movement within the venue. This ensures everyone&#39;s comfort and allows for an enjoyable and hassle-free experience for all attendees.</p>

<p><strong>What are the general guidelines that I should observe when present at any of the celebration sites?</strong></p>

<p>Follow the instructions provided by security personnel at the celebration site as well as the instructional signs at the location.</p>

<p>Adhere to traffic rules and regulations and give priority to pedestrians crossing at designated areas.</p>

<p>Avoid crowding or pushing and use designated pedestrian areas.</p>

<p>Be considerate of others and avoid behaviours that may cause distress or spoil the festive mood<span dir="RTL">.</span></p>]]></content>
					<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.emirates247.com/lifestyle/2025-new-year-s-celebrations-in-dubai-faqs-2024-12-29-1.735993"/>	
				
														<link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" length="1337" href="https://www.emirates247.com/polopoly_fs/1.735994.1735483586!/image/image.jpg" />
											
				
					
											
													
											
											
					<!-- Specifies a category that the entry belongs to. A entry may have multiple category elements.  -->
			<category term="Lifestyle"/>
				<summary type="text"><![CDATA[Where are the fireworks and drone show locations for the 2025 New Year's celebrations Burj Park Time: 11:59 PM Location]]></summary>
		
					<author>
				<name><![CDATA[E247]]></name>
			</author>		
						<rights type="html"><![CDATA[]]></rights>
	</entry>
	</feed>
